Chapter Leadership

Spoiler: Chapter Master

Name: Gabriel Angelos

Traits:

Chapter Master: "We shall not falter, my brothers. Never again, not so long as I breathe."
Significant Bionics: "My injuries nearly required internment in a dreadnought, but in the end did not. I still serve regardless."
Compassionate: "The protection of the Imperium and its citizens is one of our greatest responsibilities."
Faithful: "May the holy God Emperor find us worthy."

Prior History:

Captain of the Blood Raven's Third Company, Master of the Arsenal
Renegade of the Blood Ravens +Status as Renegade Redacted By Inquisitor Adrastia, Ordo Hereticus+

Characteristics:
Weapon Skill: 8
Ballistic Skill: 4
Strength: 6+1=7
Toughness: 8
Agility: 6
Intelligence: 8
Perception: 7
Willpower: 10
Fellowship: 9

Legendary Characteristics:

Legendary Willpower: (Raven's Will: Unyielding and unbending. Had to have it to push through the trials that the Blood Ravens have been through in the past quarter of a century.)

Current Characteristic Advancement Progress:
Ballistic Skill From 4 to 5: 164+62+Cyrus(25)=251/500]

Personal Wargear:

Godsplitter - Ordo Xenos-crafted Relic Daemonhammer (+1 Strength, +Blast Damage, +Anti-Daemon Effects) [Special Characteristics: Master Crafted, Shard of Biel-Tan Avatar Wailing Doom Weapon Implanted In Hammer]
Armor of Azariah - Legendary Terminator Armor, once worn by the Great Father Himself
Body of Gabriel - Master Crafted Bionics (Able to Survive Wounds That Would Kill A More Fleshy Marine)
Plasma Pistol
Iron Halo

Spoiler: Chapter Master's Bodyguard

Name: Apollo Diomedes

Traits:

The Bitter Champion: "All my glories are ash. I am nothing but my duty, now."
Desperate Devotee: "Please, oh God-Emperor, grant me strength against my own folly."
Elder Veteran: "In my centuries of service I have fought horrors undreamed of by many."

Prior History: Former Captain of 1st Company, Former Captain of Honor Guard, Former Right Hand of Kyras

Characteristics:
Weapon Skill: 10
Ballistic Skill: 4
Strength: 10
Toughness: 6
Agility: 9
Intelligence: 5
Perception: 5
Willpower: 6
Fellowship: 3

Legendary Characteristics:

Legendary Weapon Skill: (Bitter Blooded Champion - Automatically hits all Non-Hero units, damage dealt and skill checks receive no malus regardless of injuries sustained. Critical damage increased.)
Legendary Strength: (The Might of the Raven - The character may now operate vehicle-scale weaponry for no penalty and can inflict damage through armored targets even without a Power Weapon.)

Personal Wargear:

Standard Mk-VII 'Aquilla' Power Armor
Rogal's Fist - Power Mace said to have been forged by the very hands of Rogal Dorn himself. (Extreme Durability, Powerfield Extremely Powerful, +Impact, +Critical)
Bolt Pistol

Spoiler: Chief Librarian

Name: Justinius Probalis

Traits:

Psychic Fires: "Burn! Burn you mongrels!"
Foresight: "The Eldar believe only they can pierce the veil. They are wrong."
Encyclopedic Knowledge Of Librarian Lores: "If you cannot master the knowledge available, then you must at least come as close as possible through study."

Divination
Codex Astartes
Fulmination
Technomancy
Geokinesis
Etc...

Blood Raven Psychic Lore Master

Spoiler: Battle Sight

Battle Sight - Blood Ravens Librarians can pierce the fog of war with a thought, casting their mind far and wide across a battlefield, world, or even star system for hints and clues to the movements and deployments of their enemies that may have gone undetected by more conventional technological means. A Librarian may use this psychic power in two different ways, choosing its application before he manifests it. The first application of this power is to gain an immediate tactical edge in combat and is most useful when facing immediate battlefield threats. Used in this way, Battle Sight reveals the position of all enemies within range that have hostile intentions toward the Librarian (i.e. intend to do the Librarian harm). This does not track the movements of these enemies or their actions, but simply informs the Librarian of their presence, direction, and distance from his current location. In addition to revealing foes, this power allows the Librarian to see through cover and concealment when making attacks against enemies revealed by Battle Sight. The second use of this power is to gain a broad strategic overview of an area and information on how better to complete a mission, or overcome a foe.

Spoiler: Truth Seeker

Truth Seeker - Blood Ravens Librarians spend much of their lives seeking knowledge and looking into the origins of their Chapter by sifting through the secrets of the past. Truth Seeker allows a Librarian to find details and clues that he might have otherwise missed, drawing his attention to areas or objects of interest.

Spoiler: Warp Whispers

Warp Whispers - The Librarian can listen to the babblings of the Warp and perceive the secrets of its denizens, sifting through the noise and maddening chatter to find grains of truth. It is a practise not without peril, however, and many Librarians dare not even attempt such follies, though those of the Blood Ravens know that true knowledge can never be gained without a degree of danger.

Prior History: Student of Jonah Orion, Epistolary of the 3rd Company

Characteristics:
Weapon Skill: 5
Ballistic Skill: 7
Strength: 5
Toughness: 6+1=7
Agility: 4
Intelligence: 8
Perception: 10
Willpower: 10
Fellowship: 5

Legendary Characteristics:

Legendary Perception: (Blood Ridden Gaze: Cloaked in his psychic powers, Justinius's gaze burns through attempts at stealth and trickery with all the fury of the chapter's bloody history. Before him, all is laid bare.)
Legendary Willpower: (Jonah's Legacy: Jonah Orion was one of the rarest of psykers in the galaxy, one who had battled the full force of the tyranid Hive Mind and kept moving forward. As a student of Jonah, and a survivor of his own trials, Justinius's will is unbreakable and proves a shield against even some of the most incredible of psychic forces in the galaxy.)

Personal Wargear:

Talonstaff of Jonah - Forged in the same vein as the daemonhammer Godsplitter, this Force Staff possesses a fragment of an Ulthwé Avatar of Khaine's Wailing Doom weapon implanted in it, as well as fragments of the Force Staff used by Jonah Orion. It crackles with a deadly energy that is anathema to warpspawn, and seems to carry with it the same unrelenting will of Jonah himself at times. (+1 Toughness, +Miscast Chance Reduction, +Anti-Daemon Effects) [Special Characteristics: Master Crafted, Shard of Ulthwé Avatar Wailing Doom Weapon Implanted In Force Staff]
Plasma Pistol
Psychic Hood
Hauberk of Faith - Otherwise normal Power Armor, strangely blessed by the Emperor. (Heightened Resistance To Daemons/Warp)
Raven's Aegis - A talisman crafted from the shards of felled Avatar of Khaine [Powerful Anti-Daemon/Warp Protection]

Spoiler: Master of Sanctity

Name: Hannibal Palrun

Traits:

Faithful: "For the Emperor! Let none find us wanting!"
Gigantic: "I do not question the Emperor for granting me this size. Neither should you, little one."
Champion Of The Commons: "We are all brothers in the eternal war for humanity's salvation, are we not?!"

Prior History: Chaplain of the 3rd Company

Characteristics:
Weapon Skill: 9
Ballistic Skill: 4
Strength: 8
Toughness: 9+1=10
Agility: 4
Intelligence: 6
Perception: 5
Willpower: 7
Fellowship: 10

Legendary Characteristics:

Legendary Fellowship: (Union of Hatred: Against the foes of the Imperium, his fiery hatred inspires similar fury in his fellows. When Hannibal is upon the field, this takes the effect of brothers around him striking with greater strength and accuracy depending on whether they partake in noble melee combat or the blessed works of ranged weaponry.)

Personal Wargear:

Thunder Blood - A Relic Crozius Arcanum crafted by Master of the Forge Martellus Ravias for the hands of Hannibal Palrun, Master of Sanctity. Such is its size that what is a mace for its wielder would be a two-handed weapon in the hands of any other. It's head is that of an enormous black Imperial aquila, the center crimson. (+Blast, +Advanced Disruption Field)
Azariah's Cincture - A blessed belt handed down by Azariah Vidya, the Great Father of the Blood Ravens. (+1 T, +Specially Reduces Melee Damage Dealt To Bearer)
Standard Mk-VII 'Aquilla' Power Armor
Rosarius
Bolt Pistol

Spoiler: Master of the Forge

Name: Martellus Ravias

Traits:

Scrapmaster: "I repaired an ancient Archaeotech Astronomic Array damaged by orks and tyranids while under constant assault for an entire year. Sometimes you have to make your own parts."
Agoraphobic: "I have no issue with taking the field. I am simply of the opinion that I've been in the field quite enough thank you. If anyone needs me, I'll be in the forges, where a Techmarine belongs."
Non-Traditional: "You do what you must, for survival. I will do what I must for the Chapter, for I am not sworn to follow all the edicts of Mars."

Prior History: Senior Techmarine of 4th Company, Attendant to Strike Cruiser Armageddon, Thunderhawk Pilot

Characteristics:
Weapon Skill: 4
Ballistic Skill: 5
Strength: 5
Toughness: 10+1=10(+)
Agility: 4
Intelligence: 10
Perception: 6
Willpower: 9
Fellowship: 6

Legendary Characteristics

Legendary Toughness (Sole Survivor: After surviving the destruction and crash of his Thunderhawk into a tyranid infested Typhon Primaris, surviving alone with no support for a full year while repairing an Archaeotech Astronomic Array, few things could possibly affect this Techmarine.)
Legendary Intelligence (Liege of the Forge: Automatically succeed at any repair attempts for war machines and wargear in regular use by the Imperium and the Chapter. May attempt to repair ancient Imperial relics, archeotech and esoteric technologies not often deployed by the Adeptus Mechanicus. Relics crafted will be of higher grades than standard.)

Personal Wargear:

Resilience of Typhon, Personally Crafted Power Armor and Servo Harness (+1 Toughness, Extreme Environmental Resilience)
Power Sword
Bolt Pistol

Spoiler: Master of the Apothecarion

Name: Nero Gracchus

Traits:

Greatly Experienced: "Whatever may be said of Aramus...we certainly fought quite a few things in our time."
Savant of Medicine: "I once had a Magos Biologis compliment me on my knowledge of medicine. What do you suppose that means?"

Prior History: Apothecary of the 5th Company

Characteristics:
Weapon Skill: 5
Ballistic Skill: 5
Strength: 6
Toughness: 6
Agility: 4
Intelligence: 10
Perception: 7
Willpower: 5
Fellowship: 4

Legendary Characteristics:

Legendary Intelligence: (A Fated Healer: Greatly increases survival of aspirants, neophytes and scout marines as they become Space Marines, can make attempts to save brothers from wounds that would otherwise most certainly be fatal)

Personal Wargear:

Blooded Narthecium - Personalized and modified narthecium by the Blood Raven medical savant Gracchus when he was but an apothecary of the 5th Company. (Additional Damage To Armored Infantry, Improved Gene-Seed Recovery Chances)
Standard Mk-VII 'Aquilla' Power Armor with Apothecary-standard modifications
Chain Sword
Bolt Pistol

Spoiler: Captain of the Honor Guard

Name: Jordis Mencis

Traits:

Ever-Training: "You can be faster, you can be stronger, you can be better. You will be better!"
Bond-Maker: "Together we can do more than you could ever imagine. Work as a team, succeed as a Chapter."
Guiding Hand of War: "War is the eternal lesson, test, and teacher. Let us study well, brothers."

Prior History

Assault Marine Sergeant of 2nd Company

Characteristics:
Weapon Skill: 9
Ballistic Skill: 8
Strength: 7
Toughness: 6
Agility: 5
Intelligence: 7
Perception: 7
Willpower: 7
Fellowship: 9

Personal Wargear:

Chainsword
Standard Mk-VII 'Aquilla' Power Armor
Bolt Pistol
Jump Pack

Spoiler: Captain of the 1st Company

Name: Marcus Crixus, Marcus The Scarred

Traits:

Natural Tactician: "There is more to tactics than simply reading the Codex Astartes, though to not study it at all would be folly."
Grotesquely Scarred: "Do not be disturbed by how my body appears. My heart burns with fury and my soul remains pure."
Devastatingly Disfigured: "You may not see where where the scars begin and end. It does not matter. Focus, instead, on how short your existence shall be now that I am upon you.
Shield of Faith And Flesh: "So long as there is breath in my breast, and blood in my veins, and even beyond, you will have to go through me first!"
Ruined Roar: "You shall find no bellows from me, creature. I need them not to slay you."

Prior History: Assault Marine of 5th Company

Characteristics:
Weapon Skill: 5
Ballistic Skill: 5
Strength: 6
Toughness: 10
Agility: 5
Intelligence: 7
Perception: 7
Willpower: 10
Fellowship: 9+1=10

Legendary Characteristics:

Legendary Toughness (Forever Advance, Forever Guard - Can withstand roll to continue fighting despite multiple mortal wounds so long as there are Blood Ravens still on the battlefield, and upon the conclusion of the battle may roll again to fall into a coma from which wounds can be healed, cybernetics applied, or, should the damage be utterly unsurvivable otherwise, be put into a dreadnought instead of dying outright. )
Legendary Willpower (Scars Of The Phosphex - Unbreakable mental fortitude. Able to utterly ignore pain and mental assaults and effects entirely.)

Personal Wargear:

Wisdom - Ancient Power Sword (+1 Fellowship, Unbreakable)
Arrow of Aerus - Relic Graviton Pistol, gifted to the Captain after discovery of the Graviton Cache on Aerus [Special Characteristics: Relic Weapon, Extremely Effective Anti-Armor]
Standard Bolt Pistol
Armor Of The Scarred - The original Mk-VII Power Armor that was worn by 1st Captain Marcus Crixus was destroyed by a phosphex bomb. This second set has suffered nearly as greately in the meantime, worn by the unforgiving hellish pace set by Marcus in battle. Though it is no mastercrafted relic, in time it may well be considered a relic in its own right should Captain Marcus forge a great enough legend for himself.
Iron Halo

Spoiler: 2nd Company Captain/Master of the Watch

Name: Macharius Sicarius

Traits:

Unyielding Deathdealer: "They will keep coming, but so long as I have ammo, they'll die."
Stalwart Slayer: "Fight on, my brothers! They fall here! Now!"
Spine of Steel: "Yes, a great deal of me is metal, eldar. The better to snap you apart with."

Prior History: Veteran Devastator Sergeant of the 3rd Company, then the 1st Company

Characteristics:
Weapon Skill: 4
Ballistic Skill: 8
Strength: 8
Toughness: 7
Agility: 4
Intelligence: 5
Perception: 6
Willpower: 7
Fellowship: 8

Legendary Characteristics:

Personal Wargear:

Star Thrower - Pre M32 Plasma Cannon (Higher Average Damage, Higher Critical Damage, Reduced Chance of Misfire)
1 Plasma Pistol
Iron Halo
Standard Mk-VII 'Aquilla' Power Armor
Combat Knife

Spoiler: 3rd Company Captain/Master of the Arsenal

Name: Hantu

Traits:

Unorthodox: "Say what you will, but those of us who listen to Cyrus happen to live longer, and win more victories in the name of the Emperor."
Friendly: "Treating one another like enemies when there is no need for it leads only to unneeded suffering."
Idealist: "Yes, our lives and this universe are grim. But I shall not let that dictate who or how I am or act, nor stop me from trying to better both."

Prior History: Veteran Sergeant of the 4th Company, Assault-Devastator-Tactical Progression through 4th Company

Characteristics:
Weapon Skill: 4
Ballistic Skill: 8
Strength: 5
Toughness: 5
Agility: 4
Intelligence: 9
Perception: 7
Willpower: 7
Fellowship: 10

Legendary Characteristics:

Legendary Fellowship (Within The Raven's Shadow - Flat bonus and rerolls to Fellowship Rolls with both Blood Ravens and other Imperials in and outside of battle.)

Personal Wargear:

Standard Mk-VII 'Aquilla' Power Armor
Godwyn-Pattern Bolter
Combat Knife
Frag Grenades

Spoiler: 4th Company Captain/Master of the Fleet

Name: Hadrian Priscus

Traits:

Aggressive In Combat: "The faster we kill them, the faster we can move on to our next objective!"
Unorthodox: "Victory in the name of the Emperor is all that really matters."
Armor Adherent: "We are the mailed fist! Crush them beneath our treads!"

Prior History: Veteran Sergeant of the 5th Company

Characteristics:
Weapon Skill: 4
Ballistic Skill: 8
Strength: 5
Toughness: 5
Agility: 4
Intelligence: 9
Perception: 6
Willpower: 5
Fellowship: 8

Legendary Characteristics:

Personal Wargear:

The Hand Of Aggression - A masterfully made plasma pistol crafted by Martellus Ravias, Master of the Forge of the Blood Ravens. (Rapid-fire, Reduced Chance For Catastrophic Failure, Increased Ammo Efficiency For More Shots Before Reload, Boosted Range/Accuracy/Bayonet Fitted)
1 Plasma Pistol
Bionic Left Arm+Shoulder (Highest Chapter Quality)
Standard Mk-VII 'Aquilla' Power Armor
Iron Halo
Combat Knife

Spoiler: 5th Company Captain, Master of the Marches

Name: Tarkus Varianus

Traits:

Experienced Veteran: "Fear not, brothers, this is not the worst that I have ever faced."
Master Of All Trades: "The weapon matters not, I can wield it."

Prior History: Veteran Sergeant Tactical Marine of the 5th Company, Sergeant Tactical Marine of the 5th Company, Tactical Marine of the 5th Company, Assault Marine of 5th Company

Characteristics:
Weapon Skill: 7
Ballistic Skill: 8
Strength: 5(6)
Toughness: 10(11)
Agility: 5
Intelligence: 6
Perception: 6
Willpower: 10
Fellowship: 8

Legendary Characteristics:

Legendary Toughness (Strength Of Will, Strength of Honor - Can apply Willpower as well as Toughness to survive/ignore wounds up to and including mortal until rolls are unsuccessful.)
Legendary Willpower (Venerable Raven - Unbreakable mental fortitude. Able to utterly ignore pain and mental assaults and effects entirely.)

Personal Wargear:

The Barding of Tarkus: This masterful creation bears the engraved valorous deeds of Captain Tarkus of the Blood Ravens, along with zealous denials of the lies of traitors and madmen. A quirk of its manufacture has somehow further hardened the materials of its make, to the point of conferring greatly improved durability even amongst power armors, while its servos and artificial muscle fibres confer greater strength. Such magnificent armor inspires greater fervor in fellow sons of the Emperor in battle. (+1 Toughness, +1 Strength, Improved Resistance Against Anti-Armor Weaponry)
Deathdealer - A Legendary Bolter of the Blood Ravens (Allows Two Ranged Attacks For Bearer Instead of One Per Attack Phase, Reloads Less Often)
Krak Grenades
Frag Grenades
Iron Halo

Spoiler: 10th Company Captain, Master of Recruits/Master of Reconnaissance

Name: Cyrus Octavius

Traits:

Encyclopedia Of Death: "I know the ins and outs of more xeno species than some space marines will know in their entire lifetimes, and more importantly, how to kill them."
Explosive Assassin: "For some foes, like Greater Daemons or fortified enemy positions, you need to get in close and plant explosives without them noticing. I can do that easily. Can you?"
Unorthodox: "Tradition serves a purpose. When that purpose is actively detrimental to your efforts, you do away with it. It is a very simple concept to grasp, my students."
Instructor of War: "Listen and I shall teach. Observe and you shall learn."

Prior History: Veteran Scout Sergeant of 10th Company, 195 Years In Death Watch (Kill Team Member, Kill Team Leader, Kill Marine), Veteran Teacher of Scout Marines, Neophytes, Aspirants For Much Of History Within Chapter.

Characteristics:
Weapon Skill: 6
Ballistic Skill: 8 (9)
Strength: 4
Toughness: 4
Agility: 10
Intelligence: 7
Perception: 8
Willpower: 7
Fellowship: 4

Legendary Characteristics:

Legendary Agility (Silenced Bloodspiller - Perfectly silent when moving unless purposefully moving audibly, may seemingly hide in plain sight if one does not obviously clash with the surroundings, can use items silently and uninterrupted when in stealth.)

Personal Wargear:

Unseen Demise of the Vain - Prized Sniper Rifle of the 10th Company (+Accuracy, +Range, Reduced Reload Time)
The Eye of Cyrus - An extremely advanced cybernetic eye granted to Cyrus by the Deathwatch after his extensive time among them before he returned to the Blood Ravens. (+Accuracy, +Multiple Scanning)
Astartes Assault Shotgun
Krak Grenades
Melta Bombs
Bolt Pistol
Shadow Hunter's Raiment - Cameleoline-integrated high grade armor with accompanying camo-cloak. Contains sound-dampening materials, as well as additional thermal reduction technology for stealth purposes. Integrated targeting links of the armor are specially adapted for integration with Cyrus Octavian's own cybernetics. (+1 Ballistic Skill, +Further Improved Stealth Capabilities)

Character Creation - Part 2

Vote closed.

[X] Intrigue: The Spymaster is the master of soft power in the realm, responsible for hiding the Elector Count's secrets and uncovering those of everyone else. Gives you a great deal of leeway in how you go about things, but also makes you a target for everyone trying to get away with skulduggery in the province, and being anything short of omniscient is often considered a failing by those that don't have to do the job.
Number of voters: 10
veekie, bryanfran36, wingstrike96, lavanderjasmine, Skycrafterf, Azurath, Hannz, butchock,Troglodyte, EVA-Saiyajin
[X] STIRLAND
Number of voters: 9
veekie, bryanfran36, wingstrike96, lavanderjasmine, Skycrafterf, Azurath, Drucchi, EVA-Saiyajin, Kingofbooks
[X] Sleeper Agent: Perhaps you did not quite attain the position; perhaps it was thrust unto you, and perhaps those that did the thrusting have attached several strings to the position.
Number of voters: 6
veekie, bryanfran36, wingstrike96, lavanderjasmine, Skycrafterf, Azurath

You are the Spymaster of Stirland, and you aren't entirely sure who it is you owe that to. But you do know they won't let you forget it.

As the Spymaster of Stirland, your job will involve quite a bit of keeping a wary eye on Sylvania. Whether the local Witch Hunters of the province will start off answering to you, to the Faith advisor, or only to themselves, will depend on your Background and on whoever the Faith advisor ends up being. There will doubtless also the usual mish-mash of spying on neighbours, unruly nobles, and unhappy peasants.

Here you will select your life prior to achieving your current office. This stage and the next involve a form of chargen currency I've called, for my own amusement, shinies. These can be spent in the next stage of character development on traits, special resources, unique items, skilled followers, and other bits and bobs, mostly based on the background you select in this stage. Any shinies remaining unspent after that will carry over into the game and can be spent on powerful strokes of good luck in the first few turns.

YOU HAVE THREE (3) SHINIES.

Birth - will affect how people treat you.

[ ] Peasant: Though your position is a worthy one, your origins mean that you will have to earn respect a dozen times over before it is given to you. +2 shinies
[ ] Burgher: Coming from a comfortably well-off family, you attract neither scorn nor respect from the noble classes.
[ ] Petty Noble: Though your family can no longer boast of land or wealth, your blood demands respect. -1 shinies
[ ] Minor Noble: Your family is of noble blood and landed, and as such you wield power in your own right. -2 shinies

Province of Birth - will affect your appearance and options available to you in the next step of chargen.

[ ] Local: Already being tied in to the local power structures can be a significant advantage. -1 shinies.
[ ] Averland: A wide-open land of rivers and cattle.
[ ] Hochland: Small, densely-forested province of able hunters.
[ ] Middenland: Homeland of the Cult of Ulric, a largely uncivilized land of fierce fighters.
[ ] Nordland: Home of the Imperial Navy and the sea god Manann, Nordlanders are a hardy and loyal people.
[ ] Ostermark: An odd experiment in democracy, Ostermark lacks a single ruler, filled with largely self-sufficient townships and farming villages.
[ ] Ostland: A grim and terrifying land, dominated by the Forest of Shadows.
[ ] Reikland: The noble capital of the Empire, home to the Emperor, the Colleges of Magic, and the Reiksguard.
[ ] Talabecland: A large, thriving province built on commerce, Talabecland dominates the Empire's internal trade routes.
[ ] Wissenland: Famous for the Imperial Gunnery School of Nuln, Wissenland is a productive land of industry and technology.
[ ] Rootless: You either travelled too much to build up contacts, or lost them somewhere along the way. +1 shinies

Gender - no mechanical effects, some cultural ones.

[ ] Male
[ ] Female

Background - will dictate your base stats. By default they will be the total of 3d6. You will reroll the lowest for a particular stat for each + you have in it, and reroll the highest for each -. Traits picked in the next step of char creation will increase or lower these scores by a set amount. Your background will also heavily effect the options available to you.

[ ] Innkeeper: Not the most typical of precursors to being a spymaster, but the ability to keep track of comings and goings and make sure nobody's going to start breaking the furniture while just looking like you're placidly cleaning a glass is a useful skill to have.
+Diplomacy, +Stewardship, -Learning

[ ] Bounty Hunter: They give you a name, you return with a head. All the steps between those two stages have honed your skills to a razor's edge.
+Martial, +Intrigue, +Diplomacy, -Learning, -Stewardship

[ ] Criminal: You started with thievery, moved up to blackmail, and reached the pinnacle of your career ruling the criminal underworld of a major city. Being master of whispers for an entire province is a logical upgrade.
+Intrigue, +Stewardship, -Faith

[ ] Exciseman: The most hated citizens in the Empire. To do your job, you had to be sneaky. To survive your job, you had to be tough. But it didn't win you any friends.
+Intrigue, +Martial, -Diplomacy

[ ] Road Warden: Your public role was to keep the roads clear and deliver important messages along them. Your secret role was to read and pass on the information in those letters. Trickier than it sounds, to read and memorize a letter at a full gallop while watching out for threads from the woods.
+Learning, +Martial, -Stewardship

[ ] Knight of Morr: You spent many years under the vow of silence of the Knights of Morr. You have a great deal of experience with combatting the undead, but your other skills have eroded.
+Martial +Faith -Diplomacy

[ ] Priest of Morr: Your battles were not physical, but spiritual. You safeguarded the souls of the dead, and now you have expanded the battlefield in your war.
+Faith +Stewardship -Intrigue

[ ] Rat Catcher: You fought the secret war under the cities of the Empire against the ratman menace. A filthy but necessary job, what you lack in refinement you make up for in the ability to win a fight in a pitch-black tunnel with a small but fierce dog as your only ally.
+Martial +Intrigue -Learning

[ ] Witch Hunter: You sought out witches, heretics and mutants wherever they hid. A very polarizing role, but a necessary one.
+Faith +Intrigue +Martial -Learning -Stewardship

[ ] Grey Wizard: You have only just completed your apprenticeship, and now are able to usefully wield the winds of Ulgu, the grey magic of shadow and illusion. Very fitting for a spymaster.
-4 shinies, +Magic

[ ] Amethyst Wizard: You have only just completed your apprenticeship, and now are able to usefully wield the winds of Shyish, the purple magic of death. Anywhere but Stirland, an Amethyst Wizard as a spymaster would be a terrifying prospect and a sign that the Elector Count has gone seriously around the bend, but in Stirland it is... still terrifying, but understandable.
-4 shinies, +Magic

Magic is absolutely a valid and interesting choice, but I do feel the need to warn you that the voting did pick Sleeper Agent, and the sort of person with enough heft to get a wizard reassigned according to their desires is going to be a much bigger deal than, say, someone pulling the strings of a rat catcher.

If there's a background you feel is an appropriate precursor to being a Spymaster that isn't listed here, post it and if I agree, I'll stat it and add it to the list.

Chapter Characteristics/Deeds/Specialists

Special Blood Raven Gene-Seed Characteristics:

It is unknown why, but larger than average numbers of marines of this Chapter often manifest psyker abilities, many of whom begin doing so after Gene-Seed implantation. Blood Raven Librarians are furthermore more powerful on average than their counterparts in other Chapters alongside their higher than average numbers. This has led to long term widespread mistrust and constant allegations of mutations, corrupted implants, and other things of vitriolic nature towards the Chapter from multiple sources.
Minor Mutation - Catalepsian Node [Stage 6 Implant]: Manifestation of Eidetic Memory. Inability to experience REM sleep.
Other than the above two, the gene-seed of the Blood Ravens is remarkably pure and stable, despite rumors to the otherwise.

Average Chapter Characteristics
Weapon Skill: 5
Ballistic Skill: 6
Strength: 5
Toughness: 6
Agility: 5
Intelligence: 6
Perception: 7
Willpower: 8
Fellowship: 6

Average Chapter Veteran Characteristics
Weapon Skill: 5
Ballistic Skill: 6
Strength: 6
Toughness: 7
Agility: 5
Intelligence: 7
Perception: 8
Willpower: 9
Fellowship: 8

Explanation of Various Skills/Characteristics

Spoiler: Weapon Skill

Represents the capability to connect blows with a melee weapon.

WS-0: Completely Untrained
WS-2: Moderately Drilled, Imperial Guardsman Minimum Standard
WS-4: Hardened Warrior, Space Marine Average
WS-6: Talented Swordsman, Eldar Aspect Warrior
WS-8: Unparalleled Blademaster, Eldar Exarch
WS-10: Legend of the Blade, Gain Legendary Weapon Skill[

At WS-10, a swordsman will forge his own legend, and cut into the pages of history with the edge of his blade. Once a character reaches Rating 10 in Weapon Skill, he will attain Legendary Weapon Skill, and gain a Legendary Perk that will resonate with their style of combat.

Examples:
Commissar Ciaphas Cain, Hero of the Imperium: Reluctant Shield of Liberation: Gain bonuses when on the defensive, ignore penalties to parrying attacks from multiple opponents.

Lord Commander Cervan Dante, The Old Angel: Final Champion of Eternity: Ignore penalties when wielding axes, gain bonuses when dueling enemy champions, gain additional bonuses when dueling monstrous creatures.

Apollo, Forlorn Hero: Bitter Blooded Champion - Automatically hits all Non-Hero units, damage dealt and skill checks receive no malus regardless of injuries sustained. Critical damage increased.)

Spoiler: Ballistic Skill

Represents the capability to accurately shoot a target with projectiles and energy discharges.

BS-0: Completely Untrained
BS-2: Moderately Drilled, Imperial Guard Minimum Standard
BS-4: Well-Drilled Gunner, Space Marine Average
BS-6: Sharpshooter, Imperial Guard Sniper Minimum Standard
BS-8: Master Sniper, Space Marine Designated Marksman
BS-10: Legendary Marksman, Gain Legendary Ballistic Skill

At BS-10, a marksman will carve his own passage into the annals of history, one shot at a time. Once a character reaches Rating 10 in Ballistic Skill, he will attain Legendary Ballistic Skill, and gain a Legendary Perk that will resonate most with their style of shooting.

Examples:
Vindicare Temple Assassin/Watch Commander Vergilius Rios: Accuracy Without Distance: Ignore range penalties with any weapon. With a Sniper Rifle, double maximum range, gain an additional roll for the purposes of confirming a critical hit, inflict additional critical hit damage on Named Characters and instantly kill everything else.

Kasmr Gough: Metal Storm of Death: Ignore recoil penalties with automatic and heavy weapons. With a Heavy Bolter, inflict double the attacks for no penalty. With a Lascannon, gain an additional roll for the purposes of confirming a critical hit. With a Plasma Cannon, double blast radius. With a Multi-Melta, double range. With a Missile Launcher, double range and fire rate.

Spoiler: Strength

Represents the amount of force that may be exerted.

S-0: Sickly, Unable to move under own power
S-2: Reasonably Fit, Imperial Guard Minimum Standard
S-4: Strong, Space Marine Minimum Standard
S-6: Very Strong, May Carry Crew-Serve Weaponry Single-Handedly
S-8: Mighty, May Lift Vehicles for Short Periods
S-10: Arms of the Emperor, Gain Legendary Strength

At S-10, a strongman has reached the very pinnacle of strength, and legends of his might shall remain for all time across a hundred worlds. Once a character reaches Rating 10 in Strength, he gains Legendary Strength and the following benefits:

- The character may now operate vehicle-scale weaponry for no penalty
- The character may inflict damage through armored targets even without a Power Weapon

Spoiler: Toughness

Concerns the amount of punishment that may be taken before unconsciousness and death.

T-0: Sickly, May Die to a Stiff Wind
T-2: Mortal, Imperial Guard Minimum Standard
T-4: Tough, Space Marine Minimum Standard
T-6: Hardened, Feels No Pain From Unarmed Combat
T-8: Bulwark, May Survive Point-Blank Explosions
T-10: Cast From Steel, Gain Legendary Toughness

At T-10, a warrior attains the strength of form that allows them to survive that which could slay two men, forever etching themselves into living memory. Once a character reaches Rating 10 for Toughness, he gains Legendary Toughness and the following benefits:

- Weapons Fire rated below a Boltgun no longer do damage
- Upon suffering fatal wounds not inflicted by a Vortex Weapon, may act for an additional 10d10 Minutes, during which they are impervious to all further injury

Spoiler: Agility

Represents the speed and dexterity capable by the character.

A-0: Disabled, unable to move under own power
A-2: Brisk Walk, Imperial Guard Minimum Standard
A-4: Swift as Wind, Space Marine Minimum Standard
A-6: Lightning Speed, Fast and swift, able to sprint without overly loud footsteps
A-8: Thunderbolt, Fast as lightning and quiet as a mouse
A-10: Winged Spectre, Gain Legendary Agility

At A-10, a scout gains speed, grace and control that allows them to slip into nothingness, in doing so paradoxically making their mark as Legend. Once a character reaches Rating 10 for Agility, he gains Legendary Agility and a Legendary Perk that befits their specialisation:

Examples:
Son of Angels: Half of raw Agility applied to Dodge instead of one-third, may apply dodge rating against indirect fire

Ghost of Baal: Perfectly silent when moving unless purposefully moving audibly, may move at full speed without stealth penalties, may seemingly hide in plain sight if one does not obviously clash with the surroundings

Spoiler: Intelligence

Represents education, learning capacity, and one's ability in deductive reasoning.

I-0: Literally an idiot
I-2: Imperial Citizen of upper-mid class
I-4: Educated, Space Marine Minimum Standard
I-6: Teacher, capable of Instruction
I-8: Professor, Expert of a Field
I-10: Luminary Genius, Gain Legendary Intelligence

At I-10, a mind gains foresight and intellect that demands that future generations study the events that lead to the formation of a talent such as theirs. Once a character reaches Rating 10 for Intelligence, he will attain Legendary Intelligence, and gain a Legendary Perk that best suits their field of expertise.

Examples:
Ursarkar E. Creed: Tactical Genius: Never be caught off-guard by an enemy commander, gain a flat bonus to all command actions. Gain additional bonuses when fighting Chaos-related foes, exploiting flanks, and repositioning forces. Once a battle, may perfectly reposition a single unit, regardless of size, logistical footprint or visibility.

Chief Librarians In General: Purview of the Warp: May perfectly call upon any spell known to the Chapter and Legion. Gain bonuses when wielding spells related to one's panoply or legend. Ignore failure occurrence for all spells of Mastery 2 or less.

Most Forgemasters: Liege of the Forge: Automatically succeed at any repair attempts for war machines and wargear in regular use by the Imperium and the Chapter. May attempt to repair ancient Imperial relics, archeotech and esoteric technologies not often deployed by the Adeptus Mechanicus. Relics crafted will be of higher grades than standard.

Spoiler: Perception

Represents preceptiveness and ability to quickly react to new stimuli.

P-0: Blind
P-2: Typical eyesight, Imperial Guard Standard
P-4: Sharp eyes, Space Marine Average
P-6: Deep Perception, Imperial Guard Spotter Standard
P-8: Eagle Vision, Capable of perceiving disruptions on the Horizon
P-10: Eyes of the Emperor, Gain Legendary Perception

Spoiler: Willpower

Represents strength of will and mental resilience against madness.

W-0: Irrevocably Broken
W-2: Frightened, Imperial Guard Minimum
W-4: Acceptance, Space Marine Minimum
W-6: Resolute, Veteran Space Marine
W-8: Pure, Saint of the Imperium
W-10: Incorruptible, Gain Legendary Willpower

Spoiler: Fellowship

Represents strength of character and personal charisma.

F-0: Inherently Despicable
F-2: Typical
F-4: Charming
F-6: Inspiration
F-8: King's Disposition
F-10: Voice of the Emperor, Gain Legendary Fellowship

Last Campaigns/Deeds Of M41

Spoiler: Logs Of The Past

Fall of the Black Fortress of Vespa [Victory, Won By Initiate Davian Thule] 500.M41
Cleansing of Obscurus [Victory, Commanded By Honor Guard Captain Apollo Diomedes] 824.M41
The Dark Crusade [Victory, Commanded by 4th Company Captain Davian Thule] 942.M41
Purging of Cyrene [Victory, Commanded By 3rd Company Captain Gabriel Angelos] 950.M41
Tartarus Campaign [Victory, Commanded By 3rd Company Captain Gabriel Angelos] 970.M41
Battle of Rahe's Paradise [Phyrric Victory, Commanded By 3rd Company Captain Gabriel Angelos] 972.M41
Battle of Lorn V/Battle of the Black Library [Victory, Commanded By 3rd Company Captain Gabriel Angelos] 972.M41
Cadian Aid [Initial Victory, Commanded by 4th Company Captain Davian Thule Before Retreat Ordered By Chief Librarian Kyras] 974.M41
Kaurava Campaign [Defeat, Commanded by Captain Indrick Boreale] 980.M41
Hadrian Campaign [Victory, Commanded by 6th Company Captain Claudius] 985.M41
Defense of the Targa System [Victory, Commanded by 3rd Company Captain Gabriel Angelos] 986.M41
First Aurelian Crusade [Victory, Commanded by Force Commander Aramus] 986.M41
Second Aurelian Crusade [Victory, Commanded by Force Commander Aramus] 987.M41
Third Aurelian Crusade/Blood Raven Civil War/Chapter Purge [Victory, Commanded by Honor Guard Captain Apollo Diomedes] 997.M41
Disciplinary Action On Meridian [Victory, Commanded by 5th Company Captain Tarkus Varianus ] 998.M41
Cleansing of Calderis [Victory, Commanded by Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos] 998.M41

Major Campaigns/Deeds Of 0-100M42

Trontiux II Intervention [Victory, Commanded by Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos] 004.M42
Reclamation of Forge World Aerus [Victory, Commanded by Captain Marcus Crixus, then Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos] 015.M42
Split Heart Kabal Anchorage Assault [Victory, Commanded by Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos] 020.M42
Trontiux III Culling [Victory, Shared Command By Captain Tarkus/Captain Cyrus] 030.M42 To 035.M42
Polonius Liberation Crusade Aid [Victory, Commanded By Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos] 030.M42 To 035.M42
Polonius Subsector Cleansing [Victory, Commanded By Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos] 035.M42 To 045.M42
Polonius Reclamation Crusade+Exterminatus [Victory, Commanded By Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos] 045.M42 To 050.M42
Eldar Corsair Hunt In Sector Korianis And Beyond Imperial Borders [Victory, Commanded By Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos] 050.M42 To 055.M42
Doom-Eater Kill-Nought WAAAGH!! Extinction Beyond Imperial Borders [Victory, Commanded by Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos] 060.M42 To 65.M42
Libration of Jahal System, Xenocide of Suysh Campaign [Victory, Commanded by Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos] 065.M42 To 70.M42
Destruction of a Black Legion Anchorage [Victory, Command By Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos] 070.M42 To 75.M42
Helba Campaign and Reinforcement of the Mede Subsector [Victory, Commanded by Captain Cyrus] 070.M42 To 75.M42

Spoiler: Librarium

Chief Librarian: Justinius Probalis [Raven's Aegis]
1st Company Epistolary Lucan
2nd Company Epistolary Flekton
3rd Company Epistolary Idmon
5th Company Damion Tyrin [Raven's Aegis]
4th Company Nero Achillian [Raven's Aegis]
10th Company Trajan Maphar [Raven's Aegis]
Honor Guard Epistolary Rasmus
Codicier Aeneas [Raven's Aegis]
Non-Assigned Epistolaries: 0
Non-Notable Epistolaries: 0
Codiciers: 12
Lexicanum: 18/11*
*Recruits sourced from Astra Telepathica

Spoiler: Armory and Forges

Master of the Forge: Martellus Ravias
Senior Techmarines: 0
Techmarine Calus
Techmarine Daedal
Techmarine Quarius Zergan
Techmarine Hestior
Techmarine Janos
Non-Notable Techmarines: 16
9 Techmarine Trainees: Began 065.M42. Estimated Complete 095.M42

Spoiler: Apothecarium

Chief Apothecary Nero Gracchus
Honor Guard Apothecary Ikai
1st Company Apothecary Constantius Romallius
2nd Company Apothecary Nabonidus
3rd Company Apothecary Aratos
4th Company Apothecary Caesar
5th Company Apothecary Medici
10th Company Apothecary Marius Astophiles
Apothecary Talm
Non-Notable Apothecaries: 4

Spoiler: Reclusiam

Master of Sanctity Hannibal
Honor Guard Chaplain Tasanor
1st Company Chaplain Ares Actus
2nd Company Chaplain Ravias
3rd Company Chaplain Galloss
4th Company Chaplain Ateren [Powerful Bionic Arm/Leg]
5th Company Chaplain Bellero
10th Company Chaplain Augustine
Chaplain Antonius
Chaplain Alastair
Chaplain Sardus
Non-Notable Chaplains: 2

Chapter 4

As it happened, Tapu Lele was waiting for her outside of the cave. The second she stepped out Diglett Tunnel, a pink aura grabbed her by the scruff of her shirt and lifted her to face it. The Island Guardian blinked at her for a second, before pulling her along so quickly that Olivia had to remember to breathe. Finally, after a quick, if painful, journey, Olivia was settled down in front of the Ruins of Life, Tapu Lele staring at her quietly.

Olivia knelt just as quietly, just for a second, and Tapu Lele danced around her in amusement before a heavy, almost crushing weight entered her head. Olivia slacked her jaw and didn't fight it. Like in all things, Tapu Lele was not particularly careful about what it did with its psychic powers. But at the same time, they weren't as savage as people made them out to be.

Yes, memories were drawn towards the front of her mind and casually perused without her explicit consent, but they weren't ripped forwards, torn from her mind. Tapu Lele hummed quietly, head tilting above her shell as images of Izuku, Inko, Blanket and the pulsing of the Ultra Wormhole.

Interesting, the voice that came was soft but powerful. It was part of the unique relationship that the Kahuna of Akala had with their Tapu that the others didn't. While she wouldn't insult Tapu Koko, Bulu or Fini by implying they were less intelligent then Tapu Lele, They are.

Well, they were certainly more modest Tapu Lele.

That got a shake that counted as a laugh from the Island Guardian of Akala, Modesty is for the weak, Pet. They would boast the same about me.

Somehow she doubted that.

Another shake of laughter, Continuing on, Pet, this is a very interesting thing.

Anyways, as she was saying. The other Tapus weren't Psychic types, so they couldn't hold conversations with their chosen Kahunas. It made interpreting their will, Far easier?

"Yes," Olivia agreed.

You're quite welcome for me taking the time to make your life easier then the other's pets, Pet. Now, let me consider what to do with the new aberration… very well, I've decided, you can keep it, it should prove quite amusing.

That was fast.

I always love things that make my life more interesting, Pet, and I feel this will prove quite interesting. I will raise my face to the other Gods, and they will abide by my desires.

"You're confident," Oliva said.

It is a child, Pet, not one of those… What do the people of Aether call it? Ultra Beast? It is not an Ultra Beast, it is a child. It will not cause harm to Alola. You will foster the thing, take it under your wing.

He has a mother."

Ah, yes. Then not foster, what is the term… babysit? Mentor it. Teach it to live alongside the people of Alola. Act as if it will become the next "Kahuna". It won't, but it will let it learn to be undisruptive to the world we have crafted for ourselves. You have already done the first step with, a smile curved across Tapu Lele's eyes "Blanket". Go now, prepare to show him Akala. I will send a servant to meet with you then. Ah, and find what Kosei means and does, it's quite interesting.

—

Izuku walked out of his bedroom with Blanket holding onto one hand. The minute they were out, Blanket let go and rushed over to the hill of sand Olivia had left last night and immediately dived in, happily chewing on the sand. Izuku smiled and walked over to sit on the floor next to him, "Don't eat too fast, Blanket, you'll give yourself a tummy ache."

"Tar?" Blanket looked up and tilted his head, before going right back to eating just as fast. Well, if he got a tummy ache, it wasn't Izuku's fault. He had tried to warn him!

Izuku sat at the table as his mom made rice and fish for breakfast, jumping up and down in his chair as he waited. He had a Quirk, and a new friend, and was gonna see new stuff today, it was gonna be awesome!

Izuku ate his breakfast quickly (but not too quickly!) before standing up and hopping in place, "Ready Mom?"

"I suppose," his Mom sighed, watching Izuku tap Blanket's head and his pokemon stand up from his breakfast. Izuku cracked his fist before throwing a Detroit Smash punch at the air. The air cracked like a plate and shattered, opening a portal in the middle of the house. Izuku took his mom's hand in one and Blanket's in the other, and they walked through the portal into Alola.

His mom blinked and looked around, mouth opening and closing.

"Hey, Keiki," Olivia said, sitting on a rock outside the cave, "Midoriya-San, welcome to Alola."

—

Inko looked around the quiet road in shock, breathing in and taking in the salty air. Part of her was still trying to understand that her son could open portals hundreds of miles, if not more, away. Macro scale portal Quirks were rare. Very rare.

"I feel like we were having a two way conversation yesterday," Olivia said, "I didn't know what a Quirk was. And I still really don't. Is it a psychic power?"

"I… You don't know what a Quirk is?" Inko asked, "How? Eighty percent of the population has them!"

"Eighty percent of the population where you're from," Olivia corrected, "Do you know what that is?"

She punctuated the "that" with a nod towards the pulsing portal that was slowly closing behind them.

"A portal!" Izuku chirped, smiling broadly.

"More specifically, it's what we call an Ultra Wormhole. Rifts across space, time and dimensions. What you're doing, keiki, is opening portals in between dimensions. That's why we don't have Quirks and you don't have Pokemon. Because this isn't your earth, and your earth isn't-"

"-ours," a slimey voice said from behind the portal, apparently uncaring of the fact that everything Olivia had just said had sent Inko's mind spiraling into freefall. Portals between dimensions? That was possible? That was what Izuku was doing when he punched?

Out of behind the portal came a man with slicked back blonde hair, wearing large green sunglasses and a white lab coat. The hungry look in his eyes as he stared at Izuku immediately set Inko on guard, and she did what came naturally. She stepped between him and Izuku, hearing shuffling behind her. When she glanced back, she saw Blanket had forced his way in front of Izuku, stony lips rolling back so he could bare his fangs at the man behind Inko.

Good Larvitar.

"You should have said it was a child that opened those Ultra Wormholes, Olivia," the man said, and Inko shot a glare at Olivia, only to see she was standing ramrod straight, an aura of authority seeming to radiate from her.

"It was none of your business, Faba," Olivia spat, "I've spoken to Tapu Lele, she doesn't care if you interact with Izuku, but they have ruled that I am to protect Izuku on Akala. You're not going to harass him while I'm around. And staying to spy on a private meeting is harassment. Leave, Faba."

"He revolutionizes-"

"He has a name," Inko snapped, on guard.

"Tar!" Blanket snarled out, purple energy seeming to leak from the corners of his mouth.

"Stop acting like he's one of your research subjects, Faba. He's a child who can't give consent for your experiments, and I won't let you touch him so long as he's under my care," Oliva continued. Inko's respect for the woman was rising in time with any respect she might have had for Faba dropped, "Come on, we can continue this at my house in Koneki City. Away from harassment."

—

Mimikyu stood in the shadows, staring out at the streets through the holes in her costume. It wasn't fair that these damn Pikachu got the love. What did they have that she didn't? After carefully checking to make sure the vendor was busy with a Litten, she rushed out of the shadows, leaping onto the stall and quickly scooping up some berries. Oran, mostly, ones that won't be missed, but a couple of Aguav.

Before she could jump off, she turned to find herself face to face with a young human with curly green hair and green eyes. Mimikyu locked up, prepared for herself to be caught and-

"Olivia, can we try some of these fruits?" the boy asked in a language Mimikyu had never heard before, walking forwards and taking the berries from her before picking up Mimikyu and sliding her down his shirt with weird symbols on it. Mimikyu dug her claws into his back, but if he felt any pain, he didn't show it. Why was he doing this? Why wasn't he scared of her!?

"You sure you wanna try that one, Kenki? It's really bitter," another voice said.

"Yeah, M sure," the boy said.

"Alright then," Mimikyu listened to the transaction of money before they started walking. Suddenly, something slid up the shirt towards Mimikyu. The Aguav berry!

Mimikyu grabbed it, only to remember she had been gripping onto the boy with both hands and fell out of the shirt and onto his hands with a faint "plop". Mimikyu blinked up at the tanned woman staring at the two with an amused expression on her face, "Those berries weren't for you, were they, keiki?"

"It was gonna steal them!" Keiki said, "stealin's wrong! This way it gets the fruit and the seller sells!"

"Mimikyu that live in cities often have to steal food. People don't like them very much," the woman said.

"Why not?" Another woman said, "It's kinda cute."

"They're seen as omens of death."

"Omen of death?" Keiki repeated.

"It means people think they make you die," the first woman said.

"But… it's a Pokemon," Keiki said, staring down at Mimikyu, "Why aren't you eatin', little guy?'

Mimikyu blinked again, before pulling her hands into the shadows of its costume and beginning to chew. A hand suddenly pulled up the costume, and the boy stared at Mimikyu.

Here they went, the screaming, the thrashing, the pain and hatred.

"So that's what you look like under there," Keiki said, "I'm Izuku. What's your name?"

"Mi- mimi- Mimikyu," Mimikyu croaked out as the costume dropped back over it and another berry was handed over to her.

"Mimimimkyu?"

"Just Mimikyu, Keiki," the first woman said.

"Can we bring it with us, at least until it's done eatin'?" Izuku said.

"...I suppose," the second woman sighed.

Mimikyu didn't want to admit it, not yet.

But she thought she found a home.

—

Yes, yes, I know, "The pokedex says anyone who sees Mimikyu dies-" I don't fuckin' care. This is supposed to be a sweet, heartwarming story and that means Izuku, somehow, blame Aura if you have to have a reason, managed to see what Mimikyu looked like and accepted it through pure hearted love and understanding.

Next chapter, we time skip to the Pokemon League.

Thoughts, questions, opinions? Good? Bad? Meh?

Famed Members of the Chapter

Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
Born and raised upon the world Cyrene, Gabriel Angelos distinguished himself amongst his peers even before the Blood Trials were undertaken, and only more so during and afterwards. In time, he would advance from initiate to Captain of the 3rd Company of the Blood Ravens, a truly esteemed position won through sheer excellence and valor without any of the politicking that characterized the Blood Ravens under Azariah Kyras, the previous Chapter Master. When heresy was discovered upon Cyrene, it was he who contacted the Inquisition, showing his dedication to the Emperor above all else, despite the torturous realization that to do so would spell Cyrene's doom by Exterminatus. In the aftermath of that darkest hour, he met and befriended Inquisitor Adrastia of the Ordo Hereticus, a friendship he would later call on in the aftermath of the Second Aurelian Crusade. Gabriel would go on to lead with distinction in in the years afterwards before the Tartarus Campaign, where he would end WAAAAGH!! Orkamungus, battle the Alpha Legion, destroy the foul artifact known as the Maledictum, slay his close friend the Librarian Isador Akios who had fallen to Chaos, battle eldar of the Biel-tan Craftworld before temporarily allying with them, and save a significant portion of the populace despite greenskins and chaos space marines. Once again, his resolve held in circumstances that could have broken lesser men. Later, at the Battle of Rahe's Paradise, he came into contact with the eldar of Craftworld Biel-tan once more, even going so far as to make a rare attempt at trust, but it came largely to naught. In the end, he made the hard but necessary decision to enact Exterminatus once the planet was revealed to be a Necron Tombworld, despite the fact that it was a precious recruiting world of the Blood Ravens. His task done, he headed to Lorn V in response to Imperial distress signals.

In the void over Lorn V, despite accusations of heresy from Captain Ulantis of the 9th Company (who himself had long been corrupted by Kyras), Gabriel followed the Farseer Taldeer of Ulthwé into the Webway to the hidden Eldar planet Arcadia, the Eldar World of Law, to locate a weapon to use against the Necrons. On Arcadia, the Blood Ravens would come to blows with the infamous Ahriman of the Thousand Sons, who also sought the blade as well as other secret knowledge on the world. It was only the intervention of the mysterious Eldar known as Harlequins that allowed them to repulse the sorcerer and escape with their lives. Once they returned, Farseer Taldeer managed to succeed at destroying the Necrons of Lorn V, disappearing at the battle's end. She would return only a short time later in the Dark Crusade, her actions against the Imperium on Lorn V slating her for destruction by the demands of Segmentum Command, the one in charge of such an expedition being Lukas Alexander, who would come to blows with the Blood Ravens on Kronus. With that done, Gabriel would turn to the Targa System, recently invaded by the Tau in the course of their so-called 'Third Sphere of Expansion'. He would face them on all five planets of that system, the 3rd Company alone proving enough to absolutely crush the Tau and repulse them from the system entirely before the Imperial Guard could be ferried there by the Imperial Navy. No sooner was that done than he turned about to Subsector Aurelia, being the nearest Blood Raven fleet able to assist during the First Aurelian Crusade. Despite the best efforts of the Hive Mind, and the death of many Librarians and Astropaths, he would succeed in rescuing the beleaguered Heroes of Typhon - not yet named as such - as they had begun their final stand after poisoning the Hive Ships and Norn Queens of the Hive Fleet assaulting Subsector Aurelia.

Throughout the Second Aurelian Crusade, Gabriel grew more and more open with his defiance of Kyras, refusing to abandon the Subsector to the Black Legion despite the orders of the traitorous Chief Librarian and Chapter Master. Kyras ordered the Heroes of Typhon to stand down and deploy to the Ferox Rift Crusade, on the southern rim of Segmentum Tempestus. Both Gabriel and Force Commander Aramus flatly refused. Both knew that to do so would be to possibly lose three of their handful of remaining Recruiting Worlds, as well as abandon billions of Imperial Citizens to the depredations of Chaos. The 3rd Company was, however, too large to move as discreetly as the Heroe of Typhon on their sole strike cruiser, and so Gabriel was forced to move more subtly. In the end, however, as Kyras squeezed those unwilling to leave the Subsector through his hand in Apollo Diomedes, he absconded with what war material he could, being subsequently declared a renegade by the Chapter Master and Chief Librarian. Even even then, it was Gabriel who aided Aramus in the final battle with Ulkair and Eliphas on the ruined planet Aurelia, and it was Gabriel who subsequently banished Aramus on Penitent Crusade to the Eye of Terror. For he knew that to compromise the soul of himself and his brothers as Aramus had would be to ensure that Kyras would win. Yet he also believed it was possible for Aramus to find redemption, whether in survival or death in the course of said Penitent Crusade. In the aftermath, Gabriel found that the majority of the 3rd Company had been depleted in the fighting, and so folded in loyal members of the 1st and 4th Company into his forces to supplement. Even so, he knew that he could not defeat Kyras alone. Thus, he called not just upon the remaining Heroes of Typhon but an ally within the Inquisition. In the Third Aurelian Crusade, Gabriel called upon his friend and ally Inquisitor Adrastia of the Ordo Hereticus to investigate the allegations Gabriel levied against Chapter Master Kyras. During the Third Aurelian Crusade, Gabriel coordinated with both Adrastia and Apollo Diomedes, who had come to admit that there lay rot within the Chapter and was willing to investigate. He would be the first to arrive on blasted and burnt Cyrene, members of the 3rd Company joining him in battling a newly ascended Kyras. Though he fell to the titanic blows of the former space marine turned daemon prince, his life was saved by loyal apothecaries and significant bionic replacement.

After a short period of adjustment, these bionics have proven to further aid him, increasing his combat capabilities and strength. He now stands resolved to rebuild not just the numbers of the Blood Ravens, but their very character in a new era, even if the eternal question of the Unknown Primarch and the words of the thrice damned Eliphas will forever ring in his ears. After the death of Kyras, he has seen to the rebuilding of the Chapter's relations with other Imperial organizations and their numbers, all whilst wielding the increasingly legendary hammer known as Godsplitter.

One of greatest Blood Ravens in recent history, it was Gabriel Angelos who first uncovered the heresy at the heart of the Chapter and it was he who struck the first blows against it. Such was his will and reputation that the twisted Azariah Kyras did not even attempt to corrupt him, instead the fallen Chapter Master attempted to brand Angelos as a renegade and set the Chapter against itself. In this, Kyras succeeded, but he did not expect that those remaining pure members of the Chapter to actually fight back, much less have any chance of success. During the vicious Blood Raven Civil War which occurred just after the Third Aurelian Crusade, it was Gabriel who triumphed and not the corrupted scions of Kyras. A veteran of battle against every single major xeno foe of the Imperium and then some, sworn foe and many-times victory against the forces of Chaos, and now Chapter Master, Gabriel Angelos is known as a stalwart, noble, and nigh-incorruptible hero of the Imperium to numerous worlds and officials across the Imperium. He has fought in every Segmentum, and his battle honors are many. He has faced warbosses and squiggoths, daemons and daemon princes. He is one of the few living members of humanity to ever visit the Black Library and return, facing the infamous sorcerer of the Thousand Sons known as Ahriman. He crushed the Tau in the Targa System. Friend and many times ally to the Inquisition, his position is nearly unassailable politically.

The Imperium's opinion on his Chapter is far less favorable.

Former First Company Captain, Then Honor Guard Captain, Current Chapter Master Bodyguard Apollo Diomedes
The Captain of the Honor Guard and previously the Right Hand to the traitor Kyras, Captain Diomedes has spent his time since the revelation of just who he had served so faithfully for so long alternatively brooding and being filled with absolute fury. Previously one of the most politically involved members of the Chapter, the Captain has in recent times retreated from such things entirely, focusing solely on his combat abilities and protecting Chapter Master Angelos with incredible ferocity.

Still, despite reaching his former position with no small amount of political maneuvering, he is perhaps the best living fighter in the whole of the Chapter, though it is rumored that the exiled Force Commander Aramus could have matched or even eclipsed him. As it is, he reigns supreme on the battlefield while Chapter Master Angelos leads. Apollo Diomedes remains the space marine who once defeated the Chaos Sorcerer Anupharis the Cruel and Warboss Manstompa Megakilla in the same day, who later fought on against and defeated the accursed Kyras. He simply finds no glory in his actions any longer. Once a fiery and prideful champion of the Chapter, Apollo Diomedes is known as a singularly depressive figure to his fellow Blood Ravens, whose demeanor and words can turn even the most aggressive and energetic marine morose. He restricts himself from doing so when not directly approached, and as such has found himself increasingly isolated from his brothers. Yet this is rarely held against him, for he was a blind puppet to Azariah Kyras for over two centuries, and to have the veil ripped from his eyes as it was in the Third Aurelian Crusade nearly broke him. For his close association with Kyras and having been traitor's most powerful personal agent in dealings with the rest of the Imperium and all of its foes including the Inquisition, a great amount of scrutiny has been focused on Diomedes. Such is his shame and acknowledgement of his folly, the former Captain of the Honor Guard has relinquished his position - knowing he could not possibly retain such a position of importance in the Chapter any longer.

Even now, however, it cannot be forgotten that he remains one of the greatest warriors in the Chapter's history. But whether he will rise from the depths of his own self-loathing or burn in a pyre of his own bitter fury remains to be seen.

Tomb-Captain Davian Thule
Once the second most well beloved Blood Raven in the Chapter behind Chapter Master Angelos, Captain Davian Thule was head of the 4th Company for quite some time. With a list of accomplishments stretching quite high indeed, one of the the greatest of his feats was the Dark Crusade on the planet Kronus whence he fought against and found victory against the simultaneous armies of Chaos, Eldar, Necron, Ork, Tau, and more regrettably the Imperial Guard who refused to obey and leave the planet. It is said that during the Dark Crusade he uncovered strange and dark secrets regarding the Chapter and had said records burned into non-existence. Now, he is the only one privy to the secrets of Kronus, refusing to answer even Chapter Master Angelos's questioning. The price for his defiance was being posted for the long-term on the Recruiting Worlds of Sub-Sector Aurelia.

A respected leader by all, he was unfortunately struck down during the arrival of the tyranids in the First Aurelian Crusade with their vile poisons though thankfully he survived long enough to be interred into a holy dreadnought. In the past, his moments of lucidity were few and passing though treasured as a result of the Tyranid toxins which ravaged him most terribly, but over the years steady work by the Apothecarium and time to heal has returned him most fully. He speaks as easily as he ever did, and only by his unshakable will does he stave off the great exhaustion and slow descent many of the entombed suffer as the centuries go on.

Captain of the 10th Company and Master of Recruits Cyrus Octavius
The taciturn and eternally grim Cyrus is now one of the oldest marines in the entire Chapter after the near destruction of it during the Civil War of 749.M41. His deeds are legend, though more of the whispered kind than the boasts of others. This is due to his unusual political and social status in the Chapter. Highly unorthodox, whispers of impiety and worse drove him to prove himself by serving in the Deathwatch for nearly two centuries where his eccentricities were welcomed and fully embraced.

It was only after the battle of Victoria Primus that he ended his tour of duty, returning to his former company which had come under the command of Captain Indrick Boreale. After decades of resistance to his knowledge and expertise, Cyrus finally requested to serve under Captain Davian Thule. Thule was quickly convinced and soon began to implement many of Cyrus's tactics as a matter of course. Fighting alongside Thule in the Dark Crusade of Kronus solidified their eternal bonds of friendship and brotherhood.

More recently, he fought in all three of the Aurelian Crusades, and highly protested the banishment of Force Commander Aramus at the conclusion of the Second. His attachment to his scouts, which has slowly grown to encompass all scouts of the Chapter, is second to none, as is his fury at the now dead Boreale for sacrificing so many as he did in the lamented Kaurava Campaign. This is due to the fact that Cyrus was and still is the premier teacher amongst the Blood Ravens, having participated in the training of Aspirants, Neophytes, and Scout Marines since his return from the Death Watch about a century ago even when he was part of different Companies.

In 997.M41 he was advanced to Captain of the 10th Company and Master of Recruits.

5th Company's Brother-Captain Tarkus Varianus
One of the eldest Blood Ravens alive, Sergeant Tarkus has many centuries of experience. A native of Calderis, he was once second in command to Captain Davian Thule himself, under who's command he gained the reputation of a legendary steely demeanour and confidence in the face of overwhelming odds, as well as being a trustworthy and wise advisor. During the Dark Crusade, Tarkus especially distinguished himself twice, once against the Tau, then against the Necrons. In the former, he faced down a charging Knarloc and Crisis Suit Team simultaneously while holding down a recently established FOB as the Blood Ravens pushed into the city of Asharis (renamed Or'es Tash'n by the Tau). In the second, he willingly sacrificed his left hand and forearm to destroy a Tomb Spyder with a grenade while the detonator to collapse the Thur'Abis Plateau was still being armed in the most critical moment of the battle. It was the latter that gained him Terminator Honors. Later on, he would serve under the infamous Force Commander Aramus during the first two Aurelian Crusades, and there acted ably as a stalwart defender of the Chapter against WAAAAGH! Bonesmasha, an Eldar Warhost led by the Farseer Idranel, and a Hive Fleet of Tyranids. He would personally execute the witch Idranel at the conclusion of the Battle of Angel Forge.

Yet, during the course of the Second Aurelian Crusade, matters took a turn for the worse. While he faithfully served Force Commander Aramus, he increasingly questioned matters as the crusade progressed. The shattering of Angel Gate, the desecration of Daedus' Tomb on Typhon, these were all supposedly practical measures. But the slaughter of a great many Blood Ravens on Calderis when confronting the unwitting Diomedes was one of the most despicable things done, even in the name of the Chapter and the greater good. When Sergeant Avitus, a close ally and friend, was revealed as the traitor amongst the Heroes of Typhon, it was Tarkus who slew him. In the end, with Ulkair defeated, Tarkus was judged pure enough to remain within the Chapter, unlike Aramus, who Tarkus reluctantly spoke against for his actions. Yet, feeling that he had grievously failed the Blood Ravens by not sensing the corruption within Avitus and all else done during the crusade, he donned the helm of the Ancient and took a Vow of Silence as penitence, only breaking it when Captain Diomedes was shattered by the revelation of Kyras's heresy during the Third Aurelian Crusade. Well known and greatly respected amongst the Chapter if not extensively liked on a personal level, he is especially noted for a hatred of Eldar after being tricked and betrayed by them when he was convinced to work with them against a group of orks - losing a number of battle brothers in the process.

In 999.M41 he was advanced to Captain of the 5th Company, also known as The Fated Company.

Forge Master Martellus Ravias
Martellus Ravias was previously an largely unremarkable Senior Techmarine of the Blood Ravens. He had, of course, served for centuries, and had battled xenos and traitor alike across the galaxy as a part of his secondment to various companies of the Chapter. But, as a techmarine, he spent a considerable amount of his time in the forges, building and maintaining equipment for his brothers. All this changed, however, upon his assignment to the command of Force Commander Aramus. Thrust into battle against a massive Splinter Fleet, his true legend began when under a truly tremendous weight of anti-air fire from the tyranids in the final battle of the First Aurelian Crusade his Thunderhawk was struck low on Typhon Primaris. Presumed dead, Martellus in fact lived to crawl away from the crash and discovered he was trapped deep within the jungle filled to the brim with newly feral tyranids and orks. Half dead, almost all equipment shattered beyond repair, he refused to die. Instead, he dragged himself to a powerful Astronomic Array, a device that Commander Aramus had made great use of during the First Aurelian Crusade. Once there, he repaired the device and what of his own equipment he could over the course of a long year while under constant attack, and was subsequently rescued. Following such, he would participate valiantly in the Third Aurelian Crusade. One of the few remaining Techmarines after the Blood Raven Civil War, he was the most senior and most skilled, and as such was made the Master of the Forge.

Chief Librarian Justinius Probalis
Formerly of the 3rd Company is a good man, having served as a subordinate of the lamented Jonah Orion for over a century and had what may be considered the luck to not be travelling with the majority of the 3rd Company against the Tyranid Hive Mind during the First Aurelian Crusade. As it is, Jonah was a tremendously powerful force on the direct and psychic combat who passed many of his teachings down to Justinius. Still, the man is no carbon copy of his instructor and has focused many of his energies on parsing the future and piercing the fog of war from across the battlefield, a traditional Blood Raven Librarian discipline but one he has refined. As a result his skills are far more suited for ranged battle, not close pitched warfare. In terms of personality, he is an incredibly calm marine, and it was whispered amongst the initiates and scouts that his near unflappable nature is due to him having perceived his own death and thus becoming practically fearless as a result.

In 997.M41 he was advanced from Epistolary of the 3rd Company to Chief Librarian. Since then he has overseen a careful rebuilding of Librarius.

Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun
In those dark times when you were unsure just who you could trust in the Chapter while Kyras was its Master, Hannibal was there. A master orator and a deadly combatant, he has fought alongside you since Tartarus, and all the years afterwards. Then, he was but a student under Chaplain Mikelus, who was a good friend of yours and one well missed in the Chapter. Alas, Mikelus died on Kronus, seconded to Captain Davian Thule's command there - and is credited with the slaying of the Necron Lord there. Afterwards, Hannibal threw himself into his mentor's duties. His fiery rhetoric and piety kept the 3rd Company strong in those dark times when hope seemed so bleak, and he denied that you were possibly heretics for entertaining treachery against the traitor Kyras. One of the largest marines you’ve ever seen not just amongst the Blood Ravens but amongst any Space Marines in general, his bulk reflects his abilities to stalwartly wade through oceans of enemy fire while bellowing blessed hatred.

In 997.M41 he was advanced to Master of Sanctity, and set about rebuilding the Chaplaincy of the Chapter.

Master of the Apothecarion Nero Gracchus
An extremely young marine at the time of his promotion to Master of the Apothecarion, though skilled at his craft. Recruited from Calderis, he is one of the few parts of the 5th Company who did not go with Aramus on his Penitent Crusade. As it is, he is one of those who worked alongside the honored Brother Gordion on the bio-toxin used against the Hive Mind in the First Aurelian Crusade, and has spent much of his time doing similar work. While not precisely skilled when it comes to combat like some might expect of a Space Marine, he is a startlingly good researcher with an intimate knowledge of not just the human and marine body but of xenos as well. He may not be as potent on the battlefield as some would prefer, but based on the reports when it comes to sheer medical ability he outstrips all other candidates. As of late he has begun growing a reputation for being one of the most fearsome dangers that a Blood Raven may face should they find themselves on his tables more often than absolutely necessary by his own reckoning. [+Intelligent, Savant of Medicine]

In 998.M41 he was advanced to Master of the Apothecarion

Honor Guard's Brother-Captain Jordis Mencis
Formerly a 2nd Company Assault Sergeant, Brother Jordis displayed skilled leadership and exemplary combat capabilities that ensured that his squad achieved the maximum possible result with the greatest possible efficiency. The bonds of brotherhood he forged with his old squad in the 2nd Company squad are amongst the most close-knit in the entire Chapter. Most recently, he showed great valor and skill during combat against the Suysh, managing to be credited with one solo Suysh Queen kill by weathering the alien’s fury at close range in order to slay it. Jordis has long proven himself a remarkably adept leader and superlative fighter. For all that he was a sergeant of a squad of Assault Marines, he maintained and maintains still a cool and disciplined demeanor both in and outside of battle. When not fighting, he worked tirelessly to improve the skills and coordination of his 2nd Company squad, to the point that even after a short time even new arrivals to his squad grew capable of coordination on the level of chapter veterans. This behavior has not ceased since his advancement to Captain of the Honor Guard. [+WS, +Guiding Hand of War, +Fellowship, +Toughness]

Advanced to Honor Guard Captain in 075.M42

1st Company's Brother-Captain Marcus Crixus
An assault marine of the 5th Company, and one of its few survivors after the Blood Raven Civil War. Curiously, however, instead of distinguishing himself for leaping into battle and splitting apart dozens or hundreds of enemies, he instead became known to the Chapter for helping organize and direct forces numerous times during the 3rd Aurelian Crusade and the Blood Raven Civil War with greatly appreciated skill. Apollo speaks well of him, saying that while he and the rest of his immediate command squad would pursue objectives, oddly enough it would by Brother Crixus who would somehow end up being listened to about where squads and vehicles should go. His grasp of wider battlefield tactics is quite interesting. Despite his youth, he does appear at the least relatively skilled. [+Perception, Natural Tactician]

Was Promoted To Captain of the 1st Company in the last few years of M41

2nd Company's Brother-Captain Macharius Sicarius
A Devastator Sergeant of the 3rd, then 1st Company, now promoted to Captain of the 2nd. Out of all the marines in the Chapter he is likely the only one who could match Chapter Master Angelos in terms of bionics. This has actually somewhat aided him in his duties, his augmented strength and vision allowing him to wield heavy weaponry with accuracy and ease. He distinguished himself by facing down three Predator Tanks of the Traitors during the Third Aurelian Crusade alone while the rest of his squad died. Wrenching the dead hulk of the honorable Tomb-Brother Achillan about with his immense strength, he used his experience with heavy weaponry to reactivate the dreadnought’s connected multi-melta and obliterate the foe. Since then, he has distinguished himself as an unyielding warrior and stalwart leader for his fellows. Many times, it is his gruff frame which provides the rallying point, all the while he ensured death from afar found its target amongst the enemy. A constant, steady presence for the Chapter's leadership, something direly needed in a Chapter so near to the edge for so long. [+Ballistic Skill, +Strength, Unblinking Deathdealer, Stalwart Slayer]

3rd Company's Brother-Captain Hantu, Master of the Arsenal
Formerly a veteran sergeant of the 4th Company, Hantu is quietly known to be one of the 'Distant Brothers' who fought in the Aurelian Crusades. He was there, on Calderis, when his Brother-Captain in Davian Thule was slain, and had in fact served with Captain Thule since Kronus on. While he was not part of the detachment of Force Commander Aramus, he was amongst those Blood Ravens who fought to keep the tide back while Aramus' strike force focused on precise strategic strikes. It was not until more recently that he distinguished himself significantly above many other Blood Ravens. During the Helba Campaign, Hantu found himself proving not simply adept in battle in excess of many of his battle brothers but furthermore remarkably diplomatic. As the campaign went on, he found himself being tapped regularly for cooperative and coordinative measures between the Imperial Guard and the Sisters of Battle also fighting in the campaign. Captain Hantu is one of the last ever recruits from the world of Typhon, now lost to Exterminatus. Noted to possess a remarkable affinity for combined forces combat, he was even granted the honor of commanding certain battles during the Helba Campaign with Guardsmen and Sisters of Battle under his banner following his orders. Later, he was tapped to helm the revived 3rd Company, an auspicious task given that it was the former company of Chapter Master Angelos. (Legendary Fellowship: Within The Raven's Shadow, +W, +I)

In 075.M42 the 3rd Company was revived, and Brother Hantu was promoted to be its Captain.

4th Company's Brother-Captain Hadrian Priscus, Master of the Fleet
A veteran sergeant of the 5th Company with quite a few accomplishments to his name. Visiting the 10th Company at the time of the Third Aurelian Crusade, the senior sergeant instead rallied not only the scouts there in slaying their traitor brethren, but directed the Company’s flagship into battle against the rest of the traitor fleet, boarding and reclaiming ships one at a time. It is at his hands that you have some ships at all, even if their conditions are less than preferable. If anyone was wondering why the Chapter Fleet was not more present during the Third Aurelian Crusade, here is the reason, the mad, mad reason who leapt from ship to ship again and again throughout the entire Crusade until victory was achieved. [+Intelligence, Void Craft Prodigy]

In 998.M41 he was advanced to Master of the Fleet, but did not ascend to actual Captaincy of the 4th Company as would be typical due to the lack of an actual 4th Company to take control of.

In 025.M42 the 4th Company was re-established, and Hadrian took command of the Company that had always been meant for him.

Force Commander (Disgraced) Aramus Valorun [4th Company] On Penitent Crusade
One of the most famed yet controversial members of the Blood Ravens in living memory, Aramus Valorun's rise from Sergeant to Force Commander has retroactively been forever tainted by the reveal that his promotion was heavily influenced by the traitorous, corrupted, and heretical Azariah Kyras, former Chapter Master and Chief Librarian of the Blood Ravens. Recruited as an initiate from the planet Typhon Primaris, Aramus quickly displayed exceptional abilities as both a warrior and tactician, abilities that were only further displayed when he was promoted to a battle brother of the 4th Company. Participating in numerous campaigns with valor, Aramus was originally assumed by many to have risen to prominence when as a sergeant he gathered together the remnants of three different squads and led them in a daring artillery raid during the Hadrian campaign and returned with zero casualties. Shortly afterwards promoted to Force Commander - barely past a century old making him the youngest ever promoted to such a position - by the order of Kyras, Aramus would go on to successfully defend Subsector Aurelia during the first two Aurelian Crusades. In the first Aurelian Crusade, he would accomplish many staggeringly improbable tasks. With only a bare handful of space marines at his side, he would end a powerful greenskin WAAAAAGH!, personally slaying Warboss Bonesmasha and a number of chieftains across multiple worlds. He would go on to defend Angel Forge on Meridian, aid in the slaying of the eldar witch Idranel, and went on to bring down an Avatar of Khaine - and would do so again during the Second Aurelian Crusade - and stymied the efforts of an Eldar Warhost across three worlds. He reclaimed shrines and manufactorums, and protected ancient archaeotech creations. Against the tyranids, he would lead his small band of Blood Ravens and successfully hold back their invasion before breaking them at the Battle of Typhon with powerful bio-weapons crafted at Angel Forge. Some of the greatest exemplars and abominations from three xenos races fell before his hammer and the weaponry of his forces alike, all within less than a hundred days.

Yet then he faltered.

Some say that it was due to the fact that he was promoted too quickly, raised up without the proper seasoning and experience required to weather the insidious nature. Others say that his victories in the first Aurelian Crusade made him too prideful, blind to the danger. Others whisper that it was only the blatant corruption of Kyras and others that made those who even stumbled upon the edge worthy of punishment and suspicion. None can say for certain, now. What is known, however, is that the return of Eliphas the Inheritor, long-time foe of the Chapter, and Araghast the Pillager, a monstrous Chaos Lord of the Black Legion, spelled the end of Aramus' ascension within the Chapter. Over the course of the second Aurelian Crusade, he would undertake many questionable actions. He broke Angel's Gate to more quickly reach the enemy, he willingly broke open the tomb of an honored fallen brother on Typhon for the wargear within, utilized tainted wargear looted from the enemy, and worst of all, led his forces into direct conflict with members of the Blood Ravens Honor Guard and 1st Company under Apollo Diomedes. Some, likely, were corrupted. But many were not, and so the killing of loyal Blood Ravens - even with the killing of Galan - was almost inexcusable. Failing to stop the corruption of Avitus, another Blood Raven recruited from Typhon, was only one more failure. In the end, even after landing the final blow on Ulkair, it was deemed that Aramus had nearly fallen too far to countenance, yet would be granted the chance of redemption by way of Penitent Crusade by way of the Eye of Terror. He would be followed by a number of his battle brothers who fought alongside him, but not all. Some, such as the Librarian Jonah Orion, Sergeant Tarkus, Sergeant Cyrus, and Captain Davian Thule, would remain, being judged pure. Others, such as Thaddeus Rex, would willingly join him even without being ordered to do so. Even judged as quite possibly the best individual combatant in the whole chapter, possibly only contested by Apollo Diomedes, he was sent away.

Since then, he has been sighted fighting in the 13th Black Crusade in multiple theaters.

Veteran Assault Sergeant (Disgraced) Thaddeus Rex [4th Company] On Penitent Crusade
When he was recruited, Thaddeus was the first initiate to come from Meridian in over seven centuries, the planet in the past having long ceased at providing any viable initiates at all for so long that the Blood Ravens had even ceased to look. However, all that changed during one of the city's many riots under Governor Vandis. At one point, the riots had grown so fierce as to involve the Blood Ravens, and it was there that Captain Davian Thule sighted young Thaddeus holding of crowds of rioters to protect common Imperial citizenry, having become a member of an Underhive Gang out of sheer grit, skill, and luck despite his youth. He was promptly recruited after the disturbance ended and passed through the Blood Trials with remarkable ease, Davian Thule acting as a warmly regarded mentor throughout the process. In time he would quickly find that his true skill and purpose lay as an Assault Marine of the 4th Company under Captain Thule. He would be promoted to Sergeant shortly before the first Aurelian Crusade after only 80 years as a Blood Raven. He would later become known as a startlingly idealistic leader, brash and bold in battle, regularly contributing his squad to battling the greenskins of Typhon Primaris and Calderis.

It was during the Aurelian Crusades, however, where he truly came to prominence under Force Commander Aramus. In said fighting, then-young Thaddeus would contend with the tyranids and many of their most hideous bio-forms, aiding in the slaughter of numerous ork chieftains and the death of Warboss Bonesmasha. It was during the Aurelian Crusades that Thaddeus battled the Eldar for the first time, combating and defeating numerous Eldar warlocks and war machines amidst their own masses of troops. The sheer quantity and variety of foes fought throughout the first of the Aurelian Crusades meant that it was a matter of course that Thaddeus would distinguish himself again and again, to the point that he was nominated for Terminator Honors, a great honor especially for one so young. The inciting battle which granted him thus was fought on Calderis, where he and his squad would face three powerful tyranid carnifex beasts in succession in the defense of an Imperial shrine to the Emperor while the rest of the strike force fought off zoanthropes and hordes of gaunts attacking from another direction. Other major accomplishments include the slaying of a duo of Hive Tyrants on Calderis and Typhon within the same day, defeating an Eldar Wraithlord with a single power axe while the rest of the strike force was occupied, and tallying over a hundred shattered tanks of Eldar and ork varieties with melta bombs over the course of the First Aurelian Crusade. He would prove to possess a strong belief in defending the citizens of the Imperium, his idealism quite at odds with others amongst the strike force time again save for in Force Commander Aramus.

During the second Aurelian Crusade, however, he would prove too willing to follow Force Commander Aramus into near-damnation, utilizing tainted wargear in battle far more than any others while almost never questioning the darker acts performed therein. Even so, it was most clearly the fault of Aramus, leading his troops into corruption, who would bear the brunt of the punishment. None others needed go. Yet, after a short and private meeting with the entombed Davian Thule, Thaddeus would immediately request to accompany Aramus on his Penitent Crusade, as would a small number of other marines of the 4th Company.

Since then, he has been sighted fighting in the 13th Black Crusade alongside Aramus at a variety of locations.

Sergeants/Champions/Etc.

Spoiler: 3rd Company ChampionAmicus Antal

A tragic tale. Five times, has his entire squad been wiped out with him as the sole survivor. Five times, by five distinct major foes of the Imperium, has he nearly been slain. The first was from an ork force that outnumbered his squad 20-1. The second, from a blasted Eldar strike force. The third, the tau during the Vorga campaign. The fourth time came from tyranids while fighting against the Hive Tyrant during the last battle of the First Aurelian Crusade. The fifth, from traitors…his own squad, turned against him and towards Chaos. No sergeant should have lost what he has, much less be forced to fight and kill his entire own squad as they attempted to slay him. His sheer fortitude keeps him going physically, and regular meetings with your Master of Sanctity for many years has ensured his spiritual and mental strength remaining stalwart and strong. He has, as of 075.M42, been elevated from the 1st Company to Company Champion of the 3rd Company. [+Toughness, Last Man Standing)

Spoiler: 1st Company Terminator Sergeant Stromahn

Any member of the 1st Company is one of the greatest veterans of the chapter, and Sergeant Stromahn is no different. A terminator under Chapter Master Angelos as far back as Tartarus, Stromahn has proven himself again and again. He has stood against the tide again and again to preserve the lives of his brothers, striking the foe with unrelenting fury while trusting in the artifice of his terminator armor to preserve him. The amount of glories he has won, and the sheer effort he puts into advising his brethren in battle and outside of it marks him as a solid foundation for younger brothers to seek out guidance from. [+Elder Veteran, +Guiding Heart]

Spoiler: 10th Company Veteran Sergeant Kaius Jacobus

One of the immediately promoted members of the 10th Company to complete battle brother. Cyrus has indicated that out of his many students that Jacobus is one of the few to actually satisfy him when it comes to stealth, something few ever truly manage to master. He distinguished himself during the Second Aurelian Crusade against the damned Eliphas the Inheritor as one of those scouts who never even received an injury during the dangerous moments when the forces of Chaos had managed to isolate a large number of Scouts on Calderis. Mostly because they could never find or hit him while he popped in and out of stealth with a combat shotgun, flamer, and sniper rifle strapped all about him in ramshackle webbing that he nonetheless used quite skillfully. [+Agility, Shadow Hunter]

Spoiler: 1st Company Champion Hamul

One of the youngest marines to ever be promoted to the 1st Company, and a former sergeant of the 2nd Company, Hamul is an aggressive marine who never truly gave up his preference for close combat as an assault marine. A close devotee to Chapter Master Kyras, he was struck terribly by the knowledge of his master's heresy, and so plunged himself into the most deadly of combats against the incredibly dangerous necron for some sort of redemption during his stint in the Deathwatch. His experience and skill eventually advanced him to Kill Team Leader amongst the Deathwatch, at a remarkably fast pace. His energy and passion is remarkable, likened to by those where he cannot hear them as similar to much more aggressive Chapters such as the Flesh Tearers - though with a perhaps stronger core of discipline and restraint. [+WS, Aggressive Slayer]

Spoiler: 2nd Company Champion Obasi

A former Assault Marine Sergeant that led by martially excellent example, Brother Obasi exemplified this in the battles against the Suysh, as one of the best swordsmen in the entire Chapter he is credited with slaying two Queens and their Royal Guard with nothing but a chainsword. After proving himself an able leader and fighter, a series of duels were fought out amongst the entire 2nd Company at the behest of Captain Macharius who sought to find the absolute best fighter of his subordinate brethren. Brother Obasi won out, even against the Captain himself in the final duel, and as such was awarded the position of Company Champion. Still beholden to his former status, Obasi elects to continue bearing his jump pack, making his efforts as Champion particularly violent and sudden as he leaps forward on wings of fire. [+WS , Exemplar]

Spoiler: Veteran Scout Sergeant Persean

One of the greater unseen veterans of the chapter, Sergeant Persean was a mere tactical marine under Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos when he was a mere Captain of the 3rd Company. He fought alongside the Captain for many decades, and was present on Tartarus to witness Isador's heresy and the condemnation of the world. He was a stalwart combatant against the Tau as well. In every major campaign the Captain had fought in as master of the 3rd, Persean was there, until his commander's ascension to Chapter Master and the Civil War. He found, in the end, his place amongst the scouts, something he took to with surprising gusto and ability, becoming a dangerously effective scout leader. He is dedicated to preserving the chapter's legacy through its gene-seed, while being sometimes even more taciturn and stoic than even Captain Cyrus. [Murderous Guardian/Silent Dervish]

Spoiler: 4th Company Champion Trexus Nubius

Trexus Nubius is a marine whose loyalty has never been questionable since his induction as an initiate. He stood alongside his Chapter Master when Gabriel Angelos was but the Captain of the 3rd Company. There, he fought in the crucible that was Tartarus, though many battlefields before and after found his boots marching across them. He fought alongside his Captain for over two centuries, up until the Aurelian Crusades, where he partook in the event known as Gabriel’s Miracle, the fight against the daemon Ulkair and its minions, and yet still on against Kyras himself. Now, he stands with the 4th Company, an unflinching champion marching forth in the name of the Chapter. While he may not possess the lightning speed of other astartes, his strength and skill are near unmatched amongst the Blood Ravens. (+S, +WS, Stoic Champion)

Spoiler: 5th Company Champion Trogus

Identified during the Hunt for Vandis for successfully keeping his entire squad alive throughout the fighting, whereas every other sergeant was either killed or lost members of their squad, despite repeatedly taking on spear-tip position alongside or occasionally outright replacing the marines of the 1st Company if required. A true protégé of Captain Tarkus, Sergeant Trogus possesses an equally stoic and taciturn temperament mixed with significant if tempered aggression in battle. A true warrior, a true leader. (+F, +W, Bedrock of Battle)

Spoiler: 2nd Company Veteran Nicholas

A Meridian High Spire-sourced assault marine who bears all the aggressive tendencies of Captain Hadrian Priscus, Veteran Nicholas repeatedly distinguished himself in the campaign for accomplishing the highest number of high-value target kills through individual combat, exceeding even Force Commander Cyrus. Slaying Hive Tyrants in their nests, ambushing Lictors as they skulked through the battlefield, and cutting down Zoanthropes before they could fully unleash their might, Veteran Nicholas bears a considerable amount of skill, outperforming all others in the 4th Company at the time of this notation. (+WS, +P)

Spoiler: 4th Company Veteran Sergeant Gelon

Due to the rapid pace of the campaign, Sergeant Gelon found himself and his squad often made do with only basic equipment, himself wielding only a bolt pistol and chainsword for the majority of the conflict. However, this did not prevent Sergeant Gelon from leading several rescue missions for Blood Raven positions as well as that of their allies, at one point preventing advancing fronts from collapsing on ten different occasions in a single month during a crucial phase. Provided invaluable support and guidance to younger scouts and neophytes during the campaign as well. Became targeted by the Hive Mind for assassination, survived all twelve attempts. (+F, +W)

Specialists

Spoiler: Techmarine Daedal

Part of a pair of techmarines recruited out of the now lost Typhon Primaris, the Techmarine Daedal showed a high aptitude for vehicle technology from the start. As it turned out, the animistic shamanic traditions upon his recruiting world translated strongly into communing with the Machine Spirits of humanity's technology. One of the survivors of the Purge, Daedal is characterized as a slightly reckless techmarine when the machines of the chapter are threatened, as well as when it comes to his piloting of Thunderhawks. The latter is said to be because of his unshakable faith in the machine spirits, but most marines simply appreciate how quickly he can deliver troops to the battle. Also notable is his close friendship with the Techmarine Calus, despite both being from two different tribes who were genocidally opposed to the existence of the other. [Machine Spirit Speaker, +Intelligence]

Spoiler: Techmarine Calus

Part of a pair of techmarines recruited out of the now lost Typhon Primaris, the Techmarine Calus has shown a high propensity for more exotic technologies. It so happened that the tribe he was recruited from was the most technologically advanced on their world, and despite leaving them behind more than a century ago he retains their tendency for seeking out the highest possible limits for the arsenal of his brothers. One of the survivors of the Purge, Calus personally slew a full thirty traitor Blood Ravens with a supercharged multi-melta and lascannon alone, trusting in the machine spirits of his lovingly treated wargear. He is known to be somewhat unflappable compared to his more volatile compatriot Daedal, and happens to be the most highly skilled Thunderhawk Gunship pilots in the Chapter, often electing to guard over his brothers from the skies when allowed. [Adepta Exotica, +Intelligence]

Spoiler: 1st Company Chaplain Ares Actus

A veteran Sergeant of the 3rd, now 1st Company, who led many a guard action during Chapter Master Angelos's campaigns when he was Captain of the 3rd. He has held the line again and again while others deep strike into enemy territory, and on those few occasions where retreat was necessary he was there, all the while. Not the most skilled, but perhaps one of the most stalwart, he has been struck again and again but never fallen, all the while calling out for his brothers to go to greater lengths to fight and kill in the name of the Emperor with holy zeal. He was accepted for Chaplaincy training under Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun in 998.M41. Became a Chaplain in 003.M42 [+Fellowship, Fiery Demagogue]

Spoiler: Techmarine Quarius Zergan

One of the youngest marines in the Chapter to have achieved the rank of sergeant in the history of the Blood Ravens. Nonetheless, besides his youth the sheer amount of battles and campaigns he has fought alongside you have made him worthy enough of his title. What truly interests you however, or rather, Martellus, was his potentially heretical habit of tinkering with his own weapons to squeeze out just a bit more efficiency or death dealing capabilities. After speaking to Martellus however and being informed of just how close he was coming to death, he ceased immediately. That does not mean he could not begin again, if properly instructed of course. After further testing he was sent to Mars for true Techmarine training. In 028.M42 he returned from Mars, brimming with new knowledge. He is, however, happy to be home amongst the Chapter once more. The sheer dogma of Mars was daunting to one such as him, apparently. [+Intelligence, Tinkering Talent] Returned From Mars In 028.M42

Spoiler: 1st Company Apothecary Constantius Romallius

A 3rd Company then 1st Company veteran who was present on Tartarus and almost all the other battlefields beyond. There is not much to outwardly differentiate himself from the rest of the Chapter, though after getting to know the man you can proudly call yourself amongst the handful of individuals who know that he carries a strange fondness for puns and laughter, a rarity amongst the more usually taciturn versions of his kind. Also included in that is his affection for ranged weapons – an unusual habit for an Apothecary – and can often be found wielding a flamer or dual wielding bolt pistols instead of a more customary chain sword. This is not to say he is defenseless in melee combat, but he personally prefers to kill his enemies from afar so that they do not get close enough to disturb him while he operates at all. Some might question his more unorthodox methods, but you have long accepted them as part of who he is. [Ranged Inclination, Vaguely Unorthodox Methods]

Spoiler: 10th Company Apothecary Marius Astophiles

The Apothecary of 10th Company. Brother Astophiles has overseen the recruitment, implantation, and growth of over a century and a half’s worth of Blood Ravens – though he felt great shame for not realizing the corruption of his Company from within under Kyras’s influence. Few can blame him for this, as any attempts to do so must be acknowledged that none discovered the traitor’s treachery until it was almost too late. His brusque nature melds together with his status as one of the most puritanical members of the entire Chapter, outright refusing to do some things that might go against tradition or the Emperor without a Chaplain and Librarian’s explicit approval. On the other hand, is he were not an apothecary he would most certainly have become an Assault Terminator of the First Company, given his combat skills and the fact that in a unique circumstance as a more standard battle brother that he did in fact manage to make Terminator Honors before being selected for his position. [+Weapon Skill, Highly Orthodox]

Spoiler: Techmarine Janos

Techmarine Janos proved himself willing to battle the technologies of the alien Suysh without hesitation, trusting in his skill and the Omnissiah to bring him to victory. During the Suysh campaign, he quickly and often chose to participate openly in battle, all the better to service the vehicles and wargear of his brothers even while under fire. His stoicism is already a growing legend, the steel in his spine quite possibly Omnissiah-given. [+Combat Engineer, +Willpower]

Spoiler: Apothecary Talm

Brother Talm seems almost upset at being as skilled and capable an apothecary that he is, though he has spoken to none other than the Chaplains about such things, if he does at all. He excises this discontent in the most appreciable of means: slaying the enemies of the Emperor whenever possible with a shotgun or plasma pistol while standing over the bodies of his brothers. It has been noted, more than once, that he was destined to be an exemplary devastator marine before being selected as an apothecary. [+Violent Protector, +Ballistic Skill]

Spoiler: Honor Guard Apothecary Ikai

During the battles against the Suysh, on those few occasions where Blood Ravens fell, Brother Ikai was the one who led the charge to retrieve them. Inevitably, his white armor was covered from head to toe in alien gore by the end of it, all to preserve the precious progenoid glands of his brothers. Though bereft of a jump pack, as skilled with the chainsword and as brash as he is, it is unsurprising that he was expected to be a superb assault marine before taken into the ranks of the apothecaries. As of 075.M42, he was elected to be join the Honor Guard as its Apothecary. [+Assault Apothecary, +Weapon Skill]

Spoiler: Chaplain Alastair

Much to the consternation of the Master of the Apothecarion, Chaplain Alistair has readily followed the example of Hannibal Palrun, Master of Sanctity of the Blood Ravens. Alistair has proven a ready member of the Fist of Faith formation, utterly willing to weather the storm of enemy fire with nothing more than his body, and a violent inspiration to his brethren. All of which was done without a rosarius. Even so, his durability is matched perhaps only by the Master of Sanctity himself, with Chaplain Alastair also shielding the wounded with his own body. His battlefield sermons on fury and hatred are held up as examples even amongst his fellow Chaplains, his skill with a crozius and pistol undeniable. [+Toughness, +Thunderous Orator]

Spoiler: 3rd Company Chaplain Galloss

Chaplain Galloss is an eccentric, even amongst the Chaplains, for his incredible quiet outside of battle. In the flames of war, he is just as bombastic and exulting as his fellows, but outside of it he rarely speaks much at all, leaving sermons for his brothers. Even so, his nature has allowed him to be remarkably capable of pinpointing chinks in the spiritual and mental armor of his brethren, speaking to them and buoying their faith and will in the aftermath of battle. By the time Chaplain Galloss has finished counseling any one marine, they are all the stronger for it, their souls tempered and salved with his aid. As of 075.M42, he was named as the Chaplain for the 3rd Company. [+Fellowship, +War Counselor]

Spoiler: Honor Guard Chaplain Tasanor

It has been remarked amongst the Chaplaincy that Brother Tasanor would have been a Company Champion were it not for his position. He has displayed incredible combat ability, even amongst fellow Astartes, and formed a highly effective part of the first Fist of Faith formation during the Suysh campaign. Though he wields a crozius, as is befitting his position, he also carries a multitude of other weapons depending on the enemy he is facing at the time. Displaying a remarkable flexibility in mentality for a chaplain, he encourages the same in his fellows when attached to squads, leading them to victory again and again. As of 075.M42 he was elevated to Chaplain of the Honor Guard. [+Encyclopedia of Violence, +Heroic Challenger]

Spoiler: Chaplain Sardus

Became especially notable after surviving a thunderhawk transporter crash behind enemy lines caused by tyranid flying bio-forms during the Helba campaign. Dragged other Blood Ravens forced into suspended animation for survival to safety, proceeded to hold out against non-stop tyranid attacks for three days straight until rescued after having run out of ammo on the second. A true student of Hannibal Palrun, the Master of Sanctity, tireless in energy and unfaltering in battle to the extreme. (+T, +W)

Spoiler: 5th Company Chaplain Bellero

Slew a tyranid bio-titan after surviving getting stepped on by the beast directly into a highly acidic reclamation pool, Brother Bellero's armor and entire first layer of skin was gone from him even as he climbed and beat the bio-titan to death about the head with his half-broken crozius. Collapsed into suspended animation afterwards, but later returned to battle after healed. Became most proficient at targeting the larger bio-forms of the tyranids despite being largely on foot and began to lead others to do the same as the fighting intensified. Distinguished himself a dozen times over and received commendations of appreciation from both Imperial Guard forces and the Order of the Lost Rosetta as a result. (+S, +T, +F)

Spoiler: 3rd Company Apothecary Aratos

Headed and protected field hospitals set up to support the advances on multiple different worlds, not merely from tyranid swarms but from various Lictors as well. Swiftly became known amongst the Imperial Guard and Sisters of Battle for taking in patients from their own medical camps when capacity was exceeded. Provided expert healing and is personally responsible for saving the lives of the Canoness Preceptors Lanati Kahele and Elizabeth Drake of the Lost Rosetta after both were nearly killed by tyranids. Protects his patients with remarkable ferocity, whether by chainsword or heavy bolter. As of 075.M42 he was named as the Apothecary of the 3rd Company. (+I, +F)

Librarians

Spoiler: Honor Guard Epistolary Rasmus

Though he is obviously capable, Rasmus does not often wield the most visible psychic powers known to the Chapter. Rather, he has proven himself to be a master with the unseen. Skilled at piercing the veil to analyze possible futures, tracking the enemy, communicating with fellow Librarians at great distances, Rasmus is no easy foe in combat either. He has proven adept at shattering the minds and shackling the nervous systems of his enemies, or utilizing technomancy to ruin their weapons and armor to allow his brothers to kill with impunity. Brother Rasmus has proven his abilities time and again. [+ Deadly Telepath, +Esoteric Master]

Spoiler: 1st Company Epistolary Lucan

As a Codicier, Epistolary Lucan unearthed rare and powerful knowledge hidden within the Librarius of the Litany of Fury, left behind by the Librarian Jonah Orion before the fateful battle against Kyras began on the planet Cyrene. He dedicated many years to studying and mastering this knowledge before fully unleashing it in the Suysh campaign. Though not particularly skilled in visibly impressive abilities, Epistolary Lucan is a master at enhancing his brethren, greatly empowering their strength and psychically accelerating their very bodies until the squads he was attached to became little more than blurs amongst the enemy. Should they take wounds, he has proven quite the capable healer as well, albeit with the powers of his mind rather than the tools of the Apothecary, a legacy of Jonah Orion’s lessons. [+Psychic Booster, +Support Specialist, +Master Biomancer]

Spoiler: 2nd Company Epistolary Flekton

Though he is quite a capable Librarian, learned and powerful as befitting an Epistolary of the Blood Ravens, Brother Flekton has proven a true master of defensive psychic abilities, crafting powerful domes and barriers of pure thought that have withstood the most powerful weapons of tyranids, tau, greenskins, Suysh, and more. His wards also protect his brothers from intrusion into their minds and souls, and for those incredibly rare times that something bypasses his defenses he can quickly set about mending flesh with nothing more than his purifying will as the notable Librarian Jonah Orion once could. While providing and fortifying his barriers he is an able shot with pistol or psychic blast. [+Barrier Lord, +Support Specialist]

Spoiler: 4th Company Epistolary Nero Achillian

Epistolary Nero Achillian ascended to Codicier from a lowly Lexicani during a scrying ritual upon the world of Trontiux II. Yet he and the Epistolary guiding the ritual found themselves nearly slain by psychic backlash from the brutish might of a cabal of greenskin psykers. In fact, his eyes erupted in their sockets. Yet for some reason despite the loss of his physical eyes his ability to pierce the veil of the warp is undiminished and if anything magnified in sophistry and accuracy allowing him to exercise his powers from great distances. Blind he may be, but there is a steady power in him. He now bears bionic replacements for what he has lost. During extensive studies over the anti-daemon effects of multiple Avatar of Khaine corpses, he learned that he possesses a skill in that arena as well. [+Perception, Far Seer, Daemonologist]

Spoiler: 5th Company Epistolary Damion Tyrin

Chosen by Kyras for his extreme hatred of Chaos, more likely than not, for the Ghoul Stars Explorator expedition so that he did not interfere in the traitor's machinations. A master of biomancy, he relishes in burning the foe and blasting out lightning towards the enemy while enhancing and preserving his brethren, skills for which he was valued highly during the expedition. He bears some of the more rare relics of the Librarium, having left before the Purges could occur. [+Willpower, Lord of Lightning]

Spoiler: 10th Company Epistolary Trajan Maphar

Trajan is one of the few Librarians to survive the civil war, the reason being that he was simply distant from much of the chapter beforehand, and that his talents lay not nearly as much in the powers of fire or lightning, nor healing or piercing the veil of reality, but in telepathy. It was this which forewarned him of the intent of the heretic Blood Ravens and saved his life. His abilities are now used to ensure the mental purity of the scouts and other marines, ever watchful for the slightest hint of issue that went missed before the civil war. He is, nevertheless, a Librarian who has reached the level of Epistolary and a Librarian of the Blood Ravens besides. His psychic power is not to be discounted. [+Fellowship, Major Telepath]

Spoiler: 3rd Company Epistolary Idmon

Fighting within tight confines in the tunnels and caverns of the Suysh, Epistolary Idmon showed a true talent for geomancy and general telekinetic combat in excess of his other codicier level abilities. Whether literally throwing tanks or forming shields of stone and lightning, Idmon proved himself a deadly foe to the enemies of Mankind. He is credited with slaying a Suysh Queen by literally bringing the cavern down around it, manipulating hundreds of tons of rock into spikes that obliterated the foul alien and its Royal Guard at the same time. At other time, he formed new tunnels and entrances that allowed his brothers to move flank the enemy easily. Metal and stone bend and twist with ease before him, and he seems to see through them almost as well. As of 075.M42 he was named as the Epistolary of the 3rd Company. [+Geokiller, +Perception]

Spoiler: Codicier Aeneas

Amongst his brother Librarians, Brother Aeneas has proven a duelist without peer. Such was his skill that the Librarius saw fit to release one of their most valuable relics, the blade of Azariah Moriah, thought lost. Furthermore, Brother Aeneas has proven an adept at teleporting through the warp into the bodies of his enemies, enhancing his own strength and speed to incredible levels. If his foes are at range, he can step through the veil to reach them. Even the Chief Librarian has voiced his acknowledgement of Brother Aeneas’ abilities, but at the same time Aeneas has not yet mastered some of the abilities required of an Epistolary. It is rumored that this is deliberate, so that Aeneas may be deployed wherever he can rather than being forced to be stationed in any single Company. [+Champion Duelist, +Teleport Specialist] Entrusted with the Relic known as the Blade of the Martyr.

Fallen Notables

Spoiler: Honor Guard Chaplain Uther

The 7th Company may by the Codex Astartes be a Reserve Company, yet that does not mean that it did not often go into battle such is the state of the galaxy. Leading with fire and faith, Chaplain Uther was struck painfully by the devastating casualties sustained by his Company during the Kaurava campaign, his fury at the slain Boreale for his failures, and at the ork Warlord Gorgutz who was responsible for killing five Companies of the Blood Ravens in one battle. In despair, he joined the Deathwatch to truly exercise his hatred upon the xenos of the galaxy, to cleanse himself in purifying death. Now he has returned, tempered and his soul resolute to aid the Chapter as best he can. [+WS, Tempered Hatred]

KIA by Chaos Lord Mortirex of the Black Legion

Spoiler: Honor Guard Apothecary Falkor Ryll

Falkor has spent over three centuries fighting, killing, and healing. His hands have been drowned in the blood of a dozen and more xenos species, that of traitors and daemons as well, and throughout it all he has remained utterly stoic. His assignment towards the Ghouls Stars now ended, this unflappable and quiet apothecary has moved forward without hesitation to serve the chapter as best he can. [+Toughness, Chirurgeon]

KIA by Chaos Lord Mortirex of the Black Legion

Spoiler: Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris

A elder veteran of the 5th Company, Doukas was selected by Kyras personally to lead his squad from the 5th Company as an escort alongside an Explorator Fleet heading towards the Ghoul Stars. This is due to the fact that Doukas has proven himself to be unshakably loyal to the Imperium and staunchly watchful for heresy, and is was noted more than once in the rolls of the specialist groups that it is a shame that he was not selected as a Chaplain. Quiet and stoic, he shows little pride or fury compared to the vast majority of his brethren. It is likely that Kyras expected Doukas and his brothers to die in the darkness, facing threats undreamed of. Instead, Doukas returned, hard-bitten and worn, but steady as well. He was granted a masterfully crafted power sword by Explorator Valens of Zerann for his service. [+Fellowship, +Weapon Skill, Weathered Guardian, Relentless Killer]

KIA by Chaos Lord Mortirex of the Black Legion

Spoiler: 1st Company Assault Terminator Sergeant Minos

Brother Minos has fought for the Chapter and specifically Chapter Master Angelos for an extensive period of time, always willingly at the forefront either as an assault marine or as an assault terminator. As a part of the 3rd Company, Brother Minos fought the daemon Sindri Myr in person, withstood the ranged techno-sorcery of the Tau while facing a pack of krootox alone to allow his brothers to redeploy at the rear of the enemy formation, and survived the deadly battle of Aurelia that killed so many others. His close combat skills and flat refusal to fall no matter the injury until the battle is done has won many victories for the chapter. [+Elder Veteran, +Duels Like A Mountain]

KIA by Chaos Lord Mortirex of the Black Legion

Spoiler: 4th Company Tomb-Librarian Konan Barbariel

Brother Konan was well known for being a calm, collected, and remarkably powerful psyker, even by the Chapter's standards. Indeed, were it not for the fact that he felt personally responsible for every Blood Raven loss during the 1st and 2nd Aurelian Crusades, it is likely that he may well have been elected Chief Librarian of the Chapter over Justinius Probalis. As it is, however, he did, and having fought to protect initiates, some of which died, proved the final straw, and as such the Epistolary volunteered to join the Penitent Crusade of Aramus. Grievously wounded, interred in a dreadnought, his second and final death would come after a great many deeds of remarkable heroism and strength, aiding not only his battle brothers, but the loyal servants of the Imperium as well. His sacrifice is now well-remembered, and already the Adeptas Sororitas who fought to defend the planet Xersia hail the fallen brother as a holy martyr in proving pivotal in the defeat of the Great Unclean One Pestilax the Despairer.

KIA By Psychic Pyrocataclysmic Suicide In Banishing Greater Daemon of Nurgle On Cardinal World of Xersia In 13th Black Crusade

Turn 1 Results - 2470

First things first; the next morning, you seek out Wilhelmina and ask about finances. With the help of a couple of Greatswords stripped of their armour she's moving crates and chests from the back of a wagon into the depths of the castle, and when you interrupt her and tell her what you're after, the long, piercing look she gives you makes you quite uncomfortable. But then she goes back to the wagon, rummages around, and then throws a bag with the unmistakable clink of coin to you, slightly harder than necessary but not so much that you have trouble catching it.

"That should tide you over until we can get payroll sorted out," she says. "Talk to me later, and we'll draw up a budget."

Over the next few months, you spend a fair bit of time with the woman, but she never quite defrosts with you. It doesn't appear to be a matter of bias against wizards, she doesn't have that blend of hatred and fear; it just seems she's pigeonholed you in her mind, and not in a good place. However, she doesn't let her personal feelings get in the way of her responsibilities, and you manage to convince her that you do have a legitimate need for funds for discretionary spending.

While you are having these discussions, you remember your decision to check with her about the budget of your predecessor, and when asked about it she hesitates and confesses that she's yet to find the records. That shocks you; you know for a fact that the records for an entire province would take up at least an entire room, having seen the Grey College's own archives. She seems surprised at this, apparently having been looking for a single ledger or similar.

You volunteer to help her out and she agrees, and the two of you spend a great deal of time scouring the castle, finding empty room after empty room but no record of the archives, and over time her attitude towards you thaws. As you get to know her, she tells you that she's known the new Elector Count since he was barely more than a boy, and has been the paymaster for hiring, equipping, housing and feeding soldiers and mercenaries for his campaigns against the undead for fifteen years. As such, when he was granted the current position, she was his choice for his Steward.

Having repaired the relationship you inadvertently damaged with the woman so close to your new liege, you would consider all the effort you spent poking around well-spent. Then one day, on a hunch, you were poking around the rooms nearest to the treasury (attracting a number of suspicious stares from the Greatswords guarding it) when you notice, under the ever-present scent of stale air and dampness, the familiar scent of papyrus - very faint, but not quite faded.

Looking closer at the empty room, you find slight impressions in the stone where heavy shelves stood for what may have been centuries, and the scratch-marks from when they were finally dragged away. And finally, in an overlooked crevice, you pull fistful after fistful of crumpled paper where a mouse once made a nest. Numbers and names are barely visible, but they're definitely records of taxes flowing in, and the date attached to it is centuries old. Stirland's archives were definitely here, and when you inform Wilhelmina of your discovery, the two of you agree that there's no innocent explanation for why they were here no longer. She thanks you for your help, sincerely and warmly.

Rolls:
[ASKING FOR PERSONAL PAY: Req 40, Diplomacy, 32+9=41. Slight relation hit with Wilhelmina, +50 personal gold/turn.]
[ASKING FOR OPERATIONAL BUDGET: Req 40, Stewardship, 25+10=35. Wilhelmina requires convincing.]
[BUDGET NEGOTIATIONS: Req 50, Stewardship, 52+10=62. Wilhelmina agrees with your requirements, +200 discretionary gold this turn only. Further gold will require further negotiations.]
[TRACKING DOWN THE PAYROLL: Req 60, Intrigue, 92+12=104. There was none to be found, but you uncovered evidence that it was deliberately taken, endearing yourself to Wilhelmina and to Van Hal.]

---

With the payroll for your predecessor out of reach, you set your sights on the more mundane staff. You ask your newfound friend, who is refilling the castle with maids and servants when not occupied with panicking about the disappearance of Stirland's entire tax code, that you want to speak to anyone who previously worked at the castle. Next thing you know, the town crier's announcement that the castle was hiring was also saying that previous experience would be highly regarded. And a trickle of previous workers enters your office over the months as the castle's staff increases.

The first, at catching sight of someone in the robes and hat of a wizard, ran right out screaming. Okay, then.

Thankfully, the second is made of sterner stuff, though the former scullery maid doesn't know much. All she knows is that the former spymaster was wealthy, though not a noble. You have a word with Wilhelmina, and the kitchen staff is increased by one.

After that, it goes easier, as Wilhelmina explains during interviews it's just a part of the vetting process and assures them that the scary mage will just ask a few harmless questions and if they go along with it everything will be okay. The rest of them go smoothly, and you collect enough scraps of information to start putting a picture together. An image forms of a trader with a stranglehold on the road from Talabecland to Averland, using his position to push out competitors and being allowed to do so because it increased his ability to accumulate information. Wurtbad, Tarshof, Potting, Worden, Vigaun, every town and village along the Old Dwarf Road was dominated by his influence.

But as you piece it all together, you notice a discordant note in the symphony. Everyone you spoke to gave you overlapping information so nobody was just making it up, but there are contradictions that throw off your attempts to get a glimpse of what's going on. And the contradictions are too perfectly misleading, and they all come from the same source.

A word in the ear of the nearest Greatsword later, and the stablehand that fed you misinformation is tossed into a cell in Eagle Castle's dungeons.

[WERE PREVIOUS WORKERS TEMPTED?: Req 50, Wilhelmina's Stewardship, 51+15=66. Several were found.]
[FIRST WORKER: Req 30, Diplomacy, 5+9=14. Oh dear.]
[SECOND WORKER: Req 40, Diplomacy, 47+9=56. She's happy to answer a few questions if you can help her get her job back.]
[HOW MUCH DOES SHE KNOW?: Roll, 25. Not much.]
[THIRD WORKER: Req 30, Diplomacy, 80+9=89. Word gets out that you're not going to turn people into toads.]
[HOW MUCH DO THE REST OF THEM KNOW?: Rolls, 64, 44, 6, 34.]
[DO YOU BELIEVE THAT THIRD GUY: Req 60, Intrigue, 99+12=111. No. No you do not.]

---

Third priority: the search. Apart from your predecessor's notes, there's now also the archives to find. That would take a really big secret room, but a number of badly-printed books that circulated among the apprentices of the Colleges of Magic lead you to believe that castles like this are utterly riddled with secret rooms, passages, and devices, as well as describing in detail various torrid activities that may go on in them.

After thinking back on what tended to happen to plucky young female protagonists that went searching for secret passages in dark castles, you decide to wait for a day when Ulgu was strong, just in case. And to bring a few extra knives. Finally, on a day when the mists rolling through the streets were matched by the storm flashing overhead and grey magic was so thick in the air you could taste it, you went roaming through the castle, twisting every wall sconce and pushing every protruding brick.

Things get to a poor start when an overly enthusiastic twist leads to a wall sconce breaking off in your hand, scattering burning candle wax over the flagstones. You blow out the candle and place it gently on the floor, hoping whoever finds it thinks it fell on its own. Your prodding of suspicious-looking bricks doesn't break anything, but it doesn't get results either.

After several more days of fruitless searching, you're almost convinced that this castle is free of secrets when you notice that the doors for the servants' quarters you're currently haunting are placed in regular intervals, except for in one spot, where the place a door should be is occupied by an incongruous wall hanging. You triumphantly tear it down and find a door boarded up with rusty nails, and without even a moment's hesitation you begin levering out the nails with your knife and pulling the wooden planks free. You've finally found a secret of Eagle Castle!

And just as the last plank is pulled free, a secret of Eagle Castle finds you.

The door bursts open and a hideously gaunt figure staggers towards you, folds of skin dangling from an emaciated form and cracked teeth revealed by a rattling moan. Shock holds you in place for only half a second before you're backpedalling out of the grasp of the creature. You swipe wildly with the knife, cutting nothing but air, but your other reflex is more successful - the candles on the wall flicker and the shadows lengthen, and then they throw themselves forward and wrap around your frame. In the familiar embrace of Ulgu, you are safe.

So you stand your ground, allowing the creature to approach, and as cracked nails scrabble for purchase against the shadows covering you, you stab it in the face.

Well, then. That never happened in the books you read.

The room beyond seems no different to any other servant's rooms, except for the bloody scratchmarks on every wall. You fetch a couple of Greatswords and get them to haul the hopefully dead creature into the cell next to the former stablehand.

[WALL SCONCES: Req ??, Intrigue, 28+12=40. It was like that when I got here.]
[PROTRUDING BRICKS: Req ??, Intrigue, 62+12=74. Could adventure novels have lied to me?]
[ANYTHING ELSE?: Req ??, ??, 3+??= oh dear.]
[APPROPRIATE LEVEL OF CAUTION: Higher is better, Intrigue, 3+12=15. No caution shown. Seriously, you should stop reading adventure novels.]
[ROLL TO NOT GET EATEN: Req 40, Martial, 58+7=65. You succeed at not getting eaten.]
[ROLL TO MAKE HIM EAT STEEL: Req 40, Martial, 15+7=22. Nothing's getting eaten.]
[ROLL FOR MAGICAL REFLEXES: Req 60, Roll, 80. Aetheryical armour activate.]
[NOW IT'S JUST UNFAIR: Req 30, Martial, 64+7=71. Combat concluded.]

---

Better clean the... whatever that was... off you, because it's time for the ceremony. Thankfully your normal grey robes count as formal dress, because otherwise you wouldn't have a thing to wear.

The castle buzzes with activities as guests arrive and are shown to newly-cleaned rooms, the now-familiar smell of damp overlaid with woodsmoke and perfume. The nobility of Stirland are apparently quite keen to have a look at their new Lord. According to what you know of Stirland's political borders, there should only be less than twenty guests. You count them off on your fingers and toes - three Barons, six Counts (only human Counts count), two Countesses, one Grand Mayor, one Lord Mayor, one regular Mayor but he's the Mayor of Wurtbad so he gets an invite, two High Priests, and one Knight Commander. So why there's at least a hundred overdressed nobles filling the great hall and spilling into the courtyard, you have no idea. Still, you have a job to do, so you dive into the fray.

You're quickly lost in a sea of faces you don't recognize, but you soon spot Anton talking animatedly to someone that looks like him plus thirty years, so you head over and are introduced to Baron Anton Kiesinger I. You're introduced as 'a friend from work', which you're pretty sure isn't one of your official titles, but okay. Anton Senior quickly takes to you, and is perfectly willing to tell you what he knows, which is little.

"Old Whatshisface, he was all about the north-south road. To get to the west he wouldn't just have to get through me, he'd have to get through the shitfight of a situation with the Countess of Flensburg and the Grand Mayor of Flensburg, so he never bothered. Everything west of Sonningwiese could have been annexed by the Moot and he wouldn't have cared."

You listen politely to a series of further comments about the Flensburg Problem, taking mental notes in case it becomes your problem in the future, then Anton Senior spots a young woman he's apparently quite keen on getting Anton Junior married to and they hurry off. Having been seen talking to Someone Important, however, you're barely given a chance to look around before you're swept up into a conversational circle of various courtiers and hangers on, eager to bask in your reflected importance. You wait for a lull in the conversation and ask if anyone knows anyone who would know of your predecessor, and eager to look important, one of them introduces you to their liege, who turns out to be the Count of Schramleben. In this manner you bounce from noble to noble, collecting fragments of information and at one point being cornered by a drunken noble blabbering about his collection of Elven art (of elves, rather than by elves, you gather), until you finally strike a goldmine.

Count Artur von Treitschke of Franzen has a great deal to say about the man he identifies as Wilhelm von Tarshof, after you finally get him to understand the question and bring him another cup of wine. "Franzen, you see, is located on the branch between the River Aver and the River Lammer," he says, full of self-importance and slightly slurring, "and Baron Helmuth of Purgg and I worked together to facilitate north-south trade in competition with the so-called 'Stirlandian League' of von Tarshof. Oh, he never acknowledged any connection with them, but he's not the only one that can pay people to follow other people. So we worked around him. Goods would go up the River Lammer to Ohlsdorf, along the road to Purgg, then down the River Teichd and just like that, they're in Talabecland. A little excise for me, a little excise for him, and none for von Tarshof, who was taking a slice out of trade at every town and village along the Old Dwarf Road, unless you were in his League." The Count takes a drink of his wine. "Then Helmuth had an accident, or so it was said. He fell down some stairs, which may or may not have been related to the fourteen stab wounds in his back. Possibly contagious, since all three of his heirs caught the same thing. And just like that the Barony reverts to the Elector Count." He pauses to collect his thoughts, then peers at you suspiciously. "Who are you, anyway? One of Krebs' daughters?"

You make your excuses and melt back into the crowd, your mind buzzing.

You were too busy networking to pay much attention, but everyone agreed afterwards it had been a lovely ceremony, and that Anton had outdone himself.

[HOW MANY VIPs DO YOU FIND: Roll, 57. Five VIPs.]
[FIRST GUEST: Roll, 30.]
[SECOND GUEST: Roll, 97.]
[THIRD GUEST: Roll, 56.]
[FOURTH GUEST: Roll, 4.]
[IGNORANCE OR HOSTILITY: 72+9=81. They're just harmlessly drunk.]
[FIFTH GUEST: Roll, 69.]

---

Throughout the month, you penned several letters and sent them back to Altdorf, trying to get a read on the political situation that led to your current occupation. Your first is to your Master, a straightforward letter of mindbogglingly dull and stilted descriptions of entirely normal days that, when decrypted, is a pointed request for information; if not about matters of which he cannot speak, then in general. The second set of letters is to some former classmates of yours; you try to keep the gloating that they're still Apprentices and you're a Spymaster for an entire province out of the letter, but the complete lack of response suggests you may have failed. The third is not to any specific person, but to the Grey College as a whole; you send in a formal request for information as a member of the Grey College serving the Empire, and wait for it to be processed and responded to.

When your Master writes back, you're in awe at the masterpiece of encryption before you. A handful of entirely natural-sounding paragraphs telling you of goings-on in the College and asking after your health and how your new position is going, as well as gently reminding you to continue your studies. For a while you think he's just sent you a normal response to chide you for trying to guilt him, but then you finally work out the key and the paragraphs decrypt into information more precious than gold.

Wilhelmina Hochschild is the only Councillor that Van Hal actually chose. Everyone else was thrust upon him, as you were. Brother Kasmir Heinz was hand-picked by the Grand Theogonist for loyalty to the Cult of Sigmar over any secular authority. Detlef Schultz was the concession that bought Talabecland's vote for Van Hal, though his qualifications are solid. And Professor Lucrezio de Verezzo was a head scholar of military history from the University of Altdorf, until proof of embezzlement on a massive scale from the University was found. He had been failing half his students, retroactively removing them from the University's ledgers, then pocketing the money that had been paid to the University for their education. But the entire issue was hushed up, and he had been placed firmly under the thumb of the Emperor's spymaster and sent to Stirland.

The information from the College itself is nowhere near as earthshattering. It is simply an accounting of Van Hal's career, culminating in the extermination of a small army of Strigoi vampires under Talabheim. Interestingly, the minutiae of his career reveals that he's hired wizards on dozens of occasions to assist with his endless war against the Undead, and that he's never really lived up to the name of 'Witch Hunter' - though he definitely showed no hesitation to put the torch to the necromancers he encountered. The letter also reveals that Van Hal was the first choice of the three Cult of Sigmar votes, the Emperor, Wissenland, the Moot, and Averland, and the vote was finished when Talabecland was won over.

[LETTER TO MASTER: Req 40, Learning, 95+13: Guilt Trip Deployed.]
[LETTER TO CLASSMATES: Req 50, Diplomacy 15+9: Well, what could they possibly know, anyway? They're still Apprentices.]
[LETTER TO THE COLLEGE: Req 60 Intrigue 60+12: The wheels turn, and spit out information.]

Finally, one evening you return to your room to find a letter lodged into the doorjamb. You open it, hoping for more correspondence from Altdorf, and instead find a page of gibberish. Oddly familiar gibberish. Then you sigh, close your eyes, and consult the cipher table that still glows on the inside of your eyelids whenever you think about it.

Prepare a report on the abilities and relationships of Stirland's diplomat. Encode it using the cipher you have been given. A rider will arrive at the castle in three months time; give them the report.

---

At the end of six months, the Council is called to report in on their process. Van Hal is still dressed in his Witch Hunter's gear, though the Runefang on his hip emits all the authority he needs.

Professor de Verezzo is first, explaining in a lecturer's drone how the military of Stirland is vastly under-strength, and many of its soldiers exist only on paper and the salary that they are supposedly drawing was being channeled... somewhere. He has sketched out a number of plans for recruiting to bring Stirland's actual strength back up to its theoretical one, each expensive and time-consuming.

MILITARY OF STIRLAND: Poor. Only 25,000 men of the 40,000 on the books actually exist.

Anton is next, and basks in a rare word of praise from Van Hal. As you know, the ceremonies went off without a hitch, and Van Hal managed to negotiate the social maze of the upper classes without any significant troubles. The general impression of him is that he's going to be occupied entirely with Sylvania and will keep his nose out of whatever mischief the nobility decides to distract themselves with.

NOBLE RELATIONS: Good. The nobility think Van Hal is going to leave them be.

Wilhelmina's examination into the tax rolls hit a massive snag right at the start, in that none could be found. The centuries of accumulated ledgers, contracts and documents that tracked who owed what were completely absent, and she credits you with discovering that they had been taken away deliberately. Wilhelmina had, however, put on a surprisingly lovely gown and mingled with the nobility present at the ceremony, and convinced most of them to send their own copies of the taxation ledgers, making them think she was investigating the possibility of the former Elector Count skimming taxes owed to the Empire rather than a desperate attempt to rebuild Stirland's tax code. She also reports that the treasury is full enough to keep the state running, but the next few years are going to be lean.

WEALTH OF STIRLAND: Poor.
INCOME OF STIRLAND: Poor; will fall to Terrible if the nobles realize that they could just not pay taxes and get away with it.

Brother Kasmir reports on his efforts to liaise with the religious authorities in Stirland, almost entirely Sigmarites and Morrites. The Sigmarites report no major problems, but they seem to have developed a habit of ignoring the temporal power of Stirland's Elector Count due to unnamed issues with the previous holders of the office. It is only the fact that Van Hal has such a strong record of service to Sigmar that makes them willing to give him a chance.

The Morrites, it seems, have entered a renaissance, with record numbers of initiates to the priesthood and regular services being held in major towns. In Stirland, Morr is no longer invoked only in funerals; he is seen as a constant guardian against the assaults of the Undead. However, they, too, are standoffish towards the Elector Count, though they are willing to be won over, especially if he fulfils his stated goals of protecting against the Sylvanian taint.

SIGMARITE INFLUENCE: Good
SIGMARITE RELATIONS: Average

MORRITE INFLUENCE: Great
MORRITE RELATIONS: Average

Herr Schultz reports the castle's condition is fixable, but it will take some time to do so; it seems few townsmen are willing to work in the castle, and workers had to be brought in from surrounding villages, where news of whatever has spooked the locals had not spread. He also reports that the Greatswords have made themselves at home in the castle's barracks, but they represent the only defences of the castle - the cannon are long gone and the armoury has been emptied. On the bright side, none of these problems make the castle any less defensible - the outer walls are still solid and the gate mechanisms are working perfectly.

He brings up the sealed east wing, and is immediately told to disregard it. Hmm.

EAGLE CASTLE CONDITION: Poor; repairs ongoing.

Finally, it is your turn to report.

You can write in a report here, allowing you to either make yourself look good, underplay the importance of something that went wrong, curry favour with someone else present, or to massage the facts to fit an agenda of yours. Otherwise, you will be judged on results alone. How horrible. Please try to keep it punchy - your Elector Count is a man of action.

[] Write In

Suggest courses of action for the next six months; the Elector Count is likely to choose one of them. You can use this to your advantage. One possibility is to suggest things that align with your personal goals, another is to suggest things you can do easily and have plenty of time left over to spend elsewhere. However, if there's a pressing concern the Elector Count has that is not covered by what you put forward, he may 'write in' your orders, and cause a relationship hit due to losing respect for your abilities. Votes for this will be in plan format - the more options you give the Elector Count, the greater chance he'll pick one, but the less you can steer his instructions.

[] The Stirlandian League is a cancer eating at Stirland's economy, and it must be destroyed.
[] The Stirlandian League is a gold mine of information, and it must be yours.
[] The disappearance of your predecessor is very concerning, he must be found.
[] There is a risk of enemy agents infiltrating the castle staff - they must be watched.
[] The castle staff can be a great source of information and first line of defence - they should report to you.
[] There was an incident with a... something. You killed it, but there may be more. The castle should be searched from top to bottom.
[] A dozen centuries of tax ledgers and records don't just vanish. They need to be found.
[] Seriously what is up with the East Wing.
[] If I had proper facilities, I could do better work. Please fund me moving out of my terrible, musty guest room.
[] I need a proper information network. Please fund me wandering around making friends.
[] Other (write in)

On Detachment/Assignment/Exile

On Penitent Crusade:
NOTE: YOU CANNOT SEND AID IN ANY FORM WHATSOEVER TO THE PENITENT CRUSADE. NONE. NO SHIPS. NO MARINES. NO FUEL. NO KIND WORDS. THE CRUSADE ENDS AND THEY COME HOME, OR IT ENDS AND THEY ARE DEAD. THESE ARE THE ONLY TWO OPTIONS.

Spoiler: Penitent Crusade of Aramus

Strike Cruiser [Vanguard Refit] - Retribution

[20/28] Hangar Compliment: x10 Thunderhawk Gunships, x10 Thunderhawk Transporters
Blood Raven Gene-Seed On Vessel: 0 [43 Currently Being Transported By Others]
On-Board Forge Systems: 60BP/Turn [15/Turn Relegated To Personal Use of Senior Techmarine Sarrelen] [Remainder used for maintenance/upkeep of war material]
Modifications to various ship systems have been observed that go beyond base design specifications:

Retribution has displayed increased engine output of estimated 10% to 12% higher than base Zerann 52X1 design specifications.
Retribution has displayed weapon array damage output of estimated 10% to 15% higher than base Zerann 52X1 design specifications.
Retribution seems to have converted multiple hangar sections into billets for non-astartes personnel, fully blocking them off with hull plating modifications.
Retribution is confirmed to have obtained or otherwise gained additional armor plating and advanced void shield systems, likely as a result of close-relations to the Forge Worlds of Mordax Prime and Kentrael. This may also be related to years of accompaniment by of Salamander marines.
Retribution appears to have granted use of internal ship berths meant for Chapter/Company and crew over to non-astartes personnel for safer berthing, returning Hangar Bay to full potential capabilities, while gaining new Thunderhawks from Forge World Mordax Prime with Sororitas Pilots to operate them. Forge World Kentrael has publicly volunteered many Enginseers to supplement the crew of the ship, assisting in maintenance and repair efforts for the strike cruiser.

Mission: Penitent Crusade Within/Around The Eye Of Terror Until Death or 100 Years Have Passed. Crusade Began In 988.M41 Completion in 088.M42

Notation Primaris: May possess Relics of the Chapter beyond what is currently recorded, having been made to depart on Penitent Crusade by order of then-Captain Angelos before the Purge of the Chapter occurred.

Spoiler: Known Notable Battles/Deeds Of Penitents In General Chronological Order

Cadia, Cadian Sector
- Battle Of The Bloody Hill
- Defense Of Kasr Durend
Fortress World Vigilatum, Cadian Sector
- Vigilatum Rear Guard Rescue
Fortress World Kasr Sonnen, Cadian Sector
- Ambush And Destruction of Angels of Extermination
Forge World Mordax Prime, Scarus Sector
- Slaying Of Green Kroosade Leading Warlord
- Liberation Of Mordax Prime
Civilized World Malin's Reach, Agripinaa Sector
- Iron Warriors Armor Column Assault
Hive World Tabor, Agripinaa Sector
- Salamander Detachment Rescue
Scarus Sector
- Green Kroosade Mop Up Operations
- Chaos Cult Extermination In Eustis Majoris (Hive World) Underhive
- Night Lord Terror Squad Hunt On Rigyion (Civilized World)
- Fallen Warhound Titan Group Recovery On Malinte (Armory World)
- Space Marine Rescue And Recovery Operations
Civilized World Amistel Majoris, Agripinaa Sector
- Battle Of Ironwrought
- Defense Of Strike Cruiser Retribution While In Orbit From Ambush
- Blood Valley Supply Convoy Escort
- Assault Of Traitor Guard-held Fortress Antioch Tertius
- Defense Of Antioch Tertius
- Defense Of Listening Post Vermillion-688
- Defense Of Antioch Secundus
- Siege/Reclamation Of Rubico Starport
Thracian Primaris System, Scarus Sector
- Mordax Prime Orbital Defense Against Black Legion Cruisers Bloodshrike, Cackling Hate And Azrubael
- Hive World Gudrun Orbital Defense Against Greenskin Raiders
- Hive Word Gudrun Planetary Surface Defense Against Chaos Cult Uprising
- Hive World Gudrun Killing of Chaos Sorcerer Hyrdax
- Greenskin Purge on Mordax Prime
Scelus Subsector
- Defense Against Sons of Malice Crusade
Planet Cadia, Cadian System, Cadian Sector
- 2nd Defense Of Kasr Durend
- Extermination of Chaos Warband 'The Dread Shadow' And Its Leader: Chaos Sorcerer Abilsin of the Black Legion
- 3rd Defense of Kasr Durend
- Boarding And Destruction of Iron Warriors Battleship Ashen Vindication
- 4th Defense of Kasr Durend, Slaying of Chaos Lord Tyrik Slaughterfist
Planet Korolis, Cadian System
- Planetary Defense of High Value Structures (Atomic Material Production, Promethium Extraction/Refinement, Imperial Guard Outposts, Etc.) Alongside the Angels of Vigilance 1st Company
Cadian Sector
- Hunt for Endross, Destruction of the Exquisite Blade Kabal of Dark Eldar
Agrippina Sector
- Notable Participant in Reclamation of Agrippina Sector, Multiple Acts of Valor/Heroism
Cadian Sector
- Defense of Cardinal World Xersia, Contesting Death Guard Forces, Banishment of Great Unclean One Pestilax the Despairer
- Defense of Forge World Kentrael, Destruction of Traitor Iron Skulls Titan Legion and other Dark Mechanicus forces.
- Cleansing of Mining World Clauseten
- 7th Defense of Kasr Durend, Total Destruction of Gorehands Warband, Slaying of Chaos Lord Gracchus Gorehand
- Defending Against Ambush of Strike Cruiser Retribution while traveling through Cadian System by Contortionists of the Needle Warband of Chaos Space Marines, Counter-Boarding enemy strike cruiser and destroying Warband.
- Notable Participant In Reclamation of Fortress World Kasr Sonnen, Most Notable Deeds Include Destruction of Chaos Battleship Magnificence of Apostasy and defeat of summoned Bloodthirster Hazkanar
Planet Cadia
- Defense of Kasr Trunch/Defense of Kasr Rantik/Defense of Kasr Soliq, Defeat of Daemon Prince Veritak
Cadian Sector
- Defense of Cardinal World Sabena
- Major Participants In Ordo Malleus Operation - Silencing The Lord Ravager. Death of Abbadon's Chosen credited to Blood Raven killing blows.
Belis Corona Sector
- Dual Daemonic Defeat at Subiaco Diablo - Brought low the Daemon Primarch Angron and banished him alongside the Sisters of Silence and numerous other Imperial forces. Pict-recordings have shown the beginning, middle, and end of the Force Commander's act of superb defiance.

Spoiler: Librarius Notations Of Imperial Observations

- For Record Purposes, as of 004.M42 the personage list is edited to reflect the events of the Bloody Hill. Further edits may come later, or not.
- 009.M42: Observations and notes by Imperial forces in the Cadian theater of war have allowed for a more updated set of records on the Penitent Crusade.
- 025.M42: Strike Cruiser Retribution was sighted deploying within the worst crisis areas within the Agripinaa, Cadian, and Belis Corona Sectors. Here, survivors of a Salamanders Company are recovered.
- 040.M42: Strike Cruiser Retribution was sighted, heavily damaged, over the world of Amistel Majoris with forces deployed on-world.
- 050.M42: Strike Cruiser Retribution was sighted over the world of Mordax Prime in the Scarus Sector, undergoing repairs for nearly crippling amounts of damage. Aligned forces were sighted travelling on transports across the Thracian Primaris System while the ship remained in dock for repairs.
- 060.M42: Strike Cruiser Retribution has once more resumed strike force operations in the Scelus Subsector in defense against the Sons of Malice.
- 062.M42: The Blood Ravens and Salamanders succeed in a crucial decapitating strike which slew Anarch Kathal, leader of the Sons of Malice.
- 063.M42: Sons of Malice totally eradicated by Blood Ravens and Salamanders after most Imperial Forces dedicated to more crucial battlefields. Space marines of Raptors recalled by Chapter Master. Current location or deployment unknown to Inquisition. Storm Troopers on-board are requisitioned by the Ordo Malleus for [CLASSIFIED]
- 064.M42: New Salamanders and Sisters of Battle sighted within Retribution strike forces as they deploy across the Cadian Sector, the latter are suspected to be survivors of destroyed Sororitas battle groups.
- 065.M42: Retribution Strike Force repeatedly deploys over Fortress World Cadia. Killing of Black Legion Sorcerer Abilsin and destruction of Warband 'The Dread Shadow'. Killing of World Eater Chaos Lord Tyrik Slaughterfist. Departed Cadia.
- 065.M42-070.M42: Fighting alongside 1st Company of Angels of Vigilance Chapter defending vital atomic material production, promethium extraction and refining, and transport hub facilities from Black Legion and Alpha Legion forces on the planet of Korolis within the Cadian System.
- 070.M42-073.M42: Joined Angels of Vigilance Chapter in hunt for Exquisite Blade Dark Eldar Kabal for revenge after depopulation of Pervigilium, Angels of Vigilance Homeworld. Hunted Kabal across Cadian Sector. Joined Reclamation of Agrippina Sector as Kabal had fled there. Hunted Kabal down, aided in reclamation of 'Artifact of Vulkan' cognomen 'Song of Entropy' [SEE ATTACHED FILES] Reportedly made close contact with Adeptus Custodes and Salamander Chapter Leadership.
- 074.M42: Joined the defense of Cardinal World Xersia alongside massive detachment of the Adeptas Sororitas against first Black Legion, then Death Guard forces supplemented heavily by cultist armies and daemons. Most notable act came from the sacrifice of Librarian Konan Barbariel in banishing Greater Daemon of Nurgle, Pestilax the Despairer, see [REDACTED] and [ATTACHED FILES]. Librarian now being hailed as holy martyr by three Ordos Majoris of the Sisters of Battle, possibly named as new Saint of Xersia for deed.
- 074.M42: Fought in the defense of Forge World Kentrael as it was under assault by Dark Mechanicus forces and armies of corrupted mechanical abominations and twisted skitarii. Notably contributed by destroying the Traitor Titan Legion of the Iron Skulls and their ships. New Sororitas Auxiliaries Noted Present, Palatine Katicia has been promoted to Canoness Commander. Forge World Mordax has allocated more Myrmidon Tech-Priests to the Retribution's auxiliaries.
- 074.M42: Participated in the Cleansing of Mining World Clauseten, eradicating the teeming mutated hordes left behind by Fabius Bile's abominable work. Planet reclaimed, mines reactivated in service to the Imperium for its war efforts.
- 074.M42: Participated in what is officially designated as 7th Defense of Kasr Durend of Planet Cadia for 13th Black Crusade. Massive Chaos assault, spearheaded by all eight companies of the Gorehands Warband of Chaos Space Marines [formerly Brazen Spears Chapter]. Weeks of heavy fighting resulted in severe casualties amongst Imperial forces, but zero fatalities were suffered by Penitent Crusade forces or their auxiliaries despite becoming visibly lynchpin of defense efforts. Chaos Lord Gracchus Gorehand [formerly Chapter Master Gracchus Imperis] personally slain by Force Commander Aramus in duel.
-074.M42: Chaos ritual disrupts warp travel and Retribution systems. Slaanesh-oriented Chaos Space Marine Warband 'Contortionists of the Needle' ambush and board strike cruiser. Crew fights back, counter-boards enemy Strike Cruiser, destroy it. Champion of Chaos Namus slain in single combat by Canoness Katicia. Retribution later seen over Forge World Kentrael receiving repairs and volunteer tech-priest supplementary crew for ship.
-075.M42: Participated in Reclamation of Kasr Sonnen, Fortress-World controlled by forces of Chaos for past five years after defenders faltered. Multiple targets struck, retaken, destroyed, etc. Multiple notables destroyed - Pariahs of Gold Slaaneshi Cult/ The Corroded Nurglite Chaos Space Marine Warband/Immortal Faithful Chaos Space Marine Warband/Chaos Battleship Magnificence of Apostasy/Khornate Daemonic Horde/Slaaneshi Daemonic Horde/Nurglite Daemonic Horde/Tzeentchian Daemonic Horde/Bloodthirster 'Hazkanar'/Blighted Ones Nurglite Chaos Space Marine Warband.
-075.M42: Fighting in the 075.M42 defense efforts against the 'The Malevolent Advance' of the Despoiler's Forces on Planet Cadia across hundreds of miles of defensive lines. Sighted fighting the forces of Chaos at Kasr Trunch, then Kasr Rantik, then Kasr Soliq. Credited for destruction of Fangs of Apocalypse Chaos Space Marine Warband/Destruction of Twilight Bringers Chaos Space Marine Warband/Rescue of Palantine Maria of the Order of the Bloody Rose from Ambush/Destruction of Discordant Chorus Slaaneshi Warband/Destruction of Makers of Ash Chaos Warband/Death of Chaos Champion Martos of the Black Legion/Rescue of Palantine Patricia of the Ebon Chalice when Trench 17421BC-Tertius Collapsed/Cleansing of Daemonic Legion of Khorne Summoned By Chaos Sorcerers At Kasr Soliq/Rescue of Inquisitor Mordecai Toth of the Ordo Malleus [REDACTED]/Defeat of Daemon Prince Veritak at Secondary Defensive Line of Kasr Soliq
-075.M42: Participated in Defense of Cardinal World Sabena [World significantly rebuilt despite being raided and razed in early days of 13th Black Crusade]. Defended multiple major shrines and cathedrals from Chaos forces alongside Sororitas troops and minor Imperial Guard complements. Defeated Major Daemonic Incursions from all Four Dark Gods. Destroyed Word Bearers Warband 'Heralds of Revelation' and slew Warband Leader: Dark Apostle Claudius. Significant amount of Sororitas auxilaries noted to be traveling with Retribution, representing multiple Ordos, along with increased Thunderhawk support in numbers and crews.
-075.M42: Participated in Ordo Malleus Operation - Fleet Ambush and Boarding Aagainst of Black Legion Chaos Lord Urkanthos, Commander of the Hounds of Abbadon Warband, Lord Ravager of the Chosen of Abbadon, Admiral of the Black Fleet of the Despoiler and the Black Legion. Five near-simultaneous killing strikes on Urkanthos attributed to Blood Ravens, amidst suspected beginnings of daemonic ascension. Concentrated salvo with two multi-meltas and two lascannons from Techmarine Sarrelen, headshot with custom explosive round by Scout Sergeant Nereus, headshot with krak missile by Apothecary Kogal, blow to chest by Force Commander Aramus with thunder hammer, vertical bisection by Sergeant Thaddeus with dual chainswords. Hundreds of Hounds of Abbadon Chaos Space Marines were slain and two dozen Black Fleet vessels destroyed by Ordo Malleus requisitioned assets including strike cruiser Retribution. Kataphron Allotment of Mordax Prime lost utterly in course of battle.
-076.M42: Participated in an operation in Subiaco Diablo orchestrated by the Warmaster Saint, designed to re-open the Belis Corona shipyards to the greater Imperium by striking a heavy blow against Warp disruption in the area and the Hive Mind by assaulting Subiaco Diablo. A major task force made up of Astartes, Sororitas, and Guardsman Regiments accompanied by the mysterious Sisters of Silence, assaults Subiaco Diablo. The Daemon Prince Bel'akor is defeated by the Daemon Primarch Angron, who is in turn defeated by the efforts of the Penitents, their allies, and the Sisters of Silence.

Squad Penance-Primaris: [5/5]
- Force Commander Aramus Valorun [Bearing Relics: Eternal Blessed Cage, Bloody Banner of Aramus, Numerous Penitent Seals**] [Bearing Armory Items: Storm Shield and Thunder Hammer] [Left Arm Replaced With Masterwork Bionics] [OVERALL PHYSICAL CONDITION UNKNOWN] (4th Company)
- Apothecary Adrian Kogal [Bearing Relics: Laurels of the Crusader, Pistol of Terra, Final Absolution of Caliban, The Pitiless Lance of Vengeance] Possesses Sophisticated Bionics For Left Leg, Left Arm, Right Leg] (4th Company)
- Veteran Scout Sergeant Nereus (Vow of Silence) [Bearing Relics: Honored Silence, Angel of Silence, x2 Plasma Pistols] [Possesses Sophisticated Bionics For Throat, Lower Jaw] (10th Company)
- Veteran Assault Marine Sergeant Thaddeus Rex [Possesses Powerful Bionic Strength Enhancements] [Bearing Relics: Growling Hate/Xenosplitter, Coronet of Honor] (4th Company) [OVERALL PHYSICAL CONDITION UNKNOWN]
- Senior Techmarine Sarrelen [Possesses Artificer Masterwork Bionics For Both Eyes, Both Arms] [Bearing Either Servo-Harness or Customized War Panoply**] (5th Company)

Forgeworld Mordax Aid Allotment – Vengeance-Terminus-Alpha
- Myrmidon Magos Dominus-Militant Thallrex-17
- Myrmidon Destructor Ravenna Darus
- Myrmidon Destructor Elgred
- Myrmidon Destructor Xil-Xi 12
- Myrmidon Destructor Paxton
- Myrmidon Destructor Celine
- Myrmidon Destructor Zazcha
- Myrmidon Destructor Eish Katchoum
- Myrmidon Destructor Bron-Ai7
- Artisan Lionus [Leader of Non-Combatants, Protected By 2 Praetorian Servitors]
- Transmechanic Hollarn [Non-Combatant]
- Logis Aemilian [Non-Combatant]
- Rune-Priest Ngoc [Non-Combatant]

Sororitas Auxiliary Forces:
- Order of Our Martyred Lady
x1 Canoness Commander Katicia [Promoted from Palatine]
x2 Celestian Superior Squads
x2 Seraphim Superior Squads
x3 Dominion Squads [Promoted from Sisters of Battle]
- Order of the Bloody Rose
x1 Palantine Maria
x1 Celestian Superior Squad
x2 Dominion Squads
- Order of the Ebon Chalice
x1 Palantine Patricia
x1 Celestian Superior Squad
x2 Retributor Squads
x2 Dominion Squads
- Order of the Wounded Heart
x1 Palantine Georgina
x2 Retributor Squads
x10 Thunderhawk Transporter Pilot Teams (2 Crew Per Thunderhawk Transporter)
x10 Thunderhawk Gunship Pilot Teams (4 Crew Per Thunderhawk Gunships)

Forge World Kentrael - Supplementary Ship Personnel
- x50 Enginseers of Forge World Kentrael, Overseen By Enginseer Prime Opheli Gamma-4
- Unknown amount of Servitors of Forge World Kentrael

Blood Raven Vehicles:
Drop Pods and Assault Rams Not Individually Counted
- 3 Razorbacks
- 1 Predator Annihilator [Twin-Linked Lascannon/Lascannon Sponsons/Extra Armor Plating] Great Father's Fury
- 1 Deimos-Pattern Predator [Autocannon/Heavy Bolters/Extra Armor Plating] Spear Of Redemption
- 1 Land Raider Terminus Ultra Redemption By Fire [2 Sponson-Mounted Twin-Linked Godhammer Lascannons/1 Twin-Linked Godhammer Lascannon Mounted On Main Hull/2 Additional Mounted Lascannons Ahead Of Sponsons/Zero Troop Transport Capacity/Advanced Generators+Capacitors]

Retribution Armory:
Note: Possesses All Standard Issue Weaponry
- x12 Terminator Armor (Indominatus-Pattern)
- x1 Terminator Armory (Tartaros-Pattern)
- x13 Storm Bolters
- x38 Power Weapons (x9 Power Fists, x15 Power Swords, x10 Lightning Claw Pairs, x4 Thunder Hammers)
- x27 Plasma Guns
- x11 Plasma Pistols
- x5 Plasma Cannons
- x9 Heavy Flamer
- x11 Multi-Meltas
- x1 Missile Launcher
- x7 Assault Cannons
- x5 Lascannon
- x8 Storm Shields
- x6 Cyclone Missile Launcher [Terminator Armor Attachment]

*Force Commander Aramus bears Penitent Seals so numerous as to be uncountable, but the most notable amongst them have been noted below.
** Organs and body willed to full activation once more immediately prior to fighting at Subiaco Diablo

Spoiler: Penitent Seals of Aramus

Heart of the Just: "Death in service to the Emperor is its own reward; life in failure to Him is its own condemnation."
Larraman's Atonement: "His blessings are reserved for those who deserve them. I shall earn my place at His side anew." Larraman Organ Willed To Partial Dormancy
Brennen's Testimony: "For we knew that to save, there would be certain pain and suffering, and all we had worked for would be placed in jeopardy, yet there was no hesitation in our decision. Indeed, it was never deemed a decision to begin with."
Pilgrim's Pledge: "I shall never stop, lest the enemy escape. I shall never tire, lest the enemy strike. I shall reach salvation."
Purification Through Pain: "Feel the limitless pain of life, lest you be seduced by the comforts of death." Pain Dampening Glands Willed To Partial Dormancy
The Unturned Blow: "For each of my failings, shall I bear a scar in my flesh.
Oath of the Crucible: "Though I have faltered, I shall never fall. Let the crucible of fire come."
Oath of Penance: "I shall have no aid, no brotherhood, no succor until I atone, so swears this Penitent."
Greater Oath of Penance: "I swear to throw myself on to the pyre of war, to burn evermore, that I be cleansed of all impurity. Thus, should I survive, I may be returned to the path of the righteous."
Oath of the Crusader: "I shall neither flinch from my duty though it be terrible, nor seek rest though I grow weary; I shall neither give nor request mercy until this crusade is won."

** Senior Techmarine Sarrelen of the Blood Ravens appears to have crafted customized war panoply for himself for high intensity combat with the aid of the Tech-Priests of Mordax Prime, the Techmarines of the Salamanders, and the Tech-Priests of Kentrael.

Spoiler: Customized War Panoply

Bearer: Senior Techmarine Sarrelen of the Blood Ravens
Armor List:
- Indominatus-Pattern Terminator Armor
- Integrated Refractor Field Shield Generator
- Advanced Belt-Hopper Assault Cannon Ammo Storage And Reloading System OR Customized Power Source System For Combi-Weapons Depending On Load-Out
- Secondary Advanced Belt-Hopper Storm Bolter Ammo Storage And Reloading System
Weaponry List (Cyclone Launcher and Forearm-Mounted Storm Bolters Consistent, Combi-Weapons Vary Depending On Engagement):
- (2) Forearm-Mounted Storm Bolters With Belt-Hopper System Integrated Into Secondary Customized Ammo Storage System
- (1) Cyclone Missile Launcher With Custom-Created Krak Missiles With Secondary Liquid Incendiary Detonations or Melta Charges.

Loadout 1 [3 Assault Cannons Per Arm] With Belt-Hopper System Integrated Into Customized Ammo Storage System
Loadout 2 [1 Multi-Melta/1 Lascannon Per Arm] Powered By Customized Power Source System
Loadout 3 [1 Heavy Flamer/1 Assault Cannon Per Arm] With Belt-Hopper System and Fuel-Tank System
Loadout 4 [1 Plasma Cannon/1 Assault Cannon Per Arm] With Belt-Hopper System and Customized Power Source System

Spoiler: Inquisition Departure Notifications

Squad Superstes-2 [10/10] Returned To Death Spectres Chapter
- Veteran Sergeant Kovac [Death Spectres (2nd Company) Formerly Squad Occludus-Superstes]
- Veteran Tactical Marine Corvin [Death Spectres (2nd Company) Formerly Squad Occludus-Superstes]
- Veteran Tactical Marine Frigan [Death Spectres (2nd Company) Formerly Squad Occludus-Superstes]
- Veteran Tactical Marine Remliel [Death Spectres (2nd Company)]
- Veteran Tactical Marine Isarbul [Death Spectres (2nd Company)]
- Veteran Tactical Marine Seglur Death Spectres [Death Spectres (2nd Company)]
- Veteran Tactical Marine Aviras Death Spectres [Death Spectres (2nd Company)]
- Veteran Tactical Marine Bethian Death Spectres [Death Spectres (2nd Company)]
- Veteran Tactical Marine Cassiel Death Spectres [Death Spectres (2nd Company)]
- Veteran Tactical Marine Tabbris Death Spectres [Death Spectres (2nd Company)]

Squad Superstes-1 [10/10] Returned To Marauders+Executioners Chapters
- Veteran Sergeant Oghul Timur [Marauders (6th Brotherhood) Formerly Squad Solaris-Superstes] [Bearing Kebek-Crafted Item: Power Axe]
- Senior Techmarine Eljigidey Kebek [Marauders (6th Brotherhood) Formerly Squad Solaris-Superstes] [Bearing Self-Crafted Item: Twin Power Axes]
- Apothecary Changshi [Marauders (6th Brotherhood) Formerly Squad Solaris-Superstes] [Bearing Blood Raven Armory Item: Terminator Armor (Indominatus-Pattern), x1 Assault Cannon]
- Veteran Devastator Marine Michael [Executioners (9th Company) Formerly Squad Necromund-Superstes] [Bearing Blood Raven Armory Item: Heavy Bolter]
- Senior Techmarine Augustus [Executioners (9th Company) Formerly Squad Necromund-Superstes] [Bearing Blood Raven Armory Item: Lascannon]
- Veteran Tactical Marine Khajog [Marauders (6th Brotherhood)]
- Veteran Tactical Marine Qaja [Marauders (6th Brotherhood)]
- Veteran Tactical Marine Ogedei [Marauders (6th Brotherhood)]
- Veteran Tactical Marine Ghangar [Marauders (6th Brotherhood)]
- Veteran Tactical Marine Akhutai [Marauders (6th Brotherhood)]

Raptors Squad Talon-5: [10/10]
- Veteran Sergeant Assault Marine Celeritan [Bearing Salamander-crafted Item: Lightning Claw Pair]
- Veteran Assault Marine Locitan [Bearing Blood Raven Armory Item: Lightning Claw Pair]
- Veteran Assault Marine Cursun [Bearing Blood Raven Armory Item: Lightning Claw Pair]
- Veteran Assault Marine Quillum [Bearing Blood Raven Armory Item: Lightning Claw Pair]
- Veteran Assault Marine Lacidus [Bearing Blood Raven Armory Item: Lightning Claw Pair]
- Veteran Assault Marine Narcariel [Bearing Blood Raven Armory Item: Lightning Claw Pair]
- Veteran Assault Marine Kostis [Bearing Blood Raven Armory Item: Lightning Claw Pair]
- Veteran Assault Marine Graevast [Bearing Blood Raven Armory Item: Lightning Claw Pair]
- Veteran Assault Marine Amardova [Bearing Blood Raven Armory Item: Lightning Claw Pair]
- Veteran Assault Marine Trajald [Bearing Blood Raven Armory Item: Lightning Claw Pair]

Auxiliary Departures
33rd Gudrun Storm Trooper Squad (Led by Tempestor Meshana): Seconded To Ordo Malleus on Order of Inquisitor Moredecai Toth
x10 Enginseers [Formerly Krieger/19th Cadian Guard Attached Enginseers] Returned To Kreiger/Cadian Regiments On Planet Cadia

Spoiler: Inquisition Fatality Notifications

Blood Ravens
- Crusade Champion: Assault Terminator Gilroy Lechris (1st Company)
- Command Squad Chaplain: Prathios (4th Company)
- Veteran Tactical Squad Flagellan [10/10] (4th Company)
- Veteran Devastator Squad Perditium [10/10] (5th Company)
- Veteran Assault Squad Penitentium [10/10] (8th Company)
- Veteran Tactical Terminator Squad Repententum [5/5] (1st Company)
- Veteran Assault Terminator Squad Contemptum [5/5] (1st Company)
- Venerable Tomb-Brother Callum [Mk-V Castraferrum Dreadnought] (5th Company)
- Tomb-Brother Librarian Epistolary Konan Barbarial [Entombed In A MK-V Castraferrum Dreadnought Frame] (5th Company)

Non-Blood Raven Astartes Losses [GD = Gene-Seed Delivered To Chapter/GL = Gene-Seed Lost Or Otherwise Unrecoverable]
- Veteran Assault Marine Ustu’ran [Marauders Chapter 6th Brotherhood/Crusade Squad Necromund-Superstes] GD
- Veteran Assault Marine Flavius [Marauders Chapter 6th Brotherhood/Crusade Squad Necromund-Superstes] GD
- Veteran Tactical Marine Algor [Death Spectres Chapter 2nd Company/Crusader Squad Occludus-Superstes] GD
- Veteran Tactical Marine Pulcrum [Death Spectres Chapter 2nd Company/Crusader Squad Occludus-Superstes] GD
- Veteran Tactical Marine Umbul [Death Spectres Chapter 2nd Company/Crusader Squad Occludus-Superstes] GD
- Veteran Devastator Marine Johnathan [Executioners 9th Company/Crusader Squad Necromund-Superstes] GD
- Veteran Tactical Marine Albus [Executioners 9th Company/Crusader Squad Necromund-Superstes] GD
- Veteran Devastator Marine Tesan [Death Spectres Chapter 2nd Company/Crusader Squad Occludus-Superstes] GL

Adeptus Mechanicus Forces
- Myrmidon Destructor Flavius Justinian [Forgeworld Mordax Prime Myrmidon Allotment – Vengeance-Terminus]
- Myrmidon Necine [Forgeworld Mordax Prime Myrmidon Allotment – Vengeance-Terminus]
- Myrmidon Gelimer [Forgeworld Mordax Prime Myrmidon Allotment – Vengeance-Terminus]
- Magos Dominus Pelliad (Kataphron Marshal) [Forgeworld Mordax Kataphron Battle Servitor Vengeance-Terminus-Beta]
- Kataphron Breacher-821 [Forgeworld Mordax Kataphron Battle Servitor Vengeance-Terminus-Beta]
- Kataphron Breacher-893 [Forgeworld Mordax Kataphron Battle Servitor Vengeance-Terminus-Beta]
- Kataphron Destroyer-1111 [Forgeworld Mordax Kataphron Battle Servitor Vengeance-Terminus-Beta]
- Kataphron Destroyer-1321 [Forgeworld Mordax Kataphron Battle Servitor Vengeance-Terminus-Beta]
- Kataphron Destroyer-1214 [Forgeworld Mordax Kataphron Battle Servitor Vengeance-Terminus-Beta]
- Kataphron Destroyer-1231 [Forgeworld Mordax Kataphron Battle Servitor Vengeance-Terminus-Beta]
- Kataphron Destroyer-2244 [Forgeworld Mordax Kataphron Battle Servitor Vengeance-Terminus-Beta]
- Kataphron Destroyer-3124 [Forgeworld Mordax Kataphron Battle Servitor Vengeance-Terminus-Beta]
- Kataphron Destroyer-823 [Forgeworld Mordax Kataphron Battle Servitor Vengeance-Terminus-Beta]
- Kataphron Destroyer-715 [Forgeworld Mordax Kataphron Battle Servitor Vengeance-Terminus-Beta]

Auxilary Forces
- Single 19th Cadian Platoon
- Single Death Korps of Krieg Platoon
- Order of Our Martyred Lady [Canoness Alessa/Seraphim Squad/x3 Sister of Battle Squads]
- 1 Leman Russ Tank And Crew of Cadian 19th
- Mixed Imperial Guardsmen Platoon, Led by Cadian Commissar Markus Steiner (x1 Command Squad, x2 Infantry Squads, x1 Heavy Weapon Squad)
- Order of Our Martyred Lady: x4 Sister of Battle Squads, x1 Celestian Squad, x2 Dominion Squads
- Order of the Bloody Rose: x3 Sister of Battle Squads, x1 Celestian Squad, x1 Retributor Squad
- Order of the Ebon Chalice: x1 Seraphim Superior Squad, x1 Celestian Squad

Spoiler: Defunct Categorization Of Penitent Crusade Before Extensive Casualties

Squad Penitentus-Primaris: [3/5]
- Force Commander: Aramus Valorun (4th Company) [Bearing Relics: Crusade Eternal, Sunderhammer]
- Crusade Champion: Assault Terminator Gilroy Lechris (1st Company)
- Epistolary: Konan Barbarial (5th Company) [Entombed In Mk-V Castraferrum Frame]
- Apothecary: Adrian Kogal (4th Company) [Possesses Sophisticated Bionics For Left Leg, Left Arm, Right Leg] [Bearing Relics: The Pitiless Lance of Vengeance]
- Chaplain: Prathios (4th Company)

Crusade: 6 Members Remaining (Aramus, Thaddeus, Konan, Adrian, Sarrelen, Nereus )

Veteran Sergeants:
- Veteran Scount Sergeant Nereus (Vow of Silence) [Bearing Relics: Honored Silence, Angel of Silence, Talon of the Doom Eagle] (10th Company)
- Veteran Assault Marine Sergeant Thaddeus Rex [Bearing Relics: Growling Hate/Xenosplitter, Golden Armor of the Custodes] (4th Company)

Veteran Tactical Squad Flagellan [10/10] (4th Company)
Veteran Devastator Squad Perditium [10/10] (5th Company)
Veteran Assault Squad Penitentium [10/10] (8th Company)
Veteran Tactical Terminator Squad Repententum [5/5] (1st Company)
Veteran Assault Terminator Squad Contemptum [5/5] (1st Company)

Dreadnoughts: [1/1]
- Venerable Tomb-Brother Callum [Mk-V Castraferrum Dreadnought] (5th Company)
- Epistolary Konan Barbarial (5th Company) [Entombed In A MK-V Castraferrum Dreadnought Frame]

Spoiler: Crusade Specialists

Techmarines
- Senior Techmarine Sarrelen [Blood Ravens 4th Company]

Apothecaries
- Adrian Kogal [Blood Ravens 4th Company]

Psykers
- Epistolary Konan Barbarial [Blood Ravens - Entombed]

Chaplains

Deathwatch

Epistolary Vaikos (1st Company) [Began Vigil at Watch Fortress Oertha: 970.M41] [Estimated Time Of Return: INDEFINITE]
Tomb-Brother Palkair (4th Company) [Began Vigil at Watch Fortress Erioch: 700.M41] [Estimated Time Of Return: INDEFINITE]
Veteran Devastator Castigon (6th Company) [Began Vigil at Watch Fortress Phaedas: 950.M41] [Estimated Time Of Return: INDEFINITE]
[6/10] Veterans (5th Company) [Assigned To Segmentum Ultima Crisis Zones 741-825: 025.M42] [Estimated Time Of Return: INDEFINITE]
[2/10] Veterans (5th Company) [Assigned To Segmentum Ultima Crisis Zones 123-216: 025.M42] [Estimated Time Of Return: INDEFINITE]

[1/1] Tomb-Brother (5th Company) [Assigned To Segmentum Ultima Crisis Zones 123-216: 025.M42] [Estimated Time Of Return: INDEFINITE]

[10/10] Talon Squad [Veterans] (1st Company) [Assigned To Segmentum Ultima Crisis Zones 741-825: 055.M42] [Estimated Time Of Return: INDEFINITE]

Explorator Fleet Detachment

None Currently

Turn 2 Results - 2470.5

Okay. Getting him those books. It's only the entire feudal contract of Stirland that depends on you. No pressure.

Okay, so they're either in the castle or out of the castle. If they're in the castle, they'll be found sooner or later by Herr Schultz, so you only have to worry about outside the castle. Judging by the size of the room that used to contain them, there were a massive amount of ledgers and documents that made up Stirland's archives. And from handling tomes back in College, you know for a fact that paper is actually quite heavy. So this isn't a matter of someone loading books into a sack and sneaking off into the night - it's more like five, six cartloads of ancient, dusty paperwork. Very unwieldy, and very noticeable.

So noticeable, you're hoping, that they couldn't be stashed somewhere in Wurtbad itself. They'd have to have left the city, and that narrows down the point of egress considerably - Wurtbad has three gates, and trade can only go through the southern one, and all the carts and their contents are recorded by the Wurtbad Watch to make sure nobody's trying to sidestep tolls and tariffs. So all you have to do is look through those records until you find multiple cartloads of books and you'll have taken a significant step down the road of finding them.

(Unless, you realize with a sinking feeling, they crated up the books before moving them, then transferred them to a boat. Once they got onto the River Stir they could go just about anywhere unnoticed. You're hoping that whoever it is didn't think of that.)

Putting aside your misgivings, you round up your platoon and make your way to the gatehouse, drawing stares and parting the crowds as you lead them down Wurtbad's main street. The gate guards snap to attention as you approach - reacting more to the two dozen heavily armed and armoured men than your own slight form, if you had to guess, but you'll take it - and when you tell them your reason for being here they scramble to obey. You're shown into a cramped and poorly ventilated room filled with a battered table, a dented stove, and a small bookshelf filled with crudely-bound books. You pick one at random and open it, and feel a headache start to form as you try to make sense of the handwriting.

Your procession back to Eagle Castle is slightly less impressive on account of the armful of books each of the Greatswords is carrying.

---

You've read alphabets older than the Empire that were easier to understand than the handwriting of these bloody Watchmen.

It takes you weeks of constant effort to make your way through them. You send your Greatswords (who claimed illiteracy) out to chase down false lead after false lead, as printers, booksellers, accountants and bankers are paraded in and out of the castle to explain the most mundane of cargo. You never would have guessed how much paperwork flows into and out of Wurtbad.

And then, at long, long last, you have it. Just under a year before the previous Elector Count's death. Six cartloads over two days, each of them after dark, each of them exempt from tolls, tariffs and excise by the authority of the Castle, driven by a local carter by the name of - you squint - Jolan? Johan? You think it's Johan. Once more, you round up your Greatswords from where they had gotten off to. Some were down in the cells slowly and thoroughly working the truth out of the poor stablehand, some were following Herr Schultz around in the hope that he'll uncover more undead for them to cheerily bisect with their enormous swords, and the rest were hanging around the kitchens trying to wheedle snacks out of the head cook.

If anything, the Guild of Carters and Coachmen put up even less of a fight than the Watchmen on the Guardhouse. The moment you told them what you were there for, they gave you the address of a licensed freelance cart owner-operator by the name of Johan (you were right!). You head over there immediately before any of his coworkers can tip him off, and that his response to a pair of Greatswords knocking on his door was to climb out a window was a promising sign. Especially since you had three more waiting just around the corner from that window.

---

"I didn't know what was happening until it were too late," poor Johan blubbers to you from his position shackled to a bench. You hadn't even had to threaten him, you just sat there looking at him while it sank in for him what was going on, and he had started telling you the entire story. "I thort it was just another job from the castle. They'd bin movin all sortsa furniture and whatnot, redecoratin I think. So I go there with my cart and poor Delilah starts actin all sorts of funny, stampin' and whinnyin' and as I'm tryina calm her down the builders start pilin' all these books into the cart. None of 'em said a word, just pilin' it all in while I'm standin' there tryina calm my horse down. So I thort, okay, that was bad enough, but for what they was payin' I could put up with Delilah sulkin' for a few weeks, but then I take the instructions they gave me back to the guildhall and ask someun to read it for I, and they wanted it taken to a mound halfway to Julbach."

That got your attention. Every child raised in Stirland knew to never, ever, ever go near the burial mounds that dotted the landscape, and the books you read at College agreed - both those concerning magic and those that weren't approved parts of the curriculum. The tribal chieftains from before the coming of Sigmar did not rest soundly in their graves.

"I shoulda dumped the books right there and then, but then I think, the only thing worse than gettin inta business with the sorta folk that want things delivered to those sorta places is tryina get outta business with 'em. So I just did the job. Unloaded the books outside the mound, and when I got back with the next lot the last lot was gorn. Six loads, and Delilah still gets jumpy on dark nights, and until today I thanked Morr every night that that was the worst of it."

[VISITING THE WATCHMEN: Automatic success because Greatswords.]
[READING THE RECORDS: Req 50, Learning, 39+13=52. A long and hard-fought battle.]
[VISITING THE CARTER'S GUILD: Automatic success because Greatswords.]
[HUNTING JOHAN: Req 40, Intrigue, 68+12=80. Fish in a barrel.]
[INTERROGATING JOHAN: Req 40, Intrigue, 75+12=87. Singing like a bird.]

---

The other lead you were following was what Wilhelmina had said. Most of the nobles, she said, were inadvertently assisting her in her stopgap attempt to rebuild Stirland's tax code. So which weren't, then?

When you put the question to her, she guides you back to the room that had once been the archives, and now contained a battered desk half-covered with paper. She searches through it and finally produces a hand-written list, which she compares to a map of Sylvania hanging from a pair of nails driven into the wall.

"Alright, so not counting Abelhelm, there's thirteen centers of power in Stirland. Four each in Western, Central, and Southern Stirland, and Countess Gabriella of Nachthafen in Sylvania." She points to a town in Western Sylvania. "Flensburg, I haven't gotten anything from. But I expected that. The Lord Mayor of Flensburg told me to talk to the Countess of Flensburg, and the Countess of Flensburg told me to talk to the Lord Mayor. Weird, ugly little geopolitical argument. I doubt either of them are involved in anything but trying to screw over each other." Then she pointed to Sylvania. "I haven't received anything from Countess Gabriella. But that could be nothing, she's in the middle of Sylvania. Maybe she sent it and it never arrived, maybe she decided not to bother since tax collectors haven't penetrated that far into Sylvania in decades." She hesitated for a second, then pointed to Siegfriedhof. "Nothing from them, but the Knights of Morr don't pay secular taxes anyway." Then she pointed to Leicheburg in southern Sylvania, nestled against the Haunted Hills. "Count Petr is the last of them, and not only has he not sent me the documents but he hasn't been paying taxes either. It's almost entirely livestock and farming down then so at first I thought it might just be a bad year, but I've gotten the documents from Hornau, Sigmaringen and Schramleben, and they're all paying taxes as normal. And Sigmaringen is almost as poor as Leicheburg."

So, Leicheburg. The more you look at the map, the less you like it. Wurtbad to Worden, then down the Moot Road to Schramleben, then to Hornau and finally the Black Run up to Leicheburg... at least 500 miles. That'd be about two weeks on a typical horse, or since you were on official business, you could change horses at every post station and cut that in half. But that was travelling on a horse of flesh and blood, with the limitations of a living, breathing creature. Not on a horse of shadow that could gallop for a day and a night without rest until banished by the rising sun. On such a horse, you could make the ride in a day, except for one other limitation - the fact that sixteen hours of galloping would turn your body below the waist into pulp. Four days, maybe.

---

They say that the Moot is lovely in autumn. You'll have to take their word for it. While the blur of reds and yellows you saw was certainly vivid, the only memories you've gained of the Moot are stumbling into an inn as your horse disappears in a puff of Ulgu and pleading for a hot dinner, a cold bath, and a soft bed. Though to the Moot's credit, that was certainly delivered.

Two days later, you're dismissing your horse once more and bribing a thoroughly alarmed farmer on the road a couple of coins to carry you the rest of the way into the town, and you gratefully curl up on a pile of sheepskins in the cart he's driving. The city guards barely glance at a farmgirl napping in the back of a cart - you'd thought to change into something a little less attention-getting than your usual robes. A few more coins later, you've found a man willing to claim he'd ridden from Wurtbad to ask after the tax documents, and you trail after him as he heads into the castle where Count Petr von Stolpe is holding court.

The Count turns out to be a middle-aged man with thin features and an alarmingly aquiline nose, which he uses to great effect to look down at anyone who has the temerity to speak to him. You watch him as a dozen complaints and suits for adjudication are brought before him, and he's obviously paying as little attention as possible - an assistant leans forward after every speech to tell him what a suitable response would be.

But as your patsy is heard, he shows some animation, leaning forward with an eager smile as he's reminded that he was asked to send his tax records to Wurtbad. After your puppet trails off, he leans back in his chair, steepling his fingers with a look of satisfaction on his face. "If Wurtbad believes, as they so transparently do, that I have been remiss in my tax obligations," he says, smug grandeur radiating off him, "I invite them to compare what they have received to what the feudal contract says they are owed."

Well, that was about as subtle as a thrown brick. You make your way back out of the castle, exchanging a polite smile with the guards on the gate as you leave. Now you just have to get home again...

[RIDING A HORSE OF SHADOW: Roll, Martial, 85+7=92. Riding skill acquired.]
[BAITING THE COUNT: Req 60, Intrigue, 62+12=74. He's a bit of a shit.]
[ACTING UNNOTICED: Req 40, Intrigue, 44+12=56. Like you were never there.]

---

Though you spend a day or two recovering, you're able to leap back to work surprisingly quick after your thousand mile round trip. And you're glad you did, because in your absence the Greatswords had gone a little off the rails. You explain to them that, yes, he is technically an enemy of the Empire for obstructing the investigation of an Elector Count's councilwoman, but that doesn't mean he should be executed on the spot. You order them to deconstruct the gallows they had entertained themselves by building in the courtyard, though not before you lead the stablehand out to have a good, hard look at it.

The Greatswords may have been on the verge of taking away your lead, but they did do a passable job of softening him up. Unfortunately, he doesn't know much. All he really knows is that he was paid a handful of shillings to go to Wurtbad, present himself as a former employee of the castle, and if anyone asks about the previous occupants to tell them a set of specific lies about the spymaster.

Who told him? A man in a cloak in a bar, he says, and you fight back a grimace at the dead-end of an answer. But then you leap on one specific part - 'to go to Wurtbad', he said. Where was he living before?

"Julbach," is his answer.

[HOW MUCH DOES HE KNOW: Roll, 46. Snippets and tidbits.]
[HOW MUCH DOES HE SAY: Req 40, 37. Failure avoided only because you rolled so well riding your shadowhorse.]

---

Interspersed with your official duties, you found time to fulfil your obligation to whoever it was that was pulling your strings. Between Anton's visits to the closest of Stirland's nobles, you engage him in conversation about Stirland's political landscape to try to gauge his level of ability, and he's more than happy to cooperate. The results are... unexpected.

Anton Kiesinger II is quite possibly the least politically savvy person you have ever encountered.

You first assumed that his simplicity was a facade, a way to put people at ease while gaining their trust. But every indication is that Anton is exactly what he appears to be: open, honest, a bit dim, and entirely blind to the deeper meaning behind every word and action in high-level political discourse. And apparently that he is so non-threatening as a diplomat is why he's able to perform the job so well. He's not a threat as a politician, and because his father's lands are relatively small and out of the way, he's not a threat as a future noble.

In a world of wolves, he's a puppy. And like a puppy, now that you've shown him attention, he adores you. After you had found everything you needed to know, he continued to seek you out and ask how you've been eating and making sure that the Greatswords assigned to you are being properly respectful. Whether you like it or not, he's decided that you're his new little sister.

It was almost a shame that you went on to completely violate the trust he had in you by breaking into his quarters while he was off making friends on Van Hal's behalf. Then again, 'breaking in' might be too strong a wording. He didn't even lock his door. He even left a little note on his desk apologizing to the maids for spilling soup on his bed linen!

A search of the room revealed a trove of information in the form of a box full of correspondence, and Anton possesses that odd compulsive quirk of keeping a copy of every letter he sends. Most of it was between him and his father, and though Anton Senior is making the most of the opportunity of his son being on the council of the Elector Count, it seems his highest ambition is to encourage more overland trade to Wissenland so he can profit from the increase in tolls. Anton Junior apparently found out that Van Hal routinely used a Nuln rifle, and he was hoping that this would mean that Stirland's crossbowmen could be replaced or supplemented with handgunners in the near future.

You skim back through the thick bundles of letters, finding that most of them were between father and son and the rest polite missives thanking one noble or another for some social event or another. But as you're about to put the box away, you notice that it's deeper on the outside than on the inside, and it doesn't take you long to lever out the false bottom and find another bundle of letters entirely. These are between him and a person he addresses as 'Auntie Julia'. The letters to her are mostly filling her in on events in the family, though they frequently mention how much he misses her. The letters back are much less prosaic, filled with descriptions of a military campaign against Beastmen in some forested corner of the Empire - and from her descriptions of events, Auntie Julia appears to be a Jade Wizard.

The most recent letter is dated two years ago.

You replace everything where you found it and leave the room.

The report you prepare describes a diplomat who is skilled at building and maintaining relations with his fellow nobles, though thoroughly unsuited to the darker sides of politics. It lists his largest influence as his father, whose motives appear entirely benign, and notes friendly relations with every noble of note in Western Stirland and most of them in Central Stirland, too. It also describes his talent at making friends with those he works with.

No mention is made in the report of Auntie Julia.

Exactly three months after you received your orders, a Roadwarden arrives in the castle courtyard and mentions to a guard that you might have a letter for him. When you bring it down to him, you have a thousand ideas in your head for different ways you could try to winkle information out of him, but in the end you decide all of them are too obvious. Better not to risk it... this time.

[INNOCENT CHAT: Req 60, Diplomacy, 96+9=105. You manage to get a solid read on Anton, and won him over in the process.]
[INNOCENT B&E: Req 40, Intrigue, 67+12=79. In and out unseen.]
[ANYTHING ELSE?: Req 60, Intrigue, 73+12=85. Hidden compartment found.]
[ROADWARDEN: Req 50, Diplomacy, 34+9=41. Better not to risk it.]

---

For the past few months, your spare moments have been spent thinking about finally moving out of the terrible guest room and into your very own home. But you were thoroughly torn on what form that home would take. One half of you wanted to claim a tower along the walls of Wurtbad. You are a wizard, after all, and a wizard wears a tower like a crab wears a shell. But on the other hand, you weren't just any wizard - you were a Grey Wizard, masters of shadow and secrets, so the other half of you wanted a secret lair, secreted somewhere in Wurtbad's slums or catacombs. You went back and forth, making up and then changing your mind, until finally you decide to do the only sensible thing: you take a coin you had embezzled from your operational funds, cross your fingers, and flip it into the air.

[HEADS, A TOWER. TAILS, A DUNGEON. Result: Tails.]
[DOES THIS PLEASE RANALD?: Roll, 98. Ranald is amused.]

With your answer from on high, you start spending a great deal of time among the populace of Wurtbad, rebuilding old connections while scouting the darker corners of the town. The more you walk its streets, the more your memories of the town return, and you quickly find yourself at home in the maze of streets and alleys away from the main roads. Your slang is ten years out of date, but that just starts conversations about where you've been, and that gives you an opportunity to insult Reiklanders which is always popular. You chat easily to your new friends and let it be known you were looking for an out-of-the-way place to get some peace and quiet from the demands on your time, and would they know anywhere like that?

[HOW GOOD A HOME DO YOU FIND?: Roll, Diplomacy+Ranald's Blessing, 87+9+20=116. Well, then.]

You know, for all the cautionary tales you've read about why spirited young women shouldn't go wandering into dark tunnels, you tend to find yourself in them an awful lot.

It started with a harried innkeeper telling you that she had no use for one of the outbuildings and if you like, you could buy it off her for a handful of crowns and the promise that the Wurtbad Watch would fail to notice the still she'd set up in one of the other outbuildings. As you poked around in it, you thought for sure you wouldn't take it in a hundred years - though it was a sturdy stone construction, it was tiny and as filthy as a pigeon coop. Then you realized why, exactly, that comparison occurred to you, looking at row after row of recessions in the wall of the shack. It didn't make any sense for a pigeon coop to be here, at street level in a crowded alley where the sky overhead was barely visible. Then you looked down at the floor.

Half an hour of pushing what could have been centuries of accumulated junk out of the way (the innkeeper seemed to have forgotten about you, and from the waves of rowdy noise coming from the interior, you couldn't blame her), you finally found what you suspected you would find - a trapdoor made of wood so ancient it was nearly fossilized. It took you another ten minutes to lever it open with the help of a bent metal bar you had found in the refuse. And when you descended down the ladder, what you found took your breath away.

The explanation, you pieced together later, was fairly simple. Every few years, the River Stir would flood, depositing another layer of silt onto the streets of Wurtbad. In a single lifetime, this meant stepping up onto a street that used to be level with your door. But over the centuries that Wurtbad had served as capital of Stirland, ground floors had become basements and attics had become ground floors, and people had put an extra floor on their houses and forgotten about the now sub-basement they had no use for. Over the years, Wurtbad had risen, its walls protecting it from the erosion that washed back the flood-deposited silt everywhere else.

Underneath Wurtbad, entire buildings lay forgotten.

Entire underground ecosystems fled at your approach, the dim light of the lantern blazing like a supernova to creatures whose ancestors had forgotten the sun a hundred generations prior. Ornate windows showed a view of soil and rock. Rusted scraps of metal protruding from the wall mark where fine tapestries once hung. In places, many places, the walls had given way and soil had poured in, drowning entire wings. And only the vaguest hint of differing colours showed where frescoes once covered entire walls. But like a lingering ghost, the grandeur of this forgotten palace was still visible.

You announce to the innkeeper that you would be taking the outbuilding, thank you very much.

---

Later, as you make the entrance room of your underground home liveable and barricade the doorway into the rest of the palace (just in case), it occurs to you that there's barely anything you can do to set up more of a shrine to Ranald. It's a shack that's a palace, bought from the unknowing by sanctioning their theft of tax money. In the end, all you can really do is draw some crosses on the wall and put out milk for the cats that were already lounging around the place. And you could swear that the look the black one was giving you was especially smug, even for a cat.

SKILL ACQUIRED: Riding (Basic)
HOME ACQUIRED: Buried Palace
BLESSING ACQUIRED: Ranald's Gift (choose one action per turn; +20 bonus will apply where most needed during that action)
DISCRETIONARY GOLD EMBEZZLED: 100
DISCRETIONARY GOLD SPENT: 20 (Leicheburg investigation)
PERSONAL GOLD SPENT: 30 ('shack' purchased)
KNOWLEDGE ACQUIRED: Anton (see character sheet)
TITHE PAID: 5
STUDENT LOANS PAID: 35

---

It has been a year since you arrived back in Stirland, but it feels like much longer. You've gone from a student whose biggest problem was that the people smuggling novels into the College never manage to get all three parts of a trilogy, to being neck-deep in conspiracies that threaten the social fabric of an entire province. Van Hal has finally been convinced to stop wearing his Witch Hunter's hat everywhere he goes, but it'll be a longer battle to get him out of his armour. You're not sure whether it's Anton or Wilhelmina who are worrying about that, but you don't envy them the task.

Professor de Verezzo has reappeared from his tour of the towns of Stirland, and explains in his normal drone that he's making headway on filling up the ranks of Stirland, but he's taken on most of the 'low-hanging fruit' of Stirland, and if the task is to be completed by this time next year an additional signing bonus will be required to tempt people into joining.

MILITARY OF STIRLAND: Poor. 30,000 of 40,000 positions filled.

Anton, too, is back, describing a fairly successful tour of Western and Central Stirland. Most of the nobles are hoping that Van Hal represents stability over so many years of rapidly changing Elector Counts, and as long as he doesn't do anything to go against that impression they'll be happy to fulfil their obligations to him.

NOBLE RELATIONS: Very Good. Van Hal benefits from the contrast with his predecessors.

Wilhelmina has been continuing to manage the budget as best she can when all she can do is wait for taxes to be sent in and hope that they're the right amount. She's been focusing on Wurtbad in particular, using the Mayor's copies of the tax laws to make sure everyone in the city was paying what they were supposed to.

WEALTH OF STIRLAND: Poor; Wilhelmina managed to prevent it from falling this turn.
INCOME OF STIRLAND: Poor; will fall to Terrible if the nobles realize that they could just not pay taxes and get away with it.

Brother Kasmir has resanctified the castle's chapel to Sigmar, which had been thoroughly neglected over the decades. He also takes great pleasure in describing the adventures he and Van Hal got up to in penetrating and scourging walled-up chambers found in Schulz's charting of the castle. It seems that unlike any proper castle where the secret passages lead to hidden caches of treasures and artwork and the private hideaways of attractive nobles, Eagle Castle's passages contain only horrible creatures that hunger for the flesh of the living.

EAGLE CASTLE: Chapel built

Herr Schultz's mapping of the castle went as well as could be expected, as several more hidden chambers were found and cleared. He reports that he wasn't able to penetrate below the first floor of the dungeon - one stairway down was caved in and a second was flooded.

EAGLE CASTLE: Everything from B1 and above mapped, excluding the East Wing; no hidden chambers remain (?)

Finally, heads turn to you.

[] Write in your report

Of course, you have learned some things that are rather sensitive, especially about your fellow councillors. Maybe you should give a second report to Van Hal in private.

[] Write in a one-on-one report (optional)

Suggest possible orders for the next turn (new ones up top, old ones below):
[] A dozen centuries of tax ledgers and records don't just vanish. And I may have found them. Let's go raid a tomb.
[] Count Petr is definitely tied up in the ledger theft. I can go get him for you, and bring him back in chains.
[] The disappearance of your predecessor is very concerning, especially since he's actively trying to sabotage the hunt for him. He must be found, and I've got a lead: Julbach.
[] If I had proper facilities, I could do better work. Please fund me renovating my secret underground palace.

[] The Stirlandian League is a cancer eating at Stirland's economy, and it must be destroyed.
[] The Stirlandian League is a gold mine of information, and it must be yours.
[] There is a risk of enemy agents infiltrating the castle staff - they must be watched.
[] The castle staff can be a great source of information and first line of defence - they should report to you.
[] Seriously what is up with the East Wing.
[] I need a proper information network. Please fund me wandering around making friends.
[] Other (write in)

Relics of the Blood Ravens

Relic List - In Use

Wisdom - Ancient Power Sword (+1 Fellowship, Unbreakable) Captain Marcus Crixus [1st Company]
Arrow of Aerus - Relic Graviton Pistol, gifted to the Captain after discovery of the Graviton Cache on Aerus [Special Characteristics: Relic Weapon, Extremely Effective Anti-Armor] Captain Marcus Crixus [1st Company]
Azariah's Cincture - Blessed belt handed down by Azariah Vidya, the Great Father of the Blood Ravens. (+1 T, +Specially Reduces Melee Damage Dealt To Bearer) Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun
Deathdealer - Legendary Bolter (Allows Two Ranged Attacks For Bearer Instead of One Per Attack Phase, Reloads Less Often) Captain Tarkus Varianus [5th Company]
Fist of the Furioso - Legendary Dreadnought Claw (+Anti-Daemon Effects, +1 WS, Unbreakable) Entombed Captain Davian Thule [5th Company]
Tomb of Champions - Dreadnought Armor of lost design (+Greater Explosive Damage Resistance, Accuracy Increased) Entombed Captain Davian Thule [5th Company]
Star Thrower - Pre M32 Plasma Cannon (Higher Average Damage, Higher Critical Damage, Reduced Chance of Misfire) Veteran Sergant Macharius Sicarius [1st Company]
Unseen Demise of the Vain - Prized Sniper Rifle of the 10th Company (+Accuracy, +Range, Reduced Reload Time) Captain Cyrus Octavius [10th Company]
Armor of Azariah - Legendary Terminator Armor Worn By The Great Father Himself (Unsuppressable, Supremely Durable) Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
Godsplitter - Ordo Xenos-crafted Relic Daemonhammer (+1 Strength, +Blast Damage, +Anti-Daemon Effects) [Special Characteristics: Master Crafted, Shard of Wailing Doom Weapon Implanted In Weapon] Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
Blooded Narthecium - Personalized and modified narthecium by the Blood Raven Master of the Apothecarion Nero Gracchus when he was but an apothecary of the 5th Company. (Additional Damage To Armored Infantry, Improved Gene-Seed Recovery Chances) Master of Apothecarian Nero Gracchus
Hauberk of Faith - Otherwise normal Power Armor, strangely blessed by the Emperor. (Heightened Resistance To Daemons/Warp) Chief Librarian Justinius Probalis
Rogal's Fist - Power Mace said to have been forged by the very hands of Rogal Dorn himself. (Extreme Durability, Powerfield Extremely Powerful, +Impact, +Critical) Apollo Diomedes [Bodyguard of Chapter Master]
Gift of the Seraphim - Flamer given to the Chapter by the Order of the Lost Rosetta long ago. (Requires Far Less Fuel, Deals Greater Damage, Flames Last Longer) Sergeant Kaius Jacobus [5th Company]
Pistol of Baal - Bolt Pistol (Lower Crit Requirement For Ranged Rolls) Company Champion Hamul [1st Company]
Flesh Tearer's Pride - Chainsword named in honor of the Flesh Tearers Chapter (Increased Critical Chance In Melee Combat) Company Champion Hamul [1st Company]
Bloodtalon - Power Sword that was a gift of a Zerann Explorator. (Increased Critical Damage, Extreme-Anti Armor Effects) Shattered By Soulcleaver Of Chaos Lord Mortirex
Nightshade - Force Staff given as a gift by the Death Spectres Chapter for shared battle against the horrors of the Ghoul Stars. (Reduces Warp Peril Chances Significantly When Using Powers) 5th Company Epistolary Damion Tyrin
Umbral Barding - Relic Power Armor given as a gift by Death Spectres Librarians to Damion Tyrin for aiding the Chapter's Librarians in combating a daemon incursion. (Increases Telepathic Defenses, Boosts Willpower) 5th Company Epistolary Damion Tyrin
The Hand Of Aggression - Relic Plasma Pistol crafted by Master of the Forge Martellus Ravias, for the hands of Hadrian Priscus, Captain of the 4th Company. (Rapid-fire, Reduced Chance For Catastrophic Failure, Increased Ammo Efficiency For More Shots Before Reload, Boosted Range/Accuracy/Bayonet Fitted)) 4th Company Captain Hadrian Priscus
Thunder Blood - Relic Crozius Arcanum crafted by Master of the Forge Martellus Ravias for the hands of Hannibal Palrun, Master of Sanctity. Such is its size that what is a mace for its wielder would be a two-handed weapon in the hands of any other. (+Blast, +Advanced Disruption Field) Master Of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun
Talonstaff of Jonah - Forged in the same vein as the daemonhammer Godsplitter, this Force Staff possesses a fragment of an Ulthwé Avatar of Khaine's Wailing Doom weapon implanted in it, as well as fragments of the Force Staff used by Jonah Orion. It crackles with a deadly energy that is anathema to warpspawn, and seems to carry with it the same unrelenting will of Jonah himself at times. (+1 Toughness, +Miscast Chance Reduction, +Anti-Daemon Effects) [Special Characteristics: Master Crafted, Shard of Ulthwé Avatar Wailing Doom Weapon Implanted In Force Staff] Chief Librarian Justinius Probalis
Shadow Hunter's Raiment - Cameleoline-integrated high grade armor with accompanying camo-cloak. Contains sound-dampening materials, as well as additional thermal reduction technology for stealth purposes. Integrated targeting links of the armor are specially adapted for integration with Cyrus Octavian's own cybernetics. (+1 Ballistic Skill, +Further Improved Stealth Capabilities) Cyrus Octavius
Blade of the Martyr - A Force Sword once wielded by Azariah Moriah, a the heroic martyr who sealed away the daemon Ulkair into the planet Aurelia long ago. It still carries a psychic echo of the zeal the powerful Chief Librarian and Chapter Master had to remain standing and fighting despite grievous wounds. (Increases Power Of Defensive Psychic Powers of Librarian Wielder) Codicier Aeneas
The Barding of Tarkus: This masterful creation bears the engraved valorous deeds of Captain Tarkus of the Blood Ravens, along with zealous denials of the lies of traitors and madmen. A quirk of its manufacture has somehow further hardened the materials of its make, to the point of conferring greatly improved durability even amongst power armors, while its servos and artificial muscle fibres confer greater strength. Such magnificent armor inspires greater fervor in fellow sons of the Emperor in battle. (+1 Toughness, +1 Strength, Improved Resistance Against Anti-Armor Weaponry) 5th Company Captain Tarkus

Spoiler: Relics Known To Be Held By The Penitent Crusade As Of 009.M42

Crusade Eternal - Artificer Indominatus-Pattern Terminator Armor (Unsuppressable, +1 WP) Force Commander Aramus [4th Company] DESTROYED In Battle Of The Bloody Hill/Used In Relic Forging
Blessed Cage - Gilded Tartaros-Pattern Terminator Armor, said to have been presented to the foot of the Golden Throne itself. [Anti-Daemon Aura, Unsuppressable] Used In Relic Forging
Shield and Thunder of Lyonis - Thunder Hammer and Storm Shield (Reduces Damage Dealt To Bearer) DESTROYED In The Battle Of The Bloody Hill
Word of the Chapter – Relic Storm Bolter (+Anti-daemon, +Anti-warp, higher average damage) Destroyed In 3rd Defense of Kasr Durend
The Benediction of Fury – Relic Assault Cannon (Increased average damage, +Anti-xeno damage) DESTROYED In 3rd Defense Of Kasr Durend/Used In Relic Forging
Unrelenting – Relic Assault Cannon (Higher average damage, reduced reload time) DESTROYED In 3rd Defense Of Kasr Durend/Used In Relic Forging
Talon of the Doom Eagle - Plasma Pistol bearing Doom Eagle Chapter heraldry (Rapid Fire, Anti-Armor) DESTROYED In Destruction of the Ashen Vindication
Refrain Of The Crusader - Dreadnought Assault Cannon (Scatter Effect, Higher Average Damage) DESTROYED In Defense of Xersia By Greater Daemon of Nurgle
Sunderhammer - Thunder Hammer (Anti-Daemon Effects, Boosted Anti-Vehicle Effects) DESTROYED In Defense of Xersia by Greater Daemon of Nurgle
Golden Armor of the Custodes - Legendary Custodes Armor (+1WS, +1T, Increases Damage and Significantly Reduces Damage Taken) Reclaimed By the Adeptus Custodes
Relentless Will of the Emperor - Legendary Custodes Bolter Reclaimed By The Adeptus Custodes
Righteous Inferno - Legendary Custodes Flamer Reclaimed By The Adeptus Custodes
Honored Silence - Sniper Rifle (+Suppressed Fire, Increased Damage) Veteran Scout Sergeant Nereus [10th Company]
Angel of Silence - Scout Armor of the finest make commissioned by Inquisition with targeting links (+1 WS, Increased Stealth) Scout Sergeant Nereus [10th Company]
Growling Hate - Chainsword of Azariah Vidya Himself (+1 WS, +1 W) Veteran Assault Sergeant Thaddeus Rex [4th Company]
Xenosplitter - Chainsword consecrated by Ordos Xenos and Deathwatch (+1 WS, Additional Damage To Xenos Targets) Veteran Assault Sergeant Thaddeus Rex [4th Company]
The Pitiless Lance of Vengeance - Missile Launcher (Faster Than Average Fire, Increased Area Of Effect) Apothecary Adrian Kogal [4th Company]
Pistol of Terra - Bolt Pistol (Increased Damage To Xenos, Anti-Daemon Effects) Apothecary Adrian Kogal [4th Company]
Final Absolution of Caliban - Plasma Gun (Increased Area Of Effect, Higher Average Damage, +1 BS) Apothecary Adrian Kogal [4th Company]
Obsidian Raven – Talisman formed by Azariah Vidya himself from the blood of his enemies. (Vastly increased energy recovery for psykers, reduced chances for perils of the warp)
Coronet of Honor – Relic Iron Halo, forged under the eyes of Azariah Vidya himself. (Increased width of protective field, short recharge time if shield broken) Veteran Assault Sergeant Thaddeus Rex [4th Company]
Laurels of the Crusader – Relic Iron Halo, gilt in polished adamantium. (Increases armor durability in addition to stronger than average protective energy field) Apothecary Adrian Kogal [4th Company]
Cleansing Gift of the Inferno – Relic Heavy Flamer, gift of the Salamanders to Captain Tarkus In Times Past (Much higher average damage, higher critical damage, less reload time required)
Unrelenting Fury - Forged from the remains of The Benediction of Fury and Unrelenting, this assault cannon almost seems to hold an irrepressible hatred for the enemies of any who bear it and features an advanced loading and firing system. (Higher Damage, Reduced Reload)
Armor of Faith – Former Chaplain Armor fitted with advanced psychic hood (Integrated psychically activated Rosarius, increased resistance to psychic attacks)
The Eternal Blessed Cage – Forged from the broken remains of the relic terminator armors known as the Crusade Eternal and the intact relic armor called the Blessed Cage to become greater than the sum of its parts by the hands of the Blood Ravens and Salamanders together. It was later seamlessly integrated with an Iron Halo. (Unsuppressable, +1 WP, +Anti-Daemon Aura, Protective Field) Force Commander Aramus [4th Company]
Bloody Banner of Aramus – It has been soaked in the blood of penitents, martyrs, and heroes. It survived the Battle of the Bloody Hill and the destruction of the daemonic artifact Forgebreaker. It has been carried across the stars in hard fought last stands, glorious heroic charges, inconceivable defenses, and impossible rescues. It has tasted the hellish rage of a Daemon Primarch, and been hefted high by the Custodes themselves. This constantly rewoven and rebuilt banner flies despite everything the universe has done to destroy it. (+Increased Attack Speed in nearby allies and self, +1 T for nearby allies and self, Anti-Daemonic Aura) Force Commander Aramus [4th Company]
Torch of the Martyr - In life, the Librarian Konan Barbariel was known for his mastery of pyromancy, and remained so even in death. This heavy flamer is one of the only remnants of his that survived the the banishment of Pestilax the Despairer, a Greater Daemon of Nurgle, on the Cardinal World of Xersia. Formerly attached to his dreadnought arm, something in the weapon's internal mechanisms have been altered, resulting in a flame so bright and heated it is nearly akin to that of a melta weapon while burning almost no fuel comparatively. Furthermore, when that blue-white flame touches the unclean, it has proven itself even more effective. [Anti-Daemon, Melta-Effects In Flamer Spread+Reach, Increased Fuel Capacity] Sororitas Allies

Relic List - In Storage
None

The Sanctorium Arcanum
A secret cavernous hemispherical chamber within the battle barge Litany of Fury which contains a powerful choir of priests, mystics and astropaths. These individuals encircle a central altar that is held by a single beam of silver light which pierces from the sky doom at the apex of the massive curving ceiling. Above the altar piece is the Beacon Psykana which is tended to by the Librarians of the Secret Order of Psykana. The chambers of the Sanctorium are considered unique but pale before the majesty of the Chamber of the Astronomican on Terra. One of the benefits the Blood Ravens possess is that the Sanctorium Arcanum is a deeply held secret which has thus far prevented their enemies from assaulting it. The Sanctorium is heavily defended, capable of withstanding assault from both conventional as well as psychic means. It is also a traditional for the remains of a lost Librarian of the Secret Order of Psykana to be placed at the altar of the Sanctorium Arcanum for a hundred days. A special psychically shielded room within these chambers also holds the Psykana Armorium.

- Here, the remains of an Avatar of Khaine summoned by the forces of Biel-Tan under the Farseer Macha, defeated on the world of Tartarus, are stored for study and safekeeping.
- Here, the remains of Craftworld Ulthwé's Avatar of Khaine, slain on the planet Kronus during the Dark Crusade, are stored for study and safekeeping.
- Here, the remains of an Avatar of Khaine summoned by the Craftworld Ulthwé, slain by Aramus within the Typhon Arena before the planet's destruction later on, are stored for study and safekeeping.
- Here, the remains of the Unknown Craftworld buried on Typhon Primaris' Avatar of Khaine, slain by Aramus during the Aurelian Crusades, are stored for study and safekeeping.
- Here, the remains of the Seer Council of Craftworld Biel-Tan, from weapon, armor, and talismans are stored for study and safekeeping.

The Psykana Armorium
Deep within the Litany of Fury, located within a specially shielded chamber inside the Sanctorium Arcanum. A secret armory containing only force weapons, many of which have been procured through the ages by the Blood Raven Librarians during encounters with the Eldar. Whilst some were through victory in combat, it is whispered that some of these weapons were given voluntarily by the Eldar. The existence of the Psykana Armorium is a closely kept secret which is only revealed to initiates of the Secret Order of Psykana. Whist it is called an armory, it is not compared to normal ones as it serves as a repository of special weapons as well as serves as a conduit for psychic potentials of the weapons it held. These are channeled through the Beacon Psykana itself and amplified its psychic signal that pulses in the hearts of the Blood Ravens within the Order which it is maintained by. Whenever new Librarians are inducted into the Order Psykana, they are free to choose a weapon from the Psykana Armorium as their own.

Contents - To Only Be Known By The Order Psykana

[*] Plan Grabbing the necessary
-[*] Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far.
--[*] Combat Training: You're virtually surrounded by armed warriors of various sorts. See if you can convince one to teach you (choose who).
---[*] The Greatswords guarding the castle

-[*] As Per Orders: Perform your current assignment.
--[*] It'd be best all around if von Stolpe just quietly disappeared one night. Attempt to abduct him by stealth.
---[*] Ranald's Blessing on the abduction
--[*] You've also been asked to grab von Stolpe's heir. Ask him nicely, but don't take no for an answer.

-[*] Playing at General: Using and abusing the authority to order troops
--[*] Have some riders on standby to help restrain and escort the von Stolpes' home reduces the risk of an accident or escape along the way

-[*] Backtracking and Side Operations:
--[*] Before you head off to pester von Stolpe, Van Hal has invited you to come along to the Mound. While probably dangerous, it is an excellent chance to make a good impression, and gives you the opportunity to see what is found before a few dozen soldiers tramp through it.

-[*] Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud.
--[*] Good Neighbours: The previous owner of the 'shack' is the Innkeeper for the den of iniquity you share a wall with. Recruiting her would give you an information pipeline and an early warning system.
--[*] Castle Doctrine: You don't want just anyone wandering in. Set up locks and fortify the entrances.
-[*] Ask for a regular discretionary budget (moderate difficulty, success will be more expected of you)

---

Last time you came face to face with something that wanted to feed on your tender flesh, you defeated it by wrapping yourself in magical armour and letting it paw impotently at you while you stabbed it in the face. You've got a feeling that anything you may encounter in the ancient barrows would be more forceful than a long-starved corpse walled up in a bedroom, so it's time to learn variants of combat that aren't 'let them try to eat me' or 'wave a knife in their general direction and hope for the best'.

There's quite a few candidates for who you could learn from. Van Hal himself favours the rifle and halberd, Wilhelmina goes nowhere without at least four pistols, Brother Kasmir, of course, wields the hammer that is the signature of Sigmarite Warrior-Priests, and Anton probably learned some sort of swordplay growing up. But if you're going to learn the art of war, you eventually decide, it should be from a full-time warrior. So you change in your now mostly-unused guest room, leaving your robe and hat there in favour of a tunic and breeches, your hair tied up in a bun instead of flowing freely as you prefer. Now prepared, you make your way to the barracks protruding into the courtyard of Eagle Castle, where the clatter of wood on wood signifies that the Greatswords are battering each other with their wooden practice swords. Though when you stride into the middle of them and ask to be taught to wield a sword as they do, they all stop what they're doing and turn to watch.

The silence drags on just long enough for you to start getting angry, then one of them - an older man with a neat, grey beard and a missing ear - steps forward and holds out his practice sword to you. "Take this, then, and swing it at the dummy."

You reach out and take the sword, and the moment he lets go of it the point drops down and buries itself in the dirt before you can get control of the weight. It takes a fair bit of effort just to lift it until it's pointing upright, and then you don't so much swing it as let it fall in the direction of the dummy, and it bounces off the wooden bucket serving as a helmet with a clack.

"Again," he says. And you lift it once more, and this time try to accelerate the fall, causing a slightly louder clack to sound around the courtyard.

"Again," he says once more, and you turn to look at him, your eyes narrowed.

"For how long," you ask, already starting to breathe hard.

"Until you feel like your arms are going to fall off, and then even longer," he replies. You suspect that he's trying to mock you, but none of the other Greatswords seem to be amused. They're just watching you, seeing how you react. So instead of responding to words, you lift the massive wooden sword again and batter the dummy around the head with it. And again. And again.

And again.

After a while the Greatswords went back to their training, but the man who instructed you just stands there, watching, as sweat starts to pour down you and soak into your clothing, your arms shaking with fatigue. A time or two exhaustion causes you to stumble over your own feet, but you pick yourself up and throw yourself back into your fight against the dummy. What feels like a lifetime passes, and you want nothing more than to collapse onto the dirt and gasp for breath, but you can still feel the judging eyes of your overseer on your back, so you just keep pushing yourself to swing once more, then once more again.

"Enough," someone says, and it takes you a moment to parse the instruction. You turn and look dully at the man, and he nods to you. "Be back here tomorrow morning."

Somehow, you manage to find it in you to stagger back to your room before you collapse.

---

For the next week, every waking moment is spent swinging your sword at the man who'd stepped forward that first day, and having him bat aside your swings every time. But the margin shrinks every day, until he actually starts using footwork to avoid your strikes instead of standing there immobile. In the middle of each day, you follow the Greatswords back into the barracks and join them for lunch, fresh bread and hearty shanks of meat and stew so thick the spoon stands up in it. At the side of your teacher, your presence is accepted, and the topic at each meal is the same: combat. For all of living memory, you gather from their anecdotes, these Greatswords had been effectively banished from Wurtbad, stationed out of Naubonum and ordered to send constant raids into the depth of 'Eastern Stirland'. And they obeyed, taking heavy casualties in the process but honing the survivors into veterans of a hundred skirmishes against everything Sylvania could throw at them.

And then the last of the Haupt-Anderssens had died, and the Greatswords had been recalled to Altdorf, had their ranks refilled, and had been assigned to their new Elector Count: Abelhelm Van Hal. And they couldn't be happier.

And then lunch ends, and it's back into the training yard. Your teacher starts fighting back, tapping and prodding you just hard enough to bruise, and though it hurts the main effect is on your temper. You swear that you're going to land a blow on him, whatever it takes, and finally you think you see an opening and lunge forward, shouting as you deliver an overhand swing, only to realize far too late that you overshot hugely as your fist impacts with his head, crushing your knuckles between it and the hilt of your sword. The crack you send through the courtyard is very different to the usual wood-on-wood.

For a horrifying second you think it was his head that you cracked, then agony shoots through your hand.

"Ow," he says mildly, rubbing his brow. You hop up and down in pain, shouting profanities in Lingua Praestantia, the language of magic, causing eddies to form in the ambient magic in the courtyard. You bite back a scream as the man gently but firmly grasps your hand, probing at the knuckles with a calloused finger. "Next time, think before you swing," he comments. "Go see Brother Heinz. It won't be the first training accident he's patched up."

---

When you get to the chapel, the Chaplain is engaged in murmured conversation with one of the kitchen assistants, so you wait as patiently as you can with agony throbbing through your fingers. Finally he says a benediction over her head, then looks over to you, his eyebrows raising. "Journeywoman," he greets you neutrally. "Here to give thanks to Sigmar?"

"Not as such," you respond, holding up your hand, which is noticeably red and swollen. He moves forward and grasps your hand, causing another wave of pain to wash through you, and examines it carefully.

"Training?" he asks, a note of disbelief in his voice.

"With the Greatswords," you shoot back, annoyed both at the pain and his disbelief.

He looks a moment longer, then nods. "Good. By its very nature, magic cannot be trusted. If you will not put your faith in Sigmar, put it in steel." You narrow your eyes, annoyed that he'd have the audacity to lecture you on a topic you know better than he ever will, but then he begins to murmur a prayer to the founder of the Empire and you can feel power flow out of his hand and into yours, your knuckles audibly grinding as they slide back into place. He nods to himself. "There will be stiffness and pain for several weeks. Sigmar be with you."

You flex your hand and mutter thanks as you leave the Chapel.

---

"What's your name, anyway?" Your teacher raises an eyebrow as he deflects your latest blow. "We've been training together for almost a fortnight and it just occurred to me that you never told me your name."

He smiles and baps you on the head with his sword. "I thought it was your job to know things like that," he replies mildly, and then smiles at the scowl you shoot him. "Sir Markus von Pfaffbach, Champion of Stirland."

Oh.

[DO THE GREATSWORDS GIVE IT THEIR ALL?: Roll, Diplomacy, 94+9=103. Your adopted family grows.]
[HOW WELL DO YOU TAKE TO THE GREATSWORD? Roll, Martial, 85+7=92. Swords are fun!]
[HOW WELL DO THE LESSONS GO?: Roll, Martial, 18+7=25. Ow.]
[HEALING ROLL: Breakpoints 20/60, Piety, 42+??=50-60?. No long-term damage, but minus to combat rolls at the Barrow.]

---

"Oh?" Van Hal says distractedly, doing something finicky and complicated with his rifle, apparently unbothered by the swaying gait of his horse. "While you've been doing a great job, my impression is that you've been mostly 'spy' and not much 'master'. What do you need a regular budget for?"

"For changing that," you reply easily. "My priority so far has been finding these documents, but with that hopefully drawing to a close-" you cross your fingers and hope Ranald doesn't take that as an invitation to prove you wrong, "-I'll need to be drawing in information from many more sources. Things like watching the Stirlandian League, keeping tabs of Leicheberg in von Stolpe's absence, watching the whole Flensburg business," you and Van Hal wince in unison at the mention, "and, of course, watching 'Eastern Stirland' - all of these will require many more sets of eyes and ears than merely my own. I can only be in one place at once."

"That does make sense," he muses, grunting in satisfaction as something in the mechanism of his rifle goes click. "I'll have a word with Wilhelmina when we get back."

Smothering a grin, you thank him politely. And then conversation grinds to a halt, as one of the scouts riding ahead calls back that the Mound has been sighted.

[CONVINCING VAN HAL YOU NEED A BUDGET: Roll, Intrigue, 88+12=100. Won him over completely.]
[EXPENSES VS PAYROLL: Roll, 39. Slightly leaning towards discretionary income.]

One Elector Count, Orc Hewer gleaming in his grip. One Warrior Priest in plated armour, his faith as solid as the hammer in his hands. One Priest of Morr, pale and nervous, but resolute. Fifty Greatswords, the greatest warriors Stirland has to offer honed in battle against the undead. Three hundred crossbowmen, encircling the Mound and ready to riddle anything that moves with bolts.

And one Shadow Mage, thoroughly out of her depth.

You stand at Van Hal's side, your knuckles white around the grip of the flamberge Markus gifted you, ignoring the stabs of pain from your still-healing bones. Ulgu twists playfully in your grip from where you had folded it into the steel and the morning mist swirls around you protectively, ready to respond to your slightest thought. And the Mound just sits there, looking for all the world like a regular hill in the middle of a clearing.

Unless you can see the Winds of Magic, that is. To you, the dull purple of Death Magic defies gravity to pool around the Mound, seeping into the earth. Whether something in there is absorbing Shyish or the site is just a natural sink of the magic of death, you can't tell, but neither is a particularly attractive option.

"Well?" Van Hal asks softly, his eyes locked on the entrance to the Mound.

You swallow. "Shyish is thick here, but I can't see any necromantic energies. Not from the outside, anyway."

"The dead are probably still present, then," Van Hal notes.

"They could be undisturbed," the Morrite says, barely speaking above a whisper.

"If they are, you can say the Rites over them and send them to their rest," Brother Kasmir states, looking up from the prayer he was saying over his hammer. "But if nothing else, this site of treason against the Empire - I doubt even those that predate the coming of Sigmar could sleep through that."

"We'll see soon enough," Van Hal states, a note of excitement entering his voice. "Markus!"

"Your Grace?" he asks, stepping forward from the ranks of the Greatswords. Though standing at attention, he does give you a hint of a smile as you look over at him.

"Take up position near the entrance. Depending what we find in there, we might be calling you in to support us in combat or drawing an enemy out into the crossfire. Be ready for either contingency."

"Yes, Your Grace."

A smile on his lips, Van Hal leads the way into the darkness, and you take a deep breath and follow.

---

Within a handful of paces, the sunlight is gone and the only light is from the torches carried by Kasmir and the Morrite. They seem to barely cast any light at all, and what there is only serves to deepen the darkness instead of illuminating it. Everywhere you look, the sickly purple of Shyish shrinks from the light, flowing around the edges of the wall to pool once more in your wake. It seems to stain everything purple - the walls, the air, even the tunnel ahead of you looks almost spiderwebbed with-

The cry comes to your throat a moment too late, as Van Hal steps into a web of Shyish criss-crossing the passage, and unseen to anybody but you, it snaps into a thousand pieces and sends a pulse of deathly energy to somewhere.

"Stop," you cry, too late, far too late. "You just triggered..." You pause, recognition flashing through you. "A magical alarm. Lesser magic, formed of Shyish. Whoever cast it now knows that we crossed it."

The four of you stand frozen, your ears straining for any sound, every crackle of the flames of the torches sounding deafening in your ears. You stand there for what felt like hours, but must have been only minutes.

"How old could it have been," Van Hal asks, breaking the silence.

You see what he could be asking straight away. "Here? It was formed of Shyish and the air here is thick with it. If untriggered, it could last forever."

He relaxes a little. "From the original builders?"

"It's possible."

He thinks for a moment. "Alright. Be on guard, but we advance."

---

When you finally emerge into the main chamber, the sight takes your breath away. Sitting on a throne in the center is the skeleton of what must have once been a mighty warlord, covered in crude armour and a helm sitting in his lap, his jaw hanging open as empty sockets stared eternally at nothing. All around him lay skeletons of either his dispatched enemies or his loyal warriors, lying in haphazard piles. Each wall was lined with swords, axes, maces and spears, all so ravaged by time that those nearest to the entrance started to flake away into nothing as the air moved for the first time in what must have been millennia.

But it can't have been the first time, because piled in front of the throne like a bizarre offering was a truly astounding amount of ledgers.

The four of you advance carefully, ready at any second to response to the slightest stirring of the skeletons in the chamber. But none move. The Morrite approaches the closest cautiously and leans over to touch it, whispering something under his breath. Then he relaxes. "They are dead," he says. "Truly dead."

"Anticlimactic," Van Hal notes, sounding almost disappointed. "But it looks like we've found what we were looking for."

---

You feel uneasy. You're not sure why, everything seemed to be going perfectly well. Three cartloads of tomes had set off for Wurtbad and the Mound was emptied of corpses, most of which had received the Rites of Morr and were awaiting their turn on the pyre that was being built. Everything was going fine. But sudden disquiet had washed over you like a wave, so strong you felt almost queasy.

Wait.

You did feel queasy.

You look around wildly, finally noticing the quivering of the Winds, but you can't see anything that could be causing it. But you trust your instincts, and shout a warning. "To arms," you cry, as the crossbowmen stare at you in confusion and the Greatswords draw their arms, looking around wildly. Van Hal and Brother Kasmir look up from their conversation, their hands flying to the hilts of their weapons. "Something's coming!"

There's a moment of silence just long enough for you to wonder if you were mistaken, then you spot it - a sickening beam of spiralling brown and purple shooting through the trees and into the Mound, and in a moment of unspeakable horror you feel Dhar pulse through your soul as it radiates out.

Those who can't see the Winds of Magic know something terrible has happen when the Morrite screams in horror. The corpse he had been tending to had struck out with claws wreathed in ethereal fire, plunging into his stomach, gripping, and pulling. Near him, all lined up where they had been placed in rows to await his blessing, the dead pulled themselves to their feet, green lights burning in their eye sockets as they look around and then throw themselves at the nearest targets. Only a handful of them remained down, as Morr refused to surrender whatever grip he now held on their souls.

The Greatswords were scattered throughout the clearing, occupied as they were with hauling books and bodies. They had barely a handful of seconds to ready themselves for combat. But though some fell as skeletal claws tore through steel, many had time enough to defend themselves and everywhere you look skeletal claws clashed against steel as the Greatswords held back their attackers. Moments later the first of the crossbows are fired as the crossbowmen recover from the shock and start readying their weapons, and skeletons screech as bolts fly through their ribcages, disrupting the lattice of tainted magic holding their cursed forms together. For a moment the sudden battle is locked in equilibrium, the swords and bolts holding the skeletons at bay from their terrible assault.

But then you, Van Hal, and Brother Kasmir strike the undead like the fist of a vengeful God.

Your body reacting with instincts you've only begun to develop, you swing with all your might past the claws of the skeletons and into what little body they have. The Ulgu still contained within your blade parts the Dhar like a knife through flesh, and the skeletons are struck to the ground as the fell magics animating them are disrupted, evaporating into the air. To your left, Brother Kasmir's hammer does an equally laudable job of shattering the skeletons themselves, sending fragments of bone flying through the air like shrapnel with every strike. And on your right Van Hal's Runefang flashes, the ancient Dwarven magic contained within snuffing out the necromantic energies like a tidal wave snuffs out a candle. In your wake skeletons lie scattered on the ground, and the Greatswords freed up follow in your path, striking down the skeletons you miss.

In a handful of glorious minutes, each and every skeleton is struck down and you drive the tainted magic from the clearing. Silence suddenly descends as the skull of the last is crushed underfoot, and everyone present looks to one another with manic grins on their faces.

"STIRLAND!" cries Van Hal, and every voice - including your own - joins him.

[MAGE SIGHT: Breakpoints 30/70, Learning, 44+13=57. Death looms.]
[HOW BAD IS IT: Roll, 16. Death looms.]
[TRIPWIRE: Req 40, Learning, 19+13=32. Death pounces.]
[IDENTIFY IT: Req 40, Learning, 70+13=83.]
[INCOMING: Breakpoint 40/60, Learning, 35+13=48. You saw what direction it came in.]
[MORRITE REACTION: Req 50, Martial, 31+12=43. Brutal.]
[HOW SUCCESSFUL WERE HIS RITES? Roll, 12+16=28. Um.]
[GREATSWORDS: Req 40, 27+15=42.]
[CROSSBOWMEN: Req 60, 72+8=80.]
[VAN HAL: Req 40, 89+18=107.]
[BROTHER KASMIR: Req 40, 92+14=106.]
[YOU: Req 40, Martial, 87+7-10=84.]

---

"Why did it take so long?" Van Hal asks later, his Runefang still in hand as he watches the last of the corpses thrown onto a bonfire. "We stepped foot in that Mound over an hour before anything happened. If all of those things leapt up as we entered the central chamber they could have overwhelmed us. Why wait?"

You stared at the clearing, brooding over that very same question. The evidence of its passing is long gone, but you can still remember the direction the beam of corrupted magic came from. "Do you have a compass?"

He looks at you askance at that, but produces one from a pouch and hands it to you, and you draw a mental line from where the beam emerged from the trees and the centre of the mound, where it struck. "East-south-east," you mutter. "Delay of just over an hour... propagation speed of magic through air, about 750 miles per hour. That's... about 900 miles. 450 each way. 450 miles east-south-east of Wurtbad..."

You don't have to consult a map to know what that's pointing at, and from the alarmed look Van Hal is giving you, he doesn't either.

Drakenhof.

[WHY?: Req 40, Learning, 40+13=53]

---

After your first real taste of combat, everything seems blurred, almost unreal. Your trip back to Wurtbad seems to pass in moments, and next thing you know you have your written authorisation from Van Hal and you're once more conjuring a horse to take you to Leicheburg. You emerge from the muted funk somewhere in the Moot, as you arrive at the inn you patronized last time you were in the neighbourhood, and are halfway through dinner before you notice that you aren't a throbbing mass of pain from the waist down.

The next morning as you set off, you pay attention to what's going on. The horse underneath you is as solid as ever, but the magic that sustains it, instead of conforming directly to the shape of a horse, is enshrouding your lower form the way your shadow armour does. You're not so much riding a horse as you are wearing a horse from the waist down.

...it's actually kind of disturbing when you put it like that. But you can't deny the effectiveness. You barely feel the horse's gait beneath you as it eats up the miles, effortlessly sustaining for hours a pace that would exhaust a regular horse in minutes. By afternoon of the second day, you have arrived at your destination - not quite Leicheburg, not yet. Instead, you stand at Swartzhafen - specifically, the barracks just inside the southern gate.

Your letter of authority gets you a meeting with the Major in charge of the local forces, and you're able to get him to confirm his allegiances - to the Emperor, to the Elector Count of Stirland, and to the Count of Leicheburg in that order. He gets enough of the gist of what you're hinting at that he doesn't ask for more, instead hand-picking a team of light cavalry and roadwardens for you with the assurance that they share his loyalties. Then he wishes you good luck, smiles, and winks.

You're so convinced that you don't even remove his memories of you with Mindhole. Instead, you note his name and position and tell him you might be in touch with such a patriot in the future. And just like that, you've recruited your first informant.

[ONCE MORE TO LEICHEBURG: Roll, Martial, 99+7=106. Riding trait acquired.]
[ENLISTING AID: Req 50, Diplomacy, 88+9=97. Everyone loves Mathilde.]

You're thoroughly disgruntled that it took you all day to get the mere fifty miles down the road to Leicheburg. You spend every minute fighting down the urge to urge your steed into a gallop and leave the riders you've recruited in your wake. But you swallow the feeling down time and time again, and by evening you've finally arrived and ready to act.

As you reach the Leicheburg Castle again, you circle it warily, trying to find an unguarded approach. To your disgust, there are none. Every door and gate is watched over by alert guards, even the washerwoman's entrance that leads down to the the Black Run River. Even the shift changes overlap.

But as you watch the side entrance, you note that while the guards certainly are alert to anyone that would approach them, they barely give the washerwomen a second glance as they carry clothing back and forth. So you approach one on her own down by the river and offer her a year's wage to hand over her clothes and the basket of washing and go find another job, and she's so happy to accept she practically skips away in her shift. You quickly change into the woman's drab and scratchy frock and try to figure out a way to smuggle your flamberge in before reluctantly stashing it under a bush with your cloak.

Sure enough, the guard barely glances at you as you walk straight past him and into the castle. Navigating was trickier, before you stumbled across a winning strategy:

"The Count's chambers are that way, right?"

"No, it's down- wait, who are you?"

Mindhole

"The Count's chambers are that way, right?"

"Yes, they are."

"Thank you."

Mindhole

In this way you make your approach, getting closer with every discombobulated servant you leave in your wake. You even encounter someone carrying a dish who, when you ask about the quarters, asks you to take the Count's evening snack to him. You take a peek under the cover and find some sort of tiny roasted bird. No accounting for taste, you suppose.

When you finally get to the quarters, the guard on the door sees only the tray of food before unlocking it and letting you in. The Count, too, barely looks up from his desk, not even acknowledging you before looking back to the papers on his desk. You walk up to him, place the plate down, and summon up Ulgu to you, drawing energy from the flickering of the lamps. Then you project it out the window as forcefully as you can, and in the distance a shriek of terrifying beauty sounds.

"By Sigmar, is that a griffon?!" you ask, feigned wonder in your voice, and the Count's head snaps around to the window. Unable to see anything - because there's nothing to see, of course - he jumps up, strides to the balcony door, throws it open and steps out.

His cry of terror as you push him over the edge is drowned out by a second illusory cry, which is cut short as the Count lands right in the middle of the full gong farmer's cart that you had the riders park right underneath the balcony.

You make your way back out of the castle again, casually removing the door guard's memories of you as you do so.

[CONSIDERING APPROACH - STEALTH: Roll, Intrigue, 10+12=22. Nope.]
[CONSIDERING APPROACH - DISGUISE: Roll, Intrigue, 63+12=75. That could work.]
[GETTING IN: Req 30, Intrigue, 45+12=57. Smooth as butter.]
[GETTING AROUND: Req 40, Intrigue, 99+12=111. No tracks and a perfect excuse to enter.]
[EXIT STRATEGY: Roll, Intrigue, 87+12=99. Very cunning plan.]
[EXECUTION OF EXIT STRATEGY: Breakpoints 50/80, Intrigue, 68+12=80, RANALD'S GIFT ACTIVATES, +20=100! Literally no traces.]
[LANDING: Roll, 78. Soft landing.]

---

Maksim von Stolpe is a great deal easier.

"Did you hear about the party at Wurtbad last year?"

"I heard wonderful things about it! It's just a shame that I wasn't able to attend."

"My good friend Anton said it was a shame too, and he's extended you an invitation to another party this year. Very exclusive, very few people have heard about it. But it will be soon, so you'll have to leave straight away."

You're more than happy to loan him some bodyguards to get there. No need for him to alert his own staff.

[INVITE BY SUBTERFUGE: Req 50, Diplomacy, 47+9=56. Cordially invited.]

The return trip is long and dull, but straightforward. Judicious application of bribes and Mindhole keep anyone from paying too much attention to the prisoner being transported along the road to Wurtbad.

---

When you get back to Wurtbad, you deliver the two von Stolpes to the Castle - one to the dungeons, one to a guest room - and set off to enjoy some well-earned time off, albeit with regular trips back to the castle to brush up on your greatsword training. You've acquired a truly stupendous base of operations, and you'll be damned if anyone's going to take it from you, so you're going to do your best to make sure that nobody's going to get in and, if anyone tries, you're going to know about it.

The Innkeeper is utterly delighted to accept your offer of friendship. The benefits to her are obvious: complete immunity from liquor excises and a friend with a great deal of power to back her up should any members of the local underworld try to demand protection money. In exchange, she has even more reason to keep you feeling secure in your new dwellings, promising to pass on any information she hears as well as letting you know immediately if anyone seems to be sniffing around. But the initiative she shows in going above and beyond to secure the alliance that dropped into her lap is impressive.

You're securing the door of the shack, reinforcing the hinges and placing a high-quality lock imported from Nuln on it, when she approaches you with a suggestion. She knows most of the neighbours that back onto the alley that your Palace-Shrine is built under, and has approached them all about whether they'd be willing to sacrifice their back doors - for a reasonable price, of course. And each of them agreed. All you had to do was distribute a bit of gold and nobody would object to you boarding up every single door that fronts onto the alley - hell, they'd help do it.

So weeks pass in a blur of hammering as door after door is nailed shut, and to top it off you enlist the help of your former neighbours in bricking shut the mouth of the alley and installing a door. At the end of a couple of months, one building appears to connect directly to the next where the mouth of an alleyway used to be, and only by opening the door would one notice that on the other side is not a building, but a sealed-off alleyway, accessible only by that door or the back door of the inn. And you possess the only keys for both.

With the alley sealed off to all human traffic but yourself, there seems to be more cats than ever hanging about. You say a prayer of thanks to Ranald for your wonderful hidden home as you scratch one behind the ears.

[Befriending the Innkeeper: Roll, 44. No additional effects.]
[Barricades: Roll, 84. Entire alleyway secured.]

---

Van Hal, you're sure, is never going to stop wearing his Witch Hunter's leathers now.

He sits brooding at the head of the table, sorting through paper handed to him without registering any of it. Worried glances go back and forth among the councillors as they pick up on his mood. You share a look with Brother Kasmir, each of you suspecting the source of Van Hal's brooding.

You're soon proven wrong.

Rushing in where saints fear to tread, Professor de Verezzo comes to his feet. "With the injection of capital generously provided by Frau Hochschild, recruitment has accelerated to the point that I expect the Army of Stirland will be at full strength by the end of the year," he drones, looking pleased with himself.

"That is good news," Van Hal says neutrally. Then he draws a pistol and shoots Professor de Verezzo through the forehead.

Everyone sits stock-still as Van Hal places the pistol on the table in front of him, the ringing in your ears eventually fading into the horrified silence you all share. Your mind whirrs, trying to make sense of this. The guards must have been forewarned, you realize, or otherwise they'd be rushing in here. Was this your doing? Was this because you tipped Van Hal off about the Professor's previous crimes? You realize you haven't seen Van Hal around much since you returned from Leicheburg. Was that what he was doing? Seeking evidence to justify this execution?

"I am a man of the world," he eventually says, a touch of sorrow in his voice. "I accept that recompense comes in many forms. I know that no man but Sigmar is perfect. I understand that each of you have loyalties to yourself, to your families, to your gods.

"But if any of you deliberately sabotage the defence of Stirland for your own personal gain, you can expect the same."

He stands, leaving the smoking pistol on the table. "We'll reconvene in the Great Hall in an hour. Brother Kasmir, please see to the remains of this traitor."

---

SKILL ACQUIRED: Fitness (Basic)
SKILL ACQUIRED: Greatsword (Basic)
TRAIT ACQUIRED: Shadowrider
TRAIT ACQUIRED: Blooded
DISCRETIONARY BUDGET ACQUIRED: 150 gold/turn, beginning this turn.
PAYROLL ACQUIRED: Informants and Agents do not require discretionary budget to hire.
RELATIONSHIP IMPROVED: Abelhelm Van Hal.
RELATIONSHIP IMPROVED: Brother Kasmir.
RELATIONSHIP ACQUIRED: Sir Markus von Pfaffbach, Champion of Stirland.
INFORMANT ACQUIRED: Commander of Swartzhafen.
INFORMANT ACQUIRED: Innkeeper next door to your Palace-Shrine.

Discretionary Income: +150g
Embezzlement: -75g
Leicheburg trip: -10g
Return trip: -20g
Leicheburg bribery: -10g
---
Net: +45g

Personal Income: +50g
Embezzlement: +75g
Tithe: -5g
Student Loans: -35g
Palace-Shrine reinforcements: -20g
'Buying up' the alley: -40g
---
Net: +25g

Explanation for skills: Basic, Intermediate, Advanced, then they turn into a trait. Crits jump you up the ranking quickly and can give you superior versions of the traits. Using specialized equipment without a skill will cause a malus.

---

You have a report to give. Hopefully it goes better than the Professor's.

[] Write in your report
[] Write in a one-on-one report (optional)

Suggest possible orders for the next turn (new ones up top, old ones below):

[] Drakenhof. You almost hesitate to suggest it, but... surely this must be investigated.

[] The disappearance of your predecessor is very concerning, especially since he's actively trying to sabotage the hunt for him. He must be found, and I've got a lead: Julbach.
[] The Stirlandian League is a cancer eating at Stirland's economy, and it must be destroyed.
[] The Stirlandian League is a gold mine of information, and it must be yours.
[] There is a risk of enemy agents infiltrating the castle staff - they must be watched.
[] The castle staff can be a great source of information and first line of defence - they should report to you.
[] Seriously what is up with the East Wing.
[] I've got the budget for a proper network of informants, now it just needs building.
[] If I had proper facilities, I could do better work. Please fund me renovating my secret underground palace.
[] Other (write in)

Turn 4 - 2471.5

Winning vote: [*] Plan Conjectures -[*] Report: Stick to the facts. We very discreetly acquired Petr and Maksim von Stolpe, using the Count's authority to borrow troops. We looked at the burst of magic flooding into the mound, and calculated that it came from Drakenhof. -[*] Share some conjectures: The fact that the books were stolen at night by human shaped things that actually managed to traumatize horses by being nearby. As well as the powerful necromancer in drakenhof who put the alarm trap and then raised the dead in the mound suggests that the books were actually stolen by vampires, and that there is a pretty powerful necromancer among the vampires. The fact the books were kept rather than destroyed suggests they intended to use them, probably after installing their own patsy as a stirland elector count. The series of unfortunate deaths of Van Hal's predecessors and the connection between them and the noble we captured is further cementing the idea that we have a vampire making moves on stirland via subterfuge instead of an overt and open invasion. We should probably take steps against assassination attempts by vampires, and hopefully whatever info our guest at the dungeon provide will be a useful lead in the investigation. -[*] Possible orders: --[*] The disappearance of yourpredecessor is very concerning, especially since he's actively trying to sabotage the hunt for him. He must be found, and I've got a lead: Julbach. ---[*] Capture of predecessor can lead to taking over the Stirlandian league for purpose of spying ---[*] Could he be related to the vampire plots? if so then finding him is a priority. --[*] The Stirlandian League is a cancer eating at Stirland's economy, and it can be destroyed now that we have the ledgers. ---[*] The former spymaster has been acting against us. He probably still controls his spies in the league. Destroying it now would deprive of him of valuable resources, but may also destroy possible leads on his location --[*] I've got the budget for a proper network of informants, now it just needs building. --[*] Variant Writein: Drakenhof. This vampire plot to subtly take over stirland is concerning. We know there are vampires in sylvania, but who and where? And what exactly have they done in stirland so far? I could try to examine other stirland nobles for possible vampire connections, although this seems a bit of a shot in the dark. Alternatively, follow up any leads acquired from the interrogation of Stolpe. [*] [Execution] Surprised and curious. While you had raised the issue of embezzlement and divided loyalties, the Count had also noted and accepted both. You want to know what did he actually do to cross the line, from the implications, he had sabotaged the army in some way for an outside party. Both for your own interests and for national interests, you want to know what the Count found. --- The atmosphere at the reconvened meeting is subdued. The Great Hall echoes and amplifies the smallest sound, very different to the cozy privacy of the conference room - the conference room where several unlucky servants were scrubbing blood out of the floorboards. Blood that is still visible on Brother Kasmir's armour, as he had hauled the Professor's body out of the room and into the chapel to await the attentions of a Morrite priest. Van Hal is staring into the flickering fire, lost in thought, fingers tapping out an unconscious tune on the table. Nobody seems to want to interrupt him. But it is an hour later, and the meeting is to be reconvened, so... You clear your throat, and six heads swivel to you. "As you know, Petr and Maksim von Stolpe are now guests here at the castle. Nobody at Leicheberg Castle saw my face..." Well, nobody has memories of seeing your face, which is close enough, and that sort of thing tends to disturb non-wizards. "And the riders I borrowed from Swartzhafen transported the two of them here without drawing attention." "Well done. I will be seeing to the von Stolpes," Van Hal says. "I do have some conjecture regarding the events at the Mound," you begin, and pause, giving Van Hal the opportunity to interrupt if he saw fit. He didn't, so you continue. "The Carter that transported the books said that they were loaded up by humanoid figures who badly spooked his horse, and then the books were transported to a secure location, guarded by death magic, and then defended by necromancy. And as I felt the pulse of Dhar that raised the skeletons coming, I was able to see the direction it came from. That plus the travel time pointed to a specific location - Castle Drakenhof." The expressions on the faces of everyone present are grim at that, but not surprised. "Bloody Drakenhof," Anton mutters. Everyone nods in agreement. "Vampires?" asks Brother Kasmir, his eyes narrowed. "I believe so," you confirm. An atmosphere of grim resolution settles upon the six of you - even upon Herr Schultz, which surprises you. Anton is a native Stirlander and the others were veterans in fighting the forces of darkness, but you didn't expect the Talabeclander architect to take the news in stride. "If they had destroyed those books it would have undermined the unity of Stirland and the legitimacy of our authority. Instead, they sought to secure them. Add in the apparent complicity of von Stolpe, and possibly even the deaths of the Haupt-Anderssens..." "Subversion," Van Hal growls. "I believe so." He exhales, and stares at you thoughtfully. He's got the document you prepared for him in his hand, but he apparently doesn't need to look down at it to remember the options you placed upon it. "Stirland," he says at last, "has had nine Elector Counts in the past forty years. I do not intend for there to be a tenth before the close of the century. Build your network. I don't want a single bloodsucker stepping foot in Wurtbad without a volley of crossbow bolts being there to meet it." He shuffles the papers, then looks over to Anton. "How did you find the Knights of Morr?" "I went to Siegfriedhof and they were right there," he replies, then smiles at the look Van Hal gave him. "My impressions of the Knight-Commander are in the report. They're open to working with the secular military, but they've given some conditions - the majority of them will remain posted defending the Gardens of Morr, and they want all the dead given the Rites of Morr after battles, not just our own." "That's..." Van Hal pauses, then looks over to Brother Kasmir. "Do the Knights themselves count as Priests?" "They're a monastical order, so I believe so." "If the Knights can give the Rites, I don't see a problem with it. I'll write to the Knight-Commander, we should be able to hammer out the details. Okay, apart from that, for the next few months you'll be with me. Assuming I find the man acceptable, we'll work out how to insert Maksim as the new Count von Stolpe without causing too many waves. Wilhelmina, how's the treasury?" "Drained," she replies. "But it should start recovering once I get these ledgers sorted out and we start making everyone pay what they should." "How long?" "It'll take weeks just to get them back in chronological order," she says with a scowl. "But I should be able to start sending tax collectors after the remiss within a couple of months." "Thank Sigmar," he notes, and Brother Kasmir nods in agreement and makes the Sign of the Comet. "So Schultz, you'll get your cannon soon. In the meantime, build a castle granary - with any luck we'll soon have taxes in kind flowing in, and I want somewhere under my control to store them." "Tower or cellar?" he asks. Van Hal considers. "Cellar," he finally decides. "I'd rather run the risk of vermin than have it vulnerable to siege weapons. Kasmir, how'd the clean-up go?" "The mound will be tainted for generations to come," he notes with a frown, "but at the very least there are no restless dead remaining there. I also recovered a number of weapons that seem immune to the ravages of time that so affected everything else in there. I almost destroyed them, but while they are soaked in death they don't appear to be tainted." "Weber, if you get a chance, take a look at them - but your network takes priority. Kasmir, tend to your flock. Find out which God every soldier and servant within these walls answers to. If the goat has predilections towards proscribed cults I want to know about it. And write to Altdorf - the military of Stirland is in need of better spiritual guidance." The meeting breaks up, with your fellow councillors drifting away to go about their business, the shadow that had been over them mostly banished by the prospect of going out there and doing something. You move to do the same, then Van Hal shoots you a penetrating look. "Mathilde, a word?" --- Your mind races as you follow the Elector Count to his office. Your immediate fear is that you're about to meet the same fate as the Professor, but surely if that was the case you wouldn't have any warning, and he surely wouldn't be showing his back to you like this. Does he know about Ranald? Does he know about the Palace-Shrine? Does he know about the embezzlement? Does he know about the mysterious requests for information you know you haven't seen the last of? Does he know about the Asp? Does he know about- wait, is that all you have to worry about him knowing about? Have you forgotten anything? You're still stewing in your own concerns as he sits down at his desk and you tensely imitate him, then he demolishes your fears by pulling open a drawer and producing a pair of battered steel mugs and a bottle of something golden brown that reflects the lamplight beautifully. "Ostland brandy," he says, misinterpreting your confused look. "Terrible place, but they know their alcohol." He splashes a little into each of the mugs and slides one over the table to you. You'd experimented with alcohols in College, of course, but you doubted brandy would hold many similarities to the Brettonnian wines and the Reiklandian shandy that was often smuggled in. You sip cautiously at the drink, and manage to keep yourself from wincing as it burns all the way down your throat. "To your first kill," he notes, toasting you. "You mean-" "I wouldn't have investigated him if you had not tipped me off. The blood is on my hands, but on yours as well." He doesn't sound condemning. In fact, he sounds almost gentle, and a little proud. "What did he do?" you can't keep yourself from asking. "He was to fill fifteen thousand vacant positions. He filled four in every five of them, and filled the leadership of the new regiments with men chosen for their willingness to split the wages of the missing men." He scowls. "Not only would he have left the ranks of the Army of Stirland full of holes, but he invited corruption into some of its highest ranks." "Oh," you note. You try to picture a regiment missing a fifth of its men and led by the corrupt facing a horde of skeletons in battle. You wince. "It is a heavy weight to carry, to take the life of your fellow man," he says softly, watching your expression. "But we deal death to the corrupt to prevent the suffering of the innocent. Never forget that." --- You have six actions to spend. [ ] As Per Orders: Perform your current assignment. -[ ] The Wurtbad Watch already has their ear to the ground. Make their information flow to you. -[ ] Personally vet everyone that works in the castle, and replace everyone you're not sure of the loyalties of. -[ ] Wurtbad, like all major cities, is home to a number of guilds. Reach out to them and enforce your will. -[ ] Wurtbad, inevitably, has criminals. And you're a follower of Ranald. Maybe you could reach an understanding - they'd have access to a huge amount of information, though it would mean tacit approval of their activities. -[ ] There's a vacuum where a dozen trade guilds should be. Found one of your own, and let information and profits flow through you, and see what the Stirlandian League does about it. (warning: expensive, will need Van Hal or Wilhelmina to sign off on it) -[ ] You're from peasant stock yourself, so it shouldn't be too hard to make friends and contacts among the peasantry in the villages surrounding Wurtbad; Julbach, Biderhof and Tarshof. -[ ] Much of Western Stirland is under the de facto direct control of the Elector Count. Meet with each of the local leaders and make it clear that you're to be kept in the loop. [ ] Backtracking and Side Operations: -[ ] You haven't asked Anton about your predecessor - see if he knows anything useful. -[ ] The thing you stabbed in the face is still in the cells, and now several others that were found are keeping it company. Examine them, learn from them, see if you can identify them. -[ ] Van Hal is interrogating the Von Stolpes. Sitting in may be helpful to him, and educational to you. -[ ] A large number of Shyish-stained weapons were uncovered from the Barrow. Perhaps you should: --[ ] Examine them yourself and see if they're useful, or dangerous, or both. --[ ] Send them to the Amethyst Order for examination (does not take an action). --[ ] Allow the Morrites to examine them (does not take an action). --[ ] Just have them melted down and buried (does not take an action). [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with one of your fellow councillors, offering your help in their task and generally getting a feel for them (choose one). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: You've been given good reason to mistrust your fellow councillors. Perhaps you should see what they spent their time doing (choose one). [ ] Sucking Up To The Boss: Normally you'd just go about things and report in to the Elector Count when you've got something major to report. If you instead give him regular reports and updates, it may make him more willing to trust you, and allow you to better get to know him. Opening yourself up to oversight, criticism, and potential micromanagement is a heavy price to pay, though. [ ] Letters Home: You might be able to wring more information out of your Master, or you might just be able to get news, information and guidance in general from the Grey Order. [ ] Hang Out A Shingle: Spymasters don't advertise, but wizards sometimes do. Make an official announcement that there's a wizard in residence, and see who comes out of the woodwork. [ ] Now that you've got gold to throw around, you should stock up on spell components. They're not strictly necessary, but they do make things easier. (-personal gold) [ ] Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. -[ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills (choose one). -[ ] Tutoring: One of your fellow councillors may be willing to teach you in their chosen field (choose who). -[ ] Pretty Good Swords: You've struck up a friendship with the Champion of the Greatswords and have discovered a talent for wielding them. Continue to cultivate this. -[ ] Combat Training: You're virtually surrounded by armed warriors of various sorts. See if you can convince one to teach you (choose who). -[ ] Combat Training, In The Free Market: You haven't made many heavily armed friends yet, but gold is good for that. Go out and buy some training. (-personal gold) -[ ] You only really kept in practice with a handful of the petty and minor magics you were taught. Maybe you should brush up on the others. -[ ] You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. [ ] Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. -[ ] Diggy Diggy Hole: A wizard wielding a shovel is unnatural, but doing it yourself might be the only way to keep things secret. Clear out a new room of your Palace-Shrine by hand. -[ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Outsourced: Pay someone to do the digging, then Mindhole them on their way out. (no action required, -personal gold) -[ ] No Place Like Home: Move in furniture, set up a chimney, put in the effort to make sure that your new home actually feels like a home and not like sleeping in an underground mud cave. [ ]Research: -[ ] This is Stirland. Time to bone up on your knowledge of the Undead. -[ ] That damn Asp has still been quiet, but maybe it's just biding it's time. Finally admit it's existence to your contacts back in the College and see if they know anything that can help. -[ ] As a Journeywoman, the path to Magister is marked by mastering more than the two shadow spells you already know. Send to the Grey Order for the basics and work on figuring out one of the others. -[ ] As a Journeywoman, the path to mediocrity is marked by only learning spells created by others. Your relationship with Ulgu is between you and it. (create-a-spell, write in the effects) FINANCES: NO ACTION POINT EXPENDITURE. Personal Income: 50 gold/turn Discretionary Income: 150 gold/turn Informer Payroll unlocked Currently paying Grey College tithe (5 gold/turn) Currently paying Grey College student loans (35 gold/turn) Currently embezzling half of discretionary income [ ] Begin plumping the informer rolls (choose ratio of real:fake informers. Almost impossible to detect, but also very difficult to increase or decrease the amount quickly) [ ] Change tithe payment/loan payment/embezzlement (specify) - Voting will be in plan format, including finances. - I would like to reiterate once more that you can write in alternatives to any of the above activities. Most of the time, I write these on the spot based on what immediately occurs to me. It is very possible that you could think of better ideas. - Don't forget Ranald's Blessing! If I forget to remind you and you forget to add it in somewhere, you miss out on it. - This is a great example of the influence your reports have. Plan Reasonable and Plan Conjecture presented the same options to the Van Hal, but Plan Reasonable would have resulted in an order to go after either your predecessor or the Stirlandian League. Instead, by laying out what you think the plan of the enemy is and tying it into the fate of the Haupt-Anderssens, you've influenced him to focus on defence.

Turn 4 Results - 2471.5

[*] Plan Grassroots Improvement; Updated -[*] As Per Orders: Perform your current assignment. --[*] Wurtbad, inevitably, has criminals. And you're a follower of Ranald. Maybe you could reach an understanding - they'd have access to a huge amount of information, though it would mean tacit approval of their activities. ---[*] Ranald's Blessing --[*] You're from peasant stock yourself, so it shouldn't be too hard to make friends and contacts among the peasantry in the villages surrounding Wurtbad; Julbach, Biderhof and Tarshof. -[*] Backtracking and Side Operations: --[*] Van Hal is interrogating the Von Stolpes. Sitting in may be helpful to him, and educational to you. --[*] A large number of Shyish-stained weapons were uncovered from the Barrow. Perhaps you should: ---[*] Keep them in a lead-lined steel box, fastened to the floor, inside the treasury. -[*] Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. --[*] Pretty Good Swords: You've struck up a friendship with the Champion of the Greatswords and have discovered a talent for wielding them. Continue to cultivate this. --[*] You only really kept in practice with a handful of the petty and minor magics you were taught. Maybe you should brush up on the others. -[*] Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. --[*] No Place Like Home: Move in furniture, set up a chimney, put in the effort to make sure that your new home actually feels like a home and not like sleeping in an underground mud cave. --[*] Diggy Diggy Hole, Outsourced: Pay someone to do the digging, then Mindhole them on their way out. (no action required, -personal gold) -[*] Change tithe payment/loan payment/embezzlement (specify) --[*] Embezzlement to 35 gold per turn. --- You swear viciously under your breath and suck on the wounded tip of your finger, throwing the knife in your other hand at the wall in frustration. You were a wizard, for crying out loud. Wizards don't whittle. They bend arcane energy to their will and force reality to obey their slightest whims! But after a moment, you settle back down and regard the small wooden cube carefully. And after a moment's thought, you press your bleeding finger against it, staining it with your blood. Not much of a sacrifice, but one caused by luck, within a place holy to Ranald. Hopefully that will tip the scales. You'll give Ranald the chance to guide you to the disciples of one of his other guises, before you seek them out yourself. --- You step out into the street and look around. Okay, two directions. On a four or higher, you go left. You roll a six - a good omen, you decide. And you go left. A three-way intersection. Okay, then. 1-2 is left, 3-4 is straight, 5-6 is right. You roll the die, and it lands exactly on a corner between four cobbles and sticks there, one corner pointing straight up at the sky. You stare. You circle the die, ignoring the looks you get from passers-by; two, four and six point skyward, while one, three and five point toward the ground. You glare at someone who's about to step on the die. He finds somewhere else to step. You breathe in. You breathe out. You resist the desire to curse Ranald. You pick up the die and examine it. Okay. All three directions, or none of the directions. Neither of those made sense. Maybe Ranald was saying he couldn't help you? Or... A thought occurs to you, and you hate it. Reluctantly, knowing what you'll find, you examine the surface of the road on the intersection, and find what you just knew you would - a manhole to the sewers of Wurtbad. You toy with the thought of finding a new god. Verena, you're sure, does not tell her followers to climb into sewers. But even as you wonder if Verena likes cats too, you know you're going to end up climbing down that manhole. But first, because you're not stupid, you're going back for a lantern. --- You stomp through the sewers in a huff, knowing that you're being played. Every time you get to an intersection, you peer down each into the darkness and down one of them you see the glint of a cat's eyes staring back at you. Then the cat blinks and is invisible once more, only for the eyes to be watching you once more when you get to the next fetid crossroads. You walk, and walk, and walk, until you're not sure if you're even under Wurtbad any more. Your path diverges from that of the foul, trickling sewer, taking you into an area of even older stonework, and you slow as you sight a glimmer of candlelight up ahead. You creep towards the light and see a glimpse of a tunnel opening into a much wider room, dimly lit by candles. "What're you playing at? I know you know to take the arcana out," you hear a voice ahead of you say, and you freeze. "What're you playing at? This deck doesn't even have arcana." "Then how come you just dealt me a Priest and a Magister?" Oh, come on. Ranald was supposed to be subtle, and yet- your temper boils over. "Because it's an omen, you goddamn idiots," you yell as you stomp into the room, sending the two men scrambling away from you in shock. They draw daggers; you glare at them until they sheath them again, sheepishly. One is thin and bald, with a neatly-trimmed beard and had been speaking in a Nordland accent; the other is older but more muscled, with greying hair, a moustache, and the unmistakable tones of an Averlander. The room itself is surprisingly dry, and is filled with battered wooden tables and chairs, though only the one had been occupied. Hanging against a wall, overseeing the room, is a rather well-made tapestry of a black cat appearing to carve an X into the background with its claws. "So, uh," the Averlander says. "Is that a greatsword on your back or are you just happy to see me?" the Nordlander interjects, then ducks a swipe from the Averlander. "Did a mutual friend send you?" asks the Averlander, and you scowl. He nods, taking that as confirmation. "Were you seeking anything in particular, or were you just inspired?" "I was seeking..." you hesitate, and then decide that Ranald's gotten you this far, you might as well trust him even if he is insufferable. "The criminal underworld of Wurtbad. I want to make them part of Stirland's intelligence apparatus." There's silence as the two of them mull that over, broken only by dripping water in the distance. "The Deceiver and the Night Prowler, hand in hand," the Nordlander muses. "And in exchange?" the Averlander asks. "My main priority right now is keeping the bloodsuckers out of Wurtbad, which is good for everyone. But I can offer all sorts of payment. Coin. Favours. Pardons. The occasional blind eye. I know you know who I am." "The robes were a giveaway." The two of them exchange glances, seeming to communicate something, then the Averlander nods. "I'm Heideck. He's Wolf. We may be able to work something out." --- And you do. The two, you learn, are former bandits who retired to live off their ill-gotten gains and repay their debt to Ranald by serving as His priests. The deal is an easy sell to their criminal flock - they like powerful friends, they don't like being eaten by vampires. It's a great arrangement all around. Everybody wins, except for those that Wurtbad's criminals prey upon, but, well... priorities. [SEEK RANALD'S FAVOUR: Req 80, Piety, 77+15=92. Ranald's Blessing activated! 92+20=112! Ranald adores you.] [HOW SAFE ARE THE SEWERS: Roll, 86. Serene, in a sewer-y kind of way.] [FIRST IMPRESSION: Roll, Diplomacy, 71+9=80. They're impressed.] --- When you prepared yourself to sit in on a Witch Hunter's interrogation, you were expecting horrific violence and terrible devices. What you got was, in its own way, far more shocking. Petr von Stolpe sat bolt upright, shackled to a chair that was itself bolted to the ground, glaring at Van Hal who stood in front of him. Apart from the chair, the room was completely unadorned. Van Hal returned the glare with a steady look of his own, seemingly content to stand there until the return of Sigmar. "If your soul is feeling burdened," Van Hal finally said, "I can fetch my personal chaplain for you." "Piss on your chaplain," von Stolpe replies immediately, spittle spraying across the room. "I have rights! To have me kidnapped by foul sorcery is an assault on Sigmar's Empire!" "Rights, yes," Van Hal agrees mildly. Then he strides forward and backhands von Stolpe across the face. "Rights and duties! On this very day proud and loyal men of Stirland die to hold back the tides of the unliving, protecting your petty fiefdom, and so precious little is asked in exchange for those lives. But you would not give even that. Tell me, Count, I beg of you to tell me that it was mere greed that drove you to withhold the taxes you owe to the Province of Stirland. Tell me you know nothing of those who allowed you to get away with it as long as you did. Tell me that, prove it to me, and I would see you walk free in a heartbeat. Because otherwise I will see you burn." Von Stolpe spits blood, and in the sudden silence you hear a tooth bounce against the stone floor. "Who are you to question me," he replies, his words quiet and slurred but the rage coming through clear despite it. "My ancestors have ruled Leicheburg for centuries. This land has seen three score Count von Stolpes, and I tell you: it will see three score more. You have sat upon a stolen throne for not two years! I have taken shits more glorious than your rule!" Silence falls once more. You hold your breath. "Bloodlines," Van Hal says, at last. "Lineage. Ancestry. That is what fuels you." He leans forward. "You may be right about one thing: Stirland may yet see three score more Count von Stolpes. In fact, those three score start now." "You wouldn't-" Von Stolpe is silenced by another vicious blow, rattling the chains securing him. "Weber," Van Hal says, and it takes you a moment to remember that that's you. "Go tell Maksim that his brother has suffered a terrible accident. The Count is dead, long live the Count." He looks at the form slumped in chains. "It's not even incorrect. Just premature." --- Later, much later, as you and Van Hal wash blood from your hands, he starts to tell you a story - a story every Stirlander knows, but not near as detailed as this. A story of a half-insane Count, seething with petty hatred, who sought any marriage for his daughter to keep his brother from inheriting. And when a man-shaped creature from blighted Nehekhara arrived at the Count's deathbed, he paid more attention to the nobility of the being's blood than the dark curse it bore. "There are a hundred types of rot that can eat at a man's soul," Van Hal says absently, lost in thought. "But one of the most insidious is the idea that the titles of your ancestors matter more than their deeds." In the end, you hear the name wheezed from the former count's lips that you knew you would hear. Von Carstein. [INTERROGATION TRAINING: Roll, Intrigue, 70+12=82. Like a duck to horrible water.] --- After that, you feel an urgent need to clear your head, so you make your way to the countryside. It occurs to you, as you ride into Biderhof, just how far you've come. Just over a decade ago, you were a peasant child running around in a homespun frock, collecting frogs and throwing mud at the boy next door, occasionally roped in to do some poorly-understood task out in the fields but mostly running around freely and getting underfoot. Only a fascination with storms hinted at what was to come. Then, one day, the poorly-carved wooden horse that had been mildly entertaining bored children for generations neighed, and your life was never the same again. If not for that, you almost certainly would have married some peasant boy (hopefully not the boy next door). You'd probably have had and lost children of your own. You'd say prayers to Shallya and fret over the weather and wonder how the harvest would be and yell at your kids to stop throwing mud at the boy next door. Or you might have been eaten by something that crept over the border from Sylvania. And now here you were, reconnecting with your bucolic roots not out of nostalgia, but because you were building a spy network. You wielded powers that normal people could not even see, let alone comprehend. You were somewhere between the second and fourth most powerful person in all of Stirland. It was enough to turn anyone's head. Your entrance into the village did not go unnoticed, with conversations dying away and stares following you as you pass. Perhaps it was the robes. Perhaps it was the enormous sword strapped to your back. Perhaps it was the horse made of shadow you rode atop. You had considered acting with a bit more subtlety, but in the end you decided that doing so would only delay the moment where they decided whether or not they would accept a wizard in their midst. It does not take long for someone to step from the gathering crowd and introduce themselves. --- The headman of Biderhof is an enormous man, only slightly less intimidating for missing an arm, and you talk business with him alongside a massive pile of the logs that Biderhof's economy is built upon. He is cautious in the extreme, and his long, hard looks at you and the time he takes to answer your questions grates at you. But you make a deliberate effort to remember the dialect of your youth, slowing your speech down to match his and giving each question he asks of you in return long consideration before replying. This seems to take him by surprise, and eventually he asks, with a note of disbelief as if surprised to find himself acknowledging you as a person rather than a wizard: from where do you hail? Kelham, you reply, and a gap-toothed grin splits the headman's face. On familiar ground now, he begins that most Stirlandian of habits: he tries to find the point where his family tree intersects yours. You're there for the rest of the afternoon, but at the end of it he's built a working theory that his second cousin is your grandfather's first wife's nephew and he couldn't be happier to help you. Stirlandians need to stick together. You spend a week getting to know the locals, cementing your face as a friend rather than a mistrusted outsider as well as detailing the kind of information that would be of use to you. In the end Biderhof is eating out of your hand, seeing you as an ally against the nebulous eternal foes of corrupt merchants and indifferent nobles. Unfortunately, you're not able to replicate your success at Tarshof or Julbach. Perhaps being agricultural rather than timber towns makes them even more insular and mistrusting, perhaps the headman of Biderhof was just unusually open-minded. But you do find that while they don't trust you, their prejudice doesn't quite extend to your coin, and you secure agreements from them to keep you informed of anything out of the ordinary, and your payroll expands. And then you head back to Biderhof to spend some more time with friendly peasants. [MAKING FRIENDS WITH BIDERHOF: Breakpoints 35/65, Diplomacy, 65+9=74. Adopted.] [MAKING FRIENDS WITH TARSHOF: Breakpoints 35/65, Diplomacy, 38+9=47. Reluctantly willing to accept your money.] [MAKING FRIENDS WITH JULBACH: Breakpoints 35/65, Diplomacy, 34+9=43. Likewise.] --- "I wasn't going to say anything," Markus says as his sword clacks against yours, not even slightly out of breath, "but I'm curious. Why is a wizard learning to use a greatsword?" You take a swing at him and he sidesteps as casually as if he was allowing someone to pass in the corridor. "The sword is the symbol of the Grey Order!" you exclaim, taking another swing that he bats away without trouble. "Not a greatsword, though," he says, and he sidesteps, tapping you on the back with his sword as your charge carries you past him. "You're probably the best fighters in Wurtbad," you explain like it's obvious. "And the weapon you're best at is a greatsword." "True," he grants, and parries another swing. "Also, they look really awesome." You circle warily, looking for an opening. "Also true." You spot an opening. You strike. It was a trap. Once more, the wooden sword taps you. But you're learning. [HOW GOES IT? Req 50, Martial, 49+9=58. No worse than minor bruising.] [EXERCISE? Req 50, Martial, 80+9=89. Side-benefits to waving all that sword around.] --- What feels like a lifetime ago, there was a young girl reading poorly-printed books under her blankets by the ethereal grey light of Ulgu. But when you reached Senior Apprentice status, there was no longer an enforced Lights Out, so you read by candlelight instead. So the knack for it rusted. But, you reflect as the light wobbles back and forth across the room, it didn't fade. Another spell once as natural as breathing resurfaces as you think back to those times, and before long you're happily flinging tiny balls of force against the wall with a series of thunks. And then there's that most useful of spells for growing teenagers looking for privacy in a crowded dormitory: Magic Lock, which was also made redundant by a Senior Apprentice perk when you got your own room. So much has changed since then, but the magic remains the same. Perhaps there's comfort to be taken from that. [BRUSHING UP: Roll, Learning, 73+13=86. Three petty, one lesser.] --- It is time - finally, truly time - to sleep in a comfortable bed for the first time since you left Altdorf. You enlist Anton's aid and you're soon in the workshop of the best carpenter in town, demanding he uproot all of his plans and start building an entire bedroom of furniture for you. Who are you? Good question. Perhaps you'd like to ask your good friend, the Heir of Blutdorf. Anton waves at the man. The man uproots all of his plans and starts building an entire bedroom of furniture for you. It's nice to have friends. Soon, the furniture starts arriving at the inn, and you recruit some of the regulars to help haul it down the trapdoor, and subsequently buy a drink for and Mindhole them. A dresser, to keep your stunning array of grey robes in! A desk complete with little cubby holes to store mail in! A stove to heat the room, with a chimney leading up to a crack in the floor of the shack! A rack to put your flamberge on! A bookshelf for, well, the books you'll probably eventually get! And, blessing of blessings, a bed! A soft, warm, comfortable bed! [SHOPPING FOR FURNITURE: Roll, Stewardship, 60+10. Bargains hunted.] --- You look around the room, a smile spreading across your face as the small but wiry man smiles in pride. For the past six months, this man has been in one of two places: in his room in the inn, or in your Palace-Shrine, excavating the next room along the corridor from the entrance. A hefty requirement, but one that the man was promised equally hefty compensation for. And now it is complete. Some small part of you was hoping for buried treasure, but what he has uncovered is no less valuable: space. You lead him up and out of the Palace-Shrine, and then through the inn onto the street he hasn't stepped foot in for half a year. "Thank you for your help," you say sincerely, handing him a pouch of coins. Mindhole. The man blinks. He looks around. He looks down at the pouch in his hand. He feels its weight, hears the clink of coin on coin. And he steps back into the inn. You smile to yourself as you watch him begin celebrating his mysterious wealth in the most time-honoured fashion: by drinking it. Yes, you could have just not given him the money. But you're not the sort of person that uses your magic to rob peasants. [ANY TREASURES? Req 80, 50.] --- Another six months passed, you think to yourself as you walk through the corridor towards the meeting room. Your resources have increased, but the stakes even more so. But you swear to Ranald and any other decent God that may be listening that you won't be found wanting. You enter the room and find Van Hal at the table going over some letters, but without the company of any of the others. You take the seat on his left and return the smile he gives you, and start to arrange your own papers. As you do so, something on one catches your eye, and you remember a question you meant to ask. "What's happening with the position of Marshal?" you ask, resisting the urge to glance over at where the bloodstain on the table still hasn't come out. "With regards to our friends in Altdorf, you mean?" You nod. "It's tricky. I executed his agent, but the agent he inserted was undermining the defence of Stirland. So I wrote to Altdorf, explaining the circumstances surrounding de Verezzo's retirement, and asking if they can recommend a replacement. They more carefully vet their agent, and I get someone who can do their job. Sometimes two wrongs can make a right." "So they're sending someone?" "Three someones," he replies, waving a sheet of paper. "I can pick whoever I think will be best for the future of Stirland. That's as close to apology as we're going to get, I feel." He looks over at you. "Gods know there's not enough hours in the day - I know you haven't been able to look at those tainted weapons from the Mound yet - but if you can claw the time from somewhere, head to Altdorf or wherever they come from and do a background check on them when they arrive." You open your mouth to agree, but you stop, knowing how many different directions you're being pulled in. You instead say that you'll see if you can find the time. He smiles and nods once more as the rest of the council start filing into the room. --- INFLUENCE ACQUIRED: Wurtbad Thieves Guild CHARACTERISTIC INCREASE: Piety +1 (from Ranald's guidance) TRAIT ACQUIRED: Interrogator RELATIONSHIP INCREASED: Van Hal 9/10 INFORMANT ACQUIRED: Headman of Biderhof INFORMANT ACQUIRED: Headman of Tarshof INFORMANT ACQUIRED: Headman of Julbach INFLUENCE ACQUIRED: Village of Biderhof SKILL ADVANCED: Greatsword (Intermediate) SKILL ADVANCED: Fitness (Intermediate) SPELL LEARNED: Magic Dart SPELL LEARNED: Glowing Light SPELL LEARNED: Marsh Lights SPELL LEARNED: Magic Lock PALACE-SHRINE UPGRADED: Spare room excavated! PALACE-SHRINE UPGRADED: It's now liveable! I'll no longer make rolls to see if you catch pneumonia every turn! Discretionary Income: +150g Embezzlement: -35g Excavations: -20g --- Net: +105g Personal Income: +50g Embezzlement: +35g Tithe: -5g Student Loans: -35g Furniture: -40g --- Net: +5g New mechanic unlocked: Influence. Influence is a binary thing - you either have it or you don't. If you have it, then you not only have the influenced party as allies, but you possess a level of influence that if you saw fit, and had the backing of the Elector Count, you could effectively take it over. This will give you side-options every turn to either upgrade or utilize whatever it is you have influence over. However, you can only spread yourself so thin. If you take over more than you can handle - and you're not experienced enough to know how much that is, but you know one would be safe - you'll either start losing actions or suffering maluses to rolls as you try to do too many things at once. It is possible to install a lieutenant to do your will in handling one of them, but you would be giving them an incredible amount of influence and power. Do you trust anyone with that? Can you? - I'm moving the councils' reports to the other half of the turn, since these are long enough already. - That goddamn snake is still failing it's rolls. --- [] Write in your report [] Write in a one-on-one report (optional) Possible orders for the next turn (new ones up top, old ones below): [] You've got a whole bunch of friends now, but you could always use more! [] You've got the town of Biderhof eating out of your hand. If you could think of a reason to justify it, maybe all the taxes from it's lumber sales could flow into your pocket instead. [] The Wurtbad Thieves Guild is basically a church group right now, instead of an actual organization. If you started throwing your weight around, that could change. Imagine the power you would wield if the criminal underworld reported to you. However, imagine how much more damage they'd do to Stirland if they were united... and you're not sure that Van Hal would be easy to convince. [] Drakenhof. You almost hesitate to suggest it, but... surely this must be investigated. [] The disappearance of your predecessor is very concerning, especially since he's actively trying to sabotage the hunt for him. He must be found, and you've got a lead: Julbach. [] The Stirlandian League is a cancer eating at Stirland's economy, and it must be destroyed. [] The Stirlandian League is a gold mine of information, and it must be yours. [] There is a risk of enemy agents infiltrating the castle staff - they must be watched. [] The castle staff can be a great source of information and first line of defence - they should report to you. [] Seriously what is up with the East Wing. [] If you had proper facilities, you could do better work. Would Van Hal fund renovations to a base he's never seen? [] Other (write in)

Turn 5 - 2472

[*] [Report] We've established a network of informants reporting to us from Wurtbad itself and in the surrounding villages. We should pick up on anyone setting up operations outside of town, unusual travelers, and people hiring on local help for illicit activities. That's not going to catch every vampire or spy coming into town but it should catch the overconfident, careless, or unlucky. [*] [Solo] We can write to the Grey College requesting intelligence on his new prospects, though actually travelling to Altdorf to investigate them would leave Stirland without a spymaster for quite a while. There's no guarantee they'll give us anything useful, but we'll be writing them anyway because there's a killer illusion-snake trying to murder us. He shouldn't need to worry about that, but if we're found dead with two suspicious puncture holes in the corpse, he should probably check whether it's vampire fangs or giant snake fangs before making assumptions. [*] [Options] Plan League or Network -[*] The disappearance of your predecessor is very concerning, especially since he's actively trying to sabotage the hunt for him. He must be found, and I've got a lead: Julbach. --[*] Capture of our predecessor could lead to taking over the Stirlandian League for purposes of spying, and give us knowledge of his past actions and whether he's involved with any other threats. -[*] The Stirlandian League is a cancer eating at Stirland's economy, and it can be destroyed now that we have the ledgers. --[*] The former spymaster has been acting against us. He probably still controls his spies in the league. Destroying it now would deprive of him of valuable resources, but may also destroy possible leads on his location -[*] I've got a whole bunch of friends now, but I could always use more! --[*] If the Count wants Wurtbad truly locked down, we can focus on expanding and deepening our local network. --[*] Our current network is focused around the Wurtbad area. If suspicious activity happens farther afield we don't have any sources in place to let us know. --[*] We know that at least one Von Carstein is active. If they focus on the nobility we'll want eyes on Stirland's prominent families. --- This meeting of the Council is a lot less subdued than the last one, though the seat that de Verezzo once filled remains unfilled. Without the Professor's droning to begin the round of reports, Anton jumps in to fill the silence before it has a chance to extend awkwardly. "As you're aware, your Grace, the new Count von Stolpe is settling in well. Maksim is delighted to get out of his older brother's shadow, and has already begun to send back-taxes to make up for what Petr didn't pay. That said, he probably won't be able to change the deadlock of infighting in Southern Stirland without help." LEICHEBURG LOYALTY: SECURED Van Hal sighs. "Something to deal with another day. Right now, between the Knights of Morr and Count von Stolpe, I have agreeable vassals along most of the Sylvanian border. All that's missing is Langwald and Drebkau. Get in touch with..." There's a moment of hesitation, and Anton steps in. "Count Haupt of Steinbachthal and Count Toppenheimer of Hornau." Van Hal frowns. "Haupt. Any relation to my predecessors?" "Only very distantly, and there was a great deal of tension between the Haupts and the Haupt-Anderssens before the latter went extinct." Van Hal looks down and traces a line down the map. "Get in touch with them. If Langwald and Drebkau can be fortified, Leicheburg can be turned into the new garrison for the Army of Stirland and the border will be secured." He considers the map broodingly for another moment. "Wilhelmina, news?" "Back-taxes have started flowing in," she says, "and nobody else is putting up a fight about it like von Stolpe did. Either nobody else realizes we were missing the ledgers, or they took heed of the lesson." She looks from Van Hal to you and back again, looking uncomfortable for a moment, then moves on. "The treasury should soon start increasing, despite the climb in expenditures." "Good. Continue working on it, the money will start flowing out again soon." Wilhelmina looks pained, but nods. WEALTH OF STIRLAND: Poor. INCOME OF STIRLAND: Mediocre. "Brother Kasmir, how is the spiritual health of the castle?" "Among the servants, Sigmar is not as venerated as I would prefer, but Morr and Shallya fill the void. More concerning is the state of the souls of the Greatswords - they have not had a chaplain assigned to them in some time, and though I could find no worship of proscribed cults, there is no central uniting faith among them. The closest is Ulricans, but they only make up a third - the rest are Sigmarites, Myrmidians, Morrites and Verenans." He shakes his head sadly. "The rift between the Sigmarites and the previous rulers of Stirland left the Army without spiritual guidance. I can only hope that I continue to find no evidence of heresy among them." CASTLE SERVANT FAITH: Primarily Morrite and Shallyan. GREATSWORD FAITH: Heavily mixed. Ulrican, Sigmarite, Myrmidians, Morrites, Verenans. ARMY OF STIRLAND FAITH: Unguided. "Worse than I'd hoped, but better than I feared," Van Hal says. "I'll talk with Markus about the Greatswords, you take care of the army. Liaise with the Sigmarites, send off to Altdorf if you have to. I want at least a chaplain for every cohort in the Army proper. They'll report to you. Ensure that the Army's faith is equal to that of the task ahead of them." Kasmir seems pleased at his orders, in a grim sort of way. "Herr Schultz, any problems with the granary?" "None, your grace. I've turned it over to Frau Hochschild's authority, and I understand it is gradually filling with grains from taxes paid in kind." EAGLE CASTLE: Granary added. "Excellent. For now, the defences of Eagle Castle will have to prove sufficient. I'm sending you to Central Stirland, I want you to review the defences of the villages of Swartzhafen and Drebkau. If they're walled, I want to know how feasible improving those walls would be. If they're not, we'll have to organize a corvée to raise mottes and baileys, so survey for suitable sites." He looks at the map, measuring distances with his fingers, and grimaces. "It's about 80 miles from Langwald to Leicheberg, but to go by road means having to circle all the way around and through the Moot. Once you've seen to the villages, you are to survey the area so we can begin work to drive a road between the two." Schultz pales. "Your grace, that area of the province-" Van Hal's eyes narrow. "I'm aware. You'll have troops assigned to you." Schultz's mouth opens, then closes again. Van Hal turns to you, his expression softening. "We've established a network of informants reporting to us from Wurtbad itself and in the surrounding villages," you say proudly. "We should pick up on anyone setting up operations outside of town, unusual travelers, and people hiring on local help for illicit activities. That's not going to catch every vampire or spy coming into town but it should catch the overconfident, careless, or unlucky." "Including Julbach?" Van Hal asks. "Yes. Biderhof is the most agreeable of the villages, but the headmans of Julbach and Tarshof have both fallen into line." He looks down at the document you prepared for him, and considers the options. Uncharacteristic indecision twists his face into a grimace, and in the end he sighs. "Widen the local network. Wurtbad is the administrative center of Stirland, we cannot allow it to be compromised - especially with the Army of Stirland to be based out of the south." --- Your now-customary post-council meeting with Van Hal opens as per usual, with him barely looking up from his desk as you enter. It seems like every time you come in here, there's more papers stacked up. "So," he says, signing one document and putting it on a pile seemingly identical to all the others. "Will you have a chance to look into the replacements for the Professor, do you think?" You nod. "One way or the other. I can write to the Grey College requesting intelligence on his new prospects, or I can personally travel to Altdorf to investigate them, though doing so would leave Stirland without a spymaster for a while." "I'd prefer for you to do so in person, if possible," he says, pouring drinks for the two of you. This time, you expect the burning of the Ostland liquor, and welcome it. "Do you keep correspondence open with your alma mater?" "Letters every now and then. I'll have been getting in touch with them this year anyway because there's a killer illusion-snake trying to murder me." Van Hal's mug was halfway to his lips when you said that, and he lowers it back down onto the desk and gives you a flat look. "What have you been getting up to," he asks - he doesn't quite growl, but there's a hint of it in his voice. "Nothing recently," you assure him. "This is from back when I was still getting a hold on Ulgu." "And it didn't occur to you to tell me there was a Thorned One pursuing you?" "You know of it?" you ask, hopefully. "Barely. I once pursued an artist-cult that worshipped it as their muse. In the end, I only got the snake's leftovers, and they would have been for the asylum if they had escaped the pyre." You sigh, disappointed, and he shakes his head at you. "A Thorned One. And you're only just sending letters home to ask for advice." "I've been busy," you say defensively. He smiles and shakes his head again. "If there's a solution to the snake I can help with, let me know. Anyway, there's something I'd like your thoughts on. This whole business with our predecessors - we've barely scratched the surface, I realize, but I'd like to know what your gut is saying. Were they in league with whatever accursed Von Carstein is haunting Sylvania, or merely aligned with it? Is it a priority to root out the remnants, or to repair the damage they've done? "And this business with the Stirlandian League." He finishes his drink, grimacing. "I'm still undecided on what direction to take with them. I'm new to the title, but as an Elector Count, the thought of giving de facto immunity to those that would avoid paying the taxes and tolls Stirland needs is galling. But as a Witch Hunter, I'm quite familiar with the concept of a lesser evil. I'd like to hear your opinion on the matter." --- [ ] Weigh in - write-ins justifying a decision will have much greater weight. No action point expenditure; these are not actions, just giving your opinion to Van Hal. Choose one from each pair, or write in variations. -[ ] PREDECESSOR LOYALTY: Their self-serving nature and incompetence only gave the Von Carsteins an opportunity. -[ ] PREDECESSOR LOYALTY: I believe that they were truly suborned by the Von Carsteins. -[ ] PREDECESSOR APPROACH: The damage is done; we must repair it. -[ ] PREDECESSOR APPROACH: The rot lives on; we must excise it. -[ ] STIRLANDIAN LEAGUE: Do not clasp the snake to your bosom. Destroy the League. -[ ] STIRLANDIAN LEAGUE: Do not waste such a potent resource. Claim the League. PLAN FOR THIS TURN - CHOOSE BETWEEN SIX AND EIGHT. ANY CHOSEN BEYOND THE FIRST SIX WILL COME WITH RISKS. [ ] As Per Orders: Perform your current assignment. -[ ] The Wurtbad Watch already has their ear to the ground. Make their information flow to you. -[ ] Personally vet everyone that works in the castle, and replace everyone you're not sure of the loyalties of. -[ ] Acquire a copy of Brother Kasmir's report, and confirm everyone is worshipping as they claimed to. -[ ] Wurtbad, like all major cities, is home to a number of guilds. Reach out to them and enforce your will. -[ ] There's a vacuum where a dozen trade guilds should be. Found one of your own, and let information and profits flow through you, and see what the Stirlandian League does about it. (warning: expensive, will need Van Hal or Wilhelmina to sign off on it) -[ ] Much of Western Stirland is under the de facto direct control of the Elector Count. Meet with each of the local leaders and make it clear that you're to be kept in the loop. [ ] Backtracking and Side Operations: -[ ] You haven't asked Anton about your predecessor - see if he knows anything useful. -[ ] The thing you stabbed in the face is still in the cells, and now several others that were found are keeping it company. Examine them, learn from them, see if you can identify them. -[ ] Van Hal is considering candidates for the post of Marshal, and he has asked you to vet them. Investigate them (choose: in person, via correspondence). -[ ] A large number of Shyish-stained weapons were uncovered from the Barrow. Perhaps you should: --[ ] Examine them yourself and see if they're useful, or dangerous, or both. --[ ] Send them to the Amethyst Order for examination (does not take an action). --[ ] Allow the Morrites to examine them (does not take an action). --[ ] Just have them melted down and buried (does not take an action). [ ] Delegation: Maybe it's time to start being less spy and more master. Though Gods know where you'll find someone competent and trustworthy enough to grant such easily-abusable power. (write in source of potential lieutenants) [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with one of your fellow councillors, offering your help in their task and generally getting a feel for them (choose one). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: You've been given good reason to mistrust your fellow councillors. Perhaps you should see what they spent their time doing (choose one). [ ] Sucking Up To The Boss: Normally you'd just go about things and report in to the Elector Count when you've got something major to report. If you instead give him regular reports and updates, it may make him more willing to trust you, and allow you to better get to know him. Opening yourself up to oversight, criticism, and potential micromanagement is a heavy price to pay, though. [ ] Letters Home: You might be able to wring more information out of your Master, or you might just be able to get news, information and guidance in general from the Grey Order. [ ] Hang Out A Shingle: Spymasters don't advertise, but wizards sometimes do. Make an official announcement that there's a wizard in residence, and see who comes out of the woodwork. [ ] Now that you've got gold to throw around, you should stock up on spell components. They're not strictly necessary, but they do make things easier. (-personal gold) [ ] Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. -[ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills (choose one). -[ ] Tutoring: One of your fellow councillors may be willing to teach you in their chosen field (choose who). -[ ] Pretty Good Swords: You've struck up a friendship with the Champion of the Greatswords and have discovered a talent for wielding them. Continue to cultivate this. -[ ] Combat Training: You're virtually surrounded by armed warriors of various sorts. See if you can convince one to teach you (choose who). -[ ] Combat Training, In The Free Market: You haven't made many heavily armed friends yet, but gold is good for that. Go out and buy some training. (-personal gold) -[ ] You only really kept in practice with a handful of the petty and minor magics you were taught. Maybe you should brush up on the others. -[ ] You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. [ ] Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. -[ ] Diggy Diggy Hole: A wizard wielding a shovel is unnatural, but doing it yourself might be the only way to keep things secret. Clear out a new room of your Palace-Shrine by hand. -[ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Outsourced: Pay someone to do the digging, then Mindhole them on their way out. (no action required, -personal gold) -[ ] Filled with Potential: You've got a room cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put there. (write in the purpose of the room) [ ] Research: -[ ] This is Stirland. Time to bone up on your knowledge of the Undead. -[ ] That damn Asp has still been quiet, but maybe it's just biding it's time. Finally admit it's existence to your contacts back in the College and see if they know anything that can help. -[ ] As a Journeywoman, the path to Magister is marked by mastering more than the two shadow spells you already know. Send to the Grey Order for the basics and work on figuring out one of the others. -[ ] As a Journeywoman, the path to mediocrity is marked by only learning spells created by others. Your relationship with Ulgu is between you and it. (create-a-spell, write in the effects, much more difficult than the above) [ ] Influence: Though you haven't taken these over (yet?) you could still spend some time to influence or tap into them. Write in what you would like to do with them. - [ ] The Wurtbadian Thieves Guild is currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. - [ ] Biderhof, a village based on woodcutting and agriculture, has adopted you as one of it's own. FINANCES: NO ACTION POINT EXPENDITURE. Personal Income: 50 gold/turn Discretionary Income: 150 gold/turn Informer Payroll unlocked Currently paying Grey College tithe (5 gold/turn) Currently paying Grey College student loans (35 gold/turn) Currently embezzling 1/4 of discretionary income (35 gold/turn) [ ] Begin plumping the informer rolls (choose ratio of real:fake informers. Almost impossible to detect, but also very difficult to increase or decrease the amount quickly) [ ] Change tithe payment/loan payment/embezzlement (specify) NEW MECHANIC: OVERWORK. With an established base of operations, you can now start pushing yourself to your limits. You can perform up to eight tasks per turn, but any after the first six will have more severe consequences for poor rolling and have a high chance to accumulate negatraits from physical or mental wear and tear. Negatraits can be fixed, but it will take actions to do so. If additional tasks are chosen, label the 'additional' tasks accordingly. - As always, voting will be in plan format. Answers and action plan can be separated. - Don't forget Ranald's Blessing! - Once, you almost got in hot water over the Stirlandian League. Now you're being asked to weigh in on it. The magic of a good relationship with your boss. - You've got a lot on your plate, so Van Hal decided to give you a lighter and more flexible task; but if there's unfinished business lingering at the end of this turn, your actions might start attracting greater oversight.

Turn 5 Results - 2472

[*] Answers Reasoned To Bits -[*] PREDECESSOR LOYALTY: I believe that they were truly suborned by the Von Carsteins. --[*] Loyalty Reasoning: The primary factors are, how agents of Drakenhof knew enough to move the ledgers, which should only be known to the prior count and his administration, how the Von Carstein aligned nobles knew we didn't have them, how the League benefited from the loss of the ledgers and the various undead and monsters literally buried within the castle at the barest inspection. ---[*] While the last factor could be achieved through incompetence or sloth, this does align with the former pieces, which points to a highly competent individual who knew they were in league with monsters. Either his loyalty lies with the monsters, or his greed lies beyond mortal means to fulfill. -[*] PREDECESSOR APPROACH: The rot lives on; we must excise it. --[*] The case of the stablehand to feed us poor information, and the Ledgers placed where they could be recovered intact, rather than much more simply burned or thrown in the river, points to further plots aimed at us rather than simple obscuration of loose ends. As such, the previous spymaster should be considered an active party rather than a simpler historical note. -[*] STIRLANDIAN LEAGUE: Do not clasp the snake to your bosom. Destroy the League. --[*] Intelligence wise, with what we know of their affiliates, the entire network's integrity is suspect, and its continued operations highlight the possibility of its former master still being in control, which would make it too easily suborned a source of deliberately bad information. Economically, the vast amounts of wealth running along the League has to be funding SOMETHING, and indications are that this is not to our benefit. If there were to be such a drain upon our economy, it should at least go towards paying for our operations rather than a mystery party's. [*] Plan Backlog -[*] Do your job: --[*] The Wurtbad Watch already has their ear to the ground. Make their information flow to you. --[*] Personally vet everyone that works in the castle, and replace everyone you're not sure of the loyalties of. ---[*] ... and make sure some of the new hires and trustworthy ones report to you. ---[*] Ask the good Brother to assist you. Can't hurt to double check when it comes to HERESY. --[*] Much of Western Stirland is under the de facto direct control of the Elector Count. Meet with each of the local leaders and make it clear that you're to be kept in the loop. -[*] Secret Base: --[*] Diggy Diggy Hole, Outsourced: Pay someone to do the digging, then Mindhole them on their way out. (no action required, -personal gold) -[*] Research: --[*] A large number of Shyish-stained weapons were uncovered from the Barrow. Perhaps you should: ---[*] Examine them yourself and see if they're useful, or dangerous, or both. ---[*] Ranald's Blessing ----[*] Bring an example or two to show your master while you are in Altdorf. -----[*] Lead-lined steel case. Magic lock on top of mundane one. Carry on your person. -[*] Go to Altdorf: --[*] Van Hal is considering candidates for the post of Marshal, and he has asked you to vet them. --[*] That damn Asp has still been quiet, but maybe it's just biding it's time. Finally admit it's existence to your contacts back in the College and see if they know anything that can help. --[*] Filled with Potential: You've got a room cleared out and ready to be put to use. It should make an excellent enchanter's workshop after a bit of furnishing and some purchases in Altdorf. (no action, -personal gold) --- You consider the questions at length. "The primary factors are," you begin, unconsciously taking on the tone of voice you used to use in debates back in College, "how agents of Drakenhof knew enough to move the ledgers, which should only be known to the prior Elector Count and his administration; how the Von Carstein-aligned nobles knew we didn't have them; how the League benefited from the loss of the ledgers; and the various undead and monsters literally buried within the castle, exposed at the barest inspection. "While the last factor could be achieved through incompetence or sloth, this does align with the former pieces, which points to a highly competent individual who knew they were in league with monsters. Either his loyalty lies with the monsters, or his greed lies beyond mortal means to fulfil." "Compelling reasoning," Van Hal says, motioning for you to continue. "The case of the stablehand who attempted to feed us poor information, on top of the ledgers placed where they could be recovered intact instead of being simply burned or thrown in the river: this points to further plots aimed at us rather than simple obfuscation of loose ends. As such, the previous spymaster should be considered a still-active party rather than a simpler historical note." "I'm inclined to agree. And the Stirlandian League?" "Intelligence wise, with what we know of their affiliates, the entire network's integrity is suspect, and its continued operations highlight the possibility of its former master still being in control. This would make it too easily suborned to be a good source of information. Economically, the vast amounts of wealth running along the League has to be funding something, and indications are that this is not to our benefit. If there were to be such a drain upon our economy, it should at least go towards paying for our operations rather than those of some unknown party." "Mmm," Van Hal says neutrally, swirling what remains of his liquor in its mug. "That was my thought too, but I wasn't sure if it was the proper caution of an Elector Count or the leftover instincts of a Witch Hunter. I'm glad your thoughts on the matter align with mine." "Happy to put your mind at ease," you say, and Van Hal smiles at you. --- Your first instinct was to immediately begin galloping off to Altdorf, but it occurs to you to at least wait until they arrive, so you cast around for something else to spend your time on. You don't want to get started on something and be unable to complete it. So you visit the treasury, open up the large steel-and-lead crate, wince at the wave of Shyish that flows out, and select a candidate for investigation - a large iron greatsword. Then you glare at it suspiciously, before putting it back in the box and going to find a blacksmith that can make you a case to carry it around in. A couple of days later, you have transported the suspect greatsword back home and are ready to start examining it properly. Sure, you've got nothing more than magesight, an unhoned talent for enchantment, and some half-remembered lessons on the subject from back when you were an apprentice, but what's the worst that can happen, right? In the peaceful quiet of your excavated spare room, illuminated by a softly glowing ball of Ulgu, you peer closely at the sword. The Shyish is unmistakable, densely twisted in on itself in a spiralling lattice, and as far as you can tell untainted by Dhar. You frown and look closer, not sure what it is you're seeing. Magic, you know, is fundamentally about taking the unreality of the Winds and forcing them into reality, softening the fundamentals of what is and twisting them according to the will of the caster and the nature of the Wind in question. If you push Aqshy into reality, fire can appear from nothing, because the Aqshy temporarily and locally changes reality so that fire can come from nowhere. But where spellcasting does so for mere seconds, enchanting does so indefinitely. In reality fire needs fuel, but a magically burning sword does not, because the sword is no longer entirely real and therefore no longer beholden to that aspect of reality. But just as the sword becomes partly unreal, the Winds become partly real. An enchanter isn't just bringing the Winds into reality, they're changing the nature of the Winds themselves. But that isn't what you're seeing here. The Winds are densely-packed but unchanged in their fundamental nature - but that can't be right, because the fundamental nature of Shyish isn't being stacked up in a sword like apples in a barrel. So you look for the barrel itself, peering closer and closer to try to make out what would be a tiny amount of magical framework around the overpowering glow of the trapped Shyish. It's like trying to see a candle in front of a bonfire, and your vision blurs as your eyes strain to make it out, and you wince at the sudden coldness as your nose touches the iron of the blade but you think you just caught a glimpse of it, right at the edge of the- Sudden agony shoots up your leg and you drop the sword, its point embedding itself in the soil. You whirl around to see a cat sprinting out of the room, its mischief apparently done. You rub at your calf and wince as you feel dampness of the fabric. The little bastard drew blood through your robes, and how did it even get down here, what sort of horrible demon cat- Your thoughts are scattered as the sensation of the raw energy of death unleashed fills the room, and you whirl once more and then take several steps back as you see sinister purple light arcing across the length of the sword. The Shyish dances up and down the blade, seeking an escape, and then turns inwards and the sword turns red with rust as it ages decades in seconds. Before your eyes it flakes away to nothing, and the now-released death energy sinks into the earth. You stare in horror. If you had still been holding the sword... [TEMPTING RANALD: Breakpoints 30/60, Learning, Ranald's Blessing 11+13+20=44. Ranald's got your back.] Shaken, you spend the next few days curled up with a freshly-bought novel or two as you await the arrival of your potential new coworkers. Finally they arrive from Altdorf, escorted by pistoliers and unknowingly observed from the wall as you try to put faces to the names you've been given. The first candidate is unmistakable, with their horse just as clad in steel as the man himself, and wielding a hammer that would put Brother Kasmir's to shame. Sir Berthold of the Order of the Hammer of Sigmar, you presume. The second is more difficult to spot, blending in as he does among the ranks of the pistoliers, but you identify him by his more ornate half-plate and the missing plume on his helmet - Outrider Champion Gustav von Jungfreud. And bringing up the rear is an overweight man driving a cart, covered with a bulging sheet. That must be Master Engineer Otto of Nuln. Three very different candidates. A tricky decision to be made. Hopefully what you find in Altdorf will simplify it. --- After consulting a map, you realized that the trip by road to Altdorf is actually shorter than the trip to Leicheburg. An overnight stay in Nuln and you'll be there at the end of the second day. You are, however, reminded that no travel in the Empire is trivial as part way through the first day, you encounter a group of beastmen trotting along the path, on the hunt for travellers. You were sorely tempted to draw your greatsword and set about them, but you didn't want to risk dropping your cargo (a second greatsword from the crate in the treasury, hopefully less temperamental than the first) so you just blasted right past them at full speed, chuckling to yourself at the frustrated man-goat noises they made as they tried fruitlessly to match your speed. You report them at the next roadwarden waystation you pass. The rest of the trip is uneventful. --- Altdorf is just as you remember it - overcrowded and full of snobs. You're also struck by how... ignored you are. In Stirland, you get looks everywhere you go, albeit mostly nervously respectful ones lately. But Altdorf is practically bursting with wizards, and though you aren't exactly getting jostled by passers-by, neither are you given any undue attention. You're not sure how you feel about it. The morning after you arrive, you're enjoying a quiet drink in the tavern you've rented a room in when your Master walks in, exactly as you remember him - same robe, same hat, same hideous fox stole he insists on constantly wearing dangling from his neck. He heads straight for your table and sits himself down uninvited, not even glancing away from you as the bartender hurries over with a tankard of ale. "You could have waited until I sent word," you say with feigned exasperation. "What's the point in knowing everything if you can't show it off?" he replies, his deep, booming voice ringing around the tavern. "So, what's got you running all the way back home? Not shooting for Magister already, are you?" "Not this year," you reply breezily. "Mainly, I'm checking up on the candidates to replace the previous Marshal." "And didn't that business cause some red faces here," he chuckles. "There's an old tale about a scorpion and a frog that leaps to mind." You wonder whether the scorpion is supposed to be the late Professor or Van Hal. "I don't suppose you could save me the work?" "And what kind of teacher would I be if I did that? Go, do your investigating, then come back to me and I'll tell you if you missed anything important." You huff. "There are a couple of other reasons. The first is that I've got a bit of an ardent pursuer, if you get my meaning. Vain, too. Really likes mirrors." The smile falls off Regimand's face at that. He looks over to the bartender and jerks his head towards the door, and the man hurries out from behind the bar and starts shooing the morning crowd out the door, steins still in their hands. In moments the room is empty, and the bartender scurries through a back door and closes it behind him, leaving the two of you alone. "What foolishness have you been getting up to in that blasted province-" "Oh, it's not new," you reassure him. "This has been an ongoing thing since... '65, I think. When I filled that practice room with sticky fog that melted candles." "Why didn't you say something," he asks, aghast. You shrug. "At the time, I didn't want to admit that the incident was an even bigger screw-up than everyone thought. After that... well, I guess I just got used to it. There's actually less mirrors around than you'd think, and it's easy to get in the habit of dulling the shine on blades and silverware." He shakes his head in disbelief. "I wonder if it's too late to transfer you to the Bright Order..." "None of that. Come on, what's the solution here." He sighs, and thinks. "There's a school of thought that such manifestations should be left to run their course, to cull the wizards that result in them. But miscasts happen to the best of us, I say. Go to- wait, no, you can't. Okay, I'll have an apprentice dig through the archives. There's a book somewhere in there that has a device to catch this particular variety of creature." "Thank you," you begin, but you're interrupted. "Don't thank me yet. The cost of having a new copy printed will be added to your debts." "Can't I just borrow it?" "If we lent out books, the archives would be empty within a generation." You sigh, and finish your drink. "So what was the third reason?" "Oh, right," you say, and get up to go fetch the case from your room. When you return with it, he eyes the case thoughtfully. "Birchwood would be better," he says, taking it from you and working the clasp and opening it. "Oh, lead-lined. Well, that works too, though for short-term storage you want iron instead of steel on the outside." He eyes the sword inside thoughtfully. "Speaking of iron. Pre-Imperial?" You nod, and he leans in closer to it - though, you note sourly, not so close that he risks prodding it with his nose. "Hmf. Found in Stirland, I take it? So Asoborn construction... oh, I know what this is. Bloody primitives. There was a belief back then that the Winds of Magic were the souls of the dead, so some twit wizards put enchantments on the weapons to absorb ambient winds thinking that would mean it would eat the souls of those killed with it. Nasty stuff, except wrong in literally every way." He closes the case with a click. "So instead you end up with the swords sucking in all sorts of magic and it ends up mixing and curdling and next thing you know it's Dhar. At that point the best thing to do is find a nice volcano to drop it into. You've got the exception to the rule, though - looks like it's been soaking up nothing but Shyish, so it hasn't been tainted." He shrugs. "Not that it's any good. The enchantment itself is lost and could be interesting to work with, but you can't reverse-engineer the enchantment without grounding the Shyish, and unless you do it right the first time, that takes the blade and thus the enchantment with it and you're left with nothing." You feign a disappointed look, thank him for his insight, and take the case back to your room, your mind alight with possibilities. --- The Markets of Altdorf, however, refuse to cooperate with your ambitions. There's so much equipment that could be of use to you - looking glasses, magnifiers, prisms, crystals, lenses... and not a single one is anywhere to be found. Wizard Chic, you discover, is in fashion among every spoiled rich youth in Altdorf that wants to outrage their parents. All over the city the damn brats are using genuine components to craft absolutely useless monuments to their own foolishness, and have sucked up everything that looks like it might be magically useful, and then commissioned more on top of that, so that every glassblower in the city is too busy catering to the whims of Altdorf's feckless youth to craft you the enchanting components you need. You miss Wurtbad. [REGIMAND'S EXAMINATION. Roll, Learning, 92+18=110. This is why he is the Master.] [SHOPPING FOR ENCHANTING EQUIPMENT: Roll, Stewardship, 8+10=18. Ayn Ranald's free market destroys your dreams.] --- You abandon the markets of Altdorf in disgust and go about your official business. First order of business: the chapterhouse of the Order of the Hammer of Sigmar. You knock on their door, introduce yourself, hand them your letter of introduction, and the door is slammed in your face. You scowl at the door. Now you'll need to get a new letter of introduction. Still, you're not so easily put off. The Knights themselves might not feel like talking, but there's others inside the Chapterhouse that might not be so tightlipped. You spend days lurking in the pubs, bars, inns and taverns nearest to the Chapterhouse, and finally you find someone who works there that's willing to talk to a stranger. He peers at you through the haze of smoke and his own drunkenness as he recounts his tale. "There's a group of 'em that are always together, and though I ain't ever seen your boy getting up to mischief, the others in that group are right proper arses. Always makin' us recite hymns to Sigmar, and if we don't know the words we get a beatin'. And if we say we follow one of the other Gods we get a bigger beatin'. I asked my Priest, and he says that's not right." You murmur agreement that it's not right, your eyes narrowing. --- Four days it took, to head back to Wurtbad and ask the bemused Van Hal for a replacement letter of introduction and come all the way back to Altdorf. And now you finally stand at the door of the Outrider's Barracks. They're not a Knightly Order, so you figure they'll be lacking the heady mix of arrogance and self-righteousness that made the Knights refuse to even- The door opens. You introduce yourself. You hand them your letter of introduction. The door is slammed in your face. Literally in your face. You prod at it gingerly, hoping it's not broken. As it is, you're going to have one hell of a bruise. Four more days to Wurtbad and back. Van Hal couldn't decide whether to laugh at your predicament or worry about the hideous bruise that had spread across your face by then. When you knock on the door of the Pistolier barracks, you're ready to draw your greatsword and jam it in the doorframe if it looks like it's going to be slammed in your face. But instead, you're invited in by the enthusiastic young noble, who apparently is a follower of Wizard Chic and compliments you on how authentic your outfit looks. You assure him that it looks authentic because it damn well is authentic, and he's awestruck. You're introduced to a dizzying array of young nobles with more pistols than sense, and none of them have anything bad to say about Gustav von Jungfreud. They seem to hero-worship him, each competing to tell stories of the man charging impossible odds with a repeater pistol in each hand, dealing out improbable amounts of death. You listen carefully nonetheless, and a picture forms in your mind. Gustav is always the first into the fight, the boys are all eager to tell you. Now, you're no strategist, but it occurs to you that leading from the front is all well and good, but there's a time and a place for it, and the time isn't always and the place isn't everywhere. Hmm. --- Another day of travel to Nuln, to visit the famous Gunnery School. The famous Gunnery School that you're going to level to the ground if they even think of slamming the door in your face. Luckily for the famous Gunnery School of Nuln, they're entirely welcoming to you, and more than happy to talk of the man who put his chances of tenure in jeopardy to volunteer for service in Stirland. Everyone speaks of how brilliant he is; how he miniaturized the bird-bomb, how he demolished the stables with what he insisted on calling the greatgreatcannon, how he tried to replicate the Dwarven gyrocopter and ended up creating a sort of ballista that fires enormous spinning blades. You're shown into his workshop, which is a picture of absolute chaos. Parts and pipes and tools and scraps of parchment lie everywhere, half-covering prototype devices of unidentifiable purpose. You eye writing scrawled across the stone wall in charcoal, which appears to be calculating how big you can scale up a mortar until steel is no longer sufficient to contain the blast. Then it starts speculating about the properties of gromril. Ambitious. Inspired. And quite possibly insane. [INVESTIGATING THE KNIGHT: Req 60, Intrigue, 28+14=44. Door slammed in face.] [ALTERNATE ROUTES: Req 80, Intrigue, 73+14=87. A fortunate encounter.] [INVESTIGATING THE OUTRIDER: Req 50, Intrigue, 4+14=18. Door slammed in face, literally. Ow.] [INVESTIGATING THE PISTOLIERS: Req 70, Intrigue, 95+14=109. They're eager to gush about their idol.] [INVESTIGATING THE ENGINEER: Req 50, Intrigue, 76+14=90. They're happy to show him off.] --- In Wurtbad, you thought of Altdorf as home. But after spending time in Altdorf once more, you find yourself yearning for Wurtbad. So after you finalize your investigations, you waste no time in heading back to Stirland. Your Palace-Shrine welcomes you, and you sink into the welcoming embrace of your familiar, comfortable bed and luxuriate in finally being away from that damn stupid overcrowded impertinent sprawl of a city. But you can't luxuriate for long, because you've spent a lot of time out of the city and you've got work to do. First order of business is finding some more dumb muscle willing to become hermit miners for a few months in exchange for a hefty paycheck, and then you're off to visit the Wurtbad Watch. The Wurtbad Watch, you soon discover, is the final destination for any members of the Army of Stirland too mutilated to serve but too stubborn to quit. The average member of the Watch has three limbs and nine tenths of a face, and nowhere is this better embodied than in their leader, Captain Guion 'Lefty' Ragnier, a former Brettonnian peasant with a hook in place of his left hand and an eyepatch covering whatever happened to his left eye. He doesn't let that slow him down, though, and you find him to be worryingly sharp and surprisingly literate, his desk almost as covered in paperwork as Van Hal's. He's also openly suspicious of you, bordering on hostile. Currently, his eye is narrowed as he looks at you across the desk. "Wouldn't this be the Marshal's jurisdiction?" You shrug. "If you've got a shovel, you can dig him up and ask him." "Right, I heard about that. Treason, wasn't it?" You're not sure what he's insinuating, but you're pretty sure you don't like it. "Yes, and it was uncovered and he was executed for it." "What about the Steward, then? If we're part of the city's civil infrastructure, seems more natural we'd report to her." "And if you were nothing but petty thief-takers, that would be the case. Look, we've gone off-track. I'm not asking for you and your men to become spies. All I'm asking is that, when you're keeping an eye out for cultists and creatures as you normally do, you keep me informed of anything you find. Then I can work with you in exterminating them before they're a threat to Wurtbad." He looks at you long and hard, then, reluctantly, he nods. "Suppose I don't have much of a choice in the matter." "No. You don't." That could have gone better. But sullen obedience is still obedience. [RECRUITING THE WATCH: Breakpoints 40/60/80, Diplomacy, 51+8=59. Reluctant obedience.] --- As much as you hate leaving Wurtbad again so soon, your next priority is seeing to the allegiances of the regional representatives of the Elector Count's demesne. Before you head out, you see to the trio of diggers who you hired to clear out another room in the Palace-Shrine - it's a bit trickier to Mindhole and pay each of them individually without tipping off the other two, but since you're barely in Wurtbad recently you had no choice. Once again you're disappointed to find a lack of treasures. So off you go to find those regional representatives. It's an exceedingly dull task, because as it turns out, there's no one clear representative, just a snarled bureaucratic mess that runs off inertia. You spend days trying to find out who's centrally placed enough to be able to act as an information pipeline, then days more trying to convince them you have the authority to recruit them. But in the end, Munzhausen falls into line, and then Purgg. In Worden, however, the bureaucrats are made of sterner stuff, and they stubbornly resist your attempts to untangle the confusing mess of who reports to who. You almost suspect that you're being deliberately stonewalled, but it could be entirely innocent - after all, Worden is the largest of the three areas. In the end you have to break off and head back to Wurtbad if you're going to complete what you had planned. [ANY TREASURES? Req 80, 21.] [MUNZHAUSEN, Req 40, Diplomacy, 42+8=50.] [PURGG, Req 40, Diplomacy, 79+8=87.] [WORDEN, Req ??, Diplomacy, 22+8=30.] --- Final entry on your agenda: looking into the staff of Eagle Castle. You haven't had much contact with them since you moved out, but they're a pretty straightforward bunch, largely drawn from the surrounding villages since the Wurtbadians are oddly skittish about the castle. Things get off to a bad start right away, as Brother Kasmir gets the impression that you're checking up on his work. He declines your request to assist him with icy politeness and strides off before you have a chance to rephrase. You consider going after him to try to smooth things over, but decide to leave things be before you jam your foot any deeper into your mouth. Still, you've got a job to do. Things start off innocently enough. Some of the staff know you and the rest know of you, so they're comfortable answering your questions, and you compare everyone's stories together and find that everything matches. Then one day, you're barely paying attention to the fifteenth interview of the day when the man mentions his relation to the headman of Biderhof. You prompt him to continue, remembering the agonizing detail said headman went into when describing his family tree, and notice that the picture being painted for you doesn't line up at all with the one the headman himself gave to you. The man's voice trails off, apparently picking up on your suspicion. For a long moment the two of you stare at each other over the table, filling the room with silence. When he moves, it is with inhuman speed - if his legs hadn't been tucked under the table, he would have had you. As it is, him having to push his chair back and rise to his feet before he could throw himself at you gave you time to draw your greatsword and meet his pounce with your swing. Once again, silence descends upon the room, broken only by the the blood dripping from the enormous gash in the man's torso, almost splitting him in half. You stare in horror at the cleaved body of the man that seconds ago you were talking to. You look down at the spray of blood marring your grey robes. You look at your trusty flamberge embedded in the flesh of the thing that just tried to kill you. Then you turn away, and vomit your half-digested lunch against the wall. [RECRUITING BROTHER KASMIR: Req 30, Diplomacy, 7+8=15. You're not making a lot of friends lately.] [TRY TO UNDO THE DAMAGE: Req 60, Diplomacy, 40+8=48. Best to leave him be.] [HOW BAD IS IT: ???] [WHAT DO YOU FIND: Req ???, Intrigue, 52+14=66. Inconsistency found.] [STAY COOL: Req 40, Intrigue, 9+14=23. Failed at playing it cool.] [REACT: Roll, Martial, 82+10=92. GREATSWORD!] [POST-BATTLE COMPOSURE: Roll, Martial, 17+10=27.] --- ENCHANTED SWORD LOST. 49 remaining. STUDENT LOANS INCREASED. BOOK ACQUIRED: Light And Its Properties, by Leonardo da Miragliano. KNIGHT INVESTIGATED: Kept over-zealous company. OUTRIDER INVESTIGATED: Always the first into the fight, always. ENGINEER INVESTIGATED: There's a fine line between genius and madness, and he's trying to weaponize it. INFORMANT GAINED: Captain Guion 'Lefty' Ragnier, Head of the Wurtbadian Watch PALACE-SHRINE UPGRADED: Spare room excavated! INFORMANT GAINED: Munzhausen Bureaucrat INFORMANT GAINED: Purgg Bureaucrat BROTHER KASMIR RELATION CHANGES: -1, now 4/10. Discretionary Income: +150g Embezzlement: -35g Sword box: -5g Altdorf trip accommodation: -20g --- Net: +90 Personal Income: +50g Embezzlement: +35g Tithe: -5g Student Loans: -35g Excavations: -20g --- Net: +25g --- You have just become very aware that something is very, very wrong. WRITE IN what you do next. --- YOU are currently in a small room near the Great Hall you have been using for interviews. It is roughly equidistant between the Chapel, the Courtyard, and the Great Hall. It is not much further to the Study. It is far away from the Archives. ANTON is in Steinbachthal. WILHELMINA is either in the Archives or out of the Castle. KASMIR is sulking in the Chapel. SCHULTZ is in Southern Stirland. MARKUS is in the Courtyard. BERTHOLD is in the Courtyard. You noticed about twelve GREATSWORDS in the Courtyard. GUSTAV is with VAN HAL, wherever he is. You do not know where OTTO is. You do not know where VAN HAL is. He may be in his study. There are roughly two hundred SERVANTS in the castle. You have interviewed sixty of them without incident.

Turn 2: Drying Blood

Drying Blood
+997.M41+
+Hatred For The Xeno Is Among One Of The Most Blessed Of Virtues+

Your options are limited, but those chosen are no less worthy for that. As it is, Cyrus, already acting as the only real leadership amongst the 10th Company and having experience at training Blood Raven scouts for over fifty years, is selected both as the official Captain of the 10th Company as well as the Master of Recruits. He accepts his new duties with the same sarcasm and bitter undertones as usual, but he seems somewhat pleased that he now has official command over the initiates that he so doggedly protects and guides. As for Tarkus, you would promote him to Captain of the 4th Company as would have been his right were it not for the 4th Company to have stopped existing over the course of the purge from the intense fighting. He accepts his duty stoically and respectfully as Captain of the 5th Company, and you can only hope that under his guidance and leadership that they will grow strong once more.

As for the 3rd Company, which you have led for so long…you move them forward to the 1st Company as a whole. It would be easy for some to accuse you of favoritism, but after even a cursory examination of the circumstances only the most foolish would continue to argue against it. They are the most veteran marines in the Chapter overall, having fought with you for the totality of the Third Aurelian Crusade and many more campaigns beforehand. So now they take their place as the 1st Company of the Blood Ravens, and they have changed their heraldry to reflect that. As for the rest of the Chapter, the ten scouts that Cyrus has identified as worthy are advanced to full Battle Brothers under the ministrations of the 10th Company’s Apothecary.

Epistolary Probalis, formerly of your…of the 3rd Company, is selected as your new Chief Librarian. A good man, Justinius served as a subordinate of the lamented Jonah Orion for over a century and had what may be considered the luck to not be travelling with the majority of the 3rd Company against the Tyranid Hive Mind during the First Aurelian Crusade. As it is, Jonah was a tremendously powerful force on the direct and psychic combat who passed many of his teachings down to Justinius. Still, the man is no carbon copy of his instructor and has focused many of his energies on parsing the future and piercing the fog of war from across the battlefield, a traditional Blood Raven Librarian discipline but one he has refined. As a result his skills are far more suited for ranged battle, not close pitched warfare. In terms of personality, he is an incredibly calm marine, and it was whispered amongst the initiates and scouts that his near unflappable nature is due to him having perceived his own death and thus becoming practically fearless as a result. [BS-7, WS-5, S-5, T-6, A-4, I-8, P-10, W-10, F-5]

For your new Master of Sanctity, you select the only Chaplain left in the Chapter who is not in the Death Watch, Hannibal Palrun. In those dark times when you were unsure just who you could trust in the Chapter while Kyras was its Master, Hannibal was there. A master orator and a deadly combatant, he has fought alongside you since Tartarus, and all the years afterwards. His fiery rhetoric and piety kept the 3rd Company strong in those dark times when hope seemed so bleak, and he denied that you were possibly heretics for entertaining treachery against the traitor. One of the largest marines you’ve ever seen not just amongst the Blood Ravens but amongst any Space Marines in general, his bulk reflects his abilities to stalwartly wade through oceans of enemy fire while bellowing blessed hatred. Of course, with him ascending to Master of Sanctity there are no more Chaplains amongst the rest of the Chapter, which will hopefully be recognized in the future. [BS-4, WS-9, S-8 T-8, A-4, I-6, P-5, W-7, F-10]

However, when selecting a new Master of the Apothecarion, you find that you must first learn of the potential candidates before choosing one. After all, before this you were but Captain of the 3rd Company. Familiarizing yourself with the whole of the Chapter will take time. As it is, after realizing this you busied yourself with learning all you could about the three prospective candidates.

Brother Romallius is the most familiar to you, having fought with you on Tartarus and almost all the other battlefields beyond. There is not much to outwardly differentiate himself from the rest of the Chapter, though after getting to know the man you can proudly call yourself amongst the handful of individuals who know that he carries a strange fondness for puns and laughter, a rarity amongst the more usually taciturn versions of his kind. Also included in that is his affection for ranged weapons – an unusual habit for an Apothecary – and can often be found wielding a flamer or dual wielding bolt pistols instead of a more customary chain sword. This is not to say he is defenseless in melee combat, but he personally prefers to kill his enemies from afar so that they do not get close enough to disturb him while he operates at all. Some might question his more unorthodox methods, but you have long accepted them as part of who he is. [Ranged Inclination, Vaguely Unorthodox Methods]

Brother Gracchus, of the 5th Company, is an extremely young marine, though skilled at his craft. Recruited from Calderis, he is one of the few parts of the 5th Company who did not go with Aramus on his Penitent Crusade. As it is, he is one of those who worked alongside the honored Brother Gordion on the bio-toxin used against the Hive Mind in the First Aurelian Crusade, and has spent much of his time doing similar work. While not precisely skilled when it comes to combat like some might expect of a Space Marine, he is a startlingly good researcher with an intimate knowledge of not just the human and marine body but of xenos as well. He may not be as potent on the battlefield as some would prefer, but based on the reports when it comes to sheer medical ability he outstrips all other candidates. [+Intelligent, Savant of Medicine]

Brother Marius Astophiles is of the 10th Company and apparently known by of all people Cyrus. Brother Astophiles has overseen the recruitment, implantation, and growth of over a century and a half’s worth of Blood Ravens – though he feels great shame for not realizing the corruption of his Company from within under Kyras’s influence. Few can blame him for this, as any attempts to do so must be acknowledged that none discovered the traitor’s treachery until it was almost too late. His brusque nature melds together with his status as one of the most puritanical members of the entire Chapter, outright refusing to do some things that might go against tradition or the Emperor without a Chaplain and Librarian’s explicit approval. On the other hand, is he were not an apothecary he would most certainly have become an Assault Terminator of the First Company, given his combat skills and the fact that in a unique circumstance as a more standard battle brother that he did in fact manage to make Terminator Honors before being selected for his position. [+Weapon Skill, Highly Orthodox]

However, they are not the only brothers that you study with a critical eye over this time, also looking for those who have distinguished themselves in recent times and not only for potential Captaincy positions. Reports from Aramus pass over your desk, speaking of some, while Cyrus speaks of others that he has interacted with. Tarkus has a wealth of knowledge considering the whole of the Chapter, while you reflect on those marines you know especially in the current stock. Others, you learn of through your new Chief Librarian and therefore the access to the immense and intimately detailed records of the Librarium.

The first four are actually of your formerly commanded Company, though that is unsurprising given how long they fought alongside you.

Macharius Sicarius is a Devastator Sergeant of your 3rd , now 1st Company. Out of all the marines of your former directly commanded brothers, he is likely the only one who could match you in terms of bionics. This has actually somewhat aided him in his duties, his augmented strength and vision allowing him to wield heavy weaponry with accuracy and ease. He distinguished himself by facing down three Predator Tanks of the Traitors during the Third Aurelian Crusade alone while the rest of his squad died. Wrenching the dead hulk of the honorable Tomb-Brother Achillan about with his immense strength, he used his experience with heavy weaponry to reactivate the dreadnought’s connected multi-melta and obliterate the foe. [+Ballistic Skill, +Strength]

Ares Actus is a veteran Sergeant of the 3rd, now 1st Company, who has led many a guard action during your campaigns. He has held the line again and again while others deep strike into enemy territory, and on those few occasions where retreat was necessary he was there, all the while. Not the most skilled, but perhaps one of the most stalwart, he has been struck again and again but never fallen, all the while calling out for his brothers to go to greater lengths to fight and kill in the name of the Emperor with holy zeal. [+Fellowship, Demagogue Tendencies (Chaplain Potential?)]

Quarius Zergan is one of the youngest marines in the Chapter to have achieved the rank of sergeant in the history of the Blood Ravens. Nonetheless, besides his youth the sheer amount of battles and campaigns he has fought alongside you have made him worthy enough of his title. What truly interests you however, or rather, Martellus, was his potentially heretical habit of tinkering with his own weapons to squeeze out just a bit more efficiency or death dealing capabilities. After speaking to Martellus however and being informed of just how close he was coming to death, he ceased immediately. That does not mean he could not begin again, if properly instructed of course. [+Intelligence, Tinkering Talent (Techmarine Potential?)]

Amicus Antal…a tragic tale. Five times, has his entire squad been wiped out with him as the sole survivor. Five times, by five distinct major foes of the Imperium, has he nearly been slain. The first was from an ork force that outnumbered his squad 20-1. The second, from a blasted Eldar strike force. The third, the tau during the Vorga campaign. The fourth time came from tyranids while fighting against the Hive Tyrant during the last battle of the First Aurelian Crusade. The fifth, from traitors…his own squad, turned against him and towards Chaos. No sergeant should have lost what he has, much less be forced to fight and kill his entire own squad as they attempted to slay him. His sheer fortitude keeps him going physically, but spiritually and mentally you are less certain, though he regularly speaks to Hannibal in private meetings and thus far your Company’s former Chaplain has yet to see fit to tell you that something is explicitly wrong. [+Toughness, Last Man Standing)

Others, however, do exist amongst the Chapter who come to you through careful research and reports.

Marcus Crixus is an assault marine of the 5th Company, one of its few survivors after recent events. Curiously, however, instead of distinguishing himself for leaping into battle and splitting apart dozens or hundreds of enemies, he instead became known to the Chapter for helping organize and direct forces numerous times during the 3rd Aurelian Crusade. Apollo speaks well of him, saying that while he and the rest of his immediate command squad would pursue objectives, oddly enough it would by Brother Crixus who would somehow end up being listened to about where squads and vehicles should go. His grasp of wider battlefield tactics is quite interesting. [+Perception, Natural Tactician]

Hadrian Priscus comes to you from the 5th Company with quite the few accomplishment to his name. Visiting the 10th Company at the time of the Third Aurelian Crusade, the senior sergeant instead rallied not only the scouts there in slaying their traitor brethren, but directed the Company’s flagship into battle against the rest of the traitor fleet, boarding and reclaiming ships one at a time. It is at his hands that you have some ships at all, even if their conditions are less than preferable. If anyone was wondering why the Chapter Fleet was not more present during the Third Aurelian Crusade, here is the reason, the mad, mad reason who leapt from ship to ship again and again throughout the entire Crusade until victory was achieved. [+Intelligence, Void Craft Prodigy]

Kaius Jacobus is actually one of the immediately promoted members of the 10th Company to complete battle brother. Cyrus has indicated that out of his many students that Jacobus is one of the few to actually satisfy him when it comes to stealth, something few ever truly manage to master. He distinguished himself during the Second Aurelian Crusade against the damned Eliphas the Inheritor as one of those scouts who never even received an injury during the dangerous moments when the forces of Chaos had managed to isolate a large number of Scouts on Calderis. Mostly because they could never find or hit him while he popped in and out of stealth with a combat shotgun, flamer, and sniper rifle strapped all about him in ramshackle webbing that he nonetheless used quite skillfully. [+Agility, Shadow Hunter]

----------------

“Chapter Master…I-,”

“Do you question my decision, Apollo?” you ask, raising your own remaining eyebrow.

The void provides a somewhat intimidating backdrop as you stand before him, behind you floating the shambles of the Chapter Fleet and Calderis below. Your hands have clasped behind your back, though you have to be careful that the bionics do not crush each other but with every passing day you are growing more and more adept with them. Within the year you shall be as you ever were, albeit slower by virtue of sheer weight. Before you kneels the shamed former Captain, but the look on his face is a mixture of frustration and anger.

“But…I…I do not deserve to stand at your side,” he finally grinds out, fingers clenching hard enough that you can hear the ceramite ever so faintly groaning.

“What was your intention then?” you ask. “To go in search of Aramus to join his Penitent Crusade? To join the Death Watch as a Black Shield?”

He does not say so but the sudden tightness of his face and minutely more lowered head gives it away.

“Absolutely not,” you say flatly, each syllable falling like drop pods.

“But-,”

“You are not worthy of joining the Death Watch as you are, Apollo Diomedes.”

A ghost of a flinch ripples across his frame, one that no one else would have been able to see. Even an Astartes might miss it, yet with your bionic eye and its improvements…you still barely caught it. His self-control is astounding. You cannot afford to lose him to some distant and forlorn star, not with the Chapter as it is. You need his abilities and experience even if he does not believe the same.

“No. You shall be my direct subordinate, but you shall hold no authority of your own. You shall never do so again barring the most wild of circumstances. On the battlefield, you shall act once more as a Champion of the Chapter, but my own personal one. As my Bodyguard you shall accompany me everywhere, and in that service may you find redemption. Do you understand?”

You can hear the grinding of his teeth, but then the tension leaves him entirely. It is as Probalis predicted then. The last vestiges of his pride are dying, here and now, in bursts and twitches, but he would have accepted you telling him to slit his own throat so despondent is he. To know that he failed so utterly, to both Chapter and Emperor, was enough cause for doubt and self-loathing to fill his mind.

But he is a Space Marine, and you have no use for a Blood Raven that is tainted by doubt. So you shall forge Apollo Diomedes anew, and excise the blemishes from his frame that have come from over two centuries of direct subordination to the traitor Kyras. Either that, or he will fall in service, and in doing so find redemption another way.

“I understand…Chapter Master.”

“Good.”

Then you turn, and face the stars once more. Apollo rises, then silently joins you at your right side. Engines blaze and light up the void as Cyrus leaves with the 10th Company’s fleet and additions. Three fully armed Strike Cruisers and the Escorts alongside them should be enough. Trontiux III is your one viable Recruiting World at the moment, and so you have given him explicit instructions to perform the most exacting and strenuous Blood Trials possible. Thankfully, you have not recruited from Trontiux III in several decades…another one of Kyras’s policies that were to deceptively weaken the Chapter over time.

First he ordered Trontiux III left alone for so long that by all reports the feral orks have grown far too strong for your comfort, weakened Subsector Aurelia…the machinations of that damned soul still ignites a fiery hatred within you. Still, Cyrus knows what he is doing.

[Warp Travel To Trontiux III: 67+5(Nearness)=72/100]
[Blood Trials of Trontiux III: 94+5(Cyrus Overseeing)=99/100)]

10th Company Fleet
Strike Cruisers: Faith's Horizon, Ravenous Spirit, Spiraling Fury
3 Escorts
Gains: 150 Blood Raven Aspirants

He returns with a truly astounding bounty. After several decades of not being drawn from, Trontiux III had quite a significant amount of worthy aspirants, after fighting on a diet of increasingly numerous feral orks. On that note, by the way, Cyrus says that even after authorizing orbital bombardment on open feral encampments that he feels that Trontiux III is still in a little bit more danger than he would like for your one viable Recruiting World. After which he declared that he would begin training his aspirants immediately. The sooner they ascend to neophytes, the sooner they can become scouts, and the sooner the Chapter will return to its full strength.

-------------------------------

It burns at your soul to know that this venerable ship has languished under Kyras’s presence for so long. When you received the order you leapt into action with a veritable fleet of servo skulls, all filled with various tools and actuators but even so it has taken far longer than you thought it should have. Pacifying the Machine Spirit of the Arcanum has required a ridiculously long list of rituals that you highly suspect was put there simply to frustrate you. On the other hand, maybe not, and your fraying patience is merely due to the unsettling feeling of a ship this large being so…empty.

This vessel should have carried serfs and aspirants and many men filling it, the blood to the machine's body. Instead, so far as you have found, the vast majority of this ships population was sacrificed by Kyras and his traitorous brethren. A population of sacrifices just waiting for him to take advantage, for more than two centuries. You have suffered too much to shudder like some common mortal, but all the same you do not like it. Even on Typhon there was never a truly silent moment. Constant noise has been your companion practically since you became a Techmarine, but this is something else entirely. The only noise is your servo harness and the servo skulls, this deep into the ship.

You don't like it. Still, you've been all over this ship, in every area you can think of that might have been the holder of some last 'present' of Kyras. The Hanger Bays are largely empty but that can be solved either through your own workings or from a Forge World, the relics are...all gone, which frustrates you endlessly. Either they were destroyed in the fighting, destroyed symbolically by Kyras or his followers, or given to said followers and have likely disappeared into the Warp. As it is, you are now proceeding to the last place that requires investigation and at the same time one of the most holy.

"Brother Gracchus, are you ready?" you call to the...the word mousey should never be used when referring to a space marine, and to be fair Brother Gracchus towers over any regular human, but for a space marine he is...short.

But you've seen his work, and you can respect him enough for that. His sheer knowledge and skill are why you called him here with you should the Chambers be damaged in some way that you cannot fathom.

"I am. I can only hope that they are not too damaged."

He doesn't see you grit your teeth from inside your helmet, but he does hear you growl.

"I have just spent forty seven straight hours opening the way, if the doors did not open twelve hours ago then surely Kyras never even managed to get in here."

You performed maintenance on the Implantation Chambers on both the lost Armageddon and the Retribution, so you are well aware that they are meant to be some of the toughest and most well protected parts of a ship in the Chapter, but that does not prevent you from being annoyed. Besides, no one can see inside your helmet anyway to see the faces you make. Like the one you are making right now as you cut off the speakers of your helmet to scream in frustration as the pad on the wall in front of you flashes red again.

Thankfully it only took another six hours of Gracchus standing around awkwardly before there was a heavy and final-sounding clunk and the last of the bulkhead sized doors begin to move.

"YES!" you shout with the speakers still off. Then, after flicking them back on, "Brother Gracchus, we may proceed."

"Very good, Martellus."

Then the vast Chambers are open...

[Omnis Arcanum Implantation Chambers: 1/100]

"No...no no no no!" Gracchus cries out in grief and pain.

You match him in this, but do not fall to your knees as he does. Even so, you have to lock your armor to prevent you from falling over as your eyes continue to gaze out. The Implantation Chambers of the Omnis Arcanum...are broken. No, that is not a strong enough word. Shattered? Ruined? You barely even look at the fallen Apothecary body, a long fallen brother likely fallen in defending this place based on the blood that has dried to brown at this point. But the tubes, the precious Gene-Seed, all the equipment, all of it, all it...

"Damn you Kyras! Damn you to hell!"

There is no evidence of bolter fire or anything else. It is as if...as if some invisible force simply swept through at some point and acted like a localized hurricane of force and death. Something that you have little doubt that the former Chief Librarian could do. God Emperor...how long have these Chambers been left like this, with none to know other than the tainted Galan? You feel fury. You feel rage.

But more than all of those, you feel grief.

Omnis Arcanum Implantation Chambers Heavily Damaged, Requires Repairs.
All Omnis Arcanum Gene-Seed: Lost

New Option Added:
Repair Omnis Arcanum Implantation Chambers: 500 BP Cost

-----------------------------

Grunting, you sit down heavily in the Space Marine grade chair, and even then it groans under the force of you nearly throwing yourself into it. It has been an exhausting few days as you reviewed the utterly abysmal state of Subsector Aurelia. Ever since you brought the Exterminatus to Cyrene and…and your father, you have spent the years travelling outside of Subsector Aurelia and largely the Korianis Sector in general. Perhaps you should have come back more often rather than recruiting from Rahe’s Paradise so often…perhaps you would have been more knowledgeable about this.

Thankfully, you have the aid of those who have yet to leave in the past decade and more. Still, it somewhat concerns you how Cyrus, Tarkus, and Martellus formed up around an invisible and not actually present fourth member initially before realizing their mistake. Aramus is still not here but you still catch them every now and then shifting as if expecting him to be there.

“We have much work to do,” you rumble to several nods.

Calderis is nearly lost to you, which is of immediate concern. 10% of the PDF remain viable, while the few remaining settlements to the humans on Calderis are under extreme threat. The Planetary Governor of Calderis is lost, his space station destroyed when what must have been Kaptin Bluddflag’s Kroozer passed by on its way to the planet. Feral orks have joined up with the remnants of WAAAGH! Smashface, and the erstwhile Kaptin is nowhere visible. Worse, the feral tyranids have begun swarming in great numbers due to the bounty of biomass that the orks offer, turning the world into a three way battle that – if nothing is done soon to preserve humanities place on that world – may turn into a more simple two way battle between xenos. [Calderis Requires Immediate Intervention Within 2 Years, Or Will Be Lost]

Meridian is holding on, as it ever has, but is undergoing issues. Because why wouldn’t it. Governor Derosa has yet to finish ripping the roots of her ongoing rebellious elements out, meaning that the lower levels are still inhabited by members of traitorous Guardsmen and PDF. Some might earnestly believe they are only doing the right thing in getting rid of Derosa due to her lack of a truly noble bloodline and taking the position from the traitorous Vandis – who even now remains at large – but their association with the Black Legion during the Second and Third Aurelian Crusade has irrevocably tainted their cause. Worse, there are still feral tyranids and orks of the notorious Blood Axe type running rampant through the lower hives and in a few isolated cases the Upper Hives. Meridian is also home to the legendary Angel Forge, a massive manufactorum complex that is essentially a miniature Forge World in one. It is from here that the sophisticated technologies used in defeating the tyranids in the First Aurelian Crusade were developed. Derosa has further approached you in that same regard. If you were to aid her in finally putting down the rebels and cleansing the tyranids and orks from her world she has offered an astonishing 5% production control interests in Angel Forge as well as her solemn promise of military aid from her own Imperial Guard forces should you require them in the future. [Opportunity: Cleanse Meridian of Orks/Tyranids/Rebels. Reward: 75 BP/Turn through Angel Forge. Major Favor From Governor Derosa of Meridian. Major Favor From Aurelian Guard Regiments]

Aurelia is also of great concern. The former capital of Subsector Aurelia is a danger to all, considering the fact that according to reports and the psychic efforts of your few Librarians indicate that while Ulkair the Great Unclean One was successfully banished by Aramus’s own hand, he remains still. Evidence gained during the Third Aurelian Crusade indicates that he was even capable of corrupting the many Guardsmen on the planet save for a small fraction, and as such the planet is no longer garrisoned as such. On the other hand…Aurelia was once the home of the Blood Ravens, so very long ago. While it has been ravaged by the Warp for a thousand years, the resilience of Astartes equipment is well known. More than that, before it was swallowed up by the warp it was one of the most technologically advanced Civilized Worlds in the Sector. Who knows what may yet linger on that forlorn orb, hidden beneath the ice? What you end up doing with the world is up to you, of course. Whether that is to simply pound it further into submission, allow for careful missions to the surface in search of salvage, or just patrol above it regularly is up to you.

Cyrene and Typhon Primaris…well. Suffering from Exterminatus is quite a status. Though lifeless, they are not incapable of being used as bases for dark forces as Kyras proved. You will likely have to put watch stations of some sort or at least patrol them regularly to prevent such a thing from occurring again.

The last matter, of course, is the Judgement of Carrion. One of the larger Space Hulks on record, and the sight of far too many dead Blood Ravens. It’s connection to your Chapter is most unwelcome, through Ulkair, through Kyras and Galan and the rest. Yet it is also there that through Aramus and his own forces – most dangerously none being armored in Terminator Armor – passed through multiple times. Recovering relics and gene-seed…many of which was lost during the Third Aurelian Crusade. You cannot imagine what Aramus might think of that should he ever hear of it from wherever he has gone into the Eye of Terror. As it is, the ominous amalgamation of ships remains as full of orks and tyranids as ever, and currently shows no signs of disappearing back into the Warp like it was assumed. Is it waiting for something? Aramus’s notes say that more than once it almost felt like the entire thing was…alive in some way or another. Still, secrets may yet lie within its confines, whether in the form or relics or ancient technologies, and you do not know if you can, as a Blood Raven, allow such knowledge to be destroyed.

That, of course, is it regarding the Subsector itself. As for the Chapter…things are grim. With your actions you have now three companies, none of which is at full strength. None of which has its own Command Squad. Morale is generally low, but has the same undercurrent of utter refusal to surrender that has colored it since Kyras truly revealed his intentions. You are simply missing so many people, for positions to be filled and more.

Specifically, you have no one, save perhaps Brother Priscus with a mind for commanding fleets. Which…does not necessarily mean you do not have options. Your long period as a Fleet-Based Chapter means that you could go looking amongst the Imperial Navy. After all, in rare cases, a Chapter's Master of the Fleet may not be an Astartes officer but a mortal with a long history of space combat and commanding fleet engagements, such as a former or current flag officer of the Imperial Navy who has been seconded to the Chapter under ancient inter-service agreements. You don’t…have any of those specifically referring to you laying around but Astartes-Navy agreements may exist that you could work with. It would take you actively searching for them, however.

Leadership wise, everyone feels just a slight bit lost. The Librarians, so high in number as to cause intense suspicion by other sectors of the Imperium…are now so few. With them went their guidance, but hopefully their numbers will rebuild in the future.

No. They will rebuild. They must.

Let None Find Them Wanting.

Lead Your Chapter
[] Select a Chief Apothecary (Available Candidates: Apothecary Romallius, Apothecary Gracchus, Apothecary Astophiles)
[] Send your brothers for Specialist Training
- [] Yes (Specify)
- [] No
[] Select a Master of the Fleet (Choose One)
-[] Available Blood Raven Candidates: Hadrian Priscus, Marcus Crixus
-[] Can Potentially Ask Imperial Navy For A Flag Officer To Serve As Master of Fleet. Getting One Is Not Guaranteed
[] Dealing With Calderis
-[] Dispatch Forces (Write-In)
-[] Do Not Dispatch Forces
[] Dealing With Meridian
-[] Dispatch Forces (Write-In)
-[] Do Not Dispatch Forces
[] Repair Omnis Arcanum Implantation Chambers: 500 BP Cost

Training With Apollo
Select One Of The Below To Train With Apollo’s Aid
[] Weapon Skill
[] Ballistic Skill
[] Agility

Know Your Chapter [Choose Two]
[] Inquire about the Korianis Sector

[] Inquire about Segmentum Ultima

[] Inquire about Segmentum Obscurus

[] Inquire about brothers in the Death Watch

[] Inquire about Chapter Fleet Issues (Repair opportunities, Supplies, etc.)

Turn 3 (Part One): Ragged Yet Unbroken

GM Note: Here's part one. Meridian and Calderis are going to be in part two, potentially three depending on how the battles go.

Ragged Yet Unbroken
+998.M41+
+While the enemies of the Emperor still draw breath, there can be no peace+

The galaxy is in turmoil, though it always seems to be these days. Faint astropath messages bounce across all five Segmentum carrying messages of despair and warning. Far, far away from you, Armageddon burns once again under the menace that is Ghazghkull. Already numerous Chapters have mobilized, heading into the war that rages one more in the Segmentum Solar. Worse news, of course, comes from the direction of the Eye of Terror. Numerous Space Hulks have begun appearing in a greater concentration than has ever been seen before, carrying warbands and madness with them. Some have even whispered of the fearsome Herald of Nurgle, Typhus, being on the march though such reports are uncorroborated. Chaos raider activity has absolutely skyrocketed, resulting in a mobilization of Imperial forces across the entire galaxy. Madmen and self-proclaimed prophets are calling it the end of days, while more cognizant analysts are saying that the chances of a 13th Black Crusade are terrifyingly on the rise.

But that is not the only thing that concerns you. When a splinter of Hive Fleet Leviathan reached the Aurelian Subsector, and the Korianis Sector in general, only a short time ago, none could have realized just how tremendous Leviathan would be. Even now vast curling tendrils of the disgusting xeno race pour through cracks in the Imperium’s defenses in tide of chitin and claw. Though the left ‘half’ of the Hive Fleet was crushed at Tarsis Ultra, according to reports, the right ‘half’ of its seemingly inevitable advance has trailed off into the Octarius systems, home to one of the most powerful and longest lasting Ork Empires that the Imperium has records of. Even so, just as the Imperium learned from previous Hive Fleets, splinters shall continue to float through the void and show up more likely than not at the worst possible times.

You find yourself, in this odd times, thinking of Aramus, surprisingly. The taint wafting off of him was enough to offend the sensibilities of the Librarians you had at the time without even a casual psychic scanning, but he had remained certain of his dedication to the Emperor and the Imperium. Jonah…before he was slain, had remarked that the young Force Commander had teetered back and forth atop the precipice of truly falling to Chaos more than any he had ever seen. But he hadn’t fallen, and accepted his charge to penance wholeheartedly. He had allowed his disturbingly powerful wargear – stinking of Chaos – to be destroyed, and had left. Towards the Eye of Terror.

Where, even now, a 13th Black Crusade may be beginning. Perhaps the enemy had thought to make their measures completely unknown, in order to appear from nowhere and gain the advantage of surprise, but whether by chance or skill of those already present that is no longer possible.

As for yourself, and the Blood Ravens besides…if a 13th Black Crusade truly does begin, will you travel to that oft-fought battlefield? Or stay here to recover your strength? You do not yet know the answer to that question, but the universe will more likely than not demand an answer sooner rather than later.

-------------------------------------------------

After careful review of the available information, you eventually select Brother Gracchus as Master of the Apothecarion. While he may not be the most combat capable space marine to ever exist, you do not need him for his combat abilities. You need him for his medical expertise, for his skills and experience in watching over the Gene-Seed for any signs of taint and for the best possible implantation procedures. He accepts his position quickly, but given the current state of the Implantation Chambers on the Arcanum he currently resides on the Litany of Fury. But he is not the only specialist you deal with, sending those marines who might possess extra-normal talents. Hannibal is interested in having a student, and having more Chaplains is going to be of utmost importance in the years going forward. The spiritual and mental fortitudes of the Chapter are of highest authority. Ares Actus doesn’t quite impress Hannibal, but he isn’t rejected outright. Then again few things actually ‘impress’ Hannibal anyway. Even so, learning all that has to be learned will take time. Though, at the least, learning to be a true Chaplain will take less than the thirty standard years that Quarius Zergan must take after being checked over for Martellus for true skill.

The ship that arrives to take him departs within the same day, apparently thanks to an especially good warp current. Perhaps if he turns out to be especially skilled, he will return sooner, but you do not dare to hope for such things while there are matters to be dealt with closer to home.

Ares Actus: Chaplain Training [1/5] Years Until Complete
Quarius Zergan: 30 Years Standard Until Complete

Speaking of ships, you have selected amongst your depressingly small pool of candidates a new Master of the Fleet. Traditionally, the position would also be given over to the 4th Company Captain, but there isn’t a 4th Company in existence at the moment. Their battle cry ‘Victory Over Death’ which they garnered after Kronus seems to have fallen fallow. As it is, however, you may lack brothers but you do not lack ships. Hadrian Priscus accepts his position humbly, and immediately begins getting a feel for the Chapter Fleet through maneuvers and firing exercises, but he does note privately to you that getting the rest of the ships repaired would help things along quite extensively. Besides that, however, he openly makes use of his new position to rearrange the Fleet to better suit the current circumstances of the Chapter – though as Chapter Master you would technically be within your rights to demand he readjust things to another manner.

Fleet Master Reassigns Chapter Fleet:
1st Company Fleet – Omnis Arcanum, Ravenous Spirit, Spiraling Fury, x3 Gladius Frigates, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova Frigates
5th Company Fleet – Litany of Fury, Rage of Erudition, x2 Gladius Frigates, x1 Hunter Destroyers, x1 Nova Frigate
10th Company Fleet - Faith's Horizon, x2 Gladius Frigate, x2 Nova Frigates

Still, it is truly a tragedy that The Observer was lost. The 2nd Company’s Battle Barge shall be sorely missed.

--------------------------------------------
[Training With Apollo – Agility From 4 to 5: 0+90=97/500]

Hissing, you shift back and dodge the buzzing teeth of the chainsword that would have taken your head off, readjusting your grip on your own practice weapon, a simulacrum of Godsplitter and swinging it forward. The move is slow, slower than it used to be, but still far faster than a regular mundane human could possibly manage. Your bionics grind against your flesh but you work past the feeling, to grow used to it. You cannot afford for this life saving machinery to actually be a detriment to your combat abilities.

Apollo, on the other hand, is practically a blur as he dodges beneath the blow and rises up in front of you to rear back with the shock glove. Had it been a regular power fist it might have pulped your uncovered head, but you just barely manage to get your elbow up in time to knock him aside. But he merely slams his foot onto the ground hard enough to propel the whole of his armored frame up into the air for an overhead slash that – had you not scooted yourself to the left – split you in two.

Or at least, it would if the chainsword’s teeth were not purposefully dulled and your hammer bereft of a power field that would pulp not just what it struck but everything in the general area of the strike. Still, the point of the spar is making things quite clear indeed. The spry flesh that you possessed before is having trouble working alongside the bionics that Martellus provided you. It is not a slight against the Techmarines work, rather against your own body for utterly refusing to adjust like you want

But you are changing that. Slowly but surely, you are forcing your body to relearn itself, and with it you are growing just that fraction faster with each day of training. Perhaps, someday, you will return to as fast as you were before. It would be possible to, perhaps, ask Martellus now that he is in a more relaxed setting and not frantically trying to preserve your life to the point that you would not have to go into a dreadnought to carefully craft more powerful and sophisticated bionics. Perhaps. For now, however, you are focused on ensuring that what flesh remains to you can pick up the slack in the meantime. At the least, you are making significant progress.

---------------------------------------------

It is good that you selected a Master of the Fleet beforehand, and it is thanks to Hadrian at all that you are able to collect the information you require. The news is…not fantastic. The ships that are viable and not viable you are aware of, but you were unsure of just how to solve the problem. The Blood Ravens do not actually possess a shipyard in system, instead making use of your allies at the Forgeworld designated Zerann 52X1, of whom you actually have a close agreement with due to some Blood Ravens even now being on one of their Explorator Missions, which you had not been aware of. It was locked, this mission, under the authority of the Secret Masters of whom there are none now. That secret order within the Chapter is no more, according to its handful of surviving members, and not even they could recall just why the file was locked.

More importantly, you have learned just how many Drop Pods are missing, along with ammo stocks and the cost of such damages. Hadrian confers with Martellus, and bring back the news. The ships you have are salvageable, but it will take time to tow them to Zerann. As in, due to their inability to travel through the warp for any long period of time and the sheer damage dealt to them, at least two years just to get them to Zerann. Even then, the cost may be immense, though if you are lucky you may be able to work out some form of equivalent exchange with the Forgeworld. Given your own production capacity, it is highly likely that it will have to be the former. You are not personally opposed to aiding the Adeptus Mechanicus, but it would be quite a demand on your Chapter.

Additionally, through astropath communications Hadrian has discussed with Zevran 52X1’s current Archmagos Bertrand Orior about commissioning full on replacement ships and what it would cost to do so.

All Damaged Fleet Ships Require Forgeworld Facilities To Be Repaired.
Damage Cost: 12,050 BP of Exchange To Repair All (Can Be Paid Over Time, Will Repair Ships According To That Amount) OR Through Favor Exchanges

Battle Barge Scientia Est Potentia – 5,000 BP –2 Major Favors, 2 Minor Favors
Strike Cruiser - The Great Father's Fist – 2400 BP – 1 Major Favor, 2 Minor Favors
Strike Cruiser - The Howling Hatred– 2450 BP – 1 Major Favor, 1 Minor Favor
Strike Cruiser - Burning Seeker – 2200 BP – 1 Major Favor, 1 Minor Favor

[As in, pay 500 BP, repair 500 BP of damage that turn until ship repaired]
Zevran 52X1 Ship Prices Added To Front Page

--------------------------------------------------------------

You yourself never had the honor of being in the Deathwatch, but that does not preclude you from having relations with them. With the aid of Cyrus and your new Chief Librarian searching through the meticulous and incredibly thorough records of the Librarium you search for what brothers remain to you outside of the Chapter itself. Those who are on assignment with one of Zerann 52X1’s Explorator Missions are one thing, but those of your brothers who have been in the Deathwatch are another.

Kyras assumed leadership of the Chapter over two centuries ago, but was a member of it for far longer. You’ve purged all those traitor Blood Ravens who were present in the here and now, but you are less certain on those who were outside of Subsector Aurelia during the Third Aurelian Crusade. Questions of how far his influence spread will plague you likely for the rest of your life, whether it was his dealings with other organizations in the Imperium or with who knows what else. Still, you must banish such thoughts while you review those out on assignment.

Chaplain Uther Volkoss is, by your reckoning, the last living member of the 7th Company before the Third Aurelian Crusade claimed their lives in the brutal purge fighting. His company was largely loyalist, but those of the 7th who were traitors planted bombs at numerous locations amongst the 7th Company Fleet which claimed those same loyal lives as well as their supply of Gene-Seed. According to the records, he began his Vigil in the year 900.M41 at Watch Fortress Oertha, and his time of return was originally slated for the conclusion of the first decade of the new millennium. His records further note that he was, when he left, a staunch proponent of battling the forces of Chaos in excess of what Kyras allowed, perhaps that is why he left? Reports from the Deathwatch of his progress indicate that he is a skilled and welcomed addition, having crushed numerous Tau incursions onto the embattled world where his Watch Station is. Also, by your inquiries, the Deathwatch is requesting that he remain at Oertha until the Tau are finally defeated. [+Toughness, Black Dervish]

Epistolary Vaikos Adracus is one of the last members of the original 1st Company. This…is not a good thing, necessarily. Almost the totality of the 1st Company had been corrupted by the time of the Third Aurelian Crusade. Worse, his Vigil began a comparatively short time ago, meaning that the question of loyalty regarding him is quite nebulous indeed. At the same time, he is an extremely powerful Librarian in direct combat both physical and psychic though notes indicate that he actually had a slight deficiency in the foresight and veil piercing abilities most usually prized by your Librarum. And Kyras was a master at hiding his own true nature until it was almost too late…but regardless, you now have your information. He, like Brother Volkoss, is stationed at Watch Fortress Oertha and has been requested to extend his vigil beyond 50.M42 when he was slated to return in order to beat back the damndable Tau. [+Strength, Psychic Devastation]

Tomb-Brother Palkair on the other hand, is well known to you. Interred in a dreadnought over three centuries before Kyras even joined the Blood Ravens all that time ago, he is a venerable ancient of the 4th Company. Brother Palkair received his mortal wounds in the 8th Black Crusade and was interred in an incredible and holy Ironclad-pattern Dreadnought. He would serve the 4th Company with great distinction for several centuries until the last of his ‘generation’ as it were amongst the Chapter finally died or were interred in dreadnoughts themselves. Ever since that point, Brother Palkair would be harder and harder to awaken until finally he could not be roused for over a thousand years. This changed when the last of his brothers – also interred in a dreadnought – was slain in the year 700.M41, whereupon Palkair demanded the right to serve with the Deathwatch presumably forever out of grief. He is the absolute oldest Blood Raven alive, and currently resides at Watch Fortress Erioch where by the records of the Ordo Xenos that you are granted access to he has been a welcome ally against the eternal Xeno threat. He is also the only Blood Raven alive to have been a native of the planet Aurelia before it was sucked into the Warp for a thousand years. [Eldest Blood Raven, Ironclad Dreadnought]

Brother Micheal Castigon is an experienced Devastator Marine of the 6th Company who was ascended from a regular battle brother to a full Kill Team Leader while part of the Deathwatch. The 6th Company was, however, almost entirely traitorous though that is not saying much considering the fact that it was one of those Companies that was obliterated in the Kaurava Campaign due to Captain Boreale’s usage of the Steel Rain tactic against the now eternal foe of the Chapter who Captain Thule faced in the Dark Crusade – Gorgutz 'Ead 'Unter. Even so, Brother Castigon joined the Deathwatch before that Campaign occurred…though regardless he has no specifically stated time of return. There is no stated reason for that, which is somewhat suspicious. His Vigil at Watch Fortress Phaedas began in 950.M41 has led, by reports on his progress, to face many a dark and twisting thing in the Jericho Reach. [+Ballistic Skill, Slayer Of The Dark]

Brother Uriel Hamul is, as Epistolary Adracus, one of the last surviving members of the 1st Company. An Assault Marine, he was a veteran indeed and unlike Epistolary Adracus is known to Apollo personally from when Apollo was stationed as the Captain of the 1st Company. It was by Apollo’s personal recommendation after becoming the Captain of the Honor Guard that Brother Hamul give his services to the Deathwatch after he expressed dissatisfaction with how Kyras had commanded the 1st Company to refrain from many a battle in favor of other Companies. A little battle lust is not a bad thing for a battle brother to possess, though it can be tipped over easily. Like Volkoss and Adracus he is stationed at Watch Fortress Oertha, and like them he has been requested by the Deathwatch to remain at Oertha to battle against the Tau who crumble easily against his methods of attack – by which that means melee. If your permission in this is not granted it is possible that he would return in 5.M42, not too long a time. [+Agility, The Eager Killer]

The Chapter is incredibly weak at the moment, and could likely benefit from the experience of such Blood Ravens, but at the moment their participation in the operations of the Ordo Xenos is the only thing keeping that same Ordo from regarding you as the Ordo Malleus and Ordo Hereticus. What you do next…will require some concentrated thought.

Turn 3 (Part Two): Ragged Yet Unbroken

GM NOTE: I am...just, so tired right now. Here's this, if there's issues I'll fix them...whenever it is I wake up.

Ragged Yet Unbroken
+998.M41+
+While the enemies of the Emperor still draw breath, there can be no peace+

While you deal with the Chapter proper, what meagre forces the Blood Ravens possess go out yet again to safeguard the Imperium’s interests in Subsector Aurelia. The 1st Company which…currently does not possess a Captain, is directed down to the Calderis surface though due to your proximity in the Arcanum you can direct the battle as you see fit from orbit. As for the troubles facing Meridian, Tarkus takes the 5th and 10th Companies to the Hive World to aid Governor Derosa. She has been a constant ally to the Chapter after Vandis’s treachery was revealed, and the Blood Ravens cannot afford to lose what few allies they possess in these dark and uncertain days.

[Meridian Task Force Warp Travel: 91/100]

It is honestly a miracle that all the rapid warp travel between the various worlds of the Subsector that occurred during the Aurelian Crusades did not end in disaster at least once. On the other hand, Aramus only possessed a single Strike Cruiser and two escort vessels at the time, thereby reducing the profile of his journeys. The same cannot be said for the 5th and 10th Company as they make their way to Meridian. All those ships open up numerous rends in purplish pink space before disappearing…and reappearing with quite impressive speed indeed with no major losses. Worryingly, however, a message from Epistolary Maphar indicates that the Gellar Fields were certainly being strained more than he would find ‘normal’. You find yourself in the unenviable place of wondering if the activity at the Eye of Terror is capable of affecting the warp even here.

But then they got down to business. While Cyrus is still training the Aspirants that does not mean he is not on the ship itself, and so he is able to coordinate with Tarkus who takes command of the ground forces of the 5th Company as well as the recently made full Battle Brother Jacobus who leads the 10th Company. According to Cyrus, he was most put out that almost immediately after becoming a full space marine that he was instructed by Cyrus and Tarkus to take off his new armor and put his scout armor back on. At the least such dissatisfaction was mitigated by being granted use of one of the few relics your Chapter has left – which silenced all protests immediately.

The Governor’s Palace Gardens were graced by the arrival of the Thunderhawks of the 5th and 10th Company, and after a short meeting with Governor Derosa and Epistolary Maphar careful plan was established. Starting from the Palace, Tarkus and Brother Jacobus would thoroughly enforce order through bolter fire and more until the entire Upper Hive was fully reclaimed. The 5th Company, led by Tarkus, would move openly against the enemy while the 10th Company would make use of their training to stealthily destroy Traitor Guard depots and assassinate Rebel Leaders.

--------------------------------------------------------------------

“Derosa the Drudge is nothing but a pretender! Listening to her lies is an affront to the Emperor, my brothers!”

Dozens of medals clinked wildly against the former PDF general as he strode back and forth across the stage, watched by the thousands of his troops directly and the tens of thousands more through pict-capture broadcasts. With one hand he absentmindedly brandished his solid gold plated bolt pistol, and in the other he alternatively fist pumped or performed all a manner of jerky movements.

“When our true Lord, Governor Vandis, left to personally secure support for Meridian, what did his supposedly faithful Administrator do?! She claimed that he was a traitor himself, and took forcible command of this world! Well I say, no more!”

The cheers were deafening from the PDF troopers as they raised their arms and howled at the damn common-blooded creature who lurked in the Governor’s Palace as if it were her own.

“Yes, I have heard your concerns over our alliances with the Traitor Guard, those who serve Chaos, but fear not, my wonderful warriors, as soon as Derosa is deposed, and Vandis returns as promised with true Imperial Allies and not the traitorous and tainted Blood Ravens,” he sneered at the name of the Chapter, a sneer matched and eclipsed by hisses and booing, “We shall be rewarded ten-fold! Then, then we can fight those bastards, and bring them to heel. But for now, our true enemy is Derosa! Death to Derosa!”

“Death to Derosa!” went the cry, nearly shaking the ground itself from the volume.

Which was why no one noticed the first few bombs going off. Or why, from a full two miles away, Jacobus sternly instructed the Scout who lay on his belly to take the shot. Who promptly, despite possessing a holy sniper rifle alongside training and abilities far above a simple human being, missed, only the volume of the crowd preventing anyone from noticing the shot go wide or that there had been a shot at all. Growling, Jacobus pulled his own weapon off of his back and fired himself. Even if it had been a simple mortal human the shot was easy enough, and so with a single high pitched whine and ‘thump’ one of the most popular rebel general’s found that just about everything from the pectorals up exploded into a rain of gore to the horrified screams of his army.

Of course, they screamed more when the rest of the bombs went off and plunged them all into a wild firestorm of promethium. The scent of thousands of traitors burning to death was a sweet scent indeed.

“We aren’t done here, scout marine. We have more traitors to kill.”

Then they were gone, though across the Upper Hives whole teams of scouts were performing similar actions. Sniper rifles boomed, trapped roadways obliterated marching enemy armored columns, and leaders found themselves getting stabbed in the neck by one particularly annoyed Brother Jacobus who could not believe that he had gotten to worn his new armor for approximately ten minutes before being told to take it off again for likely an entire campaign. He wasn’t even that opposed to wearing the scout carapace again, he knew he was good at it, but it didn’t stop him from being annoyed.

So he took it out on the enemy. Again. And again. And again. The Unseen Demise of the Vain indeed.

-----------------------------------

“Is this correct, Brother Maphar?” Tarkus knew that it was likely the truth, but he still wanted the Librarian to confirm it for him audibly.

“Yes, Brother Tarkus. Under Brother Jacobus, the 10th Company is frankly tearing both the rebels and the Traitor Guard apart. He is showing a surprising grasp of command of the scouts, though that may be due to him having been one a mere moment ago. And with them faltering, the Black Legion forces remaining on the planet have begun to move…”

The Epistolary’s eyes shuttered closed as he hummed, and Tarkus leaned back slightly as psychic light whipped and frayed the air about the psyker.

“Yes. They are not moving up, they are moving down. Into the lower hives, where they will be almost utterly hidden by the sheer volume of life and filth down there. Even my own abilities may not be enough. Already they are taxed…they may have psykers of their own,” Gracchus frowned.

The Captain of the 5th Company frowned as well, and turned away to gaze at the charnel abattoir that the 5th Company had crafted out of the largest of the Traitor Guard encampments. A heavily tainted Leman Russ tank with sigils drawn out in blood and other bodily fluids that had burned with unnatural light had been flipped entirely onto its side before having a hole blasted through its underside, and it was at that tank that Tarkus narrowed his eyes.

“No. No mere psykers could have granted the Traitor Guard these kinds of tainted and darkly empowered arms. The Black Legion has with them a Sorcerer.”

“Well then. We must pursue them then.”

“Indeed, Librarian. We cannot allow a Sorcerer to have time to do anything. At the least, our efforts here have reclaimed the Upper Hives. If Derosa and Merrick cannot maintain order here then they are not the same allies they were during the Aurelian Crusades.”

And so the 5th Company began to march, soon joined by a 10th Company that melted out of the shadows to join them.

Upper Hives Reclaimed, Traitor Guard and Rebel Guard Largely Defunct (Clean Up Operations Available)
Black Legion descending to Lower Hives of Meridian, Signs Point To Leader Being A Sorcerer (Unconfirmed)
5th and 10th Company in pursuit.

---------------------------------------------

[Calderis Task Force – Perceiving The Warp (Tyranids): 85]
[Calderis Task Force – Perceiving The Warp (Feral Orks): 31]
[Calderis Task Force – Perceiving The Warp (Non-Feral Orks): 9]

The warp was not very compliant, Justinius mused, but he was no mere Epistolary. He was the Chief Librarian of the Blood Ravens, and if the warp would not be compliant he would make it so. A dangerous procedure and a potentially fatal one – but that was the nature with all things relating to that twisting realm. While his eyes saw beyond the Materium’s boundaries his hands tapped and wrote, scrawling the nature of what he saw. Much of it would have to be discarded, obviously, for wild whispers and meaningless babble, but there would be a few kernels of truth here and there.

The tyranids…though feral they might be compared to a true Splinter or even Hive Fleet had slowly begun to concentrate at one of the last vestiges of the 1st Aurelian Crusade. Biomass gathered from across the planet had been dragged to the pits there…and Justinius did not like the way he could feel nodal creatures congregating there. The towers that the tyranids would have used to harvest the planet were never fully completed, but the remains of one…deep in the eastern desert where no Calderisian tread, even the hardiest, traveled. Yes, that was where the tyranids were based. They could not be allowed to fully reconnect a synaptic web, even one made up of just synapse forms. They could not afford another Tyrant or worse, whatever that…thing was that the Cadian’s slew.

Of the feral orks, they were far too chaotic to garner any true information on their goals. On the other hand, being orks ascribing much beyond looking for a fight was not worth much. Still, Argus was one of the last remaining settlements on Calderis and its tens of thousands of inhabitants had been largely eclipsed by the number of refugees coming in from all across the world – pushed there by ork and tyranid threats. They had claimed some of the hardy cliffs far to the northeast of Argus, and made their fortress there.

Of the infamous Kaptin Bluddflag however…he could find no sign. Or rather, he found plenty of signs, but none that pointed to the location of the Freebooter. Instead, it seemed as if the Kaptin had been all over the planet, visiting numerous feral ork encampments and leaving shortly after. He hadn’t assaulted either Argus or any of the other struggling human settlements nor had he attacked the tyranids. Justinius did not like it. An ork capable of not immediately pursuing the largest possible target did not engender the best thoughts for the future. As it was, the 1st Company would have to deal with what targets that could be examined and planned for.

---------------------------------------------

Macharius rubbed his chin at the sight of the charging horde of greenskins. Slightly turning his head, the slug that would have clipped him instead bounced off of his left pauldron and then into who knew where. The devastator sergeant rolled his neck before grunting and then heaving both heavy bolters upwards with a groan of his bionics. Behind him, a bevy of tired looking serfs lugged forward the ammo for the holy weapons so that he could rapidly reload. All around him the rest of his devastators readied their own weapons, largely rapid fire weaponry. The feral’s had no armored units worth considering, and so they had prepared accordingly.

“Battle Brothers of the 1st Company! Let us remind these pathetic wastes of flesh that Calderis is now, and forever, a world of the Imperium!”

“LET NONE FIND US WANTING!” he bellowed, a cry taken up by the rest of his brothers.

Then he pressed the firing studs, as did three full squads of veteran 1st Company Devastator Marines. While he could easily lift and wield two heavy bolters with ease, others were not so capable, yet on the whole…more than two dozen heavy bolters fired at about the same time.

It was curiously enjoyable to watch orks quite nearly evaporate when enough bolter rounds struck them.

--------------------------------------------

Argus was where almost everyone had gone, but of the four other remaining fiefdoms left on Calderis, Lord Astoph surely felt that it was his beloved land that was under the most assault. As evidenced by the chitin covered beasts of the stars. It was said that the Angels fought them before and drove them away, but he was not so sure. Of course, it was blasphemy to doubt the Angels, they of the Bloody Raven, but he had seen so much death in the past decade since his father fell. Still, he refused to falter, not here, not when there were so few of his people left. A crash against the gates to the keep, however, made him flinch. It had seemed a good idea at the time to join the front, to prove to the people that their leaders were no cowards, but now he was trapped and he was going to die here, just like his father had. Where were the Angels?

Then the gates crashed again, and a mail covered hand clasped his shoulder.

“Take heart, lad, we’ll show them they shall find no wimpering prey,” his oldest friend and Master of Arms said with a smile.

“I..I hope so, Karl. I just…there were so many…”

Karl, a man thirty years his senior and the magnificent beard to prove it, sighed and clapped his shoulder one last time before unsheathing his sword. Even now it glowed with the strange light of its makers, the holy Bloody Angels. Granted to his family almost three centuries ago. Astoph shook his head and readied himself as well, gazing out at the walls where even now desperate armsmen fired arrows and slung stones uselessly against the creatures facing them. They had learned early on that there was little they had that could face them, but it was symbolic really, to show that they refused to give up.

Then a blast of light was heard and Astoph sucked his teeth slightly at the sight of the foreign monster’s magic as a green and white ball of death struck part of the wall, melting a dozen men and a hefty chunk of the wall itself. The deafening clattering and hissing from outside the walls that had been a backdrop to his sleep for the past few days grew louder.

“Well,” Karl mused, “That’s not heartening.”

“How can you be so…calm?! We’re about to die!?”

“Then we die in the name of the Bloody Ravens and the holy Emperor,” Karl shrugged. “Chin up lad, they’ll probably make it quick.”

The gate crunched again, and again, and Astoph helplessly shut his eyes when it finally exploded inward in a splash of splinters and charging monsters.

“For the Emperor!” Karl shouted, and then they charged in.

Or they would have, had a giant metal thing not slammed into the leading monsters from beyond the stars, had huge slabs of itself pop outwards to pulp more of them, and then-

“The Angels!” he shouted despite himself. “The Angels are here!”

Light so bright it nearly blinded him flew from their weapons and where the Angels strode, the beasts fell. One of the holy giants strode towards them, pausing only to dodge a swiping claw that could have bisected two men and kicked outward, sending it flying. A strange tube of glowing metal – almost crossbow like only far larger – rose up and from it spat a wondrously cleansing light which struck the monster’s head and practically disintegrated it.

Then the Angel was there, standing in front of them.

“The Emperor protects,” it uttered, and then turned away to continue the battle. Words, words he did not understand then flowed from the Angel as it descended into the carnage, and Karl had to help him to his feet.

Lord Astoph did not know what a ‘Thunderhawk’ was or why they were performing various maneuvers elsewhere that he did not see, but he could only assume that they were being helpful. He had already known that his sometime rival and sometime ally in Lord Sarkiss had been overwhelmed not a month ago by this same horde which was now being destroyed in front of his very eyes.

----------------------------------------------------------------------------

“Positions marked. Feral Ork encampments confirmed by 1st Company recon efforts and that the Chief Librarian.”

Hadrian nodded from the Throne, twitching slightly at the still unfamiliar connectors making him so much more than a simple space marine. Making him a Battle Barge. Only not. It was…confusing to his mind, but he had faith he would adapt. He had to. The Chapter Master had entrusted him as such.

“Tyranid bio-form concentrations confirmed as well. Positions marked,” said another helmsman without looking up from his console.

“So be it,” the Master of the Fleet intoned. “Let Calderis taste cleansing fire.”

Bombardment weapons across the entire 1st Company Fleet opened up, and warmed in the stark void above the slowly spinning world beneath them. The largest battle barge in the Chapter, accompanied by two strike cruisers, imperiously gazed through cogitators and firing solutions at the desert planet. Then, a twitch, a signal, a command unspoken through their Master, and they began to fire. Entire orkish encampments were scorched to slag within moments, while the tyranids found their precious collections of bio-mass torched into nonexistence.

Then the second salvo fired.

Then the third.

“We have time,” Hadrian murmured wryly. “Why not make it thorough?”

4/5 of remaining Calderis’s Feudal Zones Protected. 1 of 5 Destroyed [Signs point to presence of slug throwing weaponry and vehicles, indicating presence of Kaptin Bluddflag]. Tyranids greatly reduced in number due to heavy orbital bombardment. Feral orks greatly reduced in number due to heavy orbital bombardment.

Meridian Tactical Command
[] Write In
Calderis Tactical Command
[] Write In

Turn 3 (Part Three): Ragged Yet Unbroken

GM Note: Sorry about the delay guys. School and muses make for sporadic…ness. Anyway, last part of Turn 3, huzzah! Turn 4 will be in the year 999.M41….the dawn of the 42 Millennium is just over the horizon…

Ragged Yet Unbroken
+998.M41+
+While the enemies of the Emperor still draw breath, there can be no peace+

Neroth snarled as yet more pathetic ‘gangers’ dared to assault his forces for treading in the mass of hovels they claimed as territory. Had it been any other day, any other world, he would have relished the looks on their faces from haughty defiance to stark terror as they realized that they faced servants of the Dark Gods. Of how with a single gesture he ripped their hearts and spines apart and with another he lanced forth bolts of explosive warpfire which melted bodies and souls alike. The song of corrupted bolters firing would have been pleasant to the ears were they not being wasted against foes that were merely barring their way.

Another explosion rocked the streets of the hive, krak missiles coming down and obliterating the defensive position that his supplicants had so hastily constructed, sending a handful of cultists flying and knocking one of his few remaining marines to the ground. At the least, that one was blessed by nurgle, and so despite half of their armor being blown away and revealing putrid hanging flesh they stood and hefted the heavy bolter they wielded once more to lay down covering fire.

“That damned fool Eliphas, may his soul burn forever in the Basilica of Torments!” Neroth hissed to himself, hands frantically weaving another warp rift. He needed time to craft the proper paths so that what meagre remnants of the short lived Lord of the Black Legion’s warband could escape, time that the Blood Ravens seemed most determined not to let them have.

What a pathetic excuse for an operation this had become. Neroth’s chanting grew intense as he tried to pull apart the warp, only to growl in fury as another presence intruded. A psyker…daring to defy him? To defy the Black Legion!? Then with an opening salvo of bolter fire and plasma weaponry, he realized just how that was possible.

The Blood Ravens had finally gotten close enough.

“Strike with fury! FOR THE EMPEROR!”

“NONE SHALL FIND US WANTING!”

Neroth gave one final mighty push, straining to rip open the warp, before like an anvil the intruding presence on his ritual broke the entire thing apart. The nine carefully devised ritual circles were scattered – the entrails of the sacrifices used to mark it whipping apart as the warp screamed in outrage and tore apart the nascent tunnel. The backlash was immediate, and Neroth bit back a scream as the fires of the warp tore across his body, scorching his flesh and portions of bone beneath.

Then it exploded, a half formed daemon popping into and out of existence in the blink of an eye and sending Neroth flying backwards to slam into a nearby wall. All around him the rest of the warband turned to focus on the new threat, the gangers forgotten as the nuisances they were as loyalists appeared from the far side of the street. At their head strode both a heavily armored captain wielding a bolter that Neroth could feel the history of…as well as a marine clad in blue and carrying a force staff in one hand.

Fury bubbled up within him. The entire mission had been a mistake from the beginning, a failure twice over given command over his warband, trapped in the Subsector by Kyras and the Blood Ravens alike, and now this?

“Kain!” Neroth called as he wrenched himself out of the wall and summoned his staff to his hands, “Destroy them!”

The aspiring champion did not even dignify the order with a response, instead screaming his lungs out and sprinting towards the Blood Ravens with chainaxes in each hand. The loyalist captain immediately shifted fire, but had to dodge out of the way of the wild berserker charge as Kain leapt into the heart of the enemy ranks. Neroth, instead of facing them, turned back to his shattered ritual site.

“I will not die here, not for Eliphas, not even for the Despoiler!” he muttered, summoning the powers of the warp once again despite the torturous pain wracking him.

He had lived for millennia, and in all that time he had suffered far worse than this.

“Brother Maphar! The Sorcerer!” called out one of the Blood Ravens, but Neroth did not turn. He refused to die here, he would live, and he would have his revenge, on Eliphas, on the Blood Ravens, on every world in the blasted subsector!

“I see – guagh!”

“Blood for the Blood God!”

“Brother Maphar! No! Damn you!”

Had Neroth possessed the mind to do it, he would have loved to have expended the effort to smile at the curdling scream of the Librarian. As it was, he required all his effort here. He twisted and ripped at the warp – no longer in order to create a channel that could carry the rest of the warband, but only himself. The rest were but insects…and replacable. He, on the other hand, was most certainly not. He did not flinch when the first bolter shells began to impact against his back, for the ritual….was complete, the death and carnage of his servants serving enough for a crude yet viable rift.

He turned back and looked, just one more time, to see what remained of his servants die. Veterans of the Horus Heresy, Chaos Space Marines that eclipsed the age of even the oldest Blood Ravens, all dying like dogs. Bereft of resupply, forced on the run, and now this, all for the mad ambitions of Eliphas who simply had to die in battle against the Blood Ravens in the initial weeks of his mission, handed down from the Despoiler himself. With a loud boom, a sniper round from the distance slammed into his shoulder, destroying the whole area around the impact and sending his left arm splattering to the ground. Neroth howled, and delayed no longer. With a vicious ripping motion with his staff, the rift opened just long enough for him to step within – yet even he was not fast enough for another round to come and crack into one of his knees causing an explosion of gore and bone and leaving him with only two functional limbs. Snarling, he nevertheless threw himself through, and the warp swallowed him just as a third round flew exactly where his head was. Instead, the warp flashed away leaving only the materium behind and the round flew and created a small crater in the ground where it struck.

------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Tarkus frowned as the sorcerer escaped, but his attention was also busy with directing his forces to clearing out the last of the Black Legion. His eyes flickered towards the Librarian Maphar, and the apothecary frantically working to keep him alive, then back towards the one who would have slain the 10th Companies Epistolary had Brother Jacobus been a hair slower. The aspiring champion had died with cries to the Dark Gods on his lips, yet they had not stopped the sniper round from screaming into the head of that dark twisted thing that might have once served the Emperor in another life. The thump of approaching power armor made him look up to see the grimacing and newly promoted Jacobus hefting his sniper rifle.

“I apologize, Captain Tarkus. If I had taken the shot earlier…”

“What matters is that you slew him, Jacobus,” Tarkus replied as he stood, clasping a hand on his brothers pauldron. “Now, it is up to Apothecary Astophiles.”

Speaking of which, the two walked over to the formerly white armored healer who finally sat back, the whole of the front of his armor liberally splattered with the blood of his patient and those he had cut down earlier.

“Will he live?”

“He’ll be all right…though he’ll need a new arm. This one is too mangled even for my expertise.”

As if to prove him right, the now one armed Epistolary opened his eyes again and began to struggle to his feet.

“I apologize for worrying you Captain,” he said ruefully, his own specialized biology quickly clotting a wound that would slay a mortal man and allowing him to think clearly – or more correctly to simply ignore the pain.

“It is no matter,” Tarkus shook his head, “We’re done here. The Traitor Guard, the Rebels, this Warband, they are all finished.”

“The sorcerer escaped,” Jacobus pointed out, but Tarkus would have none of it.

“He has no forces, and ran from here. We shall remain on planet to see if he attempted to simply relocate during mop up operations, but more likely than not the cockroach has completely fled the sector after seeing their plans fall apart so – but we shall be wary, they will no doubt return some day.”

Great Victory: Chaos Warband Destroyed, Aspiring Champion Kain and Plague Champion Varius Slain, Chaos Sorcerer Neroth heavily wounded. Epistolary Maphar lost his left arm, will need Bionic Replacement. New Available Operation – The Cleansing of Meridian.

----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
[Calderis Task Force – Tracking The Green Tide (Feral Orks): 14]
[Calderis Task Force – Tracking The Green Tide (Non-Feral Orks): 1]

He was the Chief Librarian of the Blood Ravens…and he was starting to get frustrated. His eyes fluttered behind closed eyelids as willpower and effort struggled to force their way through the mire that had become of the warp in Subsector Aurelia lately. The raw psychic forces billowing about his being would have driven a simple mortal mad on sight and torn them to wet shreds to boot. Again he attempted to pierce the veil of the future, to commit fully to the battle sight….only to find himself stymied once again. He did not know what that meant, only that he had failed…again.

It had been weeks and weeks, but still he continued to come up against an impossible mosaic of futures. None of which rang true. He was quite sure that being granted a maddening series of potential truths and futures was far worse than being stymied by a blank and impassible fugue. Or perhaps that was the frustration talking. Either way, despite his attempts to pierce the veil and furthermore the best efforts of practically the whole of the entire Blood Raven forces assigned to Calderis at the moment he had been entirely unable to find the orks.

Or at least, the orks he was attempting to find. Some blinding green corona hung over the planet, tainted with remnants of the Hive Mind and the more psychic capable forms of the infesting tyranids who remained even now. Far greater in presence however were the orks.

The First Company had shifted from defense to offense, and in the process were dealing more damage to the reeling feral orks and tyranids of whom many still lived even after such thorough orbital bombardment. At the same time, he could not help but feel something was…off. He was no Eldar Farseer, yet his skills were not so unrefined as not to be able to pierce the warp when absolutely needed. But he did not need such abilities, not in this instance, for instead it was simply his instincts faintly creeping up in his mind, an almost silent alarm.

His thoughts were interrupted however by the squawk of the vox piercing his sanctum. Normally he would have such things disable but in these times it was possible for the Master of Ships to override it in times of emergency. The fact that such a course had to be taken at all was not reassuring.

“Chief Librarian, there is grave news, report to the bridge on the order of the Chapter Master.”

------------------------------------------------------------------------

You have long learned not to underestimate orks, but…this…this was surely the universe itself attempting to squeeze some last bursts of penance from you. It is not as if you would be underserving of such things – had they come at the hands of a Chaplain or the Great Father, but this is simply egregious.

“Explain to me, again, how this occurred,” you rumble quietly, bionics hissing all the while.

“The Kaptin we chased came to us,” Brother Macharius says grimly.

Between the two of you it almost looks as if two Iron Hands had gotten lost somewhere and ended up in Blood Raven colors, so heavily augmented are you both. But you find no humor in this, especially with the results of what occurred on the surface. What had occurred, in fact, a very startlingly short time ago to your mind.

“You could not resist him?”

“Perhaps,” the Devastator Sergeant muses, his voice and image crackling on the holo as the signal struggled to reach the Omnia Arcanum. “Had we not so zealously sent out almost the whole of our force, Argus Settlement may have actually been successfully defended. This is the mistake of us sergeants and none other.”

“I disagree, Macharius. Had I or the Chief Librarian been down there, this may have been avoided,” you say with earnest regret and burning fury. So foolish.

These damn bionics keeping you wary, keeping you from going forth as you once did, must be dealt with. Whether through extensive training with Apollo to completely and utterly cease the tremors from them and the reduction of your movements or some other means, it simply must be done.

“Had it not been for Brother Antal, we would have lost the entire settlement. As it is, he kept it viable, and forced Bluddflag into retreat albeit in an unexpected manner,” Macharius defends his fellow veteran sergeant, but the shame of this failure burns at true Blood Ravens.

The door opens onto the bridge and your new Chief Librarian makes his way over.

“Martellus is furious that the orks managed to force the Teleportarium to work for them, but the fact of the matter is that it did,” you intone before turning slightly to include Probalis. “Chief Libarian.”

“Chapter Master, you requested me?” he seems to be feeling the general sense of faint shame and thick annoyance cloying the air on the ship.

“It seems that your efforts in searching for the ork known as Kaptin Bluddflag on Calderis are no longer needed,” you say, folding your arms behind your back and facing the stars. “Approximately one hour ago he and the whole of his forces rammed several vehicles through the defenses set up at Argus Settlement to push to the powerful Teleportarium within and through blasphemous means engaged it.”

“He- what?”

“You heard correctly,” you do not turn to look away from space, though your gaze does drop to the main recruiting world of the Chapter which floats seemingly harmless in the void. “While the reserve forces left behind managed to destroy the majority of his force, he and a small band – numbering less than a dozen – went through. We have found no signs of them on Calderis and according to Captain Tarkus the Teleportarium on Meridian has not activated.”

“Which would leave only two places for him to have gone,” Probalis finishes, and you bow your head slightly to let him continue. “Of which, one is Aurelia which remains forbidden to all lest its taint spread….and the Judgement of Carrion.”

“Indeed,” you say, unfolding your arms and clenching your fists. “But for all his cleverness, he has left Calderis to us fully, and we shall not simply give up the chase because he has temporarily escaped. Brother Antal managed to slay his Mek and second in command after the Teleportarium was engaged but the majority of the reserve force left behind was left in serious condition.”

“I see. What of Calderis?”

“I shall make my decision on that later,” you wave a hand, mind still racing at what such a creature as Bluddflag might manage to create should he have time to once again build up his forces.

“If I make a suggestion, Chapter Master?” Macharius – who had been silent – says almost bashfully if the very concept of such a thing would be unthinkable for a space marine.

“Speak, Brother.”

“The First Company needs a Captain,” says the blunt veteran, “We have been proceeding as individual squads instead of the Company that we should be. Had we Captain we might have been able to redeploy properly rather than attempting to meld several leader’s decisions into the correct path.”

“I see. I shall make my decisions known soon, be ready.”

With that, you stride for the lift, stabbing out at the activation rune to make it descend. Victory and failure, always these things seem to be one after another in the Blood Ravens. Victory at Kronus…and a harsh time under the gaze of the Inquisition. The defeat of Kyras…and the near death of the chapter. Now this.

But.

You refuse to despair. There yet remains rounds in your bolters and fury in your hearts. The Blood Ravens are not yet done.

None shall find you wanting.

Bitter Victory: Kaptin Bluddflag Has escaped with a very small crew to one of two locations – Aurelia or the notorious and deadly space hulk Judgement of Carrion. His second in command and main Big Mek has been slain. However, of the 10% of the 1st Company left in Reserve, 23 of the current 75 Marines Present, 5 were slain and two were left in mortal condition that require Entombment or be left to die. All others were left in wounded condition but a year’s time is more than enough to heal them and so are of no real note.

Note: Now That All Leadership Options Have Been Fulfilled, New Options Are Available

Lead Your Chapter (All Technically Available):
[] Operation Available: The Cleansing of Meridian
- (Write In Forces Dispatched, Note Can Also Simply Specify To Use Forces Already Present At Location)
[] Operation Available: The Cleansing of Calderis
- (Write In Forces Dispatched, Note Can Also Simply Specify To Use Forces Already Present At Location)
[] Operation Available: The Hunt For Bluddflag – Aurelia
- (Write In Forces Dispatched)
- Note: Aurelia still sinks of the warp and is known to be tainted, the Great Unclean One Ulkair is banished, yet his touch and whispers can still be heard. Great fortitude and willpower will be required for those sent here. Note that it is not known if Bluddflag is even there or not.
[] Confer With Advisors – Judgement of Carrion
[] Recall Brothers In The Deathwatch
- (Specify In Write-In)
[] Send Ships To Zerann 52X1 For Repair (Will Begin Small Interlude for negotiations, etc.)
[] Promote Someone To Captain of the 1st Company
- Macharius Sicarius (Devastator)
- Amicus Antal (Tactical)
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Training With Apollo
Select One Of The Below To Train With Apollo’s Aid
[] Weapon Skill
[] Ballistic Skill
[] Agility

Know Your Chapter [Choose Two]
[] Inquire about the Korianis Sector

[] Inquire about Segmentum Ultima

[] Inquire about Segmentum Obscurus

Things To Consider – Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
- Remember that Chapter Master Angelos and Chief Librarian Probalis are mighty champions and can be deployed on operations. They need not remain in the Omnia Arcanum doing nothing.
- Kaptin Bluddflag has been reduced to himself, a frustratingly stealthy Kommando Nob, a brutish Stormboy Nob, and a dozen orks. It is possible that wherever he has gone, he has died there. It would not do to underestimate him again, however.
- You are slow. This must no longer be. Your agility must be bettered, you cannot allow these bionics to slow you forever!

Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (Choose 1):
[] Reconstruct Implantation Chambers of Omnia Arcanum [500 BP Cost]
[] Build Order (525 BP Available)

Things To Consider – Master of the Forge Ravias
- Priority should go to repairing the Chapter Fleet, perhaps we can contact the Mechanicus to do so? We still have good contacts with Zerann 52X1, do we not?
- Once the Implantation Chambers on the Omnia Arcanum are repaired, Brother Gracchus can move in and actually begin some real work.
- While the Chapter’s numbers remain as they are, we should turn to the Tarantula Turret. It can hold the positions we simply do not have the numbers to hold. They certainly held up quite well when I was alone on Typhon against everything that world threw against me.
- We need a bit of everything when it comes to equipment these days.

Turn 6 - 2472.5

DarkLight140 said: [*] [General Report] Plan Short And Simple -[*] Efforts to build our intelligence network have produced some results. Munzhausen and Purgg are now sending regular reports our way and the Watch here in Wurtbad will provide intelligence on anything suspicious. Checking the castle staff for infiltrators found some rather dramatically; unfortunately I can't guarantee that they were the only ones. -[*] The blades we recovered from the mound aren't usable as weapons and would kill anyone who tried to use them that way in short order. Studying them for potential magical applications might produce useful results, but that will take funding and years of work. -[*] Our written report should include more detailed information on the expansion of our network as well as a note on our failed attempt to gain contacts in a timely fashion in Wörden. [*] [Incident Report] Plan Two Sentences And Kasmir -[*] A fairly extensive interviewing process of the castle staff eventually found one spy based upon an inconsistency in his story, who attacked with unnatural speed when he realized he was discovered. At least two others revealed themselves in the aftermath, but we still haven't fully determined what exactly happened or identified the infiltrators' nature. -[*] Kasmir, next time I attempt to call upon your expertise, please provide it. [*] [One-on-One Report] Plan Small Items Of Concern -[*] Request Van Hal's support in our efforts to purge the castle of infiltrators and track down their source over the next few months. -[*] Ask Van Hal if he can explain what's happened with the East Wing. Unless it's a known variable it's a potential threat and we can't consider the castle safe. -[*] See if he has any recommendations for finding reliable lieutenants. -[*] If he ever has spare money, we want to build and equip a concealed wizard's lab. We consider our having a well-equipped enchanter's lab and a plentiful supply of reagents to be in Stirland's interest, as is concealing its existence and location from anyone who might consider us a target (read: absolutely everyone). [*] [Marshal Candidates] Plan Everything Turns Up Gustav -[*] Tell Van Hal everything we know and how we found it out, in private -[*] Recommend Gustav on the grounds that Berthold will clash with Morrites and de facto encourage proscribed cults by making all non-Sigmar religions seem less legitimate, while Otto will soak up money that the County can ill afford. Gustav is reckless, but both capable and well-loved; Stirland needs competent, popular leadership right now. [*] [Options] Plan There Are Really Only Two Important Things Happening Here -[*] The servants. Is there even any reason to suggest any other course of investigation? -[*] The disappearance of your predecessor is very concerning, especially since he's actively trying to sabotage the hunt for him. He must be found, and you've got a lead: Julbach. Click to expand... Click to shrink... --- With Schultz and Anton missing and the Marshal position still unfilled, the Council is barely worthy of the title, consisting of just you, Van Hal, Wilhelmina and Kasmir. Wilhelmina is unharmed and unbothered, but Kasmir's armour is dented and bloody, and his right arm is covered in bloody bandages and hanging limp from his body. "I'm sure you're all aware," Van Hal begins, "of the events that have led to this slightly earlier than usual meeting of the Council. Events may give a sense of urgency, but the Greatswords are sweeping the castle and will be for at least an hour yet, and all of the servants have been rounded up and are being watched. There is no reason for you all to be any less thorough than usual in your reports." There's a moment of awkwardness about order again - the Marshal position is still unfilled and Anton isn't around to step in to fill the silence - before Wilhelmina volunteers herself. She consults some hastily-scrawled notes and begins speaking. "For the first time, the treasury has something worth guarding, other than Mathilde's weird metal crate. Without de Verezzo's expenditures or Schultz's building projects, we've been able to accumulate a fair bit of money." She slides a slip of paper across the table to Van Hal, presumably with an exact figure. He glances at it, and something almost like a smile reaches his face. WEALTH OF STIRLAND: Poor. INCOME OF STIRLAND: Mediocre. TREASURY OF STIRLAND: Poor. "Good. Use some of it to reinforce the archives - I want them built into and as protected as the treasury itself. Maybe you could use it as an entryway to the treasury proper, or... well, when Schultz returns he'll probably be able to make suggestions, and I'm sure he'd be delighted to be back working within the castle. Have a guard room put in too. And traps, maybe? No, I guess people will still need to come and go... unless there's some sort of lever mechanism that disables the traps, controlled from the guard room..." He stares into space thoughtfully for a while, then shakes himself from his reverie. "Kasmir?" "I've been in regular contact with the Grand Theogonist," you bet he has, you think sourly, "and he's agreed to start dispatching Sigmarite acolytes that can act as chaplains for the military." ARMY OF STIRLAND FAITH: Sigmarite Chaplains (in progress) Van Hal opens his mouth to respond, then pauses, looking long and hard at the man. The moment stretches long enough that you and Wilhelmina exchange glances, and Kasmir begins to shift in his seat. You recognize the expression on Van Hal's face - that's the expression of his mind grinding through the facts, slowly but finely, achieving with concentration and patience what he can't with talent. Then, as suddenly as it begun, it stops. "Acceptable. See to it they are integrated into the army. Keep them to a single regiment for now... yes, the Flensburg Swords." He turns to you. "The woman of the hour." You take that as your cue. "The expansion of our information network has gone as well as can be expected," you say, consulting your notes. "Locally, the Wurtbad Watch will now be reporting anything unusual to me, and on top of that I now have informants in the bureaucracy of Munzhausen and Purgg." Reading along in your written report, Van Hal nods. "A second matter is my investigation into the weapons recovered from the Mound we assaulted. They're too volatile to be useful as weapons, though the enchantment woven into them has potential if reverse-engineered, though it will take time and funding. "The third matter is, of course, my investigation into the castle staff. I identified an inconsistency in the background of one of them, and when pressed he attacked with unnatural speed. At least two others have revealed themselves in the aftermath, but we have yet to have the opportunity to reveal their nature or objective." You hesitate for a moment, and then press on with what you had decided you were going to say. "I would have appreciated Brother Kasmir's assistance in this matter, but when asked he declined to give it." The man shoots you a dark look at that, but the one Van Hal gives him is much darker still. The moment passes, and Van Hal looks back to you. "I'm sure your assignment will come as no surprise: Investigate the infiltration of the castle staff." He gathers up the papers in front of him and tucks them into a pocket as he stands. "Wilhelmina, Kasmir, you're dismissed. Mathilde, walk with me." --- Pursued by the near-deafening clatter of two dozen Greatswords in full plate, the two of you walk through the castle. Well, Van Hal walks, his strides so furious that you have to jog to keep up. He bursts through a door leading into the courtyard, and the smash of the wooden door against stone alarms near a hundred Greatswords awaiting orders in the courtyard, and a hundred hands drop from hilts as they see the source of it. Without pausing, he advances to the training yard, and with a single motion he draws his Runefang and slashes a training dummy clean in two. "Politics, Weber," he growls, leaning on Orc Hewer. "It's always bloody politics. Of all the jobs in all the Empire, keeping a lid on bloody Sylvania should be the one where the freest hand is given. But instead I'm crippled, loaded down with thieves, idiots, cowards and zealots. If it weren't for you and Wilhelmina, I might as well take up the halberd once more and march to Drakenhof alone, I'd be doing more good than I could do here. "The religious situation in Stirland could have been very dire. Under the previous administration the Sigmarites pulled back to the major population centers and left the villages and small towns without spiritual guidance. But the Shallyans and the Morrites and even the bloody Ulricans and followers of a dozen other of our Gods stepped up and filled the void before anything else could, and saved a million souls in the process. But that's apparently not enough for the Grand Bloody Theogonist, so he sends me a goddamn zealot that spends all his time on infighting between the Gods of the Empire instead of doing his Godsdamned job." You stay silent. You could have told him that years ago, but you didn't. "I tell him to shepherd the souls of a military split five different ways and he just gets Sigmarites - and he doesn't even recruit locally, or send to Altdorf for teachers to begin teaching Stirlandian chaplains, he wants to import then en masse from the Grand Theogonist." He shakes his head in disbelief. "An army without Shallyans! I know I didn't mention them, but I shouldn't have to specify to get Shallyans. And no Morrites, in Stirland! I'm trying to build ties with the Knights of Morr and there's not a single Morrite priest attached to the army!" He looks to you. "You know why he didn't find anything when he winnowed through the servants of the castle? Because he refuses to know anything about how the other cults operate, despite me suggesting in private to him several times that he should. If someone tells him they're a Morrite or a Shallyan he has no way to gainsay them because he only knows the Sigmarite creed." "What are you going to do," you finally say. "I... don't know." He scowls. "The Emperor's Spymaster, he knows how the game is played. He sent me a broken pawn, I removed it, he owes me a new one, that's just business as usual. But the Grand Theogonist is unlikely to take it well if I oust Kasmir, even with cause. But I'm thinking: to hell with the Grand Theogonist. If he's stopping me from protecting Stirland, then surely he can't be doing the will of Sigmar." The confidence had fled from his voice at that last point, and he looks troubled. You share in a brooding silence for a time, then he seems to shake himself out of it. "Tell me what you found of the Marshal candidates." You hesitate. "Well, if you're not liking Kasmir's attitude, I'll recommend heavily against Berthold. Nothing concrete, but his company in Altdorf was made up of Sigmar supremacists." He sighs, and winces. "Of course. Well, if anyone asks, it was one of the infiltrators that knocked him out in the courtyard. Next candidate?" "Gustav is skilled and spoken well of by those who served under him, but from everything I've heard he always leads from the front. All well and good for a sergeant, not so much for a general." "Depends on the general, but I take your meaning. And Otto?" "He's exactly what he appears: a mad engineer from Nuln. He might result in some revolutionary designs, but only after soaking up massive amounts of money we don't have." "Hmm." He looks over to wear the Greatswords are gathered. "Gustav then?" "That would be my recommendation. Worst case scenario, he gets himself killed and the Spymaster has to scrape up a new set of candidates for you." Van Hal smiles a little at that. "Gustav it is. Anything to report in private?" "If you'd be available, I'd like your help in purging the castle." "Gods, it'd be nice to face an enemy I can just chop up with a sword." He stretches. "I'll be able to spare you a little time, but most of it will be spent dealing with Gustav and probably Kasmir." "I appreciate it. And speaking of the castle, can you tell me about the East Wing?" You both look over to the building protruding out of the wall into the courtyard, doors and windows barricaded. "I... suppose you've earned at least a few details. According to the Witch Hunters that investigated, the previous count was attempting to summon... the sort of thing one doesn't attempt to summon. Instead, he was summoned. I'm told it will take fifty-five and a half years for the energies released to dissipate." You blanch in horror; of all the stories new Apprentices are told of why they must never dabble in summoning, by far the worst is what would happen to anyone unfortunate enough to be sucked into the realm they were trying to draw from. "I've been looking into it when I could for the past couple of years, and it appears unrelated to the rest of the dynastic problems, thankfully. A last-ditch effort to protect himself from whatever was picking off his family, I think." "I... almost regret asking." "And I almost regret investigating." You spend some time staring together at the barricaded building. "Anything else?" "A couple of requests. Could you recommend a source of reliable lieutenants?" "For spy work, I assume?" He chews his lip thoughtfully. "Not really anyone suited to it. I can get you loyal in abundance - veterans of the Army of Stirland ready for retirement, mostly - but they'd be both suspicious of magic and mostly uneducated. Try asking Anton, there may be a son or daughter of nobility with an education, and most of the nobles would love to get in my good books after what happened to von Stolpe. And the other?" "I'd like to build an enchanter's workshop and lay in a supply of reagents, for my investigations into the enchanted swords and for future projects for Stirland." "In the castle, or in wherever it is you're living these days?" he asks, a teasing note to his voice. "...hidden," you hedge. He smiles, then thinks for a while, his fingers twitching as he moves sums around in his head. "Not right now," he finally says. "If you can make it happen with your discretionary budget you're welcome to, but we can't spare any more money right now, not when we're about to start fortifying the border and building the Langwald-Leicheburg road. Ask me again in a year or so, and we'll see." He resheaths his sword. "If there's nothing else, I think the Greatswords should have finished rounding up all the servants. We've got a job to do." [ASKING FOR ENCHANTING LAB: Breakpoints 30/50/70, Stewardship, 38+10=48. Discretionary income expenditure approved, but no extra funds.] As Van Hal walks away, a Greatsword that was hovering awkwardly waiting for your conversation to finish comes up to you and hands you a message, saying that a courier had waited at the sealed gates for an hour before handing it off to him to pass on to you. You thank him and wait for him to leave, and then unfold it, and once more you feel brightness behind your eyelids as the unwelcome sight of the strange cipher triggers the magic embedded there. Once they are appointed, prepare a report on the new Marshal of Stirland. You have four months from today. You scowl and crumple the letter. --- VAN HAL CHARACERISTIC REVEAL: Piety (12) VAN HAL TRAIT GAINED: Crisis of Faith (-3 Piety) --- PLAN FOR THIS TURN - CHOOSE BETWEEN SIX AND EIGHT. ANY CHOSEN BEYOND THE FIRST SIX WILL COME WITH RISKS. As Per Orders: Perform your current assignment. Choose ONE to have Van Hal's assistance with. -[ ] Examine closely the corpse of the slain infiltrator, trying to determine the cause of their abilities. -[ ] Examine and interrogate the imprisoned infiltrator. -[ ] Trace their actions inside the castle, investigate every facet of what they did and see if there's a way they somehow could have sabotaged something. -[ ] Walk back their movements, see whether they left the castle and if so, what they were doing. -[ ] Closely interrogate every remaining servant. -[ ] Go out to the nearby villages and confirm the details of every single servant claiming to be from there. Influencing Van Hal: You're going to be spending time with him anyway, that's a lot of time to talk. Choose up to ONE. If 'Sucking Up To The Boss' is chosen, choose up to TWO. -[ ] He's seriously considering getting rid of Kasmir. Spend some time with him and suggest a specific approach, or try to talk him out of it. (write in approach and reasons) -[ ] If Kasmir is to be removed, he'll need replacing. Suggest somewhere that Van Hal could look to find someone. (write in) -[ ] He's having a crisis of faith. If he's growing apart from Sigmar, there are other Gods you can suggest. Including one you're quite close to... (write in god) Backtracking and Side Operations: -[ ] The thing you stabbed in the face is still in the cells, and now several others that were found are keeping it company. Examine them, learn from them, see if you can identify them. -[ ] Okay. A report on the new Marshal. Follow them around for a while, see what you can find out about them. (NEW) -[ ] Write down what little you already know and send that instead. (does not cost an action) (NEW) -[ ] Try to tail the messenger who you give the report to. (NEW) -[ ] Worden failed to fall under your influence; perhaps you should backtrack and make it fall in line. (NEW) Delegation: [ ] New source: Maybe it's time to start being less spy and more master. Though Gods know where you'll find someone competent and trustworthy enough to grant such easily-abusable power. (write in source of potential lieutenants) [ ] Van Hal can get you veterans of the Army of Stirland - mostly uneducated and suspicious of magic, but unquestionably loyal to Stirland. (no action required, -10g discretionary/turn each) (NEW) [ ] Van Hal recommended asking Anton about sons and daughters of nobles to use as assistants. They're likely to be well-educated and politically savvy, but their loyalties would be to their family and they may be undisciplined. Line up some interviews and see how it goes. (NEW) [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with one of your fellow councillors, offering your help in their task and generally getting a feel for them (choose one). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: You've been given good reason to mistrust your fellow councillors. Perhaps you should see what they spent their time doing (choose one). [ ] Sucking Up To The Boss: Normally you'd just go about things and report in to the Elector Count when you've got something major to report. If you instead give him regular reports and updates, it may make him more willing to trust you, and allow you to better get to know him. Opening yourself up to oversight, criticism, and potential micromanagement is a heavy price to pay, though. [ ] Letters Home: You might be able to wring more information out of your Master, or you might just be able to get news, information and guidance in general from the Grey Order. [ ] Hang Out A Shingle: Spymasters don't advertise, but wizards sometimes do. Make an official announcement that there's a wizard in residence, and see who comes out of the woodwork. [ ] Now that you've got gold to throw around, you should stock up on spell components. They're not strictly necessary, but they do make things easier. (-personal gold) [ ] Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. -[ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills (choose one). -[ ] Tutoring: One of your fellow councillors may be willing to teach you in their chosen field (choose who). -[ ] Pretty Good Swords: You've struck up a friendship with the Champion of the Greatswords and have discovered a talent for wielding them. Continue to cultivate this. -[ ] Combat Training: You're virtually surrounded by armed warriors of various sorts. See if you can convince one to teach you (choose who). -[ ] Combat Training, In The Free Market: You haven't made many heavily armed friends yet, but gold is good for that. Go out and buy some training. (-personal gold) -[ ] You only really kept in practice with a handful of the petty and minor magics you were taught. Maybe you should brush up on the others. -[ ] You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. [ ] Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. -[ ] Diggy Diggy Hole: A wizard wielding a shovel is unnatural, but doing it yourself might be the only way to keep things secret. Clear out a new room of your Palace-Shrine by hand. -[ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Outsourced: Pay someone to do the digging, then Mindhole them on their way out. (no action required, -personal gold) -[ ] Enchantment: So far you've failed to find suitable equipment (damn Wizard Chic) but you could always try again with local goods. (-personal gold, action required to set up and learn to use equipment, action expenditure can be postponed) (NEW) -[ ] Filled with Potential: You've got a room cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put there. (write in the purpose of the room) -[ ] Wardrobe Expansion: Start wearing a tunic and breeches under your wizard's robes. (no action required, -personal gold) [ ] Research: -[ ] This is Stirland. Time to bone up on your knowledge of the Undead. -[ ] That damn Asp has still been quiet, but now you've got a lead. Peruse the book Light And It's Properties, by Leonardo da Miragliano. (NEW) -[ ] The Shyish swords are hideously dangerous as weapons, but fascinating as a subject of study. Try to reverse-engineer the lost enchantments woven into them. (NEW) -[ ] As a Journeywoman, the path to Magister is marked by mastering more than the two shadow spells you already know. Send to the Grey Order for the basics and work on figuring out one of the others. -[ ] As a Journeywoman, the path to mediocrity is marked by only learning spells created by others. Your relationship with Ulgu is between you and it. (create-a-spell, write in the effects, much more difficult than the above) [ ] Influence: Though you haven't taken these over (yet?) you could still spend some time to influence or tap into them. Write in what you would like to do with them. - [ ] The Wurtbadian Thieves Guild is currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. - [ ] Biderhof, a village based on woodcutting and agriculture, has adopted you as one of it's own. - [ ] Your grip on the Wurtbad Watch is extremely tenuous, and would be difficult to tighten without official backing. Difficult, but not impossible. (NEW) - [ ] Wurtbad, like all major cities, is home to a number of guilds. Reach out to them and enforce your will. - [ ] There's a vacuum where a dozen trade guilds should be. Found one of your own, and let information and profits flow through you, and see what the Stirlandian League does about it. (warning: expensive, will need Van Hal or Wilhelmina to sign off on it) - [ ] Your time in the sewers made you realize just how much of a maze there is down there, and you wonder what could be lurking down in the dark (apart from your fellow devotees of Ranald). Get in touch with the various groups of rat catchers, sewer jacks and gong farmers that deal with it. (NEW) FINANCES: NO ACTION POINT EXPENDITURE. Personal Income: 50 gold/turn Discretionary Income: 150 gold/turn Informer Payroll unlocked Currently paying Grey College tithe (5 gold/turn) Currently paying Grey College student loans (35 gold/turn) Currently embezzling 1/4 of discretionary income (35 gold/turn) [ ] Begin plumping the informer rolls (choose ratio of real:fake informers. Almost impossible to detect, but also very difficult to increase or decrease the amount quickly) [ ] Change tithe payment/loan payment/embezzlement (specify) - Van Hal rolled a nat 100 on his reaction to Kasmir. Shit's about to get real. - Remember way back in Turn 2 how you almost told him about Kasmir's allegiance to the Cult of Sigmar first and Stirland second, but in the end the vote was to only tell him about Anton and the Professor? Just saying. - I am trying so hard not to call the enchanted swords Shyish-kebabs.

Turn 6 Results - 2472.5

Winning vote: [*] Plan Turn This Castle Upside Down And Shake It -[*] Examine closely the corpse of the slain infiltrator, trying to determine the cause of their abilities. --[*] Van Hal assists --[*] Overwork -[*] Examine and interrogate the imprisoned infiltrator. -[*] Walk back their movements, see whether they left the castle and if so, what they were doing. -[*] Closely interrogate every remaining servant. -[*] Go out to the nearby villages and confirm the details of every single servant claiming to be from there. -[*] If Kasmir is to be removed, he'll need replacing. Suggest somewhere that Van Hal could look to find someone. --[*] The Morrites are a key part of the defense against Sylvania and care for Stirland. They can likely suggest a priest (presumably of Sigmar) who all Stirland's cults can work with well, and the other cults may have useful recommendations too. A probably-local priest well liked by the other religions here might not please the Grand Theogonist but at least they'll get things done. -[*] Van Hal is having a crisis of faith, but as someone whose religion demands that she not talk about her religion, you don't think you can help. See if you can convince Wilhelmina to talk him through this. (no action) -[*] Mention to Van Hal that you heard from your master in Altdorf that Schultz was the concession that brought Talabecland's vote. You have no reason to suspect his commitment to his role in Stirland, but it appears that Talabecland interests wanted him here. (no action) -[*] Van Hal can get you veterans of the Army of Stirland - mostly uneducated and suspicious of magic, but unquestionably loyal to Stirland. (no action required, -10g discretionary/turn each) --[*] Assign one to each of Drebkau and Langwald with orders to move in, build contacts, and send us reports regularly on recent events with an emphasis on anything unusual or suspicious. Veterans who have already retired into those locations or intend to do so anyway would be ideal. --[*] Assign one to keep an eye on opinions in the military. Put an emphasis on the new Marshal for now, from his staff if they can manage it. --[*] Assign one to keep in close contact with the Wurtbad Watch and personally get to know the Watchmen. --[*] Hire a scribe to ensure that they are literate and numerate enough to send regular legible reports. (-15g discretionary) -[*] Van Hal recommended asking Anton about sons and daughters of nobles to use as assistants. They're likely to be well-educated and politically savvy, but their loyalties would be to their family and they may be undisciplined. Line up some interviews and see how it goes. --[*] Ranald's Blessing -[*] Report on Gustav based upon the previous investigation, anything learned from initially meeting him and asking some general questions about his background and plans, and whatever the new hires turn up before the deadline. (no action) --[*] Pass anything new to Van Hal, as well. (no action) -[*] Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. --[*] Diggy Diggy Hole, Outsourced: Pay someone to do the digging, then Mindhole them on their way out. (no action required, -personal gold) -[*] Wardrobe Expansion: Start wearing a tunic and breeches under your wizard's robes. (no action required, -personal gold) --[*] Enchantment: So far you've failed to find suitable equipment (damn Wizard Chic) but you could always try again with local goods. (-discretionary gold, action required to set up and learn to use equipment, action expenditure can be postponed) ---[*] Postpone action. Just buy the stuff first. -[*] That damn Asp has still been quiet, but now you've got a lead. Peruse the book Light And It's Properties, by Leonardo da Miragliano. Click to expand... Click to shrink... --- The next few months are an exhausting flurry of action, trying to get to the bottom of the infiltration of Eagle Castle. The biggest problem is where to start. It's all urgent. It's all time sensitive. So you try your damnedest to do everything at once. But of all these urgent and time sensitive things, you finally settle in the interrogation of the imprisoned infiltrator as the most of all. The rapidly cooling corpse of the man or thing that tried to attack you demonstrates damn well that she might be more than she seems. So you weigh her down with chains and interview her from the other side of a screen of Greatswords. It's slow going at first. The woman, according to the story you got when you first interviewed her, is a simple peasant named Mihaela from Tarshof, who venerates Morr for protecting Stirland and sends money home to her family every month. That story crumbles almost immediately upon your re-asking your questions, though. "Drakenhof," she admits, her eyes downcast, the Sylvanian accent suddenly thick in her voice. "I'm from Drakenhof." "And your God?" you ask gently. "If any God watched over us, I would not be here," she responds bitterly. "Why pay tribute to Gods that have abandoned Sylvania?" You have no response to that. "Why were you trying to break into the interview room?" "Would you believe robbery?" she asks, bitter humour thick in her voice. "I was trying to free that fool Andrei." "Why?" "We were to work together. All of us, to watch over 'the usurpers' and send information back to Drakenhof. In exchange, our families would be excused taxes." She grimaces. "All taxes." "Von Carstein," you prompt. She seems surprised, then resigned. "Yes. The Elector Countess, she calls herself." She paints you a story of a young woman that has ruled the town with an army of skeletal warriors for as long as anyone can remember, claiming to be the true heir of Sylvania and demanding the obedience of all who lived in the shadow of Drakenhof. Taxes were high, and those that couldn't pay were forced to surrender family members to the castle, who were never seen again. And a few of the brighter children in Drakenhof were raised to speak in a Stirlandian accent, to be sent into Stirland to infiltrate Eagle Castle and watch over the Stirlandians. And if given the command from their handler, to act. She gives you three names, all of which were servants unaccounted for in the sweep of the castle. She gives you one more name, and an address in the city, which the Greatswords raid and find a hastily abandoned apartment, and behind one boarded-up door they find one of the servants, withered with dark magic and easily cut down when he attempted to attack them. Questioning the neighbours reveal that the inhabitant has been there as long as anyone can remember, barely ever leaving and then only for groceries, though frequently visited by people whose descriptions you recognize as the five known infiltrators. When prompted, the Watch reveal that three people that match the descriptions you give them left Wurtbad together and on foot the night of the castle being locked down. Finally, she names her price for her help. "In exchange for my cooperation, I want to be executed in the next two days." "Why?" "I'm dead anyway. We were to visit our handler in town at least twice a week, or the 'blessing' inside of us would be unleashed whether we wanted it to be or not. I don't want to be walled up to bang on the walls for the rest of eternity like those that came before me. And if I'm reported as killed, then it'll be thought I never spoke, and maybe my family won't be punished for my failure." With it pointed out to you, you can see the Dhar pulsing sullenly in her abdomen, a vicious spell waiting to be unleashed, slowly eroding its bindings. You have her shackled to a table so you can closely examine it, and from what little you know of the tainted magic she's telling the truth - even if it isn't unleashed deliberately, the spell will break free on its own within a day or two, filling her with unholy energy for a brief period before the life is burned from her. She cooperates fully, already resigned to her own death, and after a day of close investigation you think you'd be able to achieve the same results with Ulgu. You consider letting the magic inside her work itself free so you can see how it works, but in the end you decide to grant her wish. You have her hanged in Wurtbad's town square for treason. She thanks you for it, and walks to the gallows with grim determination. The town crier specifically cites her lack of cooperation as a reason for her death, and a sudden drop later, she is gone. You see to it that her body is tended to by the local Morrites before being buried in hallowed ground and allowed the rest that her masters would deny her. [INTERROGATION: Roll, Intrigue, 96+12=108. Full cooperation.] [MAGICAL EXAMINATION: Req 60, Learning, 71+13=84. May learn technique to bind delayed spells into living creatures.] --- It's a good thing you managed to secure the cooperation of the prisoner, because the dead infiltrator turns out to be a lot more protective of his secrets. The careful examination of every aspect of the dead infiltrator takes place at night, in the scant few hours that both you and Van Hal are able to wrestle from your other responsibilities. Lit by candles and shrouded in silence, it could almost be romantic if it weren't for the dissected corpse the two of you were occupied with. The problem is simple: the spell that empowered the man was hideously inefficient. After it ran its course, huge amounts of Dhar was left contained within the man, and had he still lived it would have burned him away from the inside out, consuming every ounce of meat and fat within him and transforming him into a pitiful creature animated only by the necromantic energies coursing through him, eternally hungry but denied the rest of death. Now you know where the creatures boarded up through the castle came from, and you wonder at the circumstances that led to the spell within them being unleashed. But you can only piece this together because you've seen what the spell looks like before it was triggered. If all you had to work with was the body, you wouldn't have been able to piece it together, any more than you could have figured out what shape an ice sculpture had been before it melted by examining the puddle it left. You drive yourself to try anyway, and in the end all you manage by pushing yourself so hard is almost nodding off in the chest cavity of the man before Van Hal stops you from slumping forward. Van Hal, however, is in his element, filling page after page of notes with something like excitement. At one point, he explains to you that this is an entirely new manifestation of the Necromancer's art. Though it seems to be based on something known to the Empire's scholars as Hellish Vigour, it had been modified to affect a living person. And after the effect had run its course, it resulted in an entirely new type of undead - something that resembled a zombie, but without any decomposition as the dark energy burned off flesh before rot could set in. When finished, he enlists your help in turning his notes into a formal paper on the phenomenon, and it is sent off to Altdorf to be contained within the Vaults of the Temple of Sigmar, where it can be added to the collective knowledge of the Witch Hunters. [AUTOPSY, Req 60, Learning, 35+13=48. Nothing new learned.] [OVERWORK FAILURE, Roll, 96. Severe (and gross) consequences avoided.] [VAN HAL'S AUTOPSY, Req 60, Learning, 49+16=65. He's written a paper on it.] --- During the time you spent with Van Hal, you brought up the Kasmir issue, and suggested that he reach out to the Morrites and see if they can recommend a candidate they can work with. Van Hal dismisses it out of hand, however - at this point he's convinced that there's no good way to get a clean break from the Grand Theogonist's meddling, and if anything is considering banishing Sigmarites from the position altogether and instating a Morrite instead, because at least they'd be useful against the Sylvanian threat. You also drop in a mention that Schultz seems to be in the pocket of the Talabeclanders, and all the response you get is him muttering something about gratitude, his mood darkening further. Your trying to get Wilhelmina to intervene goes poorly, too. "You're barking up the wrong tree if you're looking to me to put him back on the straight and narrow," she says to you. "I'm all for him cutting ties with the Sigmarite bastards. I've always thought they've always done more harm than good, and Abelhelm's been the only exception." [CANDIDATE SUGGESTION: Req 40, Diplomacy, 6+8=14. No dice.] --- Using the information given to you by the now-executed collaborator, the rest of the investigation goes smoothly. You finish your interviews of the castle staff, follow up on the story of every single servant with your contacts in the nearby villages, and confirm that each of them is who they say they are and are from where they claim to be from. After months of interviews and examinations, you are positive that every single person remaining is who they claim to be, and find nothing more sinister than a few people who overstated their qualifications when they were hired and one serving girl being bribed by Anton to bring him midnight snacks. And by talking with everyone the infiltrators worked with and walking back their day-to-day routines, you can confirm what the now-dead interviewee told you: they were not saboteurs, but sleeper agents. Every part of their duties was performed perfectly, and no little surprises were left behind. Though you don't find anything, your investigation pays dividends by setting up a procedure to vet new hires, which is useful since there's five freshly-vacated positions in the castle to fill. The member of the castle staff responsible for new hires sends you a report, you forward it to the villages, the villages confirm the story, and then you stop in for an interview to confirm that everything is as it should be and to run a careful eye over the candidate with your Mage Sight. [AUTOMATIC VETTING OF CASTLE STAFF ESTABLISHED.] [EAGLE CASTLE IS NOW SECURE. EAGLE CASTLE WILL CONTINUE TO BE SECURE.] --- With the Castle finally confirmed secure, you can finally get to work on matters outside those four walls. First up is the military retirees, all around their late forties and scarred from thirty years of service. They look askance at a wizard ordering them around, but when they learn that all you want is gossip and for them to learn to read, they settle down. You're able to tap them for information on the new Marshal, Gustav von Jungfreud, and what you hear is heartening. The man's first priority has been to bring the Roadwardens of Stirland under his authority, centralizing their command structure and making sure there's enough men to cover all the roads of Stirland, including and especially the road running along the newly-reinforced border. He's also begun recruiting from the minor nobility and the wealthier burghers to found a Pistolier cohort, with ambitions to expand it to a full regiment. Though the men of the Army of Stirland grumble good-naturedly about the obsession of their new leader with cavalry, they're glad to have a military man as their leader after the walking fiasco that was the Professor. You prepare a written report with this information and what you previously learned about the man, and have it ready for the courier when they arrive, sending it off to whoever your mysterious string-pullers are. If that doesn't satisfy them, they can get stuffed. With that taken care of, your veteran recruits are occupied for the duration with learning to read and write, with lessons taking place in the back room of a tavern near the castle. Soon they'll be dispatched to their assigned locations to start enjoying their retirement and start funnelling gossip, news and current events to you. --- When Anton reappeared to get his next assignment before heading off again, you managed to grab him for a moment and asked him if there were children of nobility who'd be willing to work for a spymaster. He seemed delighted to be able to help you and promised to send off some letters, before shooting off to deal with whatever political hot potato is next on his agenda. You end up with two interviews, and the first goes terribly when the young man starts responding to your questions with ones of his own and it quickly becomes apparent that somewhere along the line he got the impression that this was a date. You consider going along with it for half a second, then eye the young man's foppish clothes, braying laugh and overabundance of teeth and send him on his way, promising to yourself that you will get vengeance on Anton if it was deliberate on his part. The second, however, goes much better. The young lady in question is the third child of the Grand Mayor of Flensburg, and has a keen mind and practices archery as a hobby. She's been shut out of the family business of getting obscenely rich by trade because of her complete lack of ability when it comes to making money or friends, so she's been at a loss for something to keep her occupied, until her good friend Anton suggested you. You spend an evening getting to know her over dinner and drinks, and in the end think she might be just what you're looking for to help with your burgeoning information network. Her price would be five crowns a month, supplementing the pocket money she gets from her family. Julia Antoinette Massif Diplomacy: 6 Martial: 16 Stewardship: 7 Intrigue: 14 Faith: 10 Learning: 16 [LOOKING FOR CANDIDATES: 33+10=43, two candidates.] [FIRST CANDIDATE: 13. Awk-ward.] [SECOND CANDIDATE: 71+20. A strong possibility.] --- Also occupying your tragically limited time is a shopping trip. After the... robe incident, you're determined to never be caught out like that again, so you buy up a wardrobe's worth of suitably grey breeches and tunics to wear underneath your robes. You also go hunting for enchanting gear, only to find that Wizard Chic has spread to Stirland, and once more the local nobility has snapped up everything even slightly suitable. You want to scream. You also begin the now-familiar process of lining up a candidate willing to become a shut-in for six months while they dig out a buried room. This time, however, it ends in disaster. Three months into the digging, you're reading in your room when the sound of a shovel on soil is interrupted by a rumble and then a strangled scream as earth falls. You're unable to dig the man out in time, and end up having the money you would have paid him sent to his widow, and smuggle his body out in the dark of night to hand over to the local Morrites. And you don't even have a newly-excavated room to show for it. [ENCHANTMENT? Roll, Stewardship, 4+10=14. Ranald laughs.] [HIDDEN TREASURE?: Req 80, 9. Disaster strikes.] [HOW BAD IS IT: Roll, 90. One-off, no ongoing effects.] --- Finally, you're occupied with the book 'Light And Its Properties'. It's a densely-packed exploration of the properties of various forms of light, and you quickly find the relevant part: where it describes the properties of mirrors. Though physically they act by simply reflecting light, they're also metaphysically gateways to other dimensions, not because of any properties they intrinsically have but because of millennia of belief along those lines making it true - or so the author theorizes. He also describes a device he claims can 'store' light, and he theorizes on ways to slowly 'release' that light over time to save money on candles, though he never quite managed the release mechanism. The structure itself is a strange three-dimensional maze of baffled mirrors inside a cube, the blueprints of which take you weeks to understand. Though the concept of storing light is fascinating, you're most interested in what would happen if the bizarrely absent snake tried to manifest inside it... [STUDYING: 87+13=100. Full grasp of the concept.] --- The mood in the Meeting Room is tense. Kasmir is quietly brooding in his chair and Schultz is clearly upset over something. Even Anton has picked up on the mood, his trademark cheerfulness muted, and Wilhelmina is occupying herself with a dense ledger of figures. Only the newest face at the table, Gustav, seems immune to the atmosphere, and gives you a cheerful grin in greeting as you enter. Van Hal has yet to arrive, and you're glad you've only good news to give him. --- EAGLE CASTLE STAFF NOW IMPENETRABLE. RESEARCH NOW AVAILABLE: Bound Spells. VETERAN INFORMANTS NOW LITERATE. VETERAN INFORMANT ASSIGNED: Drebkau. VETERAN INFORMANT ASSIGNED: Langwald. VETERAN INFORMANT ASSIGNED: Army of Stirland. VETERAN INFORMANT ASSIGNED: Wurtbad Watch. MIRRORCATCH BOX: Construction will be possible next turn. Discretionary Income: +150g Embezzlement: -35g Veteran informants -40g Scribe to teach informants -15g --- Net: +60 Personal Income: +50g Embezzlement: +35g Tithe: -5g Student Loans: -35g Excavations: -20g New clothes: -10g --- Net: +15g --- Decisions: [] Do you hire Julia Antoinette Massif? If so, describe her duties, as well as where she'll be living and working. [] You, like all the Councillors, now have a squad of Greatswords assigned to you as bodyguards. Do you keep them somewhere nearby while you're at home, or do you leave them in the Castle? [] Write in your report [] Write in a one-on-one report (optional) Possible orders for the next turn: Investigation: [] There's definitely evil afoot in Drakenhof. Perhaps there's a way to survive investigating this. [] The disappearance of your predecessor is very concerning, especially since he's actively trying to sabotage the hunt for him. He must be found, and you've got a lead: Julbach. Infrastructure: [] The Stirlandian League is a gold mine of information, and it must be yours. [] If you had proper facilities, you could do better work. Would Van Hal fund renovations to a base he's never seen? [] You've got a whole bunch of friends now, but you could always use more! [] You've got the town of Biderhof eating out of your hand. If you could think of a reason to justify it, maybe all the taxes from it's lumber sales could flow into your pocket instead. [] The Wurtbad Thieves Guild is basically a church group right now, instead of an actual organization. If you started throwing your weight around, that could change. Imagine the power you would wield if the criminal underworld reported to you. However, imagine how much more damage they'd do to Stirland if they were united... and you're not sure that Van Hal would be easy to convince. Action: [] The Stirlandian League is a cancer eating at Stirland's economy, and it must be destroyed. [] The spell used by the informants is like nothing you've heard of before. You want to investigate it, and see if you can detect or replicate it. [] This religion business has gone far enough. It's not really your place, but maybe you should step in and deal with it yourself... somehow. [] Other (write in) --- - Your crit on the Interview did render most of the other investigations unnecessary, but at this point you can be absolutely sure that Eagle Castle is and will continue to be free of infiltrators, and free of surprises left behind by the infiltrators you do have. - Van Hal's crisis of faith has deepened. - I'm slightly brain-fried today, and as such there's probably something I've missed and more than usual a write-in order might be a good idea, as I couldn't really think of new approaches for you. Also, apologies for any dip in quality this may have created. - In case I didn't make it clear in the text: the gribbly you killed way back in the first turn was a previous infiltrator who triggered the spell inside them and then was shut away by their collaborators before the spell turned on them.

Turn 7 - 2473

Winning vote: [X] [Julia] Plan Townhouse -[X] Hire her, buy her a home in town near your residence. Somewhere where people coming and going at odd times won't draw a fuss. -[X] Her job would be to manage your informant networks in general, particularly sorting through the reports and picking out what's significant versus chaff. It'd also involve independently expanding the networks as funds and opportunities allow after she has settled in. -[X] The only ones who are should specifically know her position should be Van Hal, yourself, Markus and your assigned greatswords and anyone you assign to work for her. Otherwise, be subtle. -[X] Provide funding for a handful of retainers to keep up appearances. If she has any family contacts she can call on to provide reliable and vetted guards and servants, or to assist with background checks on any such new hires, have her do so. -[X] Introduce her to Van Hal. [X] [Greatswords] Greatswords will stay in the castle, except when we're going somewhere publicly, or interrogating potentially hostile persons. [X] [Public Report] Plan Points for public consumption. -[X] The castle infiltrators were sleeper agents. --[X] They have not been conducting any significant sabotage. --[X] Their loyalty was secured by a necromantic spell that would kill them if they even thought of betraying their master, or if their master did not meet them for more than a few days. --[X] Said master had fled the area the very night an infiltrator got caught. --[X] The monsters in the castle walls were previous victims of the spell. Refer to Van Hal's paper on details if anyone is interested. --[X] They were lying about having any religious beliefs, but got away with it because nobody could probe them further on Morrite or Shallyan practices. -[X] All other castle servants have been examined, their backstories hold up and all future servants would be rigorously examined to prevent more of this. [X] [Private Report] Plan Shorter Meeting -[X] Tell him about everything you learned in the interview. Especially how they produce infiltrators. -[X] You have acquired some subordinates. --[X] You have hired a lieutenant, Julia Massif, to help manage your information networks. In case any unfortunate 'accidents' happens to you, he can have some continuity through her so he wouldn't need to start from scratch. --[X] Several veterans have been assigned to gather low-level information. -[X] You have a lead on permanently sealing the snake away. Give him as much information on the process as you have, if he's interested. Suggest he approve a one-time increase in the discretionary budget in the interests of keeping his favourite spymaster un-eaten-by-a-snake. It'll be around a hundred gold for the mirrors, plus the cost of a skilled artisan to assemble the mirrorbox. [X] [Orders] Plan Now, Back To That Other Guy... -[X] The disappearance of your predecessor is very concerning, especially since he's actively trying to sabotage the hunt for him. He must be found, and you've got a lead: Julbach. -[X] The Stirlandian League is a cancer eating at Stirland's economy, and it must be destroyed. --[X] This would likely be difficult while the previous spymaster is still at large to run counterintelligence, but it can be done. -[X] The spell used by the informants is like nothing you've heard of before. You want to investigate it, and see if you can detect or replicate it. --[X] If you can replicate the technique, it will be a powerful tool for the Empire's defense. There's the problem of killing the user, but that is potentially a problem of source -- Dhar is corrosive by nature. -[X] There's definitely evil afoot in Drakenhof. Perhaps there's a way to survive investigating this. --[X] Recommend against it. With their sleeper agents uncovered and in the wind, there's no immediate threat, and the potential gain isn't worth the risk of a dead spymaster. Hint hint. Click to expand... Click to shrink... --- When he arrives and opens the meeting, Van Hal's first order of business is the introduction of the newest member of the council. Outrider Champion Gustav von Jungfreud, proven warrior and able commander, et cetera, et cetera. You're all introduced to him, and you give him a smile and nod when it is your turn, though in all honestly you doubt he'll last much longer than the Professor did. "So, Gustav," Van Hal begins the meeting proper. "We've spoken at length of your plans to establish pistoliers in Stirland. I feel it will be a worthy addition to Stirland's forces, both in times of war and to keep the roads clear in times of peace. Work with Wilhelmina and Anton in arranging the importation of the firearms you'll need. Make sure there's close ties between the pistoliers and the Roadwardens - they'll be working hand-in-hand." Gustav looks pleased, but he's barely given an opportunity to express his thanks before Van Hal's moving on. "Anton, report." "Everyone along the Stirland-Sylvanian border is on board with the fortification plans, and the corvée are being organized for Herr Schultz now," Anton says, looking pleased with himself. The news causes Schultz to perk up a little too, though only barely. HORNAU COOPERATION: Secured. STEINBACHTHAL COOPERATION: Secured. SIEGFRIEDHOF COOPERATION: Secured. "Speaking of, Schultz, how goes the road?" "It cuts right through a place called the Haunted bloody Hills! How do you think it's going?" he snaps, then quails under the look Van Hal gives him. "It... progresses. There's been attacks, nothing organized, including one where I damn near got my head bitten off by some glowing green ghost thing waving a farming implement around, but they seem unorganized and they're being suppressed by patrols from the 2nd and 3rd divisions." LEICHEBURG-LANGWALD ROAD: Construction commenced. "When you go back, it'll be with several squads of Greatswords at your back." Schultz looks even more perked up at that. "Begin construction of a permanent fortified barracks at Leicheburg, large enough for two divisions. And don't forget the embrasures for cannon and mortar - there's ten of each assigned to the 3rd. Use local labour as much as possible without sacrificing the strength of the walls." He consults his notes. "Anton... pack for..." he hesitates, and drums his fingers on the table while he considers. "Flensburg. We'll try to unravel that terrible knot while things are quiet. " Anton winces, but nods. "Wilhelmina?" "Archives are as secure as a dwarvern vault. Nothing's getting in there that isn't allowed to be. Apart from that, nothing new on the money front - we've still got a bit of a surplus but that'll change soon." She glances at Gustav and Schultz. EAGLE CASTLE: Archives reinforced. WEALTH OF STIRLAND: Poor. INCOME OF STIRLAND: Mediocre. TREASURY OF STIRLAND: Poor. "Money is for spending," Van Hal says dismissively. He checks the papers in front of him again, and then compares two side-by-side. "Weber, report." "The castle infiltrators were sleeper agents," you report confidently. "They have not been conducting any significant sabotage, and I can confidently say that all other castle servants have been examined, their backstories hold up and all future servants will be rigorously examined to prevent more of this. These agents escaped detection because while they were lying about having any religious beliefs, they got away with it because nobody could probe them further on Morrite or Shallyan practices." You consult your own notes to keep from giving Kasmir an accusing look. "Their loyalty was secured by a necromantic spell that would kill them if they even thought of betraying their master, or if their master did not meet them for more than a few days. Said master had fled the area the very night an infiltrator got caught. And on a side note, the monsters in the castle walls were previous victims of the spell." You look up once more and note that your audience is rapt. You suppose it's no wonder - they're talking about humdrum matters of construction and travels and infrastructure and you're telling tales of necromantic thralls being purged from the castle. Van Hal nods. "A thorough investigation. Well done." He glances down at his notes once more. "You and Wilhelmina are to work together. The Stirlandian League has been allowed to continue for long enough. Crush them, seize everything of value they possess, and restore normal trade." You note that Schultz is unable to conceal the sudden increase in attention he's paying. "With the archives restored, you should be able to draw suitable legal authority based on non-payment of taxes." Van Hal pauses for a moment before turning to the last man at the table. "Kasmir..." He seems to struggle with himself for a moment, then sighs. "Continue with your chaplain project." --- "Subtle," is the first thing you say to Van Hal as you step into his office, drawing a questioning look from him. "Regarding Kasmir, I mean." He barks a humourless laugh in return. "I damn near told him to go back to Reikland and tell the Grand Theogonist that his services are no longer required. He tests me sorely." You don't know how to respond to that, so you remain silent as he pours the two of you drinks. "So, what have you been getting up to in the shadows of late," he prompts, pushing the steel mug across the desk to you. "Not so much in the shadows - as you may know, I spent nearly every waking moment ensuring the castle remains purged." "Mmm. Couldn't have done much of a better job myself," he notes, a note of pride in his voice. "I had my doubts about you, but you've really come into your own." You fight down a blush and forge forward with your report. "But I have started to build a staff. As you know, I've taken on some veterans from the Army of Stirland, and I've hired on an assistant in the form of a young lady from Flensburg, who'll be compiling information from my informants. Julia Massif. If anything happens to me, she'll be a decent candidate to act as an interim replacement and will be able to hand over my intelligence network." "Gods forbid," he mutters. "Wait, Massif... isn't that-?" "Yes, she's the third child of the Grand Mayor." "I really hope we're able to find a solution to that whole issue," he sighs. "Bloody Flensburg..." "I've also got a lead on the Wisdom's Asp," you say, and Van Hal perks up, visibly interested. "My Master recommended a device theorized by da Miragliano, originally designed to trap light, that hopefully will. It's going to be rather expensive to build, though - if you could-?" [REQUESTING FUNDS, Req ??, Stewardship, 89+10=99. Of course you can.] "Of course, of course," he says, sketching a note to Wilhelmina. "Can't have my spymaster being eaten by a dream snake. da Miragliano - do you just have his blueprints, or do you have one of his writings?" "A copy of Light and Its Properties, from the archives of the Grey College." "If you don't mind I'd quite like to borrow that once you're done with it," he says, smiling in anticipation. "I once fired a da Miragliano crossbow - it would recock itself, though you had to wind it quite vigorously every ten shots. Amazing device." "Of course," you say with a smile. --- With the meeting done, you make your way to the townhouse that Julia is busy settling in to, nestled snugly against the road between Wurtbad's main road and the entrance to Eagle Castle. She's busily importing furniture and staff from the family manor in Flensburg, and when she isn't having the Greatswords you introduced her to arrange furniture to her exacting specifications she's writing letters introducing herself to your informants and asking that they start sending all that they hear, rather than what seems significant. She says she'll be hiring locally since most of the staff back home would be tied into the inter-family intrigues of the most powerful burghers of Flensburg, and has started to carefully vet candidates to act as various maids, footmen and retainers. It's expensive, but a small price to pay to have a public face of your department to draw attention away from the privacy of your Palace-Shrine. --- PLAN FOR THIS TURN - CHOOSE BETWEEN SIX AND EIGHT. ANY CHOSEN BEYOND THE FIRST SIX WILL COME WITH RISKS - PLEASE SPECIFY THE 'ADDITIONAL' TASKS. As Per Orders: Perform your current assignment. The destruction of the Stirlandian League will take two actions. You will attempt to round up as much of every part of the League as you can, but you must select ONE priority to focus on: [ ] The leaders of the Stirlandian League need to be rounded up so you can question them regarding their former patron. [ ] Rounding up as many of the individual members of the League as possible will make it clear that nobody can engage in this sort of behaviour without facing eventual consequences. [ ] Though Van Hal didn't mention it, you could work with authorities in Talabecland and Averland to help them do their own purges parallel to yours. They'd likely be grateful, but it will come at the expense of your activities in Stirland. [ ] The documents of the Stirlandian League will allow you to rebuild the north-south trade network with speed and efficiency. [ ] The assets of the Stirlandian League will be a huge boost to Stirland's coffers. Delegation: [LOCKED as Julia settles in] [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with one of your fellow councillors or your liege, offering your help in their tasks and generally getting a feel for them (choose one). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: You've been given good reason to mistrust your fellow councillors. Perhaps you should see what they spent their time doing (choose one). [ ] Letters Home: You might be able to wring more information out of your Master, or you might just be able to get news, information and guidance in general from the Grey Order. [ ] Hang Out A Shingle: Spymasters don't advertise, but wizards sometimes do. Make an official announcement that there's a wizard in residence, and see who comes out of the woodwork. [ ] A Crisis of Faith: Van Hal's ongoing alienation with the Sigmarite faith is worrying. Maybe there's something you can do? (write in) Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. [ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills and internalize the lessons you've learned (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective if you've used the trait a lot lately). [ ] Tutoring: One of your fellow councillors may be willing to teach you in their chosen field (choose who). [ ] Pretty Good Swords: You've struck up a friendship with the Champion of the Greatswords and have discovered a talent for wielding them. Continue to cultivate this. [ ] Combat Training: You're virtually surrounded by armed warriors of various sorts. See if you can convince one to teach you (choose who). [ ] Combat Training, In The Free Market: You haven't made many heavily armed friends yet, but gold is good for that. Go out and buy some training. (-personal gold) [ ] You've got a handle on most of the Petty and Minor magics, but some still elude you. Dispel in particular could have come in very handy recently. Time to round up the rest of them. (NEW) [ ] You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. [ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Remixed: You're getting sick of having workmen tramping in and out of your abode. Recruit an entire team and personally oversee them to clear out all of the reachable portions of the Palace-Shrine and be done with it. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: So far you've failed to find suitable equipment (damn Wizard Chic) but you could always try again with local goods. (-discretionary gold, action required to set up and learn to use equipment) [ ] Filled with Potential: You've got a room cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put there and get started on equipping it. (write in the purpose of the room) Research: [ ] This is Stirland. Time to bone up on your knowledge of the Undead. [ ] Personally construct the Mirrorcatch Box. Though being around that many mirrors for that long makes you antsy, there's nobody else you can trust with the task. (expense paid for by Van Hal) (NEW) [ ] Commission a craftsman to construct the Mirrorcatch Box. Having to explain every facet of it means you're not going to save time, but it will minimize your exposure to the mirrors... though you wonder if any Wurtbadian craftsman could successfully craft a da Miragliano device. (expense paid for by Van Hal) (NEW) [ ] The Shyish swords are hideously dangerous as weapons, but fascinating as a subject of study. Try to reverse-engineer the lost enchantments woven into them. [ ] Though the corrosive Dhar made them high-maintenance, the design of the bound spells in the castle's infiltrators has fascinating possibilities. Try to adapt it for use with Ulgu. (NEW) [ ] As a Journeywoman, the path to Magister is marked by mastering more than the two shadow spells you already know. Send to the Grey Order for the basics and work on figuring out one of the others. Influence: Though you haven't taken these over (yet?) you could still spend some time to influence or tap into them. Write in what you would like to do with them. [ ] The Wurtbadian Thieves Guild is currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. [ ] Biderhof, a village based on woodcutting and agriculture, has adopted you as one of it's own. [ ] Your grip on the Wurtbad Watch is extremely tenuous, and would be difficult to tighten without official backing. Difficult, but not impossible. [ ] Wurtbad, like all major cities, is home to a number of guilds. Reach out to them and enforce your will. [ ] There's a vacuum where a dozen trade guilds should be. Found one of your own, and let information and profits flow through you, and see what the Stirlandian League does about it. (warning: expensive, will need Van Hal or Wilhelmina to sign off on it) [ ] Your time in the sewers made you realize just how much of a maze there is down there, and you wonder what could be lurking down in the dark (apart from your fellow devotees of Ranald). Get in touch with the various groups of rat catchers, sewer jacks and gong farmers that deal with it. [ ] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (no action required) (NEW) FINANCES: NO ACTION POINT EXPENDITURE. Personal Income: 50 gold/turn Discretionary Income: 150 gold/turn Informer Payroll unlocked Currently paying Grey College tithe (-5 personal gold/turn) Currently paying Grey College student loans (-35 personal gold/turn) Currently embezzling 1/4 of discretionary income (-35 discretionary gold/turn, +35 personal gold/turn) Currently employing 4 veteran informants (-40 discretionary gold/turn) Currently employing Julia Massif (-30 discretionary gold/turn) Currently maintaining the staff of a townhouse in Wurtbad (-20 discretionary gold/turn) [ ] Begin plumping the informer rolls (choose ratio of real:fake informers. Almost impossible to detect, but also very difficult to increase or decrease the amount quickly) [ ] Change tithe payment/loan payment/embezzlement (specify) [ ] These agents are getting expensive. Write up a proposal for your discretionary budget to be increased, instead of waiting for Van Hal to decide to increase it. (warning: attracts oversight to your current budget) (NEW) - The cost of purchasing the townhouse for Julia will be 150 gold, and will be added onto your discretionary expenses next turn. - I've removed all of the 'no action required' actions apart from the new free social action, with the hope of making a plan easier and avoiding 'automatic' picks. - I've thought about it, and I've removed the 'create-a-spell' option for now. It will return once (if?) you graduate to Magister. - You can write in orders, but something worth writing in is probably worth adding to the list of possible orders, so feel free to ask if your idea can be added. - As always, voting will be in plan format.

Turn 7 Results - 2473

Winning plan: [*] Plan Bless The Snake -[*] The documents of the Stirlandian League will allow you to rebuild the north-south trade network with speed and efficiency. -[*] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills and internalize the lessons you've learned (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective if you've used the trait a lot lately). --[*] Intrigue --[*] Learning -[*] You've got a handle on most of the Petty and Minor magics, but some still elude you. Dispel in particular could have come in very handy recently. Time to round up the rest of them. (NEW) -[*] Personally construct the Mirrorcatch Box. Though being around that many mirrors for that long makes you antsy, there's nobody else you can trust with the task. (expense paid for by Van Hal) (NEW) --[*] Ranald's Blessing -[*] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (no action required) (NEW) --[*] Julia Click to expand... Click to shrink... --- Your first thought when planning your offensive against the Stirlandian League was that you needed to move against the entirety of the League at once, to prevent the next town over from being tipped off and scattering to the winds. But it occurs to you as you are staring thoughtfully at a map of Western Stirland, you don't actually need to move everywhere at once. You just need to move faster than a conventional rider. Wurtbad to Tarshof, fifty miles. A desperate enough rider could make that in eight hours. You could make it in two without breaking a sweat. Thirty from Tarshof to Potting, thirty more to Worden, sixty more to Vigaun. You could personally see to the raids in every single town and village, spread over a couple of days, and still move faster than news could travel. Several companies of troops are borrowed from the First Division and sent southwards over several days, ostensibly to end up in Central Stirland to do patrols into Hundsheimer Wald, the only hint to their true purpose being a word that Van Hal had personally with the Captain of each. They were reminded that, should they just so happen to linger for a time in a certain town or village, and should the Spymaster just so happen to meet them there, they were to remember that she spoke with his authority and they were to obey her orders. And while troops were on the march in the open, information was flowing in the dark. The Wurtbadian Watch knew the Stirlandian League well, as they tipped them generously to keep the streets outside their properties clear of unsavoury elements. The tips had been accepted - very few in Stirland were so well off that they would say no to extra money just for doing their jobs - but to the proud veterans of the Watch, this engendered resentment, not gratitude, and you soon had a detailed list of every League property in Wurtbad. Their counterparts in the criminal underworld came through as well, and the list was supplemented by off-the-books properties containing smuggled goods and mistresses. And from out of town, the Headman of Tarshof was happy to pass on which building in the village acted as the warehouse and waystation for the Stirlandian League. When added to Wilhelmina's exhaustive records, you were confident you knew of every single possession of the Stirlandian League in Wurtbad and Tarshof. It was upsetting that you had no information flowing from the bureaucratic snarl of Worden, but you hoped that Wilhelmina's records and supplementing documents you might find in your raids would do the job. [Tapping the Innkeeper: Roll, 21.] [Tapping the Watch: Roll, 77.] [Tapping the Thieves Guild: Roll, 57.] [Tapping the Headman of Tarshof: Roll, 41.] [Wilhelmina's contributions: Roll, her Stewardship, 68+16=84.] So after a solid month of planning, on a clear, moonlit night when the Wurtbadian Watch was out in force and a substantial amount of the Greatswords slipped out of the castle and took up positions in the city, you set off a rumble of illusory thunder in a cloudless sky as a symbol to begin, before personally kicking down the door of the administrative headquarters of the Stirlandian League and leading a charge of Greatswords into the building. For a tense moment, it seemed as though the inhabitants - suspiciously scarred and muscled clerks with clubs close at hand - were going to put up a fight, and you almost regret that they don't. Some of the Greatswords clap them in chains and lead them away while the rest load up documents into a cart to be taken to Eagle Castle, while you quickly skim what you can find. You gravitate right to a bookshelf kept right next to a roaring fire and are glad you did - a record of investors, debtors, assets and agreements fills tome after tome, and though you can't easily get an up-to-the-minute record of their current assets from the chronological list of entries, it does give you a number of addresses to investigate in the southern towns of the Old Dwarf Road. The most recent of the tomes is now to join you on your journey south. [Shock and Awe: Req 50, Martial, 27+10+20(Greatswords)=57.] [Searching the place: Breakpoints 30/50/80, Intrigue, 59+14=73.] [Skimming the documents: Roll, Stewardship, 54+10=64.] Elsewhere in the city, doors were kicked down as Greatswords raid what turns out to be, in an amazing stroke of luck, the Stirlandian League's annual board meeting and shareholder gathering. Everyone with an inch of power in the League is clapped in irons and led out under the horrified eyes of the League's shareholders. Things are sewn up so quickly they join the Watch in raiding the lodgings of every known worker of the League, and soon Eagle Castle's dungeons are full to overflowing. Though the Wurtbad Thieves Guild is currently unworthy of the title, Wolf and Heideck put the word around to their flocks and you found plenty of takers for the flip side of the high-profile arrests. Almost every known warehouse and one affiliated bank has their guards either bopped firmly over the head or 'encouraged' to take the night off, and when morning rolls around and the now-exhausted Watch make their way to follow up on arrests with a wave of confiscations, they find almost every entry on their list completely unguarded and only mildly looted. [Greatsword raids: 99+20=119. Overflow goes to gathering up rank-and-file members.] [Wurtbadian Watch raids: 44+10=54.] [Thieves Guild raids: 86+6=92.] You, however, don't hear about how well the morning asset seizures go until much later, because you're already in Tarshof, overseeing a dawn raid on the League's local headquarters. The swordsmen aren't nearly as suited to the work as the Watchmen or the Greatswords you oversaw in Wurtbad but they still do sterling work, rounding up every single person, every bit of paper, every crate of cargo, and a flock of bewildered sheep. You even nab an exhausted rider who rode in just before you were about to launch the raid yelling a warning that the Wurtbad offices had been raided. The look on his face as you personally shackle him will keep you smiling for months to come. You're even able to convince him to tell you who he was going to tip off in the next town over. Then with all the cargo and prisoners on the road back to Wurtbad, it's time to head on to Potting. Potting is almost a disaster. You're not sure how word beat you down the road until you see the pigeon coop on the roof of the building, but being able to go right to the building in question means you're able to salvage things somewhat. A good many people fled into the evening, some with carts, and there's paper ashes in all the fireplaces, but you still seize papers, people, goods, and still more sheep. Mindful of how close you came to getting nothing, as soon as everything's rounded up and on the road to Wurtbad, you're on your way to the largest target after Wurtbad: Worden. Worden, amazingly, had no warning. You can only conclude that a hawk or a bow-armed peasant had messenger pigeon for tea, because when you raid the Worden Weaver's Guild, the local face of the Stirlandian League, the local leadership stares at you in sleepy shock over their breakfast until they're chained up and forced out of the building. The weaving equipment is too delicate and bulky to seize, so you leave the soldiers to stand guard until given further orders and make your way to your final stop on your journey, Vigaun. Vigaun goes poorly entirely because when you launched your raid, most of the membership were out of the building because some sheep escaped from their pen. You round up a few of the members and the sheep, but at the end of the day you're still missing some of the tiny amount of assets to be found in Vigaun. You can't really find it in yourself to be too concerned. There's limited amount of skulduggery that can be done with a few off-the-books sheep. When you get back to Wurtbad, you sleep for a day straight. [Tarshof raids: 94+10(Headman cooperation)+20(Wurtbad paperwork)=124. 24 overflows to next roll.] [Potting raids: 6+20(Wurtbad paperwork)+24(overflow)=50.] [Worden raids: 96+20(Wurtbad paperwork)=116. 16 overflows to next roll.] [Vigaun raids: 23+20(Wurtbad paperwork)+16(overflow)=59.] Final haul from shutdown of the Stirlandian League: 100% of records pertaining to assets, investors, creditors and debtors. 100% of records pertaining to trade agreements, suppliers, and buyers. 100% of League leadership in Stirland. 73% of rank-and-file members of the League. 60% of the Stirlandian League's assets seized, 30% 'missing'. 100% of Tarshof branch. 50% of Potting branch. 100% of Worden branch. 60% of Vigaun branch. League's remaining assets: 26% of the rank-and-file membership. 10% of their material wealth. 50% of Potting assets. 40% of Vigaun assets. The final tally is mind-blowing. All that remains of the Stirlandian League is low-level members, a tenth of their former wealth, less than half of the two smallest nodes of their trade network, and anyone that was out of Stirland at the time. The Stirlandian League is done. The only problem left is what to do with all these sheep. --- With so much of the League in custody, you've got plenty of chance to practice the arts of intrigue. You perform dozens of interrogations, then Mindhole the participants and interrogate them again. You turn them against each other, against the League, against their backers; you pull every scrap of information out of their head over and over and over. You engineer a phoney escape attempt, pretending to be in the previous Spymaster's employ. Then you engineer another, pretending to be in your own employ, and it's amazing how many of them would agree to become a mole in the League if offered their freedom - if it wasn't utterly dismantled, it'd be trivial to destroy it. You see their faces fill with desperate hope as they slip out of their cells and down the corridor, and see their expression fall as they run into a wall of Greatswords waiting for them. After you've convinced three of them in a row that you're their long-lost and long-forgotten sister by using the details of their youth they told you before you Mindholed them, you realize you've reached the limits of what can be learned with a captive audience like this. But you've learned so much about what makes people tick, and what would make them break down. Unfortunately, you're not able to learn much about your predecessor, simply because they don't know anything. He's been leveraging the blackmail material he collected as spymaster to force the Stirlandian League to keep paying him the same level of bribes they used to, but he hasn't actually done anything they know of in years. If he's still in Stirland, he's keeping his head very far down. [Intrigue Increase Roll: 66. +1 Intrigue. Base intrigue was <14, additional +1 Intrigue.] [Information acquired: 25+16=41. No location for predecessor.] --- You share what you learned, if not how you learned it, with Julia over a series of lunches, and she listens eagerly each time. To have joined the intelligence apparatus of Stirland as it dealt a mighty blow to revitalize free trade delights her, and she speaks with passion and enthusiasm of her vision of Stirland as a trading hub of the Southern Empire. You raise an eyebrow at this, prompting her to go on; you always primarily saw Stirland as the front line in the war against the Undead, but she's got a geopolitical point - with land borders to five other states of the Empire, six if you count the Moot, Stirland does have that potential. "If his Grace's plan works," she says animatedly, "or even if it's just partially successful, because Southern Stirland is irrelevant to this, then all we need is safe roads - and the new Marshal is tailor made for it - and the Praager Road to Ostermark is locked down. Look," she sketches a map on a notepad, "Anton Senior is a huge believer in trade with Wissenland, and honestly to hell with whoever's calling themselves the 'Count' of Flensburg, so that's Reikland and Wissenland trade nailed down. You've just swept up the biggest obstruction to North-South trade, which opens up trade with the Moot as well. Bam, Stirland's a trade nexus. If you want to get really crazy, if Southern Stirland is secure we can work on the roads to Black Water, and from there we unlock trade with Zhufbar and Karaz-a-Karak, without having to go through the nest of vipers in the Border Princes!" You stare at her, and at the map. What she lacks in people skills, she definitely makes up for in ambition, and in contagious enthusiasm. --- After the excitement of the start of the year, the next few months pass quietly in peaceful study, brushing up on long-forgotten spells and adding a couple of new ones to your repertoire. Drop and Sleep could both be amazingly useful in certain situations, and it's trivial to brush up on what you remember of it. The newer spells are trickier, but still fairly straightforward; the small books sent to you from Altdorf contain the basics and soon you're able to unravel magic when you concentrate. Silence is trickier, until you spend a handful of copper coins on a chicken, and after some long days spent trying to visualize freezing the movement of the air, you finally force the clucks to freeze in it's throat. Then you move on to the other books your Master sent you, describing magic itself rather than any way of using it. They're a collection of ways of describing magic, through the lens of a dozen different metaphors favoured by master wizards. Though known as 'Winds', many don't actually see the substance of magic as such - some see them as threads, some as light, some as waves of liquid overlapping our reality. Some don't even see them - there's a section by a Gold Wizard that describes magic as sounds, and how each wind corresponds to a specific type of instrument. The book starts an itch at the back of your head, and one day you head to the castle and borrow your copy of Light and Its Properties back from Van Hal, and read through it cover to cover in the courtyard, ignoring everything around you. It's a fantastic reference for light itself, of course, but if read as a metaphor, or rather as a lens for understanding... you stare into space as the evening rolls in, and see the Ulgu growing in prominence, and then fade as dusk gives way to night. You draw magic into you, and watch it flow into your frame. You relax, and watch as it disperses. Everything still looks the same, now. But it looks the same like a page of text would look the same to an illiterate as it would to a scholar. Where once you saw shapes, now you see meaning. [Spell study: Roll, Learning, 68+13=81. All Petty and 2 Lesser spells learned.] [Learning study: Roll, Learning, 95+13=118. +2 Learning, trait acquired: Windreading.] --- Finally, as midsummer approaches, it's time to see to your long-absent but not forgotten pursuer: Wisdom's Asp. With Van Hal's financial backing, you were able to cut through Wizard Chic and find someone to commission the innumerable small and oddly-shaped mirrors, and several months later it was time to start work putting them together. You ensure your sword is close at hand, wrap yourself in precautionary magical armour just in case, and sit down to begin work- -mrroOOOOOOOOOOOWRL- -and jump back up as the cat on your seat protests being sat on. How do they keep getting in here?! There's a skittering of its claws clicking against the tiles as it flees somewhere into the depths of the Hidden Palace, and you sigh as you look down at the fragments of the broken piece of mirror. You're going to have to get that commissioned all over again... Then you look closer, and see the tiny, pointy fragments of shimmering colour among the broken shards. The thorns of a shimmering snake, severed. You sigh again, and begrudgingly thank Ranald. Weeks pass in a haze of slotting tiny mirrors into mind-boggling patterns, forming some sort of concentric cube design of refracted light. Your mind melts into a haze of angles and patterns, and time fades into meaninglessness. Once the final mirror is slotted into place, you stare blankly at what you've created as you try to remember something other than light and angles. Then you remember, and smile. You hold your candle (you haven't actually lit the candle in ages, but it's a convenient target to cast Light upon) to the open lid of the box, and the light seems to be drawn into the box, and the visible mirrors glow brighter and brighter. You snap the lid shut, release the spell on the candle, and pause for a moment in darkness, before opening the lid again. For a brilliant second the room is illuminated white, and then fades once more. Then, as you Light the candle once more, you feel rather than hear a nightmarish skittering reverberate through the room - the sound that's haunted your dreams for many years. The sound of that damned snake manifesting in your reflection. Without a moment's hesitation, you snap the lid of the box shut. The Mirrorcatch box shivers on the desk, then jerks so violently it flips onto it's side. For half a second beautiful, malignant light coruscates out of the lid of the box where it's opened less than a crack. Then it lies still. A few seconds later, a multi-hued liquid starts to ooze out of the crack. You lay a finger against the box cautiously. You can feel the hostile energy of the snake contained within the box, and the movements of the box as it writhes in agony. You flip the box right way up again and clean the spilled fluid up with a rag, smearing a shimmering rainbow stain across the top of your desk. You place a weight on top of the box to keep it in place. A few days later, the box begins to overflow with the rainbow liquid. You stare in horrified fascination. By the end of the month, you've collected a pint of the liquid in the glass bottle you placed underneath it. It writhes with softly glowing magic, every colour intermingled but uncurdled. It evaporates slowly into raw magic when exposed to air, but when contained within a bottle it remains stable, untainted. You spend hours staring in suspicion for any sign of Dhar and find none. The leak never slows or speeds up, dripping steadily and unceasingly out. What have you created. [Thorned One made its roll for the first time ever but Ranald's Blessing prevented manifestation.] [Constructing the box: Breakpoints 60/80, Learning, 99+13=112.] [Thorned One roll after box construction: 9. It manifests again, but at the worst possible time for it.] [I thought to myself, 'more than fifty, the snake is killed. Less than fifty, it is trapped alive.': 50. Schrodinger's Snake achieved.] --- WORKED WELL TOGETHER: +1 to relationship with Wilhelmina. Stewardship stat revealed. STAT INCREASE: +2 Intrigue RELATION INCRASE: +1 with Julia, learned more of her beliefs, traits revealed STAT INCREASE: +2 Learning TRAIT GAINED: Windreading SPELLS LEARNED: Drop, Sleep, Dispel, Silence ALL PETTY SPELLS KNOWN!: +1 Magic ITEM ACQUIRED: Schrodinger's Demon Snake. INCOME ACQUIRED: One gallon of raw something every turn. TRAIT REMOVED: Snakehunted Discretionary Income: +150g Embezzlement: -35g Veteran informants: -40g Julia: -30g Replacement mirror and emergency glass bottle: -5g Townhouse for Julia's base of operations: -150g --- Net: -110g Personal Income: +50g Embezzlement: +35g Tithe: -5g Student Loans: -35g --- Net: +45g --- The Councillor's Table is much livelier this time around, with you and Wilhelmina animatedly chatting about your shared success against the Stirlandian League and even Gustav getting in on things, since his soldiers helped. To one side, Anton and Schultz are chattering happily away about the small uptick in Wissenland-Talabecland trade through Stirland that has already begun. Only Kasmir is left out of the chatter, his expression determined and the papers in his hands creased from his grip. Van Hal spoke with you and Wilhelmina earlier, and told you that your success with the League has earned you both a boon and to consider what you will ask for; you've been turning that over and over in your mind since then, exploring the possibilities. --- Public Report: Write in (optional; can write in word for word, or just outline what is focused on) Public Report: Select boon. [] Increase in personal pay [] Increase in discretionary income [] A holiday (no assignment next turn) [] Knighthood (???) [] Sheep! (substantial confiscated grazelands, many sheep, and related woolworking infrastructure in Wodern) [] Trading company (found a new trading company in the vacuum using the League's confiscated resources, with the official backing of Stirland) [] Your own military force (write in type) [] Serving Stirland is reward enough [] Other (write in; keep it sensible) Private Report: Write in (optional; the private meeting is traditional at this point and will take place, simply say whether there's anything specific you want to bring up here) Potential Orders: Investigation: [] There's definitely evil afoot in Drakenhof. Perhaps there's a way to survive investigating this. [] The disappearance of your predecessor is very concerning, but according to the Stirlandian League he's pulled out of the game with all his ill-gotten gains. If you're not willing to let that go, maybe you could track him down anyway. [] You built something you don't really understand and trapped something you very much don't understand and now something you really don't understand is leaking out. Um? [] The spell used by the informants is like nothing you've heard of before. You want to see if you can detect or replicate it. [] Something your new Lieutenant said gave you an idea. Investigate the shores of the Black Water, see if it can truly be tamed. [] If we've got vampire troubles, maybe you should spend some time investigating how to counter vampiric infiltration. Infrastructure: [] Your intelligence infrastructure is becoming worthy of the title; perhaps you could dedicate some time to expanding it. [] The Wurtbadian Watch has proven it's usefulness; despite their reluctance, perhaps it should be made part of your bailiwick and expanded to cover more of Stirland. [] You've got the town of Biderhof eating out of your hand. If you could think of a reason to justify it, maybe all the taxes from it's lumber sales could flow into your pocket instead. [] The Wurtbad Thieves Guild, despite barely being a loose gossip network, really came through during the take-down of the Stirlandian League. Maybe you should cultivate this useful tool. [] Other/s (write in)

Turn 6: Unfurling Wings

GM NOTE: I think I got everything. Lemme know if I didn't!

Unfurling Wings
+002.M42+
+Faith Is Purest When It Is Unquestioning!+

The first year of the forty second millennium passes simultaneously fast and slowly. It is agonizing.

Part of you strains to raise up the chapter and make all haste towards Cadia and all the other battlegrounds being fought as the 13th Black Crusade continues to pour forth from the Eye. To bring the might of the Blood Ravens against the Black Legion and all the other traitors there to prove yourselves. To strike out at the taint in the galaxy with genuine and full force without the trappings of the corruption that Kyras had slowly slipped into the chapter for so long. The warrior demands battle and it is a struggle to restrain it even as you hungrily search for reports and rumor as to what has and is happening in that distant war. A special iota of attention is kept on any mention of your own chapter and thus Aramus and his Penitents.

Yet the greater part of you knows the duty before you. The Blood Ravens cannot serve the Emperor if they are all dead and dying so soon after your ragged victory and purge. Would it be better to sacrifice the whole of the chapter in cleansing flame or to allow Aramus his penitence in payment for allowing the Blood Ravens to once more grow strong? Before you were a Chapter Master, you were a Captain, and there you well learned the lesson you put into practice here. You are not a young Assault Marine ready to dive into battle heedless of any and all consequences other than the death of the enemy. You have a responsibility to the bigger picture and the chapter to lead them well, which will therefore mean that sometimes that you will not lead them into battles. Wounds must heal, ranks must be refilled.

It is with that thought in mind that you order Cyrus to bring his discerning eye to Meridian once more - . The last marine to come from the Hive World in the past seven centuries was Thaddeus Rex and though the young marine proved himself time and again during the Aurelian Crusades he nonetheless was tainted alongside his commanding officer unlike the others who accompanied Aramus. Even so, after the continued ravages of traitor and xenos upon the world there is perhaps a chance that the populace has lost the softness normally associated with Hive Worlds. Perhaps even then Kyras was involved in ensuring that the planet was not recruited from but that would go into the bounds of nigh Inquisitorial paranoia and you need no such self-created mental pressures.

=======================================
[Meridian Blood Trials: 82+5=87/100]

Cyrus grunted as he looked on dispassionately upon the corpses strewn across the haphazard arena the 10th Company had crafted. In the distant past a pair of Space Marines had been present at all times with rotating shifts lasting months over the Meridian Arena. Just as there is an arena on every Recruiting World of the chapter. Unfortunately, the Meridian Arena had been destroyed during the purge, one more sacred place to the Blood Ravens destroyed by the traitors within. As such this new one constructed atop one of the spires of a fully deceased noble family was seeing blood spilt upon it for the first time. He had delved deep into Meridian in search of recruits but the chances of replicating Captain Thule’s meeting with Thaddeus revealing a noble and courageous heart in time of crisis was essentially nil.

Even so.

Five young men gasped for air as they staggered and forced themselves to stay standing, and to Cyrus’s surprise only three of them were from the Underhive. Two of them were of all things the children of some of the Hive’s nobility. Distant, distant children of course, no heirs were present. But for all that they were of so called noble blood Cyrus had shown them no preferential treatment. The noble blood of mortals did not matter to a Space Marine. Blood coated them and he refrained from commenting on how they could have used weapons with greater ease and that some would have likely benefitted from more aggression rather than defensiveness. But they were but Aspirants. If, if they managed to survive the process into becoming Scout Marines, he would speak to them further.

As it was, he gave a single nod of his head and let his better students begin walking forward to take the last of his crop into the waiting Thunderhawks.

For a world that had seen only one successful recruit in seven hundred years, forty total Aspirants were better than he had ever suspected. Perhaps losing a full third of the world’s populace to the ravages of Chaos and xenos had benefitted it more than Cyrus had initially thought.

10th Company Fleet
Strike Cruisers: Faith's Horizon, Ravenous Spirit, Spiraling Fury
3 Escorts
Gains: 40 Blood Raven Aspirants

============================================

[Specialist Search – Apothecaries: 55/100]
[Specialist Search – Tech-Marines: 16/100]
[Specialist Search – Chaplains: 94/100]

You cannot neglect the more specialized portions of the chapter, of course.

With the favor of the Emperor, amongst your newest fully ranked brothers there is one found who turns out to have some aptitude at the duties of the apothecaries. The young brother Marius is quickly inducted into the ranks but training shall take time of course for all the knowledge and skills to be properly passed on. It is not the greatest crop of potential apothecaries of course but it is better than none. It is certainly better than your search for those who may aid Martellus in his duties in that there are none found to have the specific kind of connection to the machines that Martellus demands of any who would join him in the forges. A brother is already training there however which somewhat salves the disappointment.

Truly, however, you are graced by your search for those who could take up the incredibly weighty mantle of chaplain. You cannot search amongst the new in this, and instead must look to those who have fought for the chapter for many a battle. Only those with badges denoting their merit and devoutness may even be considered for this. Ironically enough Apollo possesses these and if he had the mind for it to strip himself of all identity and become a chaplain you might have seen him become one but that is thoughts for another time. Instead it is from the First Company with its mighty veterans that you recruit from. And from the First Company comes a full four individuals selected by the Master of Sanctity to be capable of joining the ranks of his brotherhood.

They go with your blessing.

1 Apothecary Recruit Found: Brother Medici – Training to Complete in 007.M42
0 Tech-Marine Recruits Found
4 Chaplain Recruits Found: Brother Tarion, Augustine, Ravias, Antonius – Training To Complete In 007.M42
-4 Veterans of 1st Company
-1 Battle Brother of 5th Company

==================================

[Integration: 50/100]

The First Company is meant to be the highest premier fighting force in the whole of the chapter. The fact that they have not responded entirely with favor towards their comparatively inexperienced Captain is therefore not outside of your expectations. He is to their minds quite untested indeed and there is little that can be done for such a situation other than to let him prove himself or fail in shame. Still, you do what you can to try and mesh the commander and his troops together. In these dark days for the Chapter you simply cannot afford to allow dissension to fester in any shape and form. Your words are taken in, you see this, but whether or not it will sink into their hearts and minds is another question entirely.

At the least, by the end of the year after several observed training exercises the 1st Company is at least not disparaging their Captain out loud. Or at least within earshot of you or the Captain himself. It is not a perfect solution, of course. No, that shall only come when Crixus fights in a true battle alongside them.

============================

You are running ever lower on Recruiting Worlds it seems, and thus one of the only possible recourses is to pursue new ones. The only issue of course being that being allowed to recruit from a world is a matter that takes negotiations with the Administratum, Mechanicus, and so on and so forth. This is likely due to how a consistent presence of the Space Marines will paint a large target on said world for any foe willing to tangle with the Emperor’s Finest. Also how this will mean adroit calculus to determine population changes necessary to function with the methods of recruitment, and a great number of purely bureaucratic issues which you grow to hate with a considerable amount of force by the time it is all said and done. Luckily at least you’ve recently shored up your relations with the local Mechanicus establishment.

Two of the worlds you look into are within Subsector Aralakh which has been the bastion of the Order of the Lost Rosetta since before you even joined the Blood Ravens, while the third is Agrax III, a Deathworld within Subsector Krasus. Deathworlds are sure to produce strong potential recruits, and they are also for the most part undesired by anyone else save for perhaps the Imperial Guard. One only needs to look towards Catachan to see the truth of that matter. Of all of these the most controversial request is certainly your cautious question towards recruiting upon Saintsfall, the effective homeworld of the Order of the Lost Rosetta. They only recruit women, however, and so the idea is present that perhaps the other half of the populace may be worthy of induction into the space marines?

[Mechanicus Approval: Rolls Waived Due To Current Relations]
[Administratum Approval: 55, 76, 56]
[Lost Rosetta Approval: 4/100]

The results…are not encouraging. The Administratum dresses up their answers in flowery words and ‘heartfelt’ apologies but the end result is a cold one. Junius, first world you asked of cannot be allocated to you at this time. The reasoning about amounts to ‘because’ but you cannot afford in your fragile relationship with the Empire to truly press things. Saintsfall is another story entirely. The Order of the Lost Rosetta is quite unhappy with your request though at least some of their generally sour mood likely comes from the repairs and final clearing efforts they have been making against the tyranids which struck that world. All on that world are theirs and the Emperors, the men who cannot be recruiting into their Order instead becoming effective support staff, priests, servants, messengers, and so on and so forth. The whole of the world revolves around the Lost Rosetta and that you apparently attempted to infringe on this has set the already volatile tempers of the Sisters to sparking. The last detail of which makes sense – as Saintsfall is where Saint Tevalia died and is thus one of the holiest sites of their Order save for the Burial World for the Saint for whom the Order is based around.

Most stingingly, they ‘happened’ to refer to your request as a more polite version of what was exchanged between the rarely lamented Captain Boreale and his strikes against the Sisters of Battle during the Kaurava campaign. You apparently underestimated the repercussions of Boreale leading the Blood Ravens into battle against both Guard and Sisters.

Finally, Agrax III was refused to you. This was not because of some arbitrary reason but instead politics. That was always more Kyras’s game than yours, honestly. The Guard and Navy do not wish to have their authority and presence compromised by losing out on a world within the heart of the Sector and so have lobbied against your attempts to gain a foothold and therefore discredit them and bring ruination unto the Imperium. Or at least that is how they seem to perceive your request.

Lovely.

Investigation Complete: All 3 worlds are barred to the Blood Ravens. Junius may become an option if continual pressure is applied. Saintsfall, and all of System Romana is claimed by right for the Lost Rosetta. Lost Rosetta quite unhappy with your request, ripple effect of Kaurava Campaign Revealed – Sister’s of Battle factionwide unhappy with Blood Ravens due to slights and slain delivered by Captain Boreale. Relations with Order of Lost Rosetta Revealed To Be ‘Suspect’, not Honored! Guard and Navy have blocked attempts for Agrax III due to perceived endangerment of political power and status!

===================================

“Colonel Merrik,” you smile as you step off the Thunderhawk to greet the man.

He is one of the most highly regarded mortals you think the Blood Ravens have ever found, with universal approval from Cyrus to Apollo. You consider such reports as you flick your gaze upon the man and examine the carapace armor wearing mortal up and down. Hefting a rather heavy looking plasma gun with ease, he appears to have barely changed from how he looked as a sergeant so long ago. Even the green face-paint is still there. Behind him lies the Guard troops he leads, all running through a rather grueling series of obstacles and firing exercises that you even you respectable. For Guardsmen, that is. It seems the faith of your brother’s was not misplaced.

“Chapter Master Angelos,” he almost bows to you before reconsidering and saluting. “What can the 85th do for you?”

“The Blood Ravens are going into battle again, and we would know if the Guard would fight alongside us once more.”

You blink at his suddenly feral grin.

“Oh, my Lord Angelos, you have no idea how happy I am that you came to tell us that.”

“You don’t even know what the we will be facing,” you point out but Merrick only shakes his head and points at his troops – those that he can within reasonable range.

“These boys have been itching to get into a fight again. Ever since the Blood Ravens steamed through the Underhive and cleared out, well, everything, they’re starting to go stir-crazy. The Administratum was making noises about sending us towards Cadia to fight the Black Crusade but if you say that there’s something closer to home that needs fighting the 85th will be there, you can bet on it.”

“Truly?”

He snorts.

“We’re the Imperial Guard. We go where we’re told, we fight what we’re told to fight, and we get the job done. Intel is optional.”

“Then prepare yourselves, for in two years we shall move towards Trontiux II to clear it of the great Ork WAAAGH! there that is threatening the Knights who stand steward there.

Colonel Merrik spits to the side and nods.

“We’ll be there.”

85th Vendoland Shall Support the Blood Ravens against Trontiux II’s Orks!

=========================================

The 1st Meridian Consolidated are far less ready to leap into action alongside you. Their current command squad is divided between numerous mortals who had grown used to commanding their old regiments before it was all merged together and as such there is no small amount of friction there. The Colonel in command of them, a sharp faced woman by the name of Tavi – in honor of the Saint Taviana – almost refused your request outright. Not for the reasons one might expect but she sincerely wishes to try and actually unify her regiment before throwing them into battle. Especially against such a potentially terrible battlefield as Aerus. Even so however you would not be dissuaded. Especially as it is your opinion that one of the best ways to work out the ‘kinks’ – her words not yours – is to go into battle and allow the forge of war bind them.

A reminder of all the Blood Ravens have done for Meridian in the end seals the deal and she unhappily agrees to support those you send to Aerus next year.

1st Meridian Consolidated Agrees To Assist Against Aerus, Favor Used Up!

=============================================
[Training With Apollo – Agility From 4 to 5: 97+29=126/500]
[Chapter Training – Toughness: 91+Tarkus(25)=116/600]
[Chapter Training – Ballistic Skill: 74+Macharius(25)=99/400]

The bionics groan as you continue to sprint along the corridor of the Litany of Fury, your hands flashing in time with the training blade you use to just barely bat away Apollo’s strikes. You fail more than you succeed though part of that is most certainly due to his own incredible skills. It still frustrates you but every increment of speed you force upon your body and the machinery within remains there at the end of it. It is slow progress but it is that not the point of this? You cannot allow yourself to stop, to cease training your body. Not until you are at least as you were before you were almost slain upon Cyrene.

And as you train, so too does your chapter.

Tarkus is one of the most resilient marines you’ve ever seen in all your years. The tales of his refusal to fall no matter the fire levied against him during the Aurelian Crusades whether under his original name or the moniker of The Ancient are legendary amongst the Blood Ravens new and old. It was even remarked in one of the rare reports that are not locked away under a seal of shame by Aramus that he regarded Tarkus as the more durable between them – and that was from a brother who had been struck full on by the Wailing Doom of an Avatar of Khaine and the blade of Ulkair and kept fighting on regardless. His attempts to pass on that innate characteristic are brutal and unkind, yet effective. Beatings and blank bolter rounds are put against the flesh of the marines of the chapter for as Tarkus informs you the only way to be as he is…is to experience what it is to be struck until all natural law demands you fall yet remain standing in the Emperor’s name.

Brother Macharius, as it turns out, is a cold teacher as he calmly cuffs heads with enough force to crack a human skull whenever the shooting is off by a hair of accuracy. He demands excellence from all those you put before him and this even includes the scouts and aspirants as they are dragged to the ranges. The First Company acquits itself well but that is to be expected all things considered.

==================================

In the depths of the Omnia Arcanum, Test-Slaves are created. Culled from the prisons of Meridian and placed into the gestation chambers, their only purpose will be to generate gene-seed. Luckily, as they are not your brothers and would never be worthy of such, you can harvest both of the gene-seeds that will gestate within them and the destruction of their minds and sanities will be of no real consequence. Of course, the apothecaries shall keep watch with regular visits by the chaplains as well to ensure there is no corruption that may or may not seep in. With the Test-Slaves readied, all that awaits is your decision to implant them and how much shall be implanted. You would then have to wait at least a half decade to reap the rewards from them, of course, and that means gene-seed that would not be implanted into those scouts who are worthy of promotion to battle brothers.

In the depths of the forges, on the other hand, Martellus weaves a bounty of technology for the services of the chapter. Each one is given his personal stamp of approval, and though he occasionally mutters about Typhon his two younger peers are nonetheless still tireless in their work alongside him without complaint of any kind.

Added to Chapter Armory
2x Razorback with Twin-Linked Assault Cannons (90BP)
Land Speeder Tempest (45BP)
5x Plasma Pistol (20BP)
Power Fist (5BP)
3x Tarantula Sentry Gun - Hyperion AA (30BP)
3x Tarantula Sentry Gun - Twin-Linked Lascannons (30BP)
3x Tarantula Sentry Gun - Twin-Linked Assault Cannons (30BP)

Lead Your Chapter (All Technically Available):
[] Further Black Crusade Contributions – Send forces to aid in the Black Crusade, even though Aramus’s presence apparently counts enough for some. (Write-In)
[] OATHBOUND MISSION - Securing Aerus: A lost Forgeword has been rediscovered. Reclamation efforts will be difficult and deadly. And yet you are oath-sworn to your allies in Zerann to aid them in this. It is now time to determine what troops you shall send, and do so with the knowledge that the 1st Meridian Consolidated shall fight alongside you here. (Write-In Who/What is Sent) Must Be Selected
[] Recall Brothers In The Deathwatch
- (Specify In Write-In)
[] Something Else (Write-In)

(LOCKED UNTIL TURN SEVEN) Trontiux II Intervention: A massive force of orks has arisen on the Knight World of Trontiux II. Alone they will fall. Together you may push back the green tide.

Training With Apollo
Select One Of The Below To Train With Apollo’s Aid
[] Weapon Skill
[] Ballistic Skill
[] Agility

Train Your Chapter [Choose One]
The Blood Ravens have lost so many, both fresh blood and veteran. It may aid in the rebuilding of the Chapter for you to work upon them and try to impart the skill and experience that the Blood Ravens of the past once possessed.

[] Select Main Characteristic
- [] Specify Teacher

[] Select Two Secondary Characteristics
- [] Specify Teacher(s)

Things To Consider – Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
- Remember that Chapter Master Angelos and Chief Librarian Probalis are mighty champions and can be deployed on operations. They need not remain in the Omnia Arcanum doing nothing.
- You are slow. This must no longer be. Your agility must be bettered, you cannot allow these bionics to slow you forever! - While your Chapter rebuilds, it may be time to consider rebuilding the amount of Gene-Seed you possess through faster means i.e. test-slaves now that the Omnia Arcanum has been repaired.

Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary (Choose 1):
[] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest in 5 years. Write-In the amount of Gene-Seed you wish to use.
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Nero Gracchus
- We are in dire need for more gene-seed!
- If we could better understand our gene-seed, perhaps we could better improve survival rates for implantation?
- The Apothecarium really does need more, well, Apothecaries.

Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (Choose 1):
[] Build Order (250 BP Available)

Things To Consider – Master of the Forge Ravias
- While the Chapter’s numbers remain as they are, we should turn to the Tarantula Turret. It can hold the positions we simply do not have the numbers to hold. They certainly held up quite well when I was alone on Typhon against everything that world threw against me.
- We need a bit of everything when it comes to equipment these days.

Turn 8 Results - 2473.5

Winning votes: [*] [Surname] Weber [*] [Motto] Unseen, but not Unfelt. [*] [Coat]: [*][Action] In The Darkness We Watch -[*] Rewrite the relevant part of the legal code of Stirland so that the Watch reports to you, personally. (will face pushback from existing Watchmen; will take two turns; the Watch will come permanently under your control) -[*] Spread some coin around so that a cross-section of the Watch passes on information to you as well as their superiors. -[*] Delegation - Ground Floor: Start putting people on your payroll into the EIC before it even begins, so you'll have information flowing right from the start. (NEW) -[*] Investment: Wilhelmina has offered you the limited-time chance to become a founding shareholder in the EIC; the buy-in will be a cool 1000 crowns, but with Van Hal's permission, Wilhelmina has offered you an interest-free loan from the Stirlandian Treasury to cover it, and promises that unless something goes terribly wrong, the dividends will more than pay for it. (NEW) -[*] Knighthood: There's a ceremony, of course. And a number of oaths to make. And you'll have to visit your 'estate'. But gosh. Dame Mathilde. (NEW) -[*] Enchantment: So far you've failed to find suitable equipment (damn Wizard Chic) but you could always try again with local goods. (-discretionary gold, action required to set up and learn to use equipment) --[*] If unable to buy the stuff(again) do this instead of setting it up: ---[*] Final Round-up: You're so close to mastering all the lesser magics. Just one final push and you'll have them all. (NEW) -[*] Weber's Box: It has a nice ring to it, but you've got no idea what 'Weber's Box' actually is, or what's going on in there. Have a very, very careful look at it. (NEW) --[*] Ranald's Blessing on Weber's Box -[*] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (no action required) (NEW) --[*] Kasmir ---[*] Apologize for your previous sharpness, which was partly due to finding out just how badly the castle was infiltrated and having spent nearly the whole year on rooting them out. Click to expand... Click to shrink... --- Dame Weber. Gosh. You sleepwalk through the next few days, unable to shake the amazement from your mind. Knighthood. The actual knight part of things was going to be pretty straightforward, since Ulgu could supply the horse and armour at a moment's notice and you were in the habit of going around with your sword anyway, but the fact that you were being elevated to actual nobility... After wallowing in the thoughts for a few days, you force yourself to shake them off. Knight or not, you've still got a job to do, and it's time to take the Wurtbad Watch in hand. That jumped-up Brettonnian peasant didn't take kindly to being ordered to report to you, so you would make it his legal duty to do so and then he'll either fall in line or you could force him out of the position and replace him with someone more pliable. So you make your way to the castle archives and start digging for the formative documents of the Wurtbadian Watch. And you dig. And dig. And dig. Over three hundred years of paperwork and weeks of digging later, you finally find it. Early in the 2130s, during the Third Vampire War against Mannfred von Carstein, the modern iteration of the Wurtbad Watch was founded, superseding a previous organization of the same name. They were given the remit to pursue corruption both mundane and supernatural, were to be funded from the purse of the City of Wurtbad, and no man without military service was permitted to join its ranks. The document also states the authority they were to report to: 'The Elector Count, or designated military subordinate thereof'. Which would definitely discount you; you play with the idea of using your new status as a Knight of Stirland to qualify, but you want to be able to act as the Spymaster of Stirland while commanding the Wurtbad Watch, rather than having to act as two separate legal entities. So you get to work writing up a new document. It takes you days to get used to the jargon of legal documents, but you copy sentences from here and there and piece them together like a puzzle. And since you're already making a document, you decide, you may as well go all in and remould the foundation document of the Wurtbad Watch to your purposes. Weeks more pass in a manic haze of editing and revisions, as you craft a document that takes the existing loose gang of thief-takers, bellringers and busy-bodies and turns them into what could very well be described as your personal army. Or, at least, the founding company of it. When you present the document to Van Hal, he reads it three times before he signs it. When you take the signed document to the Watch's headquarters, 'Lefty' Ragnier resigns on the spot after reading it. But that doesn't even slow you down, and you plump the rolls of the Watch with veterans willing to swear loyalty to you personally as well as adding a number of existing members to your informant network. All in all, a good result for a few months' work. Now you just have to rebuild it in your image. [Finding the document: Req 40, Stewardship, 67+10=77.] [How restrictive is it? Roll, 26. Technically excludes you; new document required.] [Writing a new document: Breakpoints 40/70, Stewardship, 97+10=107.] --- After so long dealing with paperwork, you need to toy with the Winds of Magic once more to cleanse your palate. So you turn to the strangest creation of your Wizarding career: 'Weber's Box'. If you're going to call it that with a straight face, you need to understand what's happening in it, surely. So you tilt it on its side, let the liquid drain out into a bottle, and take a glimpse into the inner workings of the device. It's structurally unchanged. It's still a series of concentric mirror cubes with gaps in the 'top' to let in light and a mirrored lid to trap it. But now, intersecting those mirrors, is a mess of butchered snakeflesh, constantly writhing. It's quite disturbing to look at, and difficult to figure out what it is that you're looking at. You stare at it with mundane and magical senses, trying to figure out what it is you're seeing, but none of it makes sense. So you stop staring and instead try to reason it out. And once you do, a theory emerges. The most basic fact of the Thorned One: it can pass through mirrors. To it, the mirrorcatch box isn't solid, it's a tangle of overlapping portals. So, you reason, when it tried to move through one of the mirrors to reach you, it can't have moved more than an inch or so before running into another mirror, and then it would have passed back into the demon realm. And, if the portals possess the same relative location in the Warp as they do in realspace, maybe it passes through a second portal to appear back in the box while its back half is still in there, and intersects itself. And then add in that the smallest cube within the box is made of mirrors too small for the snake to pass through - or, at least, for all of the snake to pass through... So parts of it are obliterated as different parts of its anatomy tries to exist in the same place as other parts of it, and other parts are sliced neatly off by the edges of portals where they meet entirely different portals, and the portals too small for the snake to fit through. But the snake doesn't just die - it's not that fortunate. Half of it is still within the realm of unreality where demons (you theorize, far beyond the limits of your knowledge) cannot die, and the energies of that place are drawn into it to repair the damage done. But before those energies can become snakeflesh, the part of it that was in the warp has passed through the snarl of mirror-portals into reality, and the raw energy, suddenly subjected to the laws of reality instead of the non-laws of the warp... well, apparently it pours out of the box in the form of what you theorize is raw, liquid Qhaysh. Or at least an untainted and balanced combination of every colour of magic at the same time - isn't that what Qhaysh is? Or is there more to so-called 'high magic' than that? You don't know. You're not sure if any human knows. And it just keeps on happening, because to the snake there is no solid surface in the box. The parts of it in reality are subject to gravity, but can never stop falling because the closest thing to a bottom is a portal into the warp. It is suspended in an eternal free-fall, forever unable to either heal or die. And in that state it constantly drains magical energies into reality. That realization sends a shudder through you. If the demon that pursued you was any other warp-entity, the energies leaking out would... well, you'd be lucky if they were only Dhar. But this is the All-Knowing Serpent, Wisdom's Asp, and apparently the ever-shifting hue of its scales is mirrored by the pure combination of magical energies that it is formed from. Instead of liquid corruption pouring forth, this is pure, untainted, liquid magic. [What's in the box? Learning, Req 50, 34+16+20(Ranald's Blessing)=70.] --- Finally, the Big Day is upon you. You wear your greyest robe, polish your sword until it shines, make good use of your newly restored ability to safely look in mirrors to make sure your hair is cooperating, and summon a horse and wrap Ulgu around you to ride into Eagle Castle in a manner at least vaguely reminiscent of a Knight. The ceremony, it was decided, is going to be fairly low-key, and nobody would be invited on the grounds that any protests would be a lot less effective after the fact than if they occurred before or during. But even so, there'd be plenty of people there - Van Hal himself, of course, and Wilhelmina, Anton, Julia, and Markus. Kasmir had returned from Leicheberg to act as the ecclesiastical witness. On top of all those, there were the usual courtiers, a representative from the Wurtbad City Council, a visiting diplomat from Talabecland, representatives from a half-dozen barons and counts who were in Wurtbad at the time... by the time it was all added up, it was quite the crowd for an event that was supposed to go unnoticed. And then as you enter the Great Hall, you see someone among the chatting crowd that completely derails your train of thought - your Master, shamelessly looting a plate of entrees from a plate held by a hapless servant. "What are you doing here?" you ask as you sidle up to him, half enthused and half suspicious. "When a pawn reaches the end of the board," he says through a mouthful of cold meats, "it turns into a different piece. The question to ask is, what piece shall it become?" He smiles that infuriating smile of his, the one you spent years practising until you could project mysterious smugness as well as him. You also learned the counter to it: deliberate obtuseness. "I can clear that up for you," you say brightly. "I'm being made a knight." He opens his mouth, gives you an annoyed look, and then closes it with a snap. "I am glad you're here, though," you say, and his expression softens. "Wouldn't miss it, my girl," he says gruffly. "You were thrown in to the great wide ocean to sink or swim, and by Sigmar you swam." He clears his throat. "That said, I'm not just here to celebrate with you." "Ah," you say. Grey Order business? No, he'd send that business encrypted, standard procedure and besides, all the better to show off his encryption with. Sent either by post if it was business as usual, or pinned to your nightgown when you woke in the morning if you'd done something to irk the Order. For him to deliver it in person... "The other business." Without seeming to move or speak, he shapes Ulgu around the two of you. An illusion wrapped in ignorability, the show-off. "Afraid so. There's whispers of a campaign into Sylvania in the air, and it seems to have drawn the attention of our mutual acquaintance." He produces an envelope from his robes. "I took the liberty of reading it - I've got a different cipher glued to my eyelids than you do, but I haven't met a cipher yet I couldn't crack." "Except one-time pads," you note as you take it, ignoring his scowl, opening the already-broken seal and skimming the contents, the cipher burning to life once more. With ease of long practice you tune out his usual spiel about the problems with pseudorandomness and the in-his-opinion crippling handicap of key distribution. Have means in place to gather information re: undead types and density in Sylvania if and when Stirland forces sally across the border. When information is acquired, send via your Master. If possible, collection of live samples will be rewarded; send news of any you secure via same and we will arrange collection. "Troubling," your Master says, neatly summarizing your thoughts on the matter. "Seventh Article," you reply. "Applies only to the Orders," he responds. "Are they?" "Good question." You brood over the wording of the message. "Will be rewarded. A test? Or an acknowledgement?" "Carrot and stick, perhaps. Handling 101." You scowl. "I am not handled. I am the one who handles." "Not quite yet, Journeywoman," he says. You mull that over. "Journeywoman, yes. But also Spymistress. And now: Knight." He smiles indulgently. "Dame Weber. But still; spite alone is poor reason. It chafes, yes - but it does not throttle." "Yet," you say darkly. "Today has enough problems without borrowing tomorrow's," he replies, and you subside. "This is a grand day. You'll regret it if you let this taint it." --- In the privacy of Ulgu, you hug your Master, and resolve to follow his advice. The illusion shimmers and Ulgu shifts as you walk away, and you don't bother to look around, knowing that your Master would not be visible. You make your way to the head of the hall, where Van Hal is deep in discussion with Talabecland's diplomat, who is sketching figures on a slate. As you approach, he wraps up the conversation, pats the diplomat on the back, and turns to you. "Mathilde," he says in greeting. "You're looking..." he thinks for a moment. "You're looking very you, only more so than usual." "Thank you, your Grace," you reply politely, falling back on formulae for lack of a better response. "If you're finished saying farewell to the origins you've thoroughly outgrown, we can begin the ceremony." You nod, and he makes his way to the throne, standing before it. He does not call for silence, but he receives it nonetheless, conversation trailing to a halt all over the hall as all eyes move to him. Anton hurries out of the crowd and takes up position next to the throne - Van Hal never bothered to appoint an envoy, but the ceremony demands one so Anton is it - and he calls out, "The Count now calls Mathilde Weber to come before this Court." Okay. Just like Anton taught you. You walk forward and stand before Van Hal. You notice all over again just how tall the man is. "Mathilde Weber, have you undertaken to accept the accolade of Knighthood that was offered to you at Eagle Castle?" "I have." Without turning, Van Hal addresses Anton. "Sir Anton Kiesinger II, as a member of the Peerage, do you now affirm that Mathilde Weber has grown in virtue and honour, the hallmarks of a true and faithful Peer?" Unable to keep the smile from his face or his voice, Anton recites: "May it please my Liege to know that having heard the counsel of my Peers, and from my own certain knowledge, I am able to affirm that Mathilde Weber is a worthy lady whose achievements on the field of honour have been matched by her services to the Empire." "Mathilde Weber," Van Hal intones, "you have been deemed fit for this high estate. Do you now swear, by Sigmar and all the Gods of the Empire, that you will honour and defend the Empire of Man?" "This day do I render homage and fealty to my Lord, the Elector Count Abelhelm Van Hal of Stirland, who will, from this day forward, be my Liege. I will remain true in all ways, serving him faithfully - this do I swear, by my life and by my Gods. So say I, Mathilde Weber." "I accept your homage and fealty, and pledge to you that from this day forward until the end of my reign, you are my Liegewoman, and that I will honour and defend your rights as a Knight." You brace yourself, knowing what's coming next. "Let this be the last blow you receive unanswered." And with that, he delivers a heavy blow to your face that near sends you sprawling and marks the culmination of the ceremony. --- To all nobles to whom these present letters shall come. Abelhelm Van Hal, Elector Count of Stirland, sends greetings. Whereas Mathilde Weber has shown excellence in her feats on the field of honour, rendering high and noble service to the Empire in war and in peace, I am minded to elevate her to the rank of Knight. We do hereby elevate and affirm the attached Arms by these Letters Patent, to wit: Sable, bend argent, sword argent bendwise inverted, base dexter serpent supine vert and or, which Dame Mathilde Weber shall hold for her sole and unique use throughout the Empire. To which I set my hands this 9th day of Brauzeit, 2473. Abelhelm Van Hal, Elector Count. --- As the various coworkers, courtiers and visitors mingle and accept food from circulating servants, you find your way to Kasmir as he signs off on the papers marking you as a Knight. "A great honour," he notes without looking up. "One I will prove myself worthy of," you reply, just a touch of defensiveness in your tone. Then you wince at yourself. "Kasmir, I wanted to apologize. That business with the infiltrators, what I said-" But Kasmir has looked up from his papers, and shakes his head firmly. "You were right to make my failure known. One cannot serve Sigmar at the expense of Sigmar's Empire, and Sigmar is not the only God of Sigmar's Empire. I had forgotten that." He runs a finger along the spine of the Deus Sigmar strapped to his belt. "Had but one of them claimed to hold Sigmar as their patron God, I would have uncovered them in moments. But Morrites? Shallyans?" He sighs. "You succeeded where I failed." He seems to struggle with himself for a moment, then offers, "will you pray with me, Dame Mathilde?" That's as close to an apology from him as you're likely to get. You reach back to the prayers of your childhood, and intone with him: Lord Sigmar, hear my prayer. Let not my weapon fail me, but strengthen it against the foe. Give my blade your wisdom, to cleave the guilty from the innocent. Let your holy fire infuse the powder to burn in the eyes of the heretic. Keep your hand on mine, Sigmar, so that my grip and my faith will not slip. My arm shall strike in Thy name, against the heretic, the witch, the unclean. Amen. --- To anyone else, your estate would be an inconvenient distance from Wurtbad, up treacherous slopes and along paths riddled with potholes. But your horse, formed of Ulgu and shaped by your will, cares not for the conditions of the roads, and you contemptuously gallop across terrain that would cripple any flesh-and-blood horse attempting the same. When you arrive deep in the hills around Sonningwiese, you find an estate consisting of hill and rock and scrub. The local peasants are a scattered and hardy lot, so different to the lowland peasants of your youth. Instead of spending lifetimes working the same plot of land season after season, they drive herds of sheep over land too steep and rocky for crops and flocks of goats over land too steep for sheep. In times of war they muster with slings, and though it certainly doesn't sound like much, a chunk of rock the size of a man's fist delivered at speed to the skull deters a great many of the enemies of the Empire. It is, you ponder, a tough land; not a rich land, never a rich land, but never a poor land either. Not a threat in the Empire will ever choose to climb up the rocky foothills to chase sheep, not when there's leagues of farmland and town all around, and the hardy hill sheep ignore droughts that would leave farmers ruined. It is a land that you could ignore for a century and still be much the same as you left it. The closest thing the locals have to a leader (apart from yourself, of course) is a man with a slightly larger herd and a slightly larger hut, and representatives from the hill clans gather there to give you their oaths. The reception they give you is muted but not hostile; the general consensus seems to be that yes, you're a witch, and therefore probably a dangerously insane meddler in powers man was not meant to meddle in - but at least you're not a merchant. You ride a horse of shadow, but at least you can ride, and that sword on your back sends a clear message; you're an odd sort of knight, but you're infinitely more a knight than those of the Stirlandian League that 'owned' the land previously, so you'll do, seems to be the general consensus. Your position as lesser evil secured and your right to taxation acknowledged, you bid your subjects farewell and head back to civilization, where you're greeted with something you didn't expect: you've received mail. You've gotten letters from your Master before, and from whoever it is that's pulling your strings, but there's more in front of you now than you've received in all the years you've served as Spymaster. You sort through the envelopes, noting the ornate seals on them. You recognize one as belonging to Anton's family, and a second from your little romp through Leicheberg. Each of them, you discover, contains congratulations from the ruling classes of Stirland, welcoming you to their ranks, all stock phrases and rote best wishes. You frown, your well-honed cynicism doubting their sincerity. Okay, you grant, maybe not all of them. Anton's father is probably being sincere, or at least Anton writing on his father's behalf - you're pretty sure you recognize the handwriting. Okay, and maybe the Stirlandian League business might have won over Franzen and Wolfsbach, and considering you've got his daughter on your payroll, maybe the Grand Mayor of Flensburg is sincere too. You re-read the well-wishes from them, and smile. --- With that emotional roller-coaster out of the way, it's time to deal with cold, impersonal business. You sit in a townhouse not too far from that of your deputy spymistress, at a table that already has the EIC logo carved into it. Around the table, at the three hilts of the logo, sits three people: Wilhelmina, Markus, and you. (technically Wilhelmina is present not only as herself but also as Stirland, so in a business sense there's actually four people at the table. You're already confused.) Wilhelmina has tabulated a list of the ongoing contracts inherited from the Stirlandian League, sorted first by profitability and second by their likelihood to survive a newly reopened market; a quarter are to be dissolved by mutual agreement, a further third will be renegotiated with less profit per weight but a much higher throughput, and half of what's left are being auctioned off to the other traders of Stirland, who are eager for part of the North-South trade now that the way is clear. This leaves... a fraction, possibly, that the EIC will inherit unchanged, and the first order of business is filling them. To do this, the EIC is buying the transport infrastructure of the Stirlandian League off of Stirland; 'buying' is apparently the correct term for it even though no money is moving. The loan you took out, Wilhelmina explains, is remaining in the Stirland treasury because the funds are being used to purchase said infrastructure, so Stirland's 'loan' to you is actually in the form of what you worked so hard to have confiscated off the Stirlandian League. Are you being conned? This feels like a con. But it can't be, right? Wilhelmina's heard your reports to Van Hal. She wouldn't dare. Days pass in an ocean of numbers and terminology and jargon. As far as you can tell, things are moving back and forth, and being sold and bought, and money is changing hands, and everything's going well. The first contract is completed, and payment arrives in Wurtbad, and there's wine for the three of you and you get your first dividends, except you don't, what you get is a piece of paper saying that your dividends were used to repay your loan to Stirland, except the 'loan' never left Stirland's treasury, it's still there, and so are your dividends. What? And then Wilhelmina explains that the client in Talabheim didn't actually send money from Talabheim to Wurtbad. They sent a piece of paper to a bank in Wurtbad, and the bank has given the EIC money, except it's actually the client's money because the bank, which holds all the client's money, now owns some of that money it was holding anyway? You are so confused. [Contributing to the EIC: Stewardship, Roll, 9+10=19.] --- You finally escape from the EIC offices after what feels like the eternitieth time you tried to figure out what the hell is going on. After all that, you need a break. You'll go shopping. Finally buy that enchantment gear you wanted, surely fashion has moved on, right? [Mathilde vs Wizard Chic: Req 40, Stewardship, 10+10=20.] It hasn't. It's gotten worse. And you are to blame. Stirland's newest knight has inflamed the imagination of the feckless youths of Wurtbad, and somehow the availability of magical equipment has fallen from its previous level of zero. Everywhere you look, some twit is using something that would be very useful for your magical experiments as a necklace. And the worst part is you can't even be mad at them because whenever you go to yell at them, they notice you and start squealing in excitement and ask for you to sign their wizard hats! How can you be mad at someone that's idolizing you so thoroughly? So after your encounters with business and fashion, you retreat to something that's actually understandable: bending the very fabric of reality to your will. You write to your Master and have the last few tomes sent over, and you shut yourself away from the oh-so-frustrating world for a while and make the physical realm your plaything. Among a pair of new spells you finally pick up Magic Alarm again, and try to develop the habit of setting it on the entrance to your Buried Palace, which is instantly stymied because every single time you cast the spell, a cat wanders over and sits directly in it. The world is conspiring to drive you insane, you're sure of it. [Rounding out the last few spells, Req 50, Learning, 62+16=78.] --- TITLE, RIGHTS, AND DUTIES ACQUIRED: Knight APOLOGY NOT ACTUALLY NEEDED: +2 to relationship with Kasmir BUSINESS PARTNER: +1 to relationship with Wilhelmina, Markus. STAKE ACQUIRED IN EIC. ANOTHER MASSIVE DEBT ACQUIRED. SPELLS LEARNED: Move, Skywalk, Magic Alarm ALL LESSER SPELLS KNOWN!: +1 Magic CURRENT QHYASH-JUICE STOCKPILE: 1 gallon Discretionary Income: +150g Embezzlement: -35g Veteran informants: -60g Watch informants: -10g EIC informants: -20g Julia: -30g Townhouse staff: -20g --- Net: -25g Personal Income: +50g Estate Profit: +10g Embezzlement: +35g Tithe: -6g Student Loans: -35g --- Net: +54g --- Once more, you're all gathered around the council table. Anton sits with a look of concentration on his face, trying to think of a new pretence to ask you something just so he can call you Dame Mathilde; you'll tell him to stop it as soon as you get tired of hearing it, which will probably be never. Wilhelmina looks smugger than usual, or maybe you're just projecting that onto her after your failure to even begin to understand what it is she's doing with the EIC. Kasmir's looking serene; you actually heard word from your friends in the Thieves Guild that he's been asking around for a Priest of Ranald, putting word out that there's a chaplaincy open for one. You doubt it would ever be filled, but it's more evidence of his newfound openness to non-Sigmarite faiths. Schultz is missing an ear, but actually doesn't seem that put out about it - he's recently taken to hauling around what looks like a genuine Hochland long rifle and is animatedly engaged in conversation with Gustav about the interplay between height and range. --- The Wurtbad Watch has been completely subsumed, and you personally rewrote the document they draw their legitimacy from. What, exactly, did you write into this document? [ ] Pick a new name to reflect your Stirland-wide ambitions for the force (optional) Pick one of the following to be explicitly named in the founding documents, giving you the opportunity to shape the Watch into a force that can perform this as well as their regular duties: [ ] Underground: Absorbing the Sewer Jacks and rat-catchers into the Watch will allow you to make the underways of the city as safe as the streets above. [ ] Road Network: Bringing the Road Wardens under the Watch's banner will allow them to project force along the roads connecting the towns, not just within the towns themselves. [ ] Riverwardens: With the addition of a fleet of very small warships, the Watch extend their reach onto the waterways of Stirland, fighting piracy and smuggling in the rivers that are the Empire's lifeblood. [ ] Self-Sustaining: If the Watch took on officially sanctioned side jobs protecting caravans and merchant ships between cities, they could basically fund themselves instead of being a constant drain on Stirland's coffers, effectively fueling their own growth. [ ] Sally Force: Small unit tactics and woodsman training makes the Watch able to sally forth in strength to combat hotspots of corruption, crime and restless dead in the woods and hills of the countryside on top of their city duties. [ ] Siege Training: Training with ranged weapons and the basics of siege engineering will turn the Watch into a ferocious force multiplier if their city comes under siege. [ ] Militia: Focusing on military training will allow the Watch, in times of war, to join battlefields and give a showing equal to that of any full-time military unit. [ ] Other (write in) Note: while you could, at a later date, fold groups like the Road Wardens or Sewer Jacks into the Watch, they would act as a special branch of the Watch rather than something the mainstream Watch can do. This is a unique opportunity to create a second purpose for the organization that it can perform just as well as the first. They will not have this capability immediately, of course, but the goal of being capable of it will be written into their founding document. Public Report: Write in (optional; can write in word for word, or just outline what is focused on) Private Report: Write in (optional; the private meeting is traditional at this point and will take place, simply say whether there's anything specific you want to bring up here) Potential Orders: Investigation: [ ] There's definitely evil afoot in Drakenhof. Perhaps there's a way to survive investigating this. [ ] The disappearance of your predecessor is very concerning, but according to the Stirlandian League he's pulled out of the game with all his ill-gotten gains. If you're not willing to let that go, maybe you could track him down anyway. [ ] You kind of regret learning exactly what you did to the Thorned One, but you did it. But the liquid leaking out? That's still an unknown. Will Van Hal let you look into it on the clock? [ ] The spell used by the informants is like nothing you've heard of before. You want to see if you can detect or replicate it. [ ] Something your new Lieutenant said gave you an idea. Investigate the shores of the Black Water, see if it can truly be tamed. [ ] If we've got vampire troubles, maybe you should spend some time investigating how to counter vampiric infiltration. [ ] Wilhelmina said a lot of really complicated words at you. Maybe she's up to something. Or maybe you just don't know a goddamn thing about large-scale inter-provincial trade. Either way, something to look into. Infrastructure: [ ] Your intelligence infrastructure is becoming worthy of the title; perhaps you could dedicate some time to expanding it. And, ideally, Stirland could pay for it directly instead of it eating your discretionary income. [ ] The Wurtbadian Watch is now your pet. Given more time, you can make it your attack dog. [ ] You've got the town of Biderhof eating out of your hand. If you could think of a reason to justify it, maybe all the taxes from it's lumber sales could flow into your pocket instead. [o] The Wurtbad Thieves Guild, despite barely being a loose gossip network, really came through during the take-down of the Stirlandian League. Maybe you should cultivate this useful tool. (Van Hal has said: not until the Watch is greatly scaled up) [ ] For no particular reason, it'd be a good idea to see about informants within the military. [ ] Also for no particular reason, how about I see about building a unit in the army dedicated to catching terrible necromantic gribblies? [] Other/s (write in) --- - The Knighthood Ceremony owes more to SCA tradition than Warhammer lore; I make no apologies. - This may be the longest chapter to date of this Quest; it certainly feels like it. - Plan for the Watch and for the Reporting are separate. - Your increase in income and continued payment of the tithe means I finally have to surrender my dedication to multiple-of-5 gold amounts.

Turn 9 - 2474

Winning votes: [*][WatchDuty] Underground: Absorbing the Sewer Jacks and rat-catchers into the Watch will allow you to make the underways of the city as safe as the streets above. [*][WatchName] Stirland Watch [*] [Public] Plan The Watched -[*] The Watch is now legally under the office of the Spymaster and no longer doing their own thing on the city's budget. If anyone has areas of concern regarding law enforcement needing attention they could bring it up as well. --[*] You'd also want to talk to Kasmir about arranging some appropriate spiritual guidance for the Watch, since it doesn't have anything formal set up, and this being Stirland, they could probably use someone to talk to when they come across dead bodies, or help answer the more complicated questions they encounter in the course of their duties, like when some burgher are simply following a legal cult too enthusiastically rather than conducting an unholy sacrifice to the dark powers. [*] [Private] Plan Team Mystic -[*] Much to your chagrin the efforts at setting up a lab had been hit yet again by the latest fashion statement. Which was your own damned fault. You hope this is funding expansion in somebody's fancy glassware industries somewhere and the price drops once the fad wears out. -[*] In addition to publicly taking over the Watch, you've also put in agents throughout the middle layers to make sure that thing with the servants never happens again. -[*] Apparently you've somehow captured the Wisdom's Asp in such a manner that it got stuck threading between the mirrors, so it's half alive and half dispersed, half in the material realm and half in the Warp...well this particular snake is not going to reform as slain daemons and their ilk are wont to while the box exists. Unfortunately the method wouldn't work safely on anything BUT a Wisdom's Asp, and it'd have to be very very unlucky or extremely stupid to get stuck in this exact manner. -[*] The lands you were granted for your knighthood were very well suited to your limited availability to oversee the estates. Thanks for that. [Orders] Plan Who Ya Gonna Call? [*] If we've got vampire troubles, maybe you should spend some time investigating how to counter vampiric infiltration. [*] Your intelligence infrastructure is becoming worthy of the title; perhaps you could dedicate some time to expanding it. And, ideally, Stirland could pay for it directly instead of it eating your discretionary income. [*] The Wurtbadian Watch is now your pet. Given more time, you can make it your attack dog. [*] Write In: Given the many forms and threats of undead in the region, perhaps it might be useful to have a dedicated unit to track them down and dissect them to learn how to better kill the things, how they might form, and how they might disguise or hide their nature, so as to actually push the undead back permanently. Something like what you did together on the transformed servants, but on a bigger scale. Number of voters: 11 Click to expand... Click to shrink... Van Hal finally arrives, carrying his usual burden of papers that is swiftly added to by everyone around the table. He takes a moment to skim through them and, apparently not seeing anything unexpected, opens the meeting. "Most of my time has been spent in Leicheberg," he says, "and thus far, my impressions have been positive. The as-yet unnamed Fort outside of Leicheberg has come into its own as a new center of military might in Stirland, and to Gustav, Kasmir and Detlef, I give my thanks." The three of them accept the gratitude with nods, grins on Gustav and Schultz playing counterpart to the slightest hint of a smile on Kasmir's face. "Schultz, your report?" "The barracks now deserve the title of a Fort, which at your Grace's suggestion has been named Fort Redemption. And while the Fort is not complete - no fort is ever complete, there is always more that can be done to make it more secure - it is now completely in operation. Two Divisions call it home, and the administrative infrastructure for them is now in place. Unfortunately, I can't say as much for what the troops insist on calling the Haunted Highway - attacks have increased even further, bringing work to a standstill on both ends. Gustav has the details." At Van Hal's nod, Gustav chimes in. "The newly-formed Outriders have been taking hits just keeping the roadworks going. I've tried to scout out the Hills both myself and by sending some of the more skilled recruits, but there's just too many of the buggers out there to get far without being chased out, so I can't tell whether we've just stirred up the area or if this is indicative of some 'critical mass' of Sylvaniism. There's some good news - apart from a few gaps in the ranks from casualties, there's now two cohorts of pistoliers formed." "Attach them both to the 2nd Division," Van Hal says. "Kasmir?" "The chaplaincy project is well underway," he says. "I estimate another six months until the 2nd and 3rd are fully served. The chaplains already recruited are setting up shrines to the six most common gods within the wall of Fort Redemption; Sigmar, Ulric, Myrmidia, Verena, Shallya and Morr. These should serve the needs of the men, though I would like it to be a priority in the medium-term for these to be expanded into temples." "That road is a priority - with it, the 4th would be only a week away. Without, it's closer to three, and that's if the Moot has no objection to our forces marching through their lands. I'll return to Leicheberg with the three of you, and decide there whether the Divisions will deploy in force to protect roadworks, or whether it's time to sally into the Haunted Hills. Wilhelmina, how's the home front?" "Trade is picking up well," she says, glancing down at a page full of figures. "The EIC is already profiting from continuing the trade agreements we picked up, and the sale of the rest has been a welcome addition to Stirland's coffers." "Speaking of trade, I want you to make sure the supply chain for Fort Redemption is secure. I think the army is currently buying from the open market in Leicheberg and that's mostly been working out because the local traders have been importing from the Moot, and if that's a viable long-term solution then fine, but I don't know that it is. Come with us back to Fort Redemption and look the situation over. Mathilde, how's law enforcement?" "The Watch is now legally under the office of the Spymistress, and drawing funds from the Stirlandian treasury rather than that of the City of Wurtbad. I'll be working to expand their coverage and skills in the coming years, and I'd like for the army's chaplaincy program to be expanded to cover them - they're currently without any formal spiritual guidance." "Kasmir, when it comes time to provide Chaplains to the 1st, take care of the Watch as well," Van Hal orders. He looks down at the papers you handed him thoughtfully. "This idea you have about investigating and countering undead threats... it's an interesting idea, but how do you envision its organization?" "A tricky question," you reply. "As this is a completely new idea, it's difficult to see where it would work best. It could be attached to the military, or the Watch, or be an independent organization under the office of the Spymistress." "It does seem a natural fit for the Witch Hunters," Kasmir chimes in. "Or a branch campus of the Colleges," Van Hal says thoughtfully. "Or possibly under me directly. Too many unknowns. If you have spare time, put together a proper proposal, including where they'd fit into existing hierarchies, and I'll consider it in the future. For now, expand the Watch along the Old Dwarf Road - if the troubles in the Haunted Hills are indicative of a general uptick in undead activity, those hills east of Potting are going to become a problem, and I want forces able to maintain order in at least Worden and Potting, and ideally along all population centers along the Road. Anton, what about you?" "There was a lot of talk about how much land east of the Matting the County of Wolfsbach would get, but it all worked out in the end," Anton reports happily. "Everyone's happy with the arrangement and I made sure that everyone knew that you were to thank for it, so everyone in Western Stirland is really happy with you." Van Hal gives Anton a thoughtful look. "Including Blutdorf?" "Oh, dad was already happy," he explains. "He likes me having this job, and he likes all the pistols that we've been buying from Wissenland, and he likes that the Stirlandian League has been stomped on." Van Hal just stares at Anton blankly for a moment, then smiles. "Good to hear. Talabecland will be your next stop - they're still getting used to the idea of a Stirland that actually does things instead of slowly decomposing into a puddle of grift on their southern border, so I'd like you to remind them that I'm not a Haupt-Anderssen. Say things about trade, and sound them out regarding any assistance they'd be willing to give for an invasion in force into Sylvania. It's a long shot, but worth asking." The meeting drifts to a close after that, as Van Hal starts discussing travel arrangements with Schultz, Kasmir and Gustav. You gather up your papers and head off to await Van Hal in his office. --- "I really need to start a Leicheberg to Halstedt road," Van Hal groans as he enters his office, and takes the mug of brandy from you gratefully - you fished the bottle out of his bottom drawer while waiting for him. "Thanks. Blasted Sylvania - Stirland could be a wealthy and productive land without that millstone around our collective necks." "If wishes were fishes, there'd be no room in the rivers for water," you reply, and he snorts. "True, true. But by Sigmar, we can't even build a bloody road without ghosts coming out of the hills to try and eat us." You nod in commiseration, and he sits himself down, broodily sipping at his mug. "Not that there aren't upsides," he admits. "Any other province and I would have been drawn into Imperial politics immediately. Stirland, I had some breathing room until they started playing games." "Talabecland?" you guess. "Talabecland are the loudest of them, but that's just because they see an opportunity to rebuild southern trade and want to get the lion's share of profits from it. We'll see how well Wilhelmina does at preventing that. But Averland and Ostermark are watching, because Sylvania's partly their problem too, and Wissenland and Reikland... god, it's easy to forget that Stirland's got half the Empire as neighbours. But there's an Elector's Meet coming up, and that's going to mean all eyes on the newcomer." "Oh? What's the topic?" "Dwarf business. Some hold they want to reclaim. But there'll be the usual politicking on the side - marriage will probably come up." "An unmarried Elector Count usually doesn't stay that way for long," you note neutrally, not sure how you feel about this. "Widowed, actually," he corrects, and smiles a little sadly at your look of shock. "Ancient history. She died in childbirth in '66. There's three little Van Hals out there, ready to carry on the family mission should this experiment fail, but nobody knows about them but a few trusted allies." He lets the silence stretch a little moment, then breaks it. "Anyway. Report. How's Knighted life treating you?" You take a moment to get your thoughts in order. "Very well. The lands seem capable of thriving from neglect - thank you for that." He nods in acceptance, and you move on to the next topic. "On top of those in command reporting to me directly, I've got informants throughout the ranks of the Watch. It won't be able to wriggle free of my grip." "I'd expect nothing less. How goes that snake of yours?" "Fashion is making it aggravatingly difficult to get my hands on equipment for a proper study, but I managed to figure some things out. I somehow captured the Wisdom's Asp in such a manner that it got stuck threading between the mirrors, so it's half alive and half dispersed, half in the material realm and half in the Warp... it's not going to be able to reform like slain demons usually do, not while the box exists. Unfortunately the method wouldn't work safely on anything but a Wisdom's Asp..." You frown at a sudden thought. "Unless there's other types of warp entities out there that use untainted winds... anyway. It'd have to be a very, very unlucky or extremely stupid entity to get stuck in this exact manner." "A shame, but considering the cost, it's unlikely that the same method would enter a Witch Hunter's standard arsenal. Still, once your studies are concluded, if there's nothing unusually sensitive about the information have it written up and sent to the Archives in Altdorf. Undistributed knowledge is wasted knowledge." You nod, and he looks down at the papers he dumped on his desk when he entered and sighs. "If there's nothing else, I've got a lot of paperwork to get through before I can go gallivanting around the Sylvanian border." You take the hint, and your leave. --- Fort Redemption built outside Leicheberg 2nd and 3rd Division now have attached chaplaincy corp 1st and 2nd Pistolier Cohort added to 2nd Division Wealth of Stirland: Recovering Income of Stirland: Mediocre Treasury of Stirland: Mediocre Flensburg Issue: Solved! Western Stirland loyalty is now unshakeable. --- PLAN FOR THIS TURN ORGANIZATIONAL ACTIONS - pick ONE from EACH of the categories 'Information Network' and 'Stirland Watch': Information Network - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [ ] Consolidation: You currently have a patchwork of useful contacts. Backfill so that you can rightfully claim to cover entire towns. [ ] Interweave your network with the Watch as it expands, so that you can use the Watch to cover your network's communication lines and actions. (NEW) [ ] Expand your information network into another province (choose one) (LOCKED until information network is financially independent or discretionary income expanded) (NEW) [ ] Expand your information network into another county or barony (choose one) (LOCKED until information network is financially independent or discretionary income expanded) (NEW) [ ] Expand your information network into the military (choose a Division) (LOCKED until information network is financially independent or discretionary income expanded) (NEW) [ ] Off the Leash: Let Julia handle the network without your micromanagement from now on. (LOCKED until information network is financially independent or discretionary income expanded; will remove this from Organizational Actions) (NEW) [ ] Choose a formal name for your information network (write in - does not count as your choice for the Network) Information Network finances - expansion is hobbled by it's dependence on your discretionary income, and so is your budget. Perhaps you can get past that. Can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above. [ ] Information Broker: Start selling tidbits of information, just enough for your information network to start paying for itself. [ ] Fixer: Work with the Wurtbad Thieves Guild, supplying them information in exchange for a portion of profits. (NEW) [ ] Special Branch: Pull some financial trickery to get the information network classified as part of the Watch, so that their costs are covered by the Stirlandian treasury. (NEW) [ ] Trade Delegation: Convince Wilhelmina and Markus to partner your network with the EIC based on the value of market information. (NEW) Stirland Watch - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [ ] Expand the ranks of the Watch, so that they're able to start covering even the poorer parts of their covered area. [ ] Improve the training of the Watch, hiring trainers and dedicating paid time each week to sharpening skills. [ ] Integrate the Roadwarden network of covered areas into the Watch. [ ] Expand the administration of the Watch so that they can expand into other counties without your personal oversight. [ ] Seek out a new leader for the Watch. PERSONAL ACTIONS - CHOOSE BETWEEN FIVE AND SEVEN. ANY CHOSEN BEYOND THE FIRST FIVE WILL COME WITH RISKS - PLEASE SPECIFY THE 'ADDITIONAL' TASKS.: As Per Orders: Perform your current assignment. [ ] Complete taking control of the renamed Stirland Watch. (spend an action to complete the takeover begun last turn) [ ] Investigate the possibility of adding a River Warden branch of the Watch. [ ] Integrate the rat catchers, sewer-jacks and gong farmers into the Watch, and begin having the rank-and-file of the Watch learn from them (Watch speciality action). [ ] Expand the Watch into the rest of the County of Wurtbad, first priority being Tarshof. [ ] Expand the Watch into the County of Worden, prioritizing Worden and Potting. Miscellany: [ ] Financial Jargon: Everything with the EIC flew right over your head last time. Try again. Succeeding here will mean that you can take a more active hand in the company, adding it to the organizational actions; failing or not attempting means Mathilde will remain a silent partner. (NEW) [ ] Hang Out A Shingle: Spymasters don't advertise, but wizards sometimes do. Make an official announcement that there's a wizard in residence, and see who comes out of the woodwork. [ ] Can I Come Too?: Everyone seems to be riding off to Leicheberg lately. Tag along and see what's going on with these Haunted Hills. (NEW) [ ] Formal Proposal: Your idea for an undead research team intrigues Van Hal, but he wants more information. Write up a full proposal, including where it will fit in the existing heirarchy, and spend some time sourcing the equipment it would require. Write in details: Name, who it is technically a part of (Watch, Witch Hunters, Military, College, none), and whether it reports directly to you (becomes a new Organization you command) or not. (NEW) [ ] A Crisis of Faith: Van Hal's ongoing alienation with the Sigmarite faith seems to be on the mend. But maybe you feel like meddling anyway. (write in) Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. [ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills and internalize the lessons you've learned (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective if you've used the trait a lot lately). [ ] Tutoring: One of your fellow councillors may be willing to teach you in their chosen field (choose who). [ ] Pretty Good Swords: You've struck up a friendship with the Champion of the Greatswords and have discovered a talent for wielding them. Continue to cultivate this. [ ] Combat Training: You're virtually surrounded by armed warriors of various sorts. See if you can convince one to teach you (choose who). [ ] Combat Training, In The Free Market: You haven't made many heavily armed friends yet, but gold is good for that. Go out and buy some training. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. [ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Remixed: You're getting sick of having workmen tramping in and out of your abode. Recruit an entire team and personally oversee them to clear out all of the reachable portions of the Palace-Shrine and be done with it. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: So far you've still failed to find suitable equipment (damn Wizard Chic) but you could always try to throw your authority behind commissions from glassblowers and blacksmiths. (-discretionary gold, action required to set up and learn to use equipment) [ ] Filled with Potential: You've got a room cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put there and get started on equipping it. (write in the purpose of the room) Research: [ ] Undead Research: This is Stirland. Time to bone up on your knowledge of the Undead. [ ] Shyish-kebabs: The Shyish swords are hideously dangerous as weapons, but fascinating as a subject of study. Try to reverse-engineer the lost enchantments woven into them. [ ] Bound Spells: Though the corrosive Dhar made them high-maintenance, the design of the bound spells in the castle's infiltrators has fascinating possibilities. Try to adapt it for use with Ulgu. [ ] Qhaysh Juice: Whatever it is, it's dripping out of the box at a steady rate. It's got to be good for something. (NEW) [ ] As a Journeywoman, the path to Magister is marked by mastering more than the two shadow spells you already know. Send to the Grey Order for the basics and work on figuring out one of the others. Influence: [ ] Thieves Guild: It's currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. If it could be expanded under your aegis, it could be a powerful tool. [ ] Biderhof: This village based on woodcutting and agriculture, has adopted you as one of it's own. Maybe you should adopt it as your own, in a literal sense. [ ] Non-Thief Guilds: Wurtbad, like all major cities, is home to a number of guilds. Reach out to them and enforce your will. Relations: [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with one of your fellow councillors or your liege, offering your help in their tasks and generally getting a feel for them (choose one). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: You've been given good reason to mistrust your fellow councillors. Perhaps you should see what they spent their time doing (choose one). [ ] Letters Home: You might be able to wring more information out of your Master, or you might just be able to get news, information and guidance in general from the Grey Order. [ ] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (no action required) --- WAIFU VOTE Who, if anyone, does Mathilde desire a romantic relationship with? This only determines who, in the privacy of her own mind, Mathilde likes the look of - it does not begin a relationship or even guarantee that such a relationship is possible, and by itself it will not change anything but some of her internal dialogue when faced with the person in question. Elector Count Abelhelm Van Hal: An ambitious choice. But you are a noble now, and you do share a number of interests... The Honourable Anton Kiesinger II: The heir to the Barony of Blutdorf appears to be completely lacking in subtlety and realpolitik knowhow, but he makes friends easily and seems to be remarkably competent at his job. Sir Markus von Pfaffbach: He's well-off if he was able to invest in the EIC, he holds a position of great honour, and he's damn skilled with his sword. Outrider Champion Gustav von Jungfreud: He's a newcomer to the game, but maybe you like a guy as at home on a physical horse as you are on a shadow horse. Brother Kasmir Heinz: Is he bound to a vow of chastity? Maybe not. Or maybe it would be fun to make him break it. Magister Regimand Speiseschrank: Mandatory sensei option. Wilhelmina Hochschild: Maybe you swing the other way. She's got children, but no mention of any husband. Julia Antoinette Massif: Another option of the fairer sex. She's a member of the ruling dynasty of the technically-democratic Chartered Free Town of Flensburg and has keen interest in archery and skulduggery. None of the above: Mathilde is open to the idea, but none of the current options really do it for her. None, period: Mathilde is not for romance. Ranald: NO, THAT'S HERESY Wisdom's Asp: DEFINITELY NOT --- FINANCES: NO ACTION POINT EXPENDITURE. Personal Income: 60 gold/turn Discretionary Income: 150 gold/turn Informer Payroll unlocked Currently paying Grey College tithe (-6 personal gold/turn) Currently paying Grey College student loans (-35 personal gold/turn) Currently embezzling 1/4 of discretionary income (-35 discretionary gold/turn, +35 personal gold/turn) Currently employing 6 veteran informants (-60 discretionary gold/turn) Currently funding a number of Watch informants (-10 discretionary gold/turn) Currently funding a number of EIC informants (-20 discretionary gold/turn) Currently employing Julia Massif (-30 discretionary gold/turn) Currently maintaining the staff of a townhouse in Wurtbad (-20 discretionary gold/turn) [ ] Begin plumping the informer rolls (choose ratio of real:fake informers. Almost impossible to detect, but also very difficult to increase or decrease the amount quickly) [ ] Change tithe payment/loan payment/embezzlement (specify) [ ] These agents are getting expensive. Write up a proposal for your discretionary budget to be increased, instead of waiting for Van Hal to decide to increase it. (warning: attracts oversight to your current budget) - You can write in orders, but something worth writing in is probably worth adding to the list of possible orders, so feel free to ask if your idea can be added. - As always, voting will be in plan format. The WAIFU VOTE will be separate to the plan. The WAIFU VOTE will not be a lock-in - it will change her inner monologue and unlock new personal actions, but if none of the relevant actions are taken and discussion in the thread starts to favour a different candidate, I will hold a new WAIFU VOTE. Yes, the all-caps is necessary - As more organizations are founded or absorbed, this will become more of a 'traditional' CK2 quest, with choices in a range of specialized areas each turn and personal actions separate. This can be 'walked back' if desired by allowing leaders to act independently and not bringing more organizations on board. I know that no choice will please everyone; some people will be excited for Mathilde to go from a single confused journeywoman muddling her way through things to ruling over a personal fiefdom of powerful organizations, but other people will be sad to see the quest lose the 'down-to-earth' tone of early turns. If you've a preference, express it through voting and explaining your point of view in the thread. - Don't forget Ranald's Blessing! - Take note - you now have FIVE actions, with the option to overwork up to seven. This represents the time taken to manage both your information network and the Watch - there is no way to eliminate this without completely giving up personal control over them.

Turn 9 Results - 2474

[*] [Actions] Plan Our Jobs Take Priority -[*] Interweave your network with the Watch as it expands, so that you can use the Watch to cover your network's communication lines and actions. (NEW) -[*] Expand the administration of the Watch so that they can expand into other counties without your personal oversight. -[*] Complete taking control of the renamed Stirland Watch. (finishes action begun last turn) -[*] Integrate the rat catchers, sewer-jacks and gong farmers into the Watch, and begin having the rank-and-file of the Watch learn from them (Watch speciality action). -[*] Expand the Watch into the County of Worden, prioritizing Worden and Potting. -[*] Can I Come Too?: Everyone seems to be riding off to Leicheberg lately. Tag along and see what's going on with these Haunted Hills. (NEW) --[*] Ranald's Blessing on Can I Come Too? -[*] Overwork - Undead Research: This is Stirland. Time to bone up on your knowledge of the Undead. -[*] Formal Proposal: Your idea for an undead research team intrigues Van Hal, but he wants more information. Write up a full proposal, including where it will fit in the existing heirarchy, and spend some time sourcing the equipment it would require. Write in details: Name, who it is technically a part of (Watch, Witch Hunters, Military, College, none), and whether it reports directly to you (becomes a new Organization you command) or not. (NEW) --[*] Name: Autopsy Agency --[*] Membership: College --[*] Control: Van Hal --[*] The organization would have wizards from the colleges, along with surgeons and hunters to best locate, combat, capture and dissect the undead encountered. The key difficulties will lie in detection, location and capture, where a wizard is best suited to the parts of detection and capture, being able to identify the Dhar at work and also counter or trace any necromancers involved. --[*] While there may be political costs to a formal expansion of the colleges, the value here in Stirland should be well worth it, and there is the alternative of hiring Journeymen and keeping the control under Van Hal's personal authority if the politics prove stubborn about a formal expansion, as his position makes commanding journeymen wizards simple by law. --[*] With the information gathered, it'd be helpful to the roles of Gustav, Kasmir and your own office to get the detailed reports. Specific tactics to fighting the unliving would greatly ease the losses on the forces combating the supernatural in the field, while your informants would also greatly benefit from identifying the more subtle forms of undead hidden within the populace or lurking where the people will only report otherwise vague rumors.. Then Kasmir's office to assess if the locals are coerced, duped or in collusion. -[*] Enchantment: So far you've still failed to find suitable equipment (damn Wizard Chic) but you could always try to throw your authority behind commissions from glassblowers and blacksmiths. (-discretionary gold, action required to set up and learn to use equipment) --[*] Just buy. Defer setup if you get anything -[*] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (no action required) --[*] Wilhelmina -[*] These agents are getting expensive. Write up a proposal for your discretionary budget to be increased, instead of waiting for Van Hal to decide to increase it. (warning: attracts oversight to your current budget) --[*] Budget increase dearly needed as the information network need huge expansion to refill the void left by the demise of the League, as well as watching the Watch to prevent corruption and hostile plants. Push for increase of 100 Gold at minimal, due to need to finding and keeping reliable officers. -[*] Cut Embezzlement to 0. You have your own estate income now to cover your fees. [*] [WAIFU] None of the above: Mathilde is open to the idea, but none of the current options really do it for her. - Number of voters: 30 [*] [WAIFU] Van Hal - Number of voters: 23 Click to expand... Click to shrink... Waifu Vote Result: Mathilde will be married to her job, but will have certain thoughts regarding Van Hal. --- There was a time, you reminisce, when every problem given to you was solved by running at it with sword and magic armour at the ready, and whatever happened, it was all wrapped up in time for dinner. Now, you've got bureaucracy. Tragically, it's entirely a necessary evil. The newly-renamed Stirland Watch could be a fantastic tool in all sorts of ways - for your information network, for presenting a credible threat to the criminal underworld to force them to fall in line under your authority, and, of course, for the good of the citizens of Stirland. So you have to grit your teeth and sit down and hammer together an organization pretty much from scratch because the blasted Bretonnian peasant who used to run the Wurtbad Watch took one look at your incoming regime and chose retirement. You secure oaths of loyalty from the remaining subordinates of the Bretonnian and move the headquarters to a townhouse that just so happens to be next door to that of your information network. You try to require them to give reports in writing instead of the verbal reports they used to give, but quickly run into the problem of widespread illiteracy, so you once more set up a literacy program for your underlings. You're getting sick of working with uneducated peasants, but when recruitment for the Watch is restricted to military veterans, you don't have much of a choice. Things rapidly start falling apart when you try to build a bureaucracy, however. You spend weeks on interview after interview, and in the end you're able to divide them neatly into two categories: incompetent and infiltrators. You invite a few of the second lot back to face rather more intensive interviewing, and as it turns out there's far greater demand for competent administrators than there is supply, thanks to the trade vacuum caused by your removal of the Stirlandian League. The EIC have snapped up a number to start with, but there's also other trade leagues moving into Wurtbad, and they're looking for bureaucrats of their own. And a few of those new hires have been sent on to you, in what appears to be a defensive measure - there's concerns that your brutal breakup of the Stirlandian League and the seizure of their assets may be habit-forming, and they want agents of their own in place to tip them off should you attempt the same with them. You put away your implements, thank your interviewees for their time and honesty, and have Julia return the rather distressed candidates back to their paymasters with your best regards. You spent some time with her later, trying to find an easy solution, but there just isn't one. There's no competent administrative staff left unspoken for in Wurtbad; the only way to get your hands on some is to go elsewhere to hire some on, or to start headhunting those already hired by other organizations, and there's just not the time for that right now. At least, Julia says brightly, it makes it easy for her to sink her hooks into the Watch unimpeded, but it's no comfort to you. Fine. If you've got to do everything yourself, so be it. --- Your last task before heading off to Southern Stirland is the expansion of the Watch downwards. You're acquainted with how sprawling the underways of Wurtbad are, and you want to start projecting power down there as well as the Watch currently does on street level. The first stop is the Sewer Jacks - technically already part of the Watch, they've just been operating independently for so long that they ran as a separate organization. A reminder of their charter and they fall in line, but talk of a greater focus on their duties gains their interest. You meet with the leader of the Jacks, a short and scarred man known as Lower Hans, a number of times over several weeks in their offices beneath the southern gatehouse of Wurtbad's inner walls. You explain that you envision the Sewer Jacks with improved equipment and training as an elite force dedicated to patrolling the sewers, whereas the rank-and-file of the watch will 'only' be brought up to the current level of expertise of the Sewer Jacks. His eyes brighten, but he speaks a single word: dwarves. Given time, you manage to extract further words from him. Dwarves, he explains, are the undisputed masters of tunnel warfare. The Stirland Watch can either spend a dozen lifetimes getting anywhere close to catching up to them, or they can bring in Dwarvern trainers to teach them. Stirland has a trade relation with Zhufbar, you remember, albeit one strained by all the Sylvania in between, so it's not entirely impossible - and there was mention of some dwarf issue being raised in the coming Elector's Meet, wasn't there? Something to keep in mind. You say you'll keep it in mind, sketch out plans for the Sewer Jacks to begin training the rest of the Watch, and move on to the more difficult part of the job. You hold a series of rather fragrant meetings with representatives from two of the most avoided guilds in Wurtbad: the Rat Catchers and the Gong Farmers. You paint a picture for them: one of a new, modern Watch that ruled the streets below as well as they did those above, of the sewers being a hidden but vital part of the Wurtbad machine instead of a hive of vermin and pestilence. Either as independent contractors or officially as employees of Stirland, they would be brought aboard and their roster expanded so that no more would any street in Wurtbad know the smell of human excrement and the skitter of paws in the dark. It's a surprisingly impassioned pitch, and it wins them over - it takes you weeks to hammer out the details but in the end, both guilds are being formally adopted by the Stirland Watch. Both start to expand their rosters, taking in the poorest and most desperate of Wurtbad's populace and offering them an income and a purpose. The Rat Catchers, no longer bound by the requirement to collect tails for bounty, begin to experiment with new ways to wage war on their eternal foe (it sounds a little melodramatic to you, but hey, whatever helps them find purpose) in the form of rat traps and poisons. As for the gong farmers, the tiniest outlay of funds from the Stirlandian treasury to purchase carts, wagons and barrels pays for itself within the month, as waste flows out of the city and, to your shock, money flows back in - solid waste goes to the farms to act as fertilizer for a modest fee, and it's downright shocking what the tanneries outside Wurtbad's walls will pay for liquid waste. And every drop and dollop that flows out is no longer lying on or under the streets of Wurtbad, or being dumped into the poor River Stir. If nothing else, you can claim with pride that Wurtbad is a better-smelling city for your intervention. [Finishing the takeover: Req 50, Stewardship, 71+10=81.] [Expanding the administration: Req 40, 14+10=24.] [Spotting the plants: Req 60, Intrigue, 53+16=69.] [Julia interrupt? Roll, 4. Nope.] [Sewer Jacks: Req 30, Stewardship, 95+10=105.] [Rat Catchers: Breakpoints 30/60, Stewardship, 64+10=74.] [Gong Farmers: Breakpoints 20/40, Stewardship, 69+10=79.] --- With all that set up, it's time to join the rest of the group in Southern Stirland. They set off weeks back, but with all you've got to do in Wurtbad you can't spend all your time wandering around the Haunted Hills, so instead you decide to join Wilhelmina's rather more relaxed journey south. It'll be far slower than if you had just ridden a shadowhorse, but a lot more comfortable and it gives you the opportunity to spend some time with Wilhelmina, your long-time coworker and now cofounder of the EIC. At least, that was the idea. In reality, Wilhelmina is entirely occupied with her own concerns, and the entire column was forced to wait awkwardly outside the EIC building as Wilhelmina has a screaming row with her eldest son; you can clearly hear the details, as can everyone in this quarter of Wurtbad. The son in question apparently feels that the EIC has no business getting caught up in an inevitably disastrous crusade into haunted Sylvania, and that she was putting some damn fool of a noble ahead of her own family; Wilhelmina shoots back that that 'noble' made the EIC possible, and continues to do so, and even if he didn't she'd still throw the full weight of the EIC behind him, and if he, the son, didn't like it he could resign his place in the company and go out into the world and find some other mother figure to leech off of. From there, things spiral downward awkwardly. You don't know how things ended, because after the first hour you summoned your shadowsteed and galloped out of the city on your own. [Spending time with Wilhelmina: Roll, 2.] --- You've got a fair bit of reading to do on your way to Southern Stirland to keep you occupied, and you're comfortable enough on shadowy horseback to read as your horse gallops. You've got a number of books on the undead, and more importantly you've got all the information your still-growing network has collected on Southern Stirland. You've honestly been neglecting to read the reports that flow in, leaving it up to Julia to make sure that there's nothing important in there - there's only so many hours in the day, after all - but you suppose now is as good a time as any to start tapping into it, and Julia had busily distilled those reports into solid nuggets of background information on every corner of Stirland. Southern Stirland, you soon realize, is actually the richest third of Stirland proper. Though Wurtbad is by far the largest population center in the province, Schramleben, Hornau, Leicheberg and Sigmaringen are second through fifth, the fertile soil between the Moot and the mountains supporting fertile fields and vast herds of cattle. It comes as something of a shock to you, as you'd assumed that Western Stirland, furthest from Sylvania and where you'd spent most of your time and attention, would naturally be the biggest part of it - but it's only Wurtbad that makes Western Stirland so important, and without it, the average wealth and size of the towns and villages is far below that of Southern Stirland. You suppose it makes sense, when you think about it. Most of Western Stirland (and Central Stirland, for that matter) is hills and woods; good for sheep and hunters, but not the sort of place that makes an area rich. For that, you need crops and cows. There were decent farmlands along the Aver, but they lacked the fertility of the lands tucked up against the Moot. You think you're starting to understand why generations of Stirland's Elector Counts have resented the halflings for the loss of Stirland's most valuable soil. The next report to fall under your eye was on Maksim von Stolpe, the young man that was elevated to rule after his brother got 'disappeared' by you, and his lands. Leicheberg's largest claim to fame (before Van Hal made it the military headquarters of Stirland, that is) was that it was, technically and arguably formerly, Sylvanian. The people were Stirlanders, but when the border was still a legal entity, Leicheberg was on the Sylvanian side of it. But generations of hard work and dedication and military might had forced back the terrible things in the night that made Sylvania what it was, and now the land was as solidly Stirland as any other, with the least haunted of the Haunted Hills supporting vast flocks of sheep and the lowlands of Swartzhafen supporting cattle. Every indication was that he was very enthused about the military presence in his lands, and considering that half of those lands fell within the 'Haunted Hills' and the other half in the shadow of the 'Ghoul Woods', you can certainly see why. You skim a single page on the neglected barony of Texing, which reverted to the Elector Count after the owning family died off. Decent farmland and some timber industry, but isolated from the rest of Stirland. Perhaps that would change if Van Hal keeps building roads - a Leicheberg-Halstedt road could easily go through Hirtenfeld. Another single-page report, on Sigmaringen and Countess Alexandra von Munsterburg - the least prosperous of the southern counties, but still well off. A pious and quiet land filled with shrines and shepherds, only mildly terrorized by monsters wandering down from the mountains from time to time. Schramleben, ruled by the Grand Mayor Victor van Grissenwald, is the largest city in Southern Stirland and second-largest in Stirland proper; it is also a Chartered Free Town that has somehow expanded into the area of a county. Built on the shore of the Aver and the crossroads between Averland, the Moot, and Zhufbar, it makes incredible profits selling its famous ale to all three. It also has more head of cattle than any county in Stirland. Its wealth makes it the political juggernaut of Southern Stirland, and it apparently hosts an informal meet between its Grand Mayor and the three Counts every year to discuss business. Finally, there is the county of Hornau and the Count Robert Toppenheimer; the richest farmlands in Southern Stirland, held back by a lack of enough peasants to work them all. Nobody's that keen to live right up against the Sylvanian border, and crops need a lot more hands to tend them than cattle or sheep do. As a result, he's as positive about recent military developments as Count Maksim is, and has ordered his levy train every weekend in anticipation of a push into Sylvania. An idyllic corner of Stirland, on paper; but the fact that a simple road can't be built to link it up to Central Stirland tells otherwise. You spend a pleasant night in Schramleben, sampling their famous ales and taking in the wealth of the city for yourself in a way that you didn't manage to when you galloped through in the past. It's far smaller than Wurtbad, but it's richer, cleaner, and more cosmopolitan. About one in four of the people on the street are dwarfs, halflings, or Averlanders, and the locals are dressed much more finely than the current fashion in Wurtbad. Then you realize that the current fashion in Wurtbad is thrice-accursed Wizard Chic, and you extend your stay in the city a few more days to make some purchases, cackling with glee as you're finally able to clean out the glassblowers and smithies of a city that Wizard Chic hasn't reached. You find stills, alembics, calcinators, retorts, flasks, lenses of every colour, vises, sets of chisels and pliers, an anvil, a very small pedal-forge, and all are purchased and packed in straw and sent up the road to Wurtbad, addressed to Dame Weber, care of the EIC. The cost is outrageous but you don't care. You've finally beaten Wizard Chic. [Shopping for enchanting equipment: Req 60, Learning, 89+16=105.] --- You finally arrive in Leicheberg with a light purse and a lighter heart, and introduce yourself to skeptical soldiers at the gate of an entirely new building: Fort Redemption. Word is sent up a chain of command, and before long Van Hal arrives and welcomes you in, and the guards relax. The barracks is all tall walls and small buildings, with tents in places and ongoing construction in other places, and it bustles with activity. Something like five thousand troops call this place home, and thousands more call it their job; you pass an open-air kitchen with a long line of hungry soldiers patiently waiting, and a small shrine to Ulric, and a tent out of which wafts the smell of blood, death, and the screams of the wounded. Past all this you are led and then into the central keep, past another guard checkpoint and through a series of hallways into what can only be called a war room. Gustav, Schultz, Kasmir and Markus are already there, leaning over a map of the area, along with a face you only recognize after a moment's thought - Maksim, last seen as the dilettante little brother of the Count, now ruling in his own right, and constantly tugging at his belt as the unfamiliar weight of his rapier drags it down. You all exchange greetings as you join the huddle. "No Wilhelmina?" Markus notes. "I left a couple hours ahead of her," you reply, leaving out the 'why'. "She should be here within two or three weeks - she's at the head of an entire trade caravan, by the look of it." That draws a few surprised looks, and you practice your smirk in reply. Wizard, you don't say, but in such a way that everyone hears you not saying it. "She'd probably want to sit this out anyway," Van Hal says. "There's a burial mound about half a day into Sylvania - some local hero that was dug up and his remains resanctified in the early days of the Empire. Unlike most of the other Wight Kings, he doesn't get up and go wandering on his own - the only thing that drags him out of his rest is enslavement, and him and his retainers make their way back home after the necromancer in question is slain. If he's still there, then we'll know that our problems are the natural pulse of the Haunted Hills. Worst case scenario, the petty kind of necromancer that can only bind the already-restless dead. But if we get there and it's empty, it means there's something with real power lurking in these Hills." "I'm in," you say instantly. Van Hal smiles and nods, and you draw a thoughtful look from Gustav. "You, me, Kasmir and Markus; Gustav will lead a company of his Pistoliers with us, and we'll have flares to signal for reinforcements if necessary. Should strike a decent compromise between moving fast and moving in force." "In and out before sundown," Kasmir states firmly, and Markus nods in agreement. "Bezahltag," Van Hal says, "unless the weather shifts, in which case we push it back. Three days to prepare." --- You take the time to burrow into the bureaucracy at Fort Redemption. You know that the retirement package for soldiers is fairly generous, which means that someone must be handling that money; you make your way to the Paymasters' offices, and from there find a mess. The pay is centralized, certainly; but each Regiment handles retirements internally, and draws up the paperwork to request that their coffers are reimbursed after the fact. You had hoped there was one person you could talk to that would be handling all retirements, but no such luck. So instead you go to the paymaster of each of the eight regiments stationed at Fort Redemption and speak to them individually, braving their suspicious looks and asking them to pass on to men that retire that the Stirland Watch would welcome them with open arms. All they need do is bring their discharge papers to any watchman in Wurtbad, and they'd be directed to the offices of the Watch and welcomed into their ranks. To your surprise, each and every one of them is open to it, and tells you that they'll pass on the suggestion to their men. In hindsight, it's probably because you kept it straightforward and minimized your own place in it. "Go to Wurtbad, talk to any watchman you see" is easy to remember and seems unlikely to be part of any weird Wizard plot. But now you'll have enough manpower coming in that you can afford to send some of Wurtbad's officers down south when you get back. [Retirement bureaucracy: Roll, Stewardship, 35+10=45.] [Speaking to the paymasters: Breakpoints every 10, Diplomacy, 84+8=92.] --- You spent so much time chasing down the paymasters and convincing them to pass on your message to their retiring soldiers, you don't have a chance to catch up with anyone before it's time to go venturing off into the Haunted Hills. One hundred pistoliers, two champions, one Elector Count, a priest and a wizard head out in the first light of dawn across the uneven countryside of the Hills. The atmosphere is tense, and every horse but your own is spooked. Justification for the atmosphere is provided barely an hour into your ride. Atop a hill between you and your eventual goal, two ghostly figures float in midair, shimmering green energy glinting off the transparent scythes in their arms. You're glad you've started skimming books on the undead every night, instead of your usual reading material; you're able to identify these as cairn wraiths, the lingering souls of novice necromancers with just enough know-how to preserve their spirit, but not enough to bind it to a body. They're staring at you malevolently, but not even trying to conceal themselves. "What in Sigmar's name?" Gustav asks in shock. "Cairn Wraiths," Van Hal states, confirming your own identification. "Nasty - they can't be harmed by normal weapons." He unslings his repeater rifle and hands it to you, and after a moment's investigation work out how to pop out the cylinder and start weaving Ulgu into the bullets. This soon after dawn, it's trivial. "Fortunately for us, we're not so limited. Gustav, pass Kasmir your pistol." He does so, and the murmurs of Kasmir's prayer joins your silent concentration as you seal the doom of these fallen wizards. "Is this," you murmur distractedly, "proof enough? Of necromancers?" "Unfortunately, these will wander of their own accord just as readily as they will at a necromancer's bidding." He accepts the rifle back from you, checks the cylinder is secured, then aims down the sights. "Though they're rather limited - they tend to come from a time," the sharp crack of gunfire breaks the uneasy silence, and then shrieks rise from one of the figures as hideous spurts of Dhar pour from the spectral wound, "before gunpowder." The other figure charges, and runs into shots from both Gustav and Van Hal, and joins its fellow in shrieking in unexpected agony. Further shots from both of them finish off the figures without further trouble, and they disappear, either dispersed back into the Winds of Magic or sucked directly back into the Warp. "Shall we carry on?" Van Hal says, a hint of a smile on his lips, and you find your own smile mimicking his. [Various rolls to determine whether a threat is present and its nature and potency] [Scouting: Roll, 84.] vs [stealth: Roll, 19.] [Van Hal and Gustav clown on them] --- The rest of the trip to the Barrow is uneventful, and the sun is bright overhead as you approach it. In darkness it would be intimidating, but in the cold light of day it looks like a sad ending for a once-powerful ruler. "Mathilde?" Van Hal says, and you concentrate your senses. The ground is stained with Shyish, of course, and like everywhere in these blasted hills there's the lingering taint of long-forgotten atrocities staining everywhere with a faint overcoat of Dhar. But as far as you can see, there's no evidence of any recent magical activity, and you say so. "A promising start," he says, dismounting, and you and the other three follow suit. The Pistoliers remain mounted; Gustav barks an order for them to form a cordon, with scout patrols in every direction. "Just like last time," you say wryly as you draw your Greatsword; you give it a frown, uncomfortably aware that you've been neglecting your study of the blade since then, but you shake the thought free and begin folding Ulgu into it. "If only duty took us somewhere nicer," Van Hal agrees. "Mathilde, you take the lead this time. Keep an eye out for any magical tripwires. We're much closer to Drakenhof here." Kasmir says prayers over Gustav's repeater pistols, then Markus' sword; Van Hal's blade needs no such assistance. Orc Hewer's runes were carved when this mound was freshly dug, and rendered the blade's edge able to pass unhindered through armour and flesh and bone alike. You tear yourself away from enchantment envy, and lead the party into the darkness of the barrow. There's something different about this one; something you can't quite put your finger on. The torches carried by those behind you barely penetrate the darkness, but the Shyish in every surface means everything glows amethyst to your senses, and you step with confidence through the murk. The passage is winding, sloping downwards under the hill, and finally you emerge into a room - an antechamber, you realize, as an ancient door of long-fossilized wood bars the way further into the chamber. And to each side, skeletons stand upright against the walls, blades in hand to defend their dead king; you feel a pang of sadness, because their protection endangers the king they swore to serve in life and death, as it makes his resting place all the more tempting for those that wield the tainted magic of necromancy. Not just a Wight King, but his honour guard too; lieutenant and shock troops in one convenient place. Twenty empty eye sockets stare at you, empty of the sinister witchlight of a wraith. Shyish cloaks them, and deep in their bones, the taint of Dhar from being bound and animated again and again for countless long-forgotten battles, and each time they found their way back to this place, to stand in defence of their master; but with no defence against the hideous magic of Necromancy, they only stand ready for the next fiend who wanders this way to enslave them. Behind you, the others peer over your shoulders into the antechamber, taking in the sight. "Should we check the main chamber?" Gustav asks, his voice breaking the silence of the tomb. "If there was a necromancer anywhere near here, this honour guard would be gone," Van Hal says firmly. "I won't disturb their rest any more than it has been already." "Is there something we can do for them?" you whisper, your voice almost breaking as you stare back into the empty eyes of one of the would-be wights. "I'm no Morrite," Kasmir says gently, "and even if I were, to lay all the dead of Sylvania to rest would be the work of a hundred lifetimes." A hand falls on your shoulder, and squeezes it comfortingly. "We fight for the living. I pray that one day, we will have the luxury of fighting for the dead, as well." Boot scrapes on stone as the others turn to leave, making their way out once more. You look once more at the long-dead men, still standing in a doomed effort to protect their king from those that would defile him, and then turn and follow. --- The light of noon seems unreal to you, after the Shyish-tinged gloom of the barrow. You accept a drink from Van Hal's flask, the liquor burning down your throat and radiating from your gut, chasing away some of the sadness of the tomb that had seeped into your bones. "That answers that," you manage to say, though you can't find it in you to sound victorious. "No necromancer, not here. Just... Sylvania." "Still threat enough," Gustav mutters, drawing murmurs of agreement. "A predictable and manageable threat," Van Hal says. "No threat of strategic trickery, just the ebb and flow of the restless dead. We deploy the 2nd and 3rd in force to guard as the road is built, then the 4th comes down and joins a push into Sylvania to bring their numbers down." "Timeline?" you say, managing to make it sound like simple curiosity. "Mmm... a year?" Van Hal says, looking questioningly at Gustav. "If Schultz can hold up his end of things, I can make a year work." "Call it a bit longer for the muster. In just over a year, we purge the Haunted Hills." --- You spent some more time with Van Hal in the coming days. His office here is far from the comfortable one back home, but there's a pair of chairs and a fire so it's not too bad. He's currently reading through your budget proposal, and the attached paperwork showing your current expenditures, completely free of embezzlement for the first time since you began; he looks at you wryly, and you return the look blankly, and he smiles. "Look, I'll grant you another 50 for the Discretionary," he says, "that should cover you for a while longer. But this is supposed to be discretionary, for unexpected bits and pieces that pop up as you go along. It's not supposed to be for you to maintain an entire staff filed under miscellany." He holds up a hand to stall your coming objection. "Yes, they're important, I've no doubt. But if you keep scaling up, you can't count on Stirland to cover the cost - not when we've got so many other drains on our resources. Either find a way to make your network revenue-neutral or stop throwing money at everyone you want to tell you things. I hope patriotism is still legal tender for these purposes, but if not, I've always found a great deal of value in threats of violence." "I'll find a way to make it work," you promise. He nods. "I've no doubt. What else do you have for me?" You hand him your proposal for the Autopsy Agency, and he sits back and reads through it. "Under the authority of the Colleges," he notes. "Under the authority of my Master as a Magister of the Colleges; it'll pass to me once I graduate." "Which means that it's not bound as tightly as I'd like to Stirland proper," he says with a frown. "Oh, it'll be fine for the foreseeable, but what happens after our time?" You... hadn't actually thought that was a concern. "I... suppose it would either dissolve, or a new head would be appointed by the Grey Order," you say. "If this is to happen at all I want it ironclad," he growls. "This organization is to be a partnership between the Grey Order and the Elector Count of Stirland. When we're both dust I don't want this turning into anonymous wizards using Stirland as a laboratory." "I... can write something up to that effect," you say, more than a little confused. "Okay. Good. Go on," he says, settling back down. "Okay, uh, members would be drawn from surgeons and hunters as well as the Colleges, with the goal being to form teams that can locate, capture, and then research subjects. It's my opinion that a wizard being part of this would be vital, so they can identify the Dhar and counter any necromantic control." But Van Hal is shaking his head again. "No. Any organization that requires a wizard to function, let alone wizards plural, is doomed. The supply of competent wizard back-up we can count on, not including yourself, is measured in man-hours," he pauses. "Wizard-hours? Anyway, it's not measured in actual full-time wizards assigned to this. I'm sorry Mathilde, but this plan is good on paper but sure to end up with either incompetent baby wizards getting good people killed or, if we restrict it to competent wizards, a bunch of hunters and surgeons sitting around wondering if they'll ever see a single wizard to fill in the trio. And this part?" He points. "I control it directly? Has something led you to believe that an Elector-Count has nothing to keep them busy from day to day?" He rereads the entire the entire proposal as you sit there, feeling very small. "Unless you can make the current plan work without wizards, scrap the entire thing. Actually, if we're using regular surgeons for the actual examinations, cut out the Colleges entirely. And for Sigmar's sake decide whether it'll be under Gustav or Kasmir or Schultz or yourself or, in fact, literally anybody but me." He subsides back into his chair, then sighs and pulls out a flask, offering it to you. You drink gratefully, and mutter an apology. He shakes his head. "Look, I get it. In a perfect world this would be a fantastic way to expand our knowledge of the undead. But you and I both know that this is so terribly far from a perfect world, and we need to work with what we have. And what we have is barely-trained peasants." He waves an arm towards a window. "Look out there, the 2nd and 3rd. Ten thousand peasants with spears. Five thousand with swords. Five thousand with crossbows made of wood and scrap iron. One thousand horsemen with pistols. How many cannon? Ten. That's the kind of ratio we can sustain." He points at you. "You are our cannon. Now figure out how to make things work with thousands of peasants." You take the proposal he passes back to you and leave the room, your mind starting to go to work. --- On your way back to Wurtbad, you pass Wilhelmina as her caravan makes its way from the Moot to Schramleben; her palpable jealousy at your shadowhorse follows you all the way up the road to Halstedt, where you spend the night. More inspired than ever, you spent sleepless nights digging through books of undead, sent from the College libraries with dire threats regarding what would happen if you lose them. Not because they were especially rare or anything; the libraries were just like that. Wraiths and wights, skeletons and spirits, a hundred varieties of undead and a hundred more accursed living creatures that flock to them. You're barely scratching the surface. You pop in at Worden on your way through, and announce your annexation of the local guard; you had brought a copy of the founding charter of the Stirland Watch for this very purpose, and allow the local representatives of the tiny bands of thuggish thief-takers to read through them - or, more accurately, to find someone to read it to them - and let them decide whether they wanted to be part of the law enforcement juggernaut that was forming, or be in its way. They opted for the former, and with that in hand Potting puts up even less resistance, accepting that it was time for their local law enforcement to fall under the aegis of a province-wide organization. Since you had the momentum and manpower, you went all in. Vigaun didn't even try to say no, apparently glad that the three-man team that handled law enforcement was going to be supplemented by trained men from the capital. Nussbach didn't even have anyone acting in that roll, so you told the Headman that now there'd be someone around to deal with crime. They seemed reluctant to give up the traditional punishment for thievery, which was nailing the thieves' hands to the door of the village tavern, but he's not enough of a fool to stand in your way. And with that, your work was done, and it was time to head back to... You sigh, and turn your horse along the dirt road to Kelham. You have a duty. --- The Headman is a tall man, still muscled despite his advancing years, and well used to getting his way. But he sees the robes and the hat and the sword and the paperwork. He bows and stammers and welcomes you to the humble village of Kelham, and what could it do for such an august and powerful figure? What he doesn't see is you. He doesn't see the face of the girl that he dragged into the village square fourteen years ago, screaming for her to be burned; her mother and father had stood and watched and said nothing as the villagers started to gather firewood. Then someone arrived who argued, the single man that served as law enforcement in Kelham, who said that there was laws. That the girl had done no crime with her magic; that she hadn't harmed anyone nor raised the dead nor summoned creatures, only made a toy horse neigh. And the man that had once fought and bled for Stirland placed a hand on the hilt of his battered sword, and he insisted. Two weeks later, of living in that man's spare room and not seeing another human being and asking every day if her family had asked about her, and they hadn't, nobody did... two weeks later, answering the summons that had been sent to Wurtbad, a man by the name of Magister Regimand had arrived in the town, and demanded to see the child blessed and tainted with magic, and took her away to learn to control and cultivate the blessing and curse of magic. The Headman is still standing there, awaiting your answer, not daring to ask again even as the silence drags. And then you talk of law enforcement, and are told they have none, not since six, seven years ago when bandits got the last one, and though the news hits you like a punch in the gut you simply nod and tell him that watchmen will be sent to oversee Kelham. And he thanks you, and you leave. You spend some time looking down the even fainter dirt road leading off the village square, that you knew would lead to a too-small farm and too-busy adults and too many children and, somewhere, maybe, a carved wooden horse that had once been made to neigh. And then you leave. Never to return. Not if you could help it. --- [Undead research: Req 40, Learning, 34+16=50. Progress gained.] [Expanding watch into County of Worden: Diplomacy, 68+7+20(manpower secured)=95.] WATCH STUFF TO BE WRITTEN UP IN A NEW INFO THREADMARK HAUNTED HILLS PURGE BEGINS TURN 12 BUDGET EXPANSION ACQUIRED: +50g/turn TRAIT ACQUIRED: Bureaucrat UNDEAD LORE: Novice Discretionary Income: +200g Veteran informants: -60g Watch informants: -10g EIC informants: -20g Julia: -30g Townhouse staff: -20g Enchantment equipment: -150g, including shipping --- Net: -90g Personal Income: +50g Estate Profit: +10g Tithe: -6g Student Loans: -35g --- Net: +19g The Council Meeting is in Fort Redemption, since most everyone is there anyway; only Anton is absent. The council room is a far cry from back in Eagle Castle, but it will have to do, and you can be back in civilization soon enough anyway. Everyone else seems to be energized by the martial atmosphere; even the previously-timid Schultz is going around armed these days. You put your papers in order, and frown a little, remembering the knockbacks your proposals got earlier. But as your Master says, if you survived then you didn't fail. You just have more work to do. Public Report: Write in (optional; can write in word for word, or just outline what is focused on) Private Report: Write in (optional; the private meeting is traditional at this point and will take place, simply say whether there's anything specific you want to bring up here) Potential Orders: Investigation: [ ] There's definitely evil afoot in Drakenhof. Perhaps there's a way to survive investigating this. [ ] The disappearance of your predecessor is very concerning, but according to the Stirlandian League he's pulled out of the game with all his ill-gotten gains. If you're not willing to let that go, maybe you could track him down anyway. [ ] You kind of regret learning exactly what you did to the Thorned One, but you did it. But the liquid leaking out? That's still an unknown. Will Van Hal let you look into it on the clock? [ ] The spell used by the informants is like nothing you've heard of before. You want to see if you can detect or replicate it. [ ] Something your Lieutenant said gave you an idea. Investigate the shores of the Black Water, see if it can truly be tamed. [ ] If we've got vampire troubles, maybe you should spend some time investigating how to counter vampiric infiltration. [ ] Wilhelmina said a lot of really complicated words at you. Maybe she's up to something. Or maybe you just don't know a goddamn thing about large-scale inter-provincial trade. Either way, something to look into. [ ] The Purge of Haunted HIlls will begin in a year. Perhaps there's a way you can contribute to the preparations. Infrastructure: [ ] Your intelligence infrastructure is becoming worthy of the title; perhaps you could dedicate some time to expanding it. And, ideally, Stirland could pay for it directly instead of it eating your discretionary income. [ ] The Wurtbadian Watch is now your attack dog - let its reach spread across Stirland. [?] The Wurtbad Thieves Guild, despite barely being a loose gossip network, really came through during the take-down of the Stirlandian League. Maybe you should cultivate this useful tool. (Van Hal has said: not until the Watch is greatly scaled up, does it count yet?) [ ] For no particular reason, it'd be a good idea to see about informants within the military. [ ] How about a military police? It would mesh well with your current organization, and could be useful in keeping tabs on the military. [ ] Also for no particular reason, how about I see about building a unit in the army dedicated to catching terrible necromantic gribblies? In a way that conforms to Van Hal's criticisms. [] Other/s (write in) - Van Hal's criticisms of the Autopsy Agency aren't my criticisms; they're his, and shaped by his prejudices and experiences, and also by a roll I made behind the scenes. That said I don't think it was entirely polite to say to a non-wizard that's been fighting the undead for his entire adult life that wizards are required to properly fight the undead. - As discussed between posts, I'm trying to make Mathilde's information network more... okay, I'm sorry, I've been fighting this for days and I've just got to use the word: verisimilitudinous. So enjoy the Southern Stirland 101 that Julia condensed out of all the reports she's been getting.

Interlude: Of the 13th Black Crusade – The Bloody Hill

Of the 13th Black Crusade – The Bloody Hill

+003.M42+

Atop a great and massive hill upon which what could have been considered both a small city and combined military base, there was a place that was anointed in the blood of the pure and the corrupt in unequal measure.

It had once been a grand chapel to the Emperor, with magnificent stained glass fixtures covering every window. Statues of gold and steel crafted in the images of the greatest heroes of the Imperium lined the gaps of holy brick and marble between those same windows, from the legendary Lord Solar Macharius to the Emperor himself granted a position at the dais from which the priests had preached from. Tens of thousands of Cadians had come here to pray, to contemplate, to worship in all aspects the God-Emperor for entire generations. Rich and thick carpet covered the ground to keep the hard stone beneath from hurting the knees of the citizens who had knelt there so long that divots could be seen. Warm and comforting candle glow from a hundred and one tiny pillars of scented wax had brought comfort to a hundred thousand souls and more for the whole time that the temple had been in existence.

Little of that was in evidence now.

The windows had been shattered by a combination of bolter fire, tracer rounds, foes leaping through them, and the ear splitting booms of cannons going off with such volume as to shake the glass from the frame. Rockets and tank rounds had made a mockery of stout stone and finely carved statues, while blasts of blasphemous sorcery and more constrained psyker fury had melted apart an entire corner of the entire structure into naught but broken black slag. No Cadians prayed here anymore, the priest had been found with his throat slit by the hands of traitorous guardsmen. It had been a consistent battleground since the Black Crusade had begun as it switched between the hands of the Imperium and the forces of Chaos.

For while it had been built atop the hill so that the visage of the Emperor would personally give His piercing glare towards the damnable Eye of Terror and so that the sunlight would hit it just so at the dawn…it had been built by the sons and daughters of Cadia. As such there were defensive implications behind it as well. Stockpiles of ammo and supplies left beneath in areas that might otherwise have been used for crypts as well as medical stations for wounded soldiers who might require them during a pitched battle.

All of these had been used by one side or another, but it was just as well for those things had been meant for hands that were not the Emperor’s space marines. For it was they who held the embattled structure now, unleashing their defiant fury against a tide that they knew in their heart of hearts would overwhelm them at some point or another. It might not have been that day, it might not have been that week, but it was coming, the thought an unforgiving and never relenting shadow cast upon their hearts.

From the windowsills came hails of bolter fire and blasts of warpflame launched from the hands and mouths of possessed marines of the twisted Emperor’s Children, the worshippers of the Prince of Excess calling out in a mind bending chorus of disgusting threats and promises as to what they would do once they were victorious. A thousand mind gouging notes of memetic lust and pain burned out from the mutations and weaponry of the noise marines enough to bring low the few guardsmen that had beforehand managed to fight alongside the space marines while the seemingly endless legions of cultists advanced.

Their corpses split open, holes torn through their bodies by the returning fire of the space marines within while other slavering slave creatures were set alight by flamers when they managed to advance close enough. A great carpet of corpses had begun to be created around the chapel in varying states of decay. Some had even begun to rot and release sickly sweet scents and their meat providing a feast for the daemons and heretics who relentlessly charged towards the chapel heedless of their own potential deaths. Other bodies were fresher, falling just that day for the first time. Giggling daemonettes moaned in ecstasy even as they were torn apart, cat calling the contempt-laden souls within with promises of returning the wondrous sensations they were being granted at a later date.

Machines that had once been tanks, once been dreadnoughts, once been nothing but a chemical and drug fueled dream marched as well towards the ever more ruined structure. Black and pink lascannon fire erupted from haphazard pipes that had been stuck into them, while from within some of the machine gullets came horrific flesh and metal monstrosities upon the heads of which was burnt the sigil of Slaanesh itself. Constantly shuddering and twitching abominations that had once been tech priests of mars and servitors were strung up atop them or led them from the ground, scrap code endlessly dribbling out of rusted and painted vocoders.

Occasionally there was a great flash and a sight that would cause the eyes of mortals to flash boil in their sockets before the smoke and light would clear and reveal entire squads of chaos space marines, horns and hooks liberally spread out across their persons. Banners of skinned foes held up on the backs of especially powerful champions marked the leaders of entire warbands, while the disgusting tentacles and split open heads of the possessed marked those who had delved too eagerly into what the warp offered them. Even the rare grouping of obliterators arrived, their frames slathered with gore and offal as they eagerly shambled forward to join in the grand occasion.

The Emperor’s Children were not alone in these dozens of constant arrival though that blighted Legion was certainly the majority of those corrupted marines present if one did not count the faceless masses of those who had fallen to Slaanesh’s service in their own ways. Warbands came who had fallen after the Horus Heresy had run to its completion, handfuls and in some cases entire former companies had come to this single massive hill. Chapters lost to the warp and had never again emerged had come, here, with little sign of who they might have been even in the labyrinthine records of the Administratum.

Some had come through the warp directly, brought by sorcerers or daemons and bargains or the simple whimsy of the Warp’s masters. Many had come with ships and in fleets that were still high above the planet Cadia itself engaged in void battles that involved such numbers and complexity as to literally drive insane lesser captains who had not the fortitude and ability of their admirals and fleet masters. Vessels of the space marines, of Chaos, of the Mechanicus and its counterpart, and of the Imperial Navy fought there and with such ferocity and firepower as to light up the darkness as if a star itself had planted itself between them.

Such a mighty force could bring not just a single world to its knees, not a single solar system, but whole sectors. Perhaps if concentrated and led with a will capable of corralling the insane desires and wishes of the servants of the ever thirsting Slaanesh they might even have been capable of consuming an entire Segmentum in horrific writhing. Perhaps that will might have called itself Abaddon the Despoiler when he had managed to contact and bring together the tremendously fractured traitor legion that was the Emperor’s Children in his dark wishes to set the entire galaxy aflame.

Perhaps.

Then again, perhaps that unity and discipline were beyond them should a truly incredible prize present itself. Only a blink separated the vision of so many servants of the Dark Prince working in unison to the sight of them now tearing each other to pieces. More sonic cannons were being fired at fellow chaos space marines and ripping flesh and corrupted souls to shreds with gleeful laughter than were actually being levied at the chapel itself. Tens of thousands of devoted cultists howled with fury and a forever intensifying kaleidoscope of emotions as they crashed into each other with blade and guns in hand just as hundreds more charged the chapel.

Champions of warbands met on the field with sinuous flickering blades, while competing chaos lords smashed into each other intent on keeping the other from coming even close to the prize that awaited them within the chapel. Machines and mutilated abominations bit and clawed and shot out guns lined with warpstuff and fury given physical form at the behest of their masters in great numbers that created enough carnage to impress even a Khornate berserker.

“It is mine, it will be mine, I will have it!” screamed a corrupted marine as he beat his former comrade’s face in before a bolter round blew his head off.

“No,” boomed a voice that cowed some of the most insane of the Emperor’s Children, “We shall all have it.”

From an explosion of warp energies did emerge a hulking figure draped in daemon-forged armor and drenched in the blessings of Slaanesh. Those that still possessed eyes of flesh that had not melded with their helmets or melted away to produce several more across their bodies widened in surprise at the voice and who it heralded. For those of the Emperor’s Children who still possessed the memories or the sanity to focus it was impossible to mishear those words and the uncomfortable yet impossible to ignore discipline in that voice.

A former Lord Commander of the entire legion was not one that they could ignore, especially given his favor with their chosen God.

Eidolon glared with the six eyes that sprouted unevenly across his face at the chapel which still defiantly stood. Atop it, the ragged and badly torn banner of the despicable loyalists within remained standing and it was that which truly enraged him. Tubes and injectors across his armor activated then and he groaned under the pleasurable rush of drugs and sorcery which suddenly infused him then. His fury sparked to new heights and he shuddered at the glorious sensation.

“You are, all of you, fools! For every one of you that you slay, that is one less who shall be able to present the prize to Lord Fulgrim!”

With a wave of his armor’s claws he shredded a noise marine who had just hefted their weapon and drank the whole of their diseased soul with relish. With the opposite arm he pointed with his massive corrupted storm bolter towards the chapel.

“These...Blood Ravens,” he spat the name – how dare they lay their hands upon it – and stomped hard enough to force the earth beneath him to tremble, “Cavort and laugh at your infighting while all the while Forgebreaker itself is in our grasp!”

He roared to the skies, then, and called to the Wage of Sin which had just barely pushed itself into position between the fighting going on not just between the forces of Chaos and the Imperium but between the conflicted forces of the Emperor’s Children themselves.

“Bring them down. Bring them all down! But do not fire upon the chapel itself! Forgebreaker must be reclaimed by our hands!”

===============================================

+002.M42+

They had fought alongside one another for over a year, and so Logan Grimnar felt it appropriate that he leave his fellow son of the Emperor with the truth.

“Your plan is a mad one, Aramus. To break the authority of Abbadon from the leash of a fourth of his forces is an admirable goal, but you cannot possibly do so.”

The younger marine shook his head slowly.

“It must be done. Or at the least, attempted.”

Logan growled.

“You still have yet to tell me how you intend to do this at all,” he stabbed a finger in the marine’s direction, “And so long as you do so, as long as you break any trust in you with your secrets, then you shall find no allies amongst the space marines for your actions.”

The Old Wolf was not ignorant of the small meetings between the Blood Ravens and the Space Wolves, and their foolish and suspicious traipsing around the Imperium. Accusations of theft, of corruption, their reliance and high population of psykers, the lack of information surrounding their origins, and more was evidence enough to distrust them in all things. Yet after an entire year of hearing of the so called ‘Hammer Saint’ of the Blood Ravens and then fighting alongside the younger astartes across Cadia had lessened such things.

Until now.

All the old thoughts came back, and Logan felt his lip curl at the uncomfortable twist to the marine’s head as he turned away. He would not say how he planned to somehow do this, no information was offered and any attempts to learn more were turned away. None could sway them from their…ways…it seemed. The accusations of corruption had easily flown and from his mis-directions and occasional outright lies Logan was finding his opinion of the Blood Ravens rapidly eroding.

“Then why are you leaving,” Aramus suddenly returned, “The Black Crusade certainly hasn’t ended, why have the Space Wolves pulled out so suddenly?”

Logan scoffed.

“Some secrets must be kept, boy.”

The matter of the Wulfen across the galaxy was something that could lead to Leman Russ himself! All secrecy was thus required involving them lest the Inquisition turn against them for what the wulfen might appear as.

Aramus said nothing after that, and Logan remained silent as well. Their budding friendship died, then, strangled by competing secrets they refused to share. No other chapters would support the Blood Ravens in their insane task, for they could not afford to share the knowledge that Forgebreaker itself was kept within the strike cruiser Retribution they had arrived in. A weapon hotly desired by the Iron Hands and any who sought to try and bargain with a weapon forged by Fulgrim himself, it was a weapon that Aramus had only brought with him for the purpose of destroying it. Or at least that is what he had told himself.

But now, finally, an opportunity presented itself. The taint of the weapon meant, the Blood Ravens knew now, that it could never be returned to the Iron Hands. This would turn the First Founding chapter against them if they learned of this, but it was considered a worthy issue. If only because of the fact that Barbarial had a vision which led to a different path. A path that Aramus, for all his savaged pride, felt might provide a good death. A hundred years of Penitence would never be completed. Not for a single group of marines, a single strike cruiser, not when assigned to the Eye of Terror.

Not even he, one who had crossed weapons with an Avatar of Khaine in close combat, believed such a feat possible for he and his brothers.

Better to die.

Better to die in the service to the Emperor than live for himself.

=========================================

+003.M42+

Aramus wheezed as he collapsed, falling backwards against a massive stone pillar as a dozen heavy wounds wept blood and exposed cracked bone even through the terminator armor. He had fought every foe that the galaxy had thrown before him but that alone had been one of the hardest fights of his life. The Shield and Thunder of Lyonis was now only the Thunder of Lyonis. The shield which had been broken apart only minutes before had guarded him against some of the greatest dangers in the galaxy but beneath a never ending deluge of blows and lack of time for maintenance it had finally broken down beneath the expert assault of the just barely slain member of the Emperor’s Children who had somehow rallied his brethren against the chapel.

“C-commander,” Thaddeus gurgled from an opened throat that he was quite literally holding shut to keep himself from dying while Kogal did his best to keep Aramus alive. “W-we made it.”

A wet chuckle escaped his lips as he said this, his now obliterated jump pack abandoned next to him as the pile of unrecoverable scrap that it was. No other wound marked him, the golden armor of the Custodes – or so it was claimed as such at least – preventing such with admirable durability. So it was that one of the now dead members of the Flickering Blades had struck at one of the few parts of the marine still exposed. Slowly his throat began to clot, and a moment later he removed his hand now that a massive scab had grown there. With fumbling fingers he tore open one of the last medical kits they had left and began to apply it.

Gunfire still came from where the remains of the Penitent Blood Ravens continued to fight. Where once they had numbered forty-seven, now they were but fourteen space marines who could still exist outside of a dreadnought shell – all ten by now in use by those who could not otherwise survive their wounds. Piles of shell casings had built up besides the windows sills from which terminators let loose with their assault cannons, heavy bolter fire from their three remaining devastator marines cutting down even more foes. No statue in the chapel remained whole now save perhaps for the Emperor at the dais itself and even then the head had been blown off in the fighting leaving it only ‘mostly’ unblemished in comparison to the ruined remains elsewhere.

Eidolon, Lord Commander of the Emperor’s Children, as he had identified himself, had nearly ended Aramus five times within the first seconds of their duel while the rest of the Penitents fought against the unexpectedly unified charge of their foes from all sides. It was, Aramus contemplated as his vision greyed from the bloodloss, a worthy prize to be gained for all of this. Who could have thought that letting prisoners return to the enemy, of whispered rumors that the Blood Ravens had possessed Forgebreaker and that he had even personally used it in battle had drawn them in.

Displaying it like the prize it was had driven the servants of Slaanesh mad with greed.

“They certainly do desire it greatly as you said Barbarial,” he grunted to the smog chugging bulk that was the Librarian now that he had been interred in a dreadnought. “Though I still do not quite understand why.”

Barbarial, who had been savaged by a sextuplet of Slaaneshi sorcerers, did not respond for a moment from within the depths of his coffin before finally reacting with a tremor along his now metal fists.

“They…see it…as…a pass. A key. A prize…to gain…passage…to their Primarch,” he ground out, the effort of speaking horrifically difficult through the fog of the half dead. “He is…hidden…from…them. If…they…possess it…they believe…they…may reach their deviant God’s most secret of pleasures.”

“Ah,” Thaddeus spoke from where he now stood, having walked over to watch over his force commander. “That explains why they fight amongst themselves for it,” he gestured towards the massive basalt box which lay in the center of the room with a several visible psychic bindings placed upon it besides the chains. “Whoever claims it will be most esteemed in the eyes of their gene-father…or so they hope.”

Aramus hissed as the rest of his wounds were barely shut and waved off his brother apothecary to go and perform his holy duty now that the force commander was not in immediate danger of dying.

“We can always hope,” he groaned in pain before he leaned heavily on his thunder hammer, “That the first of them to pick it up will be instantly vaporized for bothering their daemonic father from his deviancy.”

A hail of bolter fire and las bolts from the south wall drew their attention as one of the few remaining tactical marines there popped up from behind cover to return fire with a most furious litany on his lips.

“To be fair, Commander, we all expected to die minutes after you secretly broadcast to the enemy of what we possessed,” Thaddeus piped up again, absentmindedly revving his own relic weapon. “That we’ve lasted this far at all is a blessing from the Emperor.”

“Perhaps,” Aramus grunted. “All we needed was a momentary break in their formations. A single instant that could change the course of the void theatre, and we did it,” he leant his head back within his armor with a clank as he waited for the pain to pass…though something told him that it would never fade completely before he would fight once more.

“Until the Despoiler brought in his reinforcements,” Thaddeus hung his head as well, leaning against a pillar himself as the exhaustion crept up on him once more.

“Until…yes,” Aramis sighed, “Until then.”

The two remained that way for approximately thirty seconds before Sarrelen arrived with a storm bolter in hand.

“Force Commander, as requested. Where…is the Shield of Lyonis?”

“Destroyed by the last chaos champion,” Aramus murmured before he strode to one of the windows and began to fire out at the enemy. Thaddeus left to another window of the chapel and began to let loose with his own bolt pistol.

“De-destroy-destroyed-..I suppose that was inevitable,” the tech-marine sighed before he too moved to the new hole in the wall that was in fact the result of the most recent successful enemy charge and began firing out with his heavy bolter.

Throughout it all, Apothecary Kogal carefully extracted the gene-seed from all his recently slain brothers and stored them with the rest. He hoped that he would be able to hide it from the eyes of the servants of Chaos, but considering the trouble the Blood Ravens had been making for all this time…he doubted it. They had disrupted the Despoiler’s plans, the servants of Slaanesh abandoning theatres across the Eye just to arrive over Cadia and fight amongst themselves and attempt to gain the tainted relic, and in doing so likely gained the ire of Abbadon himself.

With care, he packed the last of them away into one of his last containers and secreted it away in a place that only one other knew the location of for when the inevitable happened and they were finally overrun. The one known as Eidolon had not been the first powerful Slaaneshi warlord to rally the others and force them into concentrating solely on the chapel, and he would not be the last. At the least, they had ten mighty dreadnought brothers still in functioning condition capable of holding whole sectors down with their mighty weaponry.

“I just hope we die before we run out of ammo,” he mused to himself as he racked the slide on a bolter, “That would be just so much less…dignified.”

======================================

+004.M42+

Where there once stood a chapel there was nothing now but a vaguely shaped pile of rubble. Some chunks of scorched masonry reached the chest height of the average space marine though the vast majority were less than waist high. In many cases there was nothing at all but dust, slag, and shell casings. Abandoned and dry flamers were strewn across the ground as well, joined in some spots by ruined bolt pistols and bolters who had no more hands to hold them and no ammo to fill them, and in three separate cases lay the destroyed and blackened hulks of once living dreadnoughts of the Blood Ravens.

Craters from artillery fire were slathered about the hill before those who had ordered such bombardment were executed in case they accidentally destroyed the prize. To harm something that Fulgrim himself had forged even if it were before he had reached his ascendant perfection was blasphemous to them and so the mortal fools who had sought to do so in their ignorance were slain. The fact that the symbols of the Eight Fold Path had been carved into their flesh only worsened matters. The entire fight had taken on a great many new prongs.

Many fought each other with the confidence that if the rest of their rivals were simply dead then those who survived would be able to take the chapel by themselves. Others fought back out of self-defense in turn. Many more turned themselves against rival powers for by this point the Imperial forces had long been forced in retreat across the planet and left only a few small holdouts behind. While the orbital battle had turned greatly against the Despoiler the ground battle was nevertheless grinding on to the detriment of the God-Emperor’s children. Servants of Khorne, of Nurgle, of Tzeentch, they too found the time for treachery as they attempted to steal the prize out from beneath the hands of the Emperor’s Children.

Aramus groaned as he dragged himself into position, his storm bolter finally exhausting itself into the screaming body of a possessed marine who collapsed as the damage dealt exceeded even its own supernatural ability to survive. He blinked rapidly in order to clear the bleariness from his eyes. Even a space marine needed to rest at some point, they could not function endlessly forever without any rest while in constant combat. Even their superhuman physiology could not sustain such a pace as had been set before them for so long. It was to his shame that the most recent rest forced upon him by the apothecary had come just before another concerted push arrived, a rest he had struggled his way out of with immense difficulty due to the absolute exhaustion drenching his soul. He ducked slightly as a blast of warp-touched sound waves slammed into the chunk of rubble that had provided itself as cover before leaping above and then down from it.

The Thunder of Lyonis sparked wildly as he drove it down from the top of the former astarte’s head down past the groin. Bisecting a target, especially a space marine, with a hammer was a feat that was more strength than anything else but Aramus did not deny that there was a slight bit of satisfaction in the deed. Another possessed charged him from the left while a noise marine with three large blades shaped like musical notes of all things in mutated arms came from the right. He slew them both, the first with two swings of his hammer and the third by shoulder checking them and bringing the hammer down upon the chest to pulp it. As ever, now, he ensured to stomp the remains down to ensure that they did not somehow get back up to their feet. It was too easy for a servant of Slaanesh’s exultant scream of pleasure to match a death scream. Sometimes they were one and the same even, but not always. A costly mistake as three of his brothers had learned early on this fight. A lasbolt cracked into his forehead and though it would scar it certainly wasn’t enough to truly bring him any appreciable pain.

He was too tired for that now.

Even so, he turned and readied himself to face the bayonet charge of a hundred mortal traitor guardsmen before Thaddeus swept past him in a flash of golden armor and growling chainsword. Then, soaked in their blood, his friend and ally returned just as quickly though the bags under his eyes and lines on his face made him appear to be a marine centuries older than he actually was.

“They are getting bolder,” Thaddeus said as he ran a free hand through his hair. They’d run out of ammo for his bolt pistol weeks ago.

How many remained, at this point? Too few, ever too few.

“True,” Aramus said without emotion.

It was…interesting to be him, in that instant. To be a Hammer Saint of the Blood Ravens. To be one of their most accomplished brothers in the history of the chapter. To have been so reviled by Gabriel Angelos for doing what needed to be done to save their Recruiting Worlds. In that instant he had hated the older marine for doing that. Before the heat of his pride and arrogance had been stripped from him by the hard travel toward the Eye of Terror, and the crucible that had been the 13th Black Crusade. For he had reached, now, a place of such total exhaustion that he simply could not manifest contempt for those who had found his methods distasteful. Nor shame for when he had heard the words of the Iron Hands who had arrived months ago who had berated him for doing what he had.

Oh yes, for the tale of the Bloody Hill had spread amongst both the forces of Chaos and that of the Imperium. Somewhere within the blighted areas taken by the Archenemy, lay a hill surrounded by a great ocean of corpses. A proving ground between those that would call themselves true servants of the Dark Gods. First it had been claimed by Slaanesh, but soon enough the chance to kill and bring down the servants of rival Gods had been enough to draw in others. The tale went that at the very center of it there was a group of insane space marines of the Imperium who had somehow acquired the legendary Forgebreaker itself and offered it up as a prize to any force willing to take it from them.

Partially the truth, and yet partially obscured by the insanity of those telling the tales again and again.

For the Imperium, it was either a tale of heroes sacrificing themselves to draw even some small measure of the enemy away from the front lines back within the theatres long claimed by the Dark Powers or that of mad heretics who had clearly joined Chaos in their mindless insanity using a holy relic of the loyal Primarchs. Either way it was unknown just who ever be able to be proven right, for no Iron Hands were able to penetrate that deep into enemy territory without being destroyed themselves either on the ground or in orbit. They had tried many times, and had lost many brothers in those attempts.

All the while, the pendulum swung back and forth with gears greased in tears and blood.

Aramus stood upon the hill and looked out at the separate camps of foes which had encroached ever closer as they ran out of ammo. Out of grenades. Out of any medical supplies whatsover. Out of everything but the courage in their hearts and the knowledge that they could not die without taking as many of the enemy with them as possible. High above he could even see as the ships moved this way and that, some crashing down onto Cadia itself for how low in the atmosphere they were when they died. He could only hope that those crashing so were those of Chaos rather than the Imperium.

“Contact with the Retribution is gone, Thaddeus,” Aramus said through cracked and dried lips, “We will receive no more supply drops from them. Either the strike cruiser has gone out of range, our thunderhawks are finally all destroyed, or any number of other possibilities. The fortifications of the enemy make it impossible regardless for them to even try and attempt to relieve us.”

The sergeant froze for only a moment before continuing in his stride alongside one of the handful of Blood Ravens yet still fighting from within terminator armor.

“I…see.”

“This,” Aramus carefully clasped Thaddeus’s shoulder, “Is it. I have seen it in the enemy movement. I have seen it in the ships above as they jockey for position. I can…feel it.”

“This is it,” Thaddeus repeated quietly. “I…it has been an honor, Aramus.”

“No it hasn’t,” Aramus snorted as he strode towards the center of what had once been a chapel’s floor. “In my foolishness, I brought corruption into Avitus and many of our brothers. I dragged you all out here on a Penitent Crusade when in truth we both know I could have convinced Angelos to force but me to go.”

Before him, somehow still untouched, lay the stone and metal coffin they had elected to contain the corrupt Forgebreaker. The chains upon it had steadily turned black as the malignant influence of the weapon within worked upon them over time but they had not broken by any means. The binding rituals that the Epistolary had wrapped about it still functioned though these too were fading without regular maintenance that the dreadnought-bound librarian could no longer perform. Which was fine, Aramus knew.

With one motion he brought down his hammer upon the chains, and broke them.

Again did the Thunder of Lyonis fall, and the stone was cracked. Psychic energies exploded outwards and burned at his flesh and armor but Aramus weathered the pain all the same. He had suffered many magnitudes worse at the hands of the enemy throughout the entire overly extended fight to the death that holding the damn hill had become. He did not react at all when the hammer was revealed to the world save for a slight bracing of his feet as the tainted aura bloomed outward once more without restraint. Before him lay a perfect specimen of a weapon.

He knew, if he were to reach down and wield it, that he could slay all who would try and face him that day. He could crush entire warbands with it. He could save every one of his brothers here, those that remained, who had died for his pride and arrogance and for the Emperor. Who would know if they fled? If he, at their head, led them to some isolated part of the galaxy and waited out the rest of the Crusade so that they could return to the Chapter? None would speak against him, if he took it up. Prathios was not here, he was busy on the other side of the ruins fighting off a rush of cultists armed with nothing but blades. The Chaplain would say nothing even if he was here.

They trusted him, they trusted him to lead them, to keep them alive.

Would it be so bad…if he took up a Primarchs weapon, and with it, forged a destiny where his name was spoken with as much reverence as They?

“Yes,” Aramus grit out at the thoughts pushed into his mind by the daemon-twisted thing, “It would.”

There was no retreat. There could be no surrender. There was no chance to survive.

And so Aramus brought down the Thunder of Lyonis one more time upon the unholy hammer.

Several things happened at once.

The sudden explosion of Chaotic energies blasted both Aramus and Thaddeus onto their backs.

The Thunder of Lyonis was vaporized in Aramus’s grip for having the temerity to strike and outright shatter an object that the Daemon Primarch Fulgrim wantonly desired.

The vast majority of Slaanesh’s servants across the entire Black Crusade recoiled as a great and terrible scream echoed up from the warp and into their minds. They lashed out in turn, their minds utterly blanked by that single and seemingly endless howl of inhumanely potent emotion. Against each other, against their so-called comrades, against their slaves, against themselves if nothing else was in reach. The battle barge Wage of Sin, left bereft of Eidolon’s presence, fired upon its escorts and was subsequently invaded by the Black Legion to quell it – but so furious at the interlopers for arriving upon its decks the daemons within the ship elected to rend the entire structure apart then let them have it.

And all those who had surrounded the chapel turned, as one, as they knew within their dark blighted souls that the prize they had been slaughtering each other for all this time had been stolen from them by the audacity of the loyalists.

They were not pleased.

“I think,” Thaddeus groaned as he got to his feet with the aid of Aramus, “That was a good hit.”

“One problem,” Aramus said then, “…I don’t have a weapon anymore.”

“Of course you do, Force Commander,” called out one of the last of the terminators of Contemptum Squad.

Two separate thunder hammers sailed through the air for Aramus to catch one in each hand.

“Brother Heka…”

“It is not as if they were otherwise being used,” the assault terminator shrugged as best as he was able within his armor.

Aramus twirled them each once before nodding.

Around them rose the indignant cries, the disbelieving screams, the furious roars, the hating shrieks from all sides surrounding the chapel. Old alliances and old grudges temporarily forgotten beneath a blinding sheen of pure hatred which pleased all of the Four at the same time.

“Right. So…this is it,” Thaddeus hopped back and forth on his feet a few times before nodding and grabbing a second chainsword for himself – for indeed, there were no more ranged weapons to use by now.

“Brothers,” Aramus called out, raising one hammer in the air and pulling the shattered remains of his fellow Penitents forward. “Space marines! Blood Ravens! Our time on this world is done! We have slaughtered many, and will kill many more this day before we fall!”

They let loose ragged cheers, energy filling them for the first time in…quite a while indeed.

“We failed the chapter once, we shall not do so again! Here is our final stand!”

He thrust one thunder hammer towards the shattered remains of Forgebreaker.

“There lies the shattered remains of their precious prize! A weapon of the Primarchs themselves, but tainted by Chaos!”

With the other hammer he pointed out towards the massing hordes which were already beginning to run towards them.

“There lies the enemy! Coming to take us! Coming to slay us! And they will, but not until we reap a great and bloody toll from them!

They stamped their feet, some banging their weapons together. Thaddeus, unbidden, went and grasped Aramus’s personal banner, the banner of their penitent crusade, and attached it to the back of the force commander’s armor.

“For the Unknown Primarch! For the Emperor! For the Imperium!”

Aramus turned then, and got into one of the first combat stances he had ever learned when wearing terminator armor. His voice was no less loud for it.

“NONE SHALL FIND US WANTING!”

Within one minute, Aramus had killed fifty mortal cultists and three chaos space marines.

Within two minutes, every single Blood Raven still alive was engaged with at least three foes at once.

Within three minutes, they were completely surrounded on all sides.

Within four minutes the dreadnoughts had formed a circle within which Apothecary Kogal desperately tried to extract the gene-seed of just one more fallen brother.

Within five minutes, three of the dreadnoughts had fallen, and hundreds of traitors and heretics with them in return.

Within six minutes, Aramus had killed three more chaos champions responsible for the burning of entire worlds yet such was the crush of enemies that he did not even truly notice save for the acknowledgement that three less weapons were trying to kill him.

Within seven minutes, Chaplain Prathios had fallen, his mighty crozius was subsequently crushed beneath the heavy boots of screaming obliterators as they waded forward out a desire to outright beat their foes to death.

Within eight minutes, all but two of the dreadnoughts were all brought low, their weapons torn from them and their hulls were stripped open to reveal the barely living prizes within.

Within nine minutes, Gilroy Lechris, the mightiest and last remaining champion of the 1st Company, had his head torn from his shoulders by a daemonettes blade that he could not defend against while blocking out the attacks from five different other foes.

Aramus did not waste his breath on final defiant words, using every breath and pump of his hearts to kill just one more cultist. Just one more chaos space marine. One more daemon. His vision was nothing but the enemy, all around him. Leaping upon him, clawing into the armor, stabbing and ripping at the flesh of his face. At one point he thought he heard the voice of Thaddeus but he could not see him. The sound of chainswords was no comfort either for plenty of those weapons were wielded by the enemy all the same. His bulky terminator armor found itself a simultaneous detriment and boon in those desperate final moments. Its sheer size prevented blows that would otherwise have been fatal from being so yet he could not move fast enough to fight as he could at full speed. All around him the hill writhed with bodies that had so heavily covered it, crushed in amongst one another. In their insanity they tore at allies just to get closer to the Blood Ravens, until the forces that had surrounded them all this time old and new had packed the hilltop and last vestiges of the chapel itself in a morass that was near solid in its volume.

“In the name of the Emperor…burn, heretics!”

Cerulean and emerald fire erupted from the fist of Epistolary Barbarial’s dreadnought then as it slammed into the earth, and a great wave of it blazed outward. Aramus jerked as the weight of over a dozen frothing traitors covering him disappeared as they were burnt to ash upon him. All around them, hundreds were dealt the same fate. Daemons were banished by the flames in wordless shrieks while dozens of chaos space marines found that their long war ended in the same fires they desired to set the galaxy alight with. A magnificent explosion of psychic flame washed over those still loyal to the Emperor and left them untouched but destroyed all else. Dirt and rock disappeared beneath it for while it was fire that washed over them the fire had been of the immaterium and so carried its unnatural properties and deadliness. Much was turned to slag, or glass.

Barbarial’s dreadnought shell cracked half-open from the exertion, the arms melted apart into pooling molten liquid upon the ground, the legs of the entire dreadnought shell crumpling into rapidly aged rust, yet the explosion of fire continued to propagate outwards until it had eclipsed the entire hilltop and staggered out halfway down the entire pile of dirt, earth, and blood. From the lowliest cultist and slave to the most beloved noise marines of Slaanesh, were the servants of Chaos burnt away.

No more would come from the Librarian that day, his might fully extinguished in that single moment.

Aramus found himself standing, then, alone. Every other brother had fallen or been ripped apart. He had been in the midst of being pushed to the earth by sheer weight of foes, where he would surely have died. Blood wept from too many wounds.

The universe was still.

Then, a battered Kogal began to crawl wordlessly towards Gilroy with his sole remaining limb and the all-important device upon it. It was, for just that instant, absurdly quiet as the apothecary extracted the fallen 1st Company member’s gene-seed. Even the sound of artillery in the distance was muted. Then Kogal let out a single sigh of relief that he had preserved such a valuable example of the chapter’s precious genetic history, and lay still once more, still save for the slightest of breaths. Thaddeus rose from a vast pile of ash, sitting up from where he had been dogpiled, bleeding from a handful of wounds, each of which would slay a mortal man. His chainblades still whirred in the absence of a foe to slay, and he ever so barely managed to get to his feet after Aramus offered him a hand. Where one of the thunder hammers had gotten to, he did not know, only that it had been torn from his grip.

Finally, unexpected by all, rising up from the ash, was Nereus. The sole scout of the penitents remaining brushed the ash from him and shook his sniper rifle once to clear it of the dust, but said nothing at all, holding to his vow of silence even now.

A silence now matched by the rest of the few surviving Blood Ravens as they shuffled together. Sarrelen’s servo-harness had been torn from him, yet the tech marine himself still lived as they discovered. Even if he would require a new left eye and arm. Kogal stirred as his stimulants and the literal last drops of painkillers he possessed were injected into himself. A faint wheezing noise came from the ruined wreck of Barbariel’s coffin, the Librarian within still alive despite everything.

Aramus gazed upon them all, even as Thaddeus moved forward to aid the apothecary in retrieving the gene-seed of everyone who had fallen and would certainly not be getting back up. Everything else around them was silent, the only signs of who had once just been swarming over them being blackened ash which was even now washing away in the winds of the battlefield. Nothing remained of so many chaos space marines, so many daemons, so many cultists, abominations, creatures, and slaves, nothing but ash and the Blood Ravens who lived despite all odds.

This…was not supposed to happen.

It felt, to Aramus at least, as if it were all some cosmic joke, some…twisted roll of the die that they had lived when the universe itself had seemed quite determined to ensure that they be slain there after using and then destroying the legendary relic as they had. There was no reason for them to be standing and if he was honest he had not really planned for the ludicrous idea that they could still be alive afterwards. Uncounted tales existed in the Imperium of glorious last stands, but rare were those that ended with the ones making said standing still living. Did some dark god cackle at them for this in the Warp? Had the Emperor somehow intervened? Or was it something else?

He did not know.

But they were alive, despite everything. A bare handful compared to what they once numbered, but they still yet lived. Eleven suits of terminator armor were nothing to be scoffed at either, despite the incredible amounts of damage dealt to them. For all that their apothecary and tech marine were crippled with their skills combined much could be mended. They had destroyed the prize, and were likely to thus be hated. But the enemy had exhausted themselves as well, dealing immense damage to one another. In that final rush, those running artillery and crewing vehicles had left their machinery behind. The daemonically possessed engines had gone silent. War camps outside of the hill were wholly empty of their occupants. They were, for a wonder, completely alone with no enemy in sight. Aramus marveled and recoiled at this, for he had fully intended to die and found himself completely unprepared for the new reality of his life not yet extinguished. He marveled for a full ten seconds.

Then, comparatively sluggishly to the past, his mind once again found a path forward despite his weariness.

“Sarrelen, how long will it take to get the Epistolary functioning again?”

The tech priest froze slightly and then turned to look at him, straightening slightly.

“Commander?”

“We can’t just remain here brother,” Aramus bared his teeth. “Our task is done, the weapon destroyed. How long until we can leave?”

“I...if we use the other dreadnought frames…I could put something together in an hour, but he will require intense maintenance rites simply to move, much less use any weaponry.”

“It will have to be enough,” he nodded, “ Nereus, scout a path for us back towards Imperial lines,” the fact that they didn’t even know what direction Imperial lines were in at this point went unsaid, “Kogal, keep yourself from bleeding out, if you would. Thaddeus?”

The assault marine turned at him with only one staggered step to betray how tired he truly was before he saluted.

“Sir?”

“Patrol the immediate area. If you see more traitors or heretics coming for us, tell me.”

An hour later, the all six of them finally, finally surrendered the Bloody Hill and disappeared into the wastes that were Chaos-controlled territory. When the next batch of heretics arrived to investigate the site they were subsequently blown to pieces as Nereus's secreted detonation packs which were placed directly beneath the shattered remains of Forgebreaker went off on proximity. The Bloody Hill, as it had been known, would fade away under the endless marching boots of the enemy and treads coated in blood, but that would come some time later.

The Blood Ravens were far, far from there by that point however.

Turn 10 Results - 2474.5

Winning vote: [*] Plan Everything Checks Out -[*][Information Network] Consolidation: You currently have a patchwork of useful contacts. Backfill so that you can rightfully claim to cover entire towns. -[*][Stirland Watch] Hire administrators and clerks from Altdorf and Nuln. -[*][Personal] Expand the Watch into the rest of the County of Wurtbad. -[*][Personal] Expand the Watch into the Barony of Purgg. -[*][Personal] Undead Research: This is Stirland. Time to bone up on your knowledge of the Undead, this time with the addition of Van Hal's personal library. (NEW-ish) -[*][Personal] Pretty Good Swords: You've struck up a friendship with the Champion of the Greatswords and have discovered a talent for wielding them. Continue to cultivate this. -[*][Personal] Use a Personal Action to perform another Organizational Action; can be taken once per organization. --[*][Stirland Watch] Openly expand your information network into the military in the form of an Intelligence Attaché (Second Division) ---[*] Ranald's Blessing -[*][Free Time] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (no action required) --[*] Wilhelmina Number of voters: 23 Click to expand... Click to shrink... --- "A what?" Gustav asks distractedly, his eyes locked on the hills to your right as the two of you rode side-by-side along the completed section of the Haunted Highway. "An attaché," you repeat. "Observers attached to a military unit." He turns his full attention to you, a frown visible only by the movement of his moustache. "Observing what, exactly," he asks stiffly. "The enemy," you say, as reassuringly as you can. "I want to get a complete overview of the type and numbers we're dealing with." "And you don't trust my scouts to do so?" He's standing stiffer in the saddle now, his eyes blazing with indignation. "Your scouts are the pistoliers, aren't they? So they'd be where the fighting is thickest?" "Of course! Bravest men in Stirland!" he booms. "They can't fight and count rotting heads," you explain, resisting the urge to roll your eyes. "Well... alright," he agrees, reluctantly. "They'd better not get in the way, though." "I'll see to it they're well-prepared for life in the army," you say, concealing your smile. --- Back in Wurtbad, you organize another round of recruits fresh from the Army. For now, they'll be going through a round of literacy courses, but you also start considering how you'll train them to identify undead. You sketch out the beginnings of a training course, but the real stroke of genius comes when you have the idea to make a series of forms that could be filled out in the field to gather the required information. You'll still teach your attachés to tell their wights from wraiths and ghouls from ghasts, but if they distribute the form to the officers of the unit they're attached to, you could have that many eyes collecting useful information. And they don't need to go through specialized training to fill in a form. You also look in on Julia while your attaché candidates learn written Reikspiel in the next room. With the foundations of an information network in place, she's no longer inserting full-time agents; a handful of shillings here, a gold crown there, the occassional round of drinks, a little encouragement to the newly-hired Special Watchmen to send in reports of local events, and suddenly the influx of information has grown severalfold. Julbach has finally been ensnared, bringing you complete knowledge of goings-on in the County of Wurtbad; a few subtle enquiries later and you learn of a well-off noble from Wurtbad who maintained a house in Julbach and greatly valued his privacy, including, unfortunately, that he hasn't been seen there in several years. On top of that, she's piggy-backed off both the Stirland Watch and her family's merchants to expand the network along the Nuln Road, covering Purgg almost as completely as Wulfbach. You've instructed her to keep a careful eye on the Stirhugel, and the news is worrying - there's been attacks on herds all across the range. Without the full picture, the local leaders attributed it to wolves, but when the reports from Lochen, Purgg and Ohlsdorf are compared, they paint a worrying picture that something is going on in those hills. On top of all that, it seems almost rude of her to also have brought a few innkeepers and ferrymen in Munzhausen onto the payroll. She's thoroughly proud of her accomplishments, and preens even further under your praise. [Convincing Gustav to cooperate: Diplomacy, Req 50, 43+7=50] [Attaché training: Learning, Roll, 67+16+20 (Ranald's Gift)=103.] [Julia's network expansion: Intrigue, Roll, 89+14=103] --- You will never cease being grateful for Shadowsteed, you reflect as you return once more to Leicheberg to resume your training with Markus. Anyone else would spend weeks travelling to and fro. You've started cutting across the countryside from Halstedt to Leicheberg, your shadowy horse not caring for a moment about the broken terrain, and with that you're leaving Wurtbad at dawn and arriving at Fort Redemption at dusk, and not even that day is wasted because you're so confident on your horse of Ulgu that you spend the ride reading. Markus is pleased to see you returning to his practice field, but not for long, because it quickly becomes clear that your skills have rusted. So you spend days hacking at dummies with a wooden practice sword once more until he decides your grip and endurance are back an acceptable level, then days more sparring with the youngest member of the Greatswords, who learns to take you seriously after you smack the grin right off his unprotected face. After that you're finally declared ready to pick up where you left off, and Markus starts teaching you personally once more; weeks fly by in a haze of exertion as you learn new techniques, then practice them until they're ingrained bone-deep. More than once you spot Van Hal watching you train, which only spurs your efforts. Once you've achieved proficiency, Markus has drilled into you, then you can work on style. For now, your only priority is to swing the sword in such a way that it goes where you want it to, and to be able to do it over and over and over again until your lungs are burning and your muscles aching and then do it some more. Any fool can swing a sword when they're fresh; the mark of a soldier is to be able to keep swinging, no matter the conditions. At one point, a nasty bow slips past your guard and your entire arm ends up bruised from wrist to elbow, but you keep swinging anyway. There may come a time when the blade or claw does much worse to you, Markus instructs, and you need to keep swinging. As dusk falls on another day spent entirely in the training yard, you're sparring with Markus for possibly the thousandth time, and you finally think you're holding your own. There's a look of concentration on Markus' face as he counters his swings and returns with his own. You're not pressing him - it'd take years of training until you can make the Champion of Stirland break a sweat - but he's actually having to focus on the fight, and you redouble your efforts. Minutes pass with the clatter of wood on wood, and then "hold," Markus commands suddenly, and the possibility of disobeying doesn't even occur to you. You step back, breathing hard, and give him a quizzical look; in response, he nods at the sword in your hand. You look down at it, frowning. You're pretty sure it hasn't splintered; granted, it's a little hard to tell through the evening fog, but... You stop, and look around at a training field utterly bereft of evening fog. And you concentrate, and release a tiny piece of concentration you never even noticed forming, and the fog emanating from the practice blade dissipates in an instant. You flex your fingers, and can feel the energies that are always within you itching to extend through your hand once more. Hmm. [Greatsword practice: Martial, Roll, 93+10=103] --- There are, you know, just over forty thousand men enlisted in the Army of Stirland. The standard term is twenty years. On average, thirty-five men in every hundred would live to see retirement - and that's during times of relative peace. So, if one does the calculations, that means that around seven hundred men are retiring from the Army of Stirland every year, or about sixty a month. So why is it so godsdamn hard to find recruits? For months you've been delaying your expansion of the Watch because the numbers weren't available to support it, especially after you snapped up so many for the attaché program, but eventually you get so frustrated at looking at week after week of no new recruits that you go into the Archives and dig twenty years into the past, and quickly find the source: the transfer of power from one ill-fated Haupt-Anderssen to another, which left the political apparatus of Wurtbad in limbo for a year until they finally arrived from their holiday home in Marienburg. For that year, there was nobody to authorize even the most routine of expenditures, so there was absolutely no recruitment into the ranks of the Army of Stirland. Which means that there's nobody entering retirement now, twenty years on. Okay. Fine. That just means that in the near future there'll be a glut of them. While you're neck-deep in the archives, you go through the roster of previous retirees. They're all drawing pensions or they accepted land in lieu, so either way you've got their addresses, and sure enough the majority are living in Western Stirland - it seems that twenty years in the Army left them with an urge to be as physically far from Sylvania as they could. You spend weeks on the road, tracking down and meeting with dozens of retired soldiers. The initial reaction to you is almost universally suspicion, but that you're offering them more money from Stirland's coffers gets their attention. Half the standard pay of a Watchman is the offer, with all the rights and authorities thereof; they'd spend a month in Wurtbad being trained, then return to their homes and spend a couple of days a week working as Watchmen and the rest of their time enjoying their retirement or working on their land. A gratifying number accept, and in the end you've got enough to cover the territory, at least until recruitment picks up. And, it occurs to you, having an additional pool of manpower you could draw from in emergencies could prove to be very useful for the Watch... [Expanding into Wurtbad: Req 40, Stewardship, 22+13=35.] [Expanding into Purgg: Req 50, Stewardship, 2+13=15.] [Making it work without the numbers: Roll, Stewardship, 95+13=108.] --- With the Watch's numbers expanded again, there's more reason than ever to expand its bureaucracy. But actually achieving that turns out to be more difficult than you expected. "So," you ask, leaning slightly back in your chair to put some more distance between you and your interviewee. "What makes you think you would be a good fit for the administrative staff of the Stirland Watch?" The man scratches at his chin as he considers the question, creating a rasping sound, like sandpaper on rock. "Well," he says thoughtfully through a Kislev accent that rendered him barely understandable, "I heard somewhere that if you're in Watch, they cannot arrest you." You stare at him blankly, and he returns the look just as blankly. He drums his fingers on the table idly; you glance down and take in the tattoos of rings on his fingers, crudely done, each of a different design. "Can you read and write?" "I can spell my entire name," he says proudly. This isn't even the worst candidate you've interviewed today. Either the word 'Stirland' has scared off all the qualified candidates or somehow the Empire has run out of bureaucrats. [Hiring administrators and clerks from Altdorf and Nuln: Req 30, Stewardship, 6+13=19.] --- When you return once more to Wurtbad, you're greatly relieved to have a chance to relax for a change. Days pass in a relaxing blur of books both referential and recreational, including the reference books borrowed from Van Hal's study. They're not as much help as you'd hoped, since most of the Witch Hunter's handbooks are less about identifying and more about burning, but you're gradually building up your general knowledge of the undead. And when Wilhelmina returns to Wurtbad at the head of a caravan of fleeces, you're waiting in the sunroom EIC headquarters to greet her. She stops in her tracks when she sees you. "Mathilde?" she asks. "I thought you were at the Fort." "I was," you reply. "And also at Altdorf, and Nuln, and Oberwil, and Purgg..." "Gods, that'd make magic almost worth it," she says with a sigh, stretching and then collapsing into an armchair. You swallow your reply. "How goes the Watch?" You groan. "Could be better. Did you hire every competent clerk in the Empire?" "Hah! I'm pretty sure I cleaned out Stirland, but I can't claim credit beyond that." "Something must be up, then," you gripe, then your eyes narrow. "Actually, something might be up. Heard any news from the rest of the Empire?" "Greenskin problems in Averland," she replies. "Beastmen activity in Ostland. Dwarves are up to something, Elector's Meet soon. Nothing major." "That doesn't help. Maybe Van Hal will hear something at that Meet, though." Comfortable silence stretches, with Wilhelmina almost dozing in the sunbeam illuminating her chair. "How's things with your boys?" you ask gently. She frowns, then sighs. "Off managing deals with Worden herders. Hopefully it'll teach them some humility." She sighs again, then falls quiet for a moment, as she considers whether to continue. "I kept my sons well clear of my work with Van Hal," she finally says, "thinking that it was going to lead to an early death for both of us, like it did my husband. Instead, there's all of this. But they've got no loyalty to him. A whiff of a burgher lifestyle and suddenly they see the Hochschilds as the next Great Merchant House and are in a hurry to get there, no matter how many sheep they have to flay in the process. Gods know what they learned at university, because it sure wasn't economics." That hangs in the air for a while, before she says with forced cheer, "what about you, Mathilde? You ever think of having kids one day?" Now there was a line of thought you definitely weren't going to make public. "Maybe," is all you answer. "So you can, then? I mean, I know the Brights and Jades do, and the Golds don't..." You smile. "There's a joke in the Grey College: the ones that do probably shouldn't, and the ones that don't probably should." [Undead study: Roll, Learning, 31+16=47.] [Spending time with Wilhelmina: Roll, 77.] --- Information Network: Wurtbad and Purgg now completely covered; Munzhausen and Wolfsbach improved. Information Network: Gustav's agreement secured for attaché program, training has begun; creation of 'Undead Identification Form' ongoing Stirland Watch: Special Branch formed; covering Purgg and Wurtbad. Further expansion impossible for next two turns. Greatsword proficiency achieved! Fitness increased to Advanced. Spell mastered: Bless Weapon. Undead Lore increased to Intermediate. Nice chat with Wilhelmina: +1 to relationship Discretionary Income: +200g Regional informants: -90g Watch informants: -10g EIC informants: -20g Julia: -30g Townhouse staff: -20g Literacy lessons: -10g Attaché program: -60g --- Net: -40g Personal Income: +50g Estate Profit: +10g Tithe: -6g Student Loans: -35g --- Net: +19g --- Once more the council meeting is in Fort Redemption. This time Anton has managed to make it down, fresh from Ostermark, and is deep in conversation with Van Hal. "Now, Anton," he's saying, "when I said that I was authorizing payment for mercenaries, did you note the plural?" "Well, technically..." Anton begins. "A steed doesn't count." "I think this one does," you murmur. Once more, you look out the window at where an enormous jade-green dragon is being fed whole roast pigs by awed troops, under the watchful eye of an elf clad in bejewelled armour. --- Public Report: Write in (optional; can write in word for word, or just outline what is focused on) Private Report: Write in (optional; the private meeting is traditional at this point and will take place, simply say whether there's anything specific you want to bring up here) Potential Orders: Investigation: [ ] There's definitely evil afoot in Drakenhof. Perhaps there's a way to survive investigating this. [ ] You kind of regret learning exactly what you did to the Thorned One, but you did it. But the liquid leaking out? That's still an unknown. Will Van Hal let you look into it on the clock? [ ] The spell used by the informants in Eagle Castle is like nothing you've heard of before. You want to see if you can detect or replicate it. [ ] Something your Lieutenant said gave you an idea. Investigate the shores of the Black Water, see if it can truly be tamed. [ ] If we've got vampire troubles, maybe you should spend some time investigating how to counter vampiric infiltration. [ ] The Purge of Haunted HIlls will begin in six months. Perhaps there's a way you can contribute to the preparations. [ ] It looks like something is stirring in the Stirhugel. This should probably be looked into. Infrastructure: [ ] Your intelligence infrastructure is becoming worthy of the title; perhaps you could dedicate some time to expanding it. And though Van Hal has knocked back Stirland financing it directly, there might be a way for costs to be reduced or defrayed... [o] The Wurtbadian Watch is now your attack dog - let it's reach spread across Stirland. (impossible for the next year) [?] The Wurtbad Thieves Guild, despite barely being a loose gossip network, really came through during the take-down of the Stirlandian League. Maybe you should cultivate this useful tool. (Van Hal has said: not until the Watch is greatly scaled up, does it count yet?) [ ] How about a military police? It would mesh well with your current organization, and could be useful in keeping tabs on the military. [ ] For no particular reason, how about I see about building a unit in the army dedicated to catching terrible necromantic gribblies? In a way that conforms to Van Hal's criticisms. [] Other/s (write in) - I was going to come up with a generic mercenary unit instead of using the Regiments of Renown, but Anton critted so I rolled a d28 against a list of them, and uh. Yeah.

Turn 11 - 2475

Winning vote: [*] [Public Report] Steady Progress, Spotted Issue -[*] The Watch has continued to expand at a steady rate; we have solid coverage over the counties of Purgg and Wurtbad. Bureaucrats have continued to be difficult to come by- even when we went to Altdorf and Nuln. We need that problem to be solved or this kind of expansion won't be sustainable. Further, our source of new Watchmen is cut off for the next year or so since no one will be retiring from the army, putting a temporary halt on expansion from that as well. -[*] Gustav has kindly authorized our implementation of an intelligence attaché program; we hope that by the time the army moves into Sylvania we'll have enough well-trained observers alongside them to furnish us with detailed, accurate records of exactly what they encountered and where which we'll be able to analyze to produce all kinds of useful intelligence. -[*] We have noticed some troubling trends in the Stirhugel- nothing blatant, but the attacks on herds throughout the area are an obvious sign once all the reports are gathered together, even if the locals are attributing it to animal attacks for now. In our opinion there is something going on there. [*] [Private Report] He's Long Gone and Other Sundries -[*] We finally got decent intelligence work done in Julbach; there was a reclusive noble from Wurtbad with a home there who hasn't been seen in years. Likely our predecessor as it fits with what else we know of him, but it could be some other group and there's nothing to follow up on easily. -[*] With the Elector's Meet coming up, we're interested in Van Hal's take on external intelligence. We haven't prioritized it at all given Stirland's internal concerns and the importance of growing our network around home, but does he want us to be thinking about getting eyes elsewhere in the Empire? -[*] You suspect that Gustav might be understating the army's casualties a bit, more as a result of his personality than anything malicious. Still, something to keep in mind if he's making a habit of it. -[*] If Van Hal wishes, you could write the Colleges requesting that wizards come to Stirland for the upcoming campaign. They won't come cheap, but there's a lot to be said for a more battle-oriented wizard than you being part of any venture into Sylvania. -[*] Are we expecting to confront the Von Carstein believed to live in Castle Drakenhof, who claims the title of Elector Countess, during this campaign? Our information on her from the captured infiltrator is sparse, but she has at least one skilled necromancer in her service based upon the spell they were using, so that could turn ugly fairly quickly. [*] [Orders] Magic And Vampire Lore Would Help The Attack Too, You Know -[*] The spell used by the informants in Eagle Castle is like nothing you've heard of before. You want to see if you can detect or replicate it. -[*] If we've got vampire troubles, maybe you should spend some time investigating how to counter vampiric infiltration. -[*] The Purge of Haunted HIlls will begin in six months. Perhaps there's a way you can contribute to the preparations. -[*] It looks like something is stirring in the Stirhugel. This should probably be looked into. -[*] Your intelligence infrastructure is becoming increasingly costly, and Stirland's finances are limited; perhaps you could dedicate some time to pursuing means of making it self-financing so that it can expand without constantly demanding more of the budget. Click to expand... Click to shrink... --- "Okay," Van Hal says as the last of the council take their seats. "Anton, I believe you have some interesting news to share with us." "I spent a lot of time with Chancellor Hertwig, and we got on quite well." Van Hal opens his mouth to interrupt, then thinks better of it as Anton continues happily on. "He's very interested in pacifying his southern border, as it turns out. By the time I left they had already started mustering the army. Not to help down here, though - they're going to begin their own purge of the Dead Woods and the Eerie Downs in Ostermark, and then if all goes well they'll cross the border and see to Hel Fenn and the Misty Wood. He says that this way, if there's any pushback from Sylvania, we'll have it flanked." "Not as immediately helpful as I'd hoped," Van Hal says, "but as long as they're killing undead in and around Sylvania, it benefits Stirland, even if it doesn't benefit the immediate campaign." "Did he mention how much of the Army of Ostermark he'll be dedicating to the effort?" Gustav asked. "About four fifths, I think," Anton replied happily. Eyebrows rose all around at that. "A significant investment," Van Hal notes. "Hmm. Hertwig's a sensible man in his fifties, so it's not glory. Luitpold is young and healthy and recently married, so it probably isn't an attempt to burnish his good name for a bid at the throne. Buying a favour? Though the Elector's Meet is supposedly about dwarf business, far in the south." He frowns. "Now I'm wondering why he's bothering at all. The Dead Wood has been left be for near five hundred years, and for damned good reason. And the Eerie Downs has only been trouble to those foolish enough to wander into them." "Their population is concentrated along the Talabec and the mountains," Schultz notes. "The Veldt is fertile and vast, and they could log the Gryphon Woods for another thousand years and not run out of trees." "The southern border is also the banks of the Stir," you note. "Trade?" Wilhelmina frowns. "Ostermark's riverboats serve it very well, but they're all on the Talabec. If they've got ambitions for Stir trade, they'd have to send their boats all the way to Altdorf and then back up the Stir. That's near two thousand miles. And there's nothing to trade, anyway - southern Ostermark doesn't produce much worth trading, and anything from northern Ostermark has to go over the Bleak Moors to get there." Something tickles at the back of your mind - something Julia mentioned, in one of her fits of ambition. It never seemed all that practical for Stirland, but maybe... You know Van Hal always has his maps available at the Council meetings, and you search through them for Ostermark's and spread it out on the table, and immediately spot what you're looking for. Right at the bottom of Ostermark, you trace a line between the uppermost reaches of the River Blut and the Stir North. "Ten, maybe fifteen miles," you say. "Manpower from Eisental, expertise from Karak Kadrin..." Wilhelmina sucks in a breath. "It would be hideously expensive, but if it worked... it would give them access to trade with the southern Empire and beyond without having to go through Talabecland." You glance sideways at Schultz, who is staring wide-eyed down at the map. "It would be well worth the cost." "But it would require the upper Stir to be tamed," you say. Van Hal frowns down at the map. "I would prefer nobler motivations," he says, "but this would give them more of a vested interest in bringing Sylvania to heel. Assuming that it is what's motivating them, of course." "It's entirely guesswork," you admit, "but I can't think of any other reason they'd invest so much, and in the way they are." "For the good of the Empire?" Anton suggests. You and Van Hal snort in unison. "Well, whatever their motivations, we've got another Province willing to shave away at Sylvania from the North. And that isn't the only new ally we've acquired, as some of you may have noticed." Eyes swivel to the window. The dragon is taking up one of the drill yards with its napping form, and the elf is imperiously watching over a few camp followers as they erect a gaudy silken tent to his specifications. "Prince Asarnil," Anton says happily. "Nice fellow. A bit impressed with himself, but I would be too if I'd done even a tenth of what he has. The stories he tells! I've sent away to the University of Altdorf for someone that speaks the elf language so that they can all be recorded - he really liked the idea but insisted it be in his language, which I suppose is fair enough, but it's jolly difficult to find someone that speaks it in Stirland." "I speak it," you mention casually. Eyes swivel to you. "The language of magic, Lingua Praestantia, is technically a dialect of Eltharin." To be more precise, it is a devolved dialect, and blended with Old Reikspiel. But you, like the rest of the Grey Order, learned both, as it's necessary for some of the more fiendish and paranoid ciphers of the Grey Order. Only those that spoke Eltharin would be able to read the true message, and those that spoke only Lingua Praestantia would get a completely different one. (And then there was another cipher, where those that spoke only Eltharin would get a false message, and knowledge of the debased dialect was required to find the true message. Such is the way of things in the Grey Order.) "Gosh," Anton says. "I speak a little Bretonnian. For their poems, mostly." "I know some Kislevarin," Wilhelmina chimes in. "I learned Tilean in College," Schultz ventures. "I suppose it won't surprise anyone to learn I'm quite fluent in Old Reikspiel," Kasmir says, smiling. "Can we please get back on topic," Van Hal says. "More immediately relevant than stories is that we have a dragon on our side. I never thought I'd ever encounter something I'd consider overkill, but..." "Seems kind of a waste to only purge the Hills," you say, voicing the thought shared by all present. "I'm leery of overambition, but such an opportunity may not come around again in any of our lifetimes. The forces of two provinces, one and a half Orders worth of Knights, and one dragon. We start the purge here and push east, and if there's been no organized resistance by the time we reach the eastern edge of the Haunted Hills..." He smiles grimly. "We march on Castle Drakenhof, and tear the dark heart from Sylvania." --- After that, you take a short recess; it would be hard to follow that up with mundane reports on recruitment figures and such. Upon reconvening, Van Hal's first nod is to Gustav. "So tell us. How are the Hills?" He sits a little straighter, a proud smile twitching his moustache. "There's still all manner of creature crawling out of them, but they've stopped being trouble. The troops form an unyielding anvil and the pistoliers, the hammer." "And the road construction is uninterrupted?" Schultz consults his notes. "It will be done well in time for the 4th to travel down it to join us before the year is out." "Excellent. How goes the drilling?" "Well, there's been some interesting developments there," Gustav says, stroking his moustache. "The problem with pistoliers is that they've quite a short range and a long reload time. Conventional tactics involve either a volley followed by charging with sabers, which is bloody good fun but, I feel, doesn't make the best use of the pistols, or harassment, where the unit rides quite close to the enemy, fires as one, then rides off to reload and the whole process repeats quite tediously. So I've designed a maneuver I'm calling the Schnecke; a company advances towards the enemy, and the front rank fires and then falls back to the rear of the formation, and then the second rank - now the front rank - does the same, and so on. By the time all the ranks have fired the first rank has finished reloading, and thus the maneuver continues indefinitely, with the company as a whole remaining in place. The result is a constant withering hail of gunfire; a drain on morale for those that can feel fear and still a heavy weight of lead for those that don't. And it could even be quite easily adapted for use with repeater pistols," he finishes hintingly. "Very good," Van Hal says after a pause, ignoring the hint. "And the infantry?" "Oh, they're doing quite well, from what I've heard. I've left it to the Colonels, they seem to know the business better than I do." You feign a cough to cover your smile, and after a further moment Van Hal nods, and then turns to Kasmir. "What news?" "Morale in the ranks is good," he says; your own information agrees, and you know that morale would be poor if the drilling was going poorly, so that answered Van Hal's unasked question. "The 4th are now well-served with Chaplains; the Black Guards, sadly, declined to supply any from their ranks, but they did offer training to any Morrite chaplains that travelled to Sigfriedhof." "Not ideal," Van Hal says, "but it does show a willingness to help on their part, I suppose. Wilhelmina?" "The 4th's supplies are taken care of," she says. By the EIC, you mentally add. Though it's less to her benefit than you'd expected; apparently she lacked contracts in Central Stirland and had failed to find a local source of food, and had to eat the cost of bringing it up all the way from the Moot, which removed a significant portion of the profits. "I also looked into their logistical train, since they'll be moving here soon enough; a few wagons needed replacing or repairing, but it's all up to spec now." "Good initiative. Everything looks on course for the Purge. Gustav, continue with the drilling. Schultz, once the road's completed, start putting together a siege train, just in case we need it. Nothing too dramatic, just the men and materials to make rams and siege towers. And possibly some catapults - rocks and muscle are cheaper than cannonballs and gunpowder, after all. Kasmir, Wilhelmina, repeat for the 1st what you did for the 4th - we may need them. "And with all these military matters done with, we're left with the only one seeing to it that Stirland doesn't fall apart in our absence. How fares the Watch, Mathilde?" "The Watch has continued to expand at a steady rate; we have solid coverage over the counties of Purgg and Wurtbad. However, we may have reached the limits of expansion for now - we haven't been able to find any suitable clerks for the Watch, even after looking through Altdorf and Nuln. On top of that, because of an army recruitment freeze twenty years ago, there won't be anyone retiring from the Army for around the next year, and thus no potential Watchmen. "Our new eyes in Purgg has brought our attention to some troubling trends in the Stirhugel - nothing blatant, but the attacks on herds throughout the area are an obvious sign once all the reports are gathered together, even if the locals are attributing it to animal attacks for now. In our opinion, there is something going on there. "Finally, Gustav," you nod to him with a smile, "has kindly authorized our implementation of an intelligence attaché program; we hope that by the time the army moves into Sylvania we'll have enough well-trained observers alongside them to furnish us with detailed, accurate records of exactly what they encountered and where which we'll be able to analyze to produce all kinds of useful intelligence." "A mixed bag," he says thoughtfully. "The Stirhugel will probably keep until less busy times, as long as attacks remain restricted to herds. Will you be joining us on our jaunt into Eastern Stirland?" "Of course," you say automatically. "I mean, if my duties allowed for it." "Then for the next six months, I task you with preparing yourself. Consider what we may face, and arm yourself accordingly - with weapons, with knowledge, and with magic." --- "There is a dragon in my Fort," Van Hal says in a tone of voice somewhere between wonder and outrage, as he stares over the keep's battlements. "You did give Anton a rather free hand in Ostermark." "I thought he'd come back with a few thousand Tileans with halberds and odd ideas about politics." He shakes his head again, then tears his eyes away. "So, what other news do you have for me?" "I finally managed to get eyes into Julbach," you report. "There was a reculsive noble from Wurtbad with a home there, though he hasn't been seen in years. Chances are it's my predecessor, but the trail is truly cold by now." "As expected. If he was still lingering there I'd have you grab him, but I feel it's not worth going out of our way for." "Gustav's understating the army's casualty figures, though it's probably a personality quirk rather than any attempt to mislead. Still, something to keep in mind." "Mmm. I'll go to the Generals for accurate figures, then." You move down the mental list of things you meant to bring up. "If you want, I could write to the Colleges requesting that wizards join to the campaign. They won't come cheap, but a true battle wizard could come in very useful in Sylvania." "I had considered it. Not for the initial stages of the campaign - the Purge is going to be long, slow, and methodical, which in my experience is poorly suited to most battle wizards. When it's time to march on the castle itself, then..." he hesitates for a moment, his brow furrowing. "Hmm. A formal request from an Elector Count, or an internal request from a fellow wizard... if your Master can recommend someone suitable, I'll have you write to them, otherwise I will." "Very well. Speaking of the campaign, do you expect we'll face the Von Carstein claiming the title of Elector Countess? I don't have much information, but she has at least one skilled necromancer in her service based upon the spell they were using, so it could turn ugly fairly quickly." "I would be shocked if there was only one," he replies. "I will be prepared for them, you can be sure of that. And yes, if all goes well, this campaign will be the end of this would-be usurper." He frowns suddenly. "At least I assume that's her intention. I do hope she doesn't see herself as a suitor." So do you. Hope, that is. "Finally, with the Elector's Meet coming up, I'd like your input on our external intelligence. So far my efforts have been concentrated within Stirland..." "Mine too," he says with a smile. "But would you want us to start looking without as well?" He muses on that for a while, looking at you oddly. "Sometimes I forget how young you are." You open your mouth to reply, but no reply presents itself. He continues on. "Have you fully grasped the fact that you are the second most powerful person in Stirland?" You blink rapidly as you try to take in this sudden change in direction. "Gustav's new to the role. Kasmir was damn near fired. Anton is..." he hesitates, then moves on. "Schultz serves a very specific niche. And Wilhelmina... is a very close third, actually. She's blossomed. But none of them have the combination of abilities, resources, trust and wide-open mandate that you do. And by Sigmar you do the job damn well. But your problem is that you don't believe in yourself to the degree that this job requires you to. "You have access to all the information I do, and you have the luxury of spending the majority of your time and focus on intrigue, where I am pulled a dozen different ways. There is only one reason for you to ask me that question, rather than reaching a conclusion for yourself: because you lack confidence. "I wish I had words to instil that confidence in you, but all I can do is tell you that if you allow self-doubt to erode your resolve, you will fail in the duty to Stirland we share. And while I would not hesitate to stand alone and die against all the evils of Sylvania, I would rather have you by my side and win. "So stop thinking like a journeywoman, and start thinking like the Knight I know you are." He claps you on the shoulder and leaves you there atop the keep, and you slump against the battlements to process his words. --- PLAN FOR THIS TURN ORGANIZATIONAL ACTIONS - pick ONE from EACH of the categories 'Information Network' and 'Stirland Watch': Information Network - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [ ] Expand your information network into another province (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into another county or barony (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into the military (choose a Division) [ ] Expand your Intelligence Attaché program to another Division (choose one) [ ] Off the Leash: Let Julia handle the network without your micromanagement from now on. Information Network finances - expansion is hobbled by it's dependence on your discretionary income, and so is your budget. Perhaps you can get past that. Can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above. [ ] Information Broker: Start selling tidbits of information, just enough for your information network to start paying for itself. [ ] Fixer: Work with the Wurtbad Thieves Guild, supplying them information in exchange for a portion of profits. [ ] Special Branch: Pull some financial trickery to get the information network classified as part of the Watch, so that their costs are covered by the Stirlandian treasury. [ ] Trade Delegation: Convince Wilhelmina and Markus to partner your network with the EIC based on the value of market information. Stirland Watch - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [o] Expand the ranks of the Watch, so that they're able to start covering even the poorer parts of their covered area. (cannot be taken until army retirement resumes in one year) [ ] Expand the Special Branch into areas already covered by the Watch, so you have an additional pool of manpower you can call upon to supplement the full-time Watchmen. (NEW) [ ] Expand the ranks of the Gong Farmers, both increasing coverage of Wurtbad and expanding it to the other population centers covered by the Watch. [ ] Improve the training of the Watch, hiring trainers and dedicating paid time each week to sharpening skills. [ ] Integrate the Roadwarden network of covered areas into the Watch. [ ] Headhunt administrators from other organizations in Stirland. [ ] Seek out a new leader for the Watch. --- PERSONAL ACTIONS - CHOOSE BETWEEN FIVE AND SEVEN. ANY CHOSEN BEYOND THE FIRST FIVE WILL COME WITH RISKS - PLEASE SPECIFY THE 'ADDITIONAL' TASKS: Miscellany: [ ] Financial Jargon: Everything with the EIC flew right over your head last time. Try again. Succeeding here will mean that you can take a more active hand in the company, adding it to the organizational actions; failing or not attempting means Mathilde will remain a silent partner. [ ] Hang Out A Shingle: Spymasters don't advertise, but wizards sometimes do. Make an official announcement that there's a wizard in residence, and see who comes out of the woodwork. [ ] Formal Proposal: Your idea for an undead research team was received poorly, but Van Hal is still open to the idea in theory. Write in details: Name, who it is technically a part of (Watch, Witch Hunters, Military, College, none), and whether it reports directly to you (becomes a new Organization you command) or, if not, who it would report to. [ ] Scribe: Anton's sent away to Altdorf for someone that speaks Eltharin. Well, you speak Eltharin. Maybe you can find the time to act as amanuensis for the prince-in-exile, though it would cut into your learning-how-to-not-get-eaten-by-Sylvania time. (NEW) Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. [ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills and internalize the lessons you've learned (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective if you've used the trait a lot lately). [ ] Tutoring: One of your fellow councillors may be willing to teach you in their chosen field (choose who). [ ] Really Good Swords: You have achieved proficiency with the Greatsword. Future progress is possible, though it will take more effort to see results. (NEW) [ ] Combat Training: You're virtually surrounded by armed warriors of various sorts. See if you can convince one to teach you (choose who). [ ] Combat Training, In The Free Market: You haven't made many heavily armed friends yet, but gold is good for that. Go out and buy some training. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. [ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Remixed: You're getting sick of having workmen tramping in and out of your abode. Recruit an entire team and personally oversee them to clear out all of the reachable portions of the Palace-Shrine and be done with it. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: You've finally got the equipment, now you've just got to unpack it all and set up your laboratory. [ ] Filled with Potential: You've got a room cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put there and get started on equipping it. (write in the purpose of the room) Research: [ ] Undead Research: This is Stirland. Time to bone up on your knowledge of the Undead, this time with the addition of Van Hal's personal library. [ ] Snooping: Van Hal gave you a key to his Study. He didn't specifically say not to poke around and see what you could find. [ ] Shyish-kebabs: The Shyish swords are hideously dangerous as weapons, but fascinating as a subject of study. Try to reverse-engineer the lost enchantments woven into them. [ ] Bound Spells: Though the corrosive Dhar made them high-maintenance, the design of the bound spells in the castle's infiltrators has fascinating possibilities. Try to adapt it for use with Ulgu. [ ] Qhaysh Juice: Whatever it is, it's dripping out of the box at a steady rate. You've got two gallons of the stuff and it's still coming out. It's got to be good for something. [ ] Qhaysh Skunkworks: It would take careful study to unlock the secrets of the liquid. It would take considerably less time to find out if it can be made to burn, or explode, or do something militarily useful. (NEW) [ ] As a Journeywoman, the path to Magister is marked by mastering more than the two shadow spells you already know. Send to the Grey Order for the basics and work on figuring out one of the others. Influence: [ ] Thieves Guild: It's currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. If it could be expanded under your aegis, it could be a powerful tool. [ ] Biderhof: This village based on woodcutting and agriculture, has adopted you as one of it's own. Maybe you should adopt it as your own, in a literal sense. [ ] Non-Thief Guilds: Wurtbad, like all major cities, is home to a number of guilds. Reach out to them and enforce your will. Relations: [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with one of your fellow councillors or your liege, offering your help in their tasks and generally getting a feel for them (choose one). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: You've been given good reason to mistrust your fellow councillors. Perhaps you should see what they spent their time doing (choose one). [ ] Letters Home: You might be able to wring more information out of your Master, or you might just be able to get news, information and guidance in general from the Grey Order. [ ] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (no action required) (can be used to perform Snooping without spending an action) --- FINANCES: NO ACTION POINT EXPENDITURE. Personal Income: 60 gold/turn Discretionary Income: 200 gold/turn Informer Payroll unlocked Currently paying Grey College tithe (-6 personal gold/turn) Currently paying Grey College student loans (-35 personal gold/turn) Not currently embezzling Currently funding regional informants (-90 discretionary gold/turn) Currently funding Watch informants (-10 discretionary gold/turn) Currently funding EIC informants (-20 discretionary gold/turn) Currently funding Intelligence Attaché program (-60 discretionary gold/turn) Currently employing Julia Massif (-30 discretionary gold/turn) Currently maintaining the staff of a townhouse in Wurtbad (-20 discretionary gold/turn) [ ] Begin plumping the informer rolls (choose ratio of real:fake informers. Almost impossible to detect, but also very difficult to increase or decrease the amount quickly) [ ] Change tithe payment/loan payment/embezzlement (specify) [ ] These agents are getting expensive. Write up a proposal for your discretionary budget to be increased, instead of waiting for Van Hal to decide to increase it. (warning: attracts oversight to your current budget) --- - Last turn I rolled for Anton's mercenary recruitment efforts to see who came back to the Fort with him; this week I rolled his diplomatic efforts in Ostermark, and now Ostermark is going all in. - For those ready to beatify Anton, I will remind you that his efforts in Talabecland resulted in one notch above doing nothing. His dice aren't always ridiculous. - Technically, Lingua Praestantia is more often known as 'Magick'. With a K. I refuse to use it because it is dumb. - Just as I finally get done with figuring out the knock-on effects of Anton, Gustav nat 100s the drilling and I have to go research cavalry tactics. - A write-in order from Van Hal, but as it was due to rather unpredictable circumstances, there was no relationship loss. - A matter on the side: I invite the thread to suggest musics best suited for Mathilde's training montage. Excellence in one's suggestion may result in the granting of A Boon; the exact details of a Boon will be disclosed only to the recipient. And before anyone tries: No Rocky, and no Team America. Limit one per person, once you submit one you're locked out of further submissions, and for god's sake please at least glance at the lyrics and spend more than a couple of seconds thinking about it's suitability. - Voting will be in Plan Format; don't forget Ranald's Blessing.

Turn 11 Results - 2475

Winning Vote: [*] Plan Practical Combat and Magic -[*] Expand your Intelligence Attaché program to another Division (choose a Division) --[*] Fourth Division -[*] Expand the ranks of the Gong Farmers, both increasing coverage of Wurtbad and expanding it to the other population centers covered by the Watch. -[*] Tutoring: One of your fellow councillors may be willing to teach you in their chosen field (choose who). --[*] Gustav -[*] Undead Research: This is Stirland. Time to bone up on your knowledge of the Undead, this time with the addition of Van Hal's personal library. -[*] Bound Spells: Though the corrosive Dhar made them high-maintenance, the design of the bound spells in the castle's infiltrators has fascinating possibilities. Try to adapt it for use with Ulgu. -[*] As a Journeywoman, the path to Magister is marked by mastering more than the two shadow spells you already know. Send to the Grey Order for the basics and work on figuring out one of the others. --[*] Take No Heed --[*] Burning Shadows ---[*] Ranald's Blessing -[*] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (no action required) (can be used to perform Snooping without spending an action) --[*] Gustav Click to expand... Click to shrink... Spoiler: Winning training montage music It's not what I expected would win, but the lyrics are incredibly suitable and actually a little dark in the context of a Warhammer wizard. I looked up the song: it was written to be the training montage music in a movie called No Retreat No Surrender, about a teenager who is trained by the ghost of Bruce Lee to stop Jean Claude Van Damme from taking over all the dojos in America. The eighties were a magical time. The entire movie is on Youtube if you want to experience it for yourself. The winner, @HanEmpire, has been granted their Boon, and has decided the form it will take; if they wish they may share the details of it, but the thread is not to badger them for it if they decide to keep it to themselves. Do know, however, that they were explicitly forbidden to seek the thread's help with deciding the Boon. --- In the coming years, very much will rely on Gustav. Your past investigation of him revealed that he was a suitable if not outstanding candidate, but there's no way to tell if he'll flourish or flail with thirty thousand lives resting on his shoulders. So, you reason, there's two possibilities: either he'll rise to the occassion and therefore will be worth learning from, or he'll be a burden in the near future and will need a very close eye kept on him. Either way, you'll benefit from having spent time with him now. That reasoned out, you approach him one morning in the dining room of Fort Redemption's keep, and say to him: "Gustav, I would like you to teach me to be a better warrior." He looks up from his breakfast of bread, sausage and cheese. "Hmf. You are an odd one. Known a wizard or two in my time, and none of 'em like you - but then, none of them were your colour." He carefully cuts a piece of sausage and chews on it while he thinks. "You left that vague on purpose, I suppose?" "Yes. Whatever you think is most important." "Hmm. Hell of a question, that is. Ask fifty fighters, get fifty answers." He thinks it over for a while, munching his way through the rest of his sausage. "Suppose that was your intention. That ghost horse of yours, it only does what you want it to, right?" "That's right." "Damned useful, that. Half of training a cavalryman is teaching him how to get his horse to cooperate." He puts down his knife and fork and strokes his moustache thoughtfully, and then nods at the scabbard on your back. "I've seen you training with that thing, you seem to be decent at it, so I won't try to argue you into using a nice sensible saber instead. But here's something a lot of young would-be warriors die learning: there's many a thing in this world you cannot win against once they get at blade's length. There's no amount of training that will make you stronger than a minotaur or faster than a vampire or bendier than an elf. For things like that," he pats his hip, "you shoot them. Sure, there's a lot of things that won't die to a bullet, but nothing that fights better with a bullet in them." He takes a long drink out of the wooden mug, then stands. "Let's go. No better time to start than in the dawn light." --- You'd think it was simple - point it at the target and pull. But it turns out there's more to it than that, and as you send hundreds of rounds through the spare pistols from the Pistolier regiments, if it weren't for Gustav's instructions progress would have been agonizingly slow. Every time he visits you at the earthen bank used as a firing range, he has you fire a few shots, corrects some small thing that surely wouldn't make a difference, but sure enough you're that much closer to the target. After a few months of daily practice, you're hitting a target the size of a man's torso reliably at twenty yards, a puff of sinister-looking fog arising from each impact. You're happy with the progress you've made, but you're aware that to truly call yourself proficient, you have to start doing so without taking time to line up a shot. In what little free time he has, you spend time with the man, getting to know him better while picking his mind further; while a master of light cavalry, you're starting to get the impression that as a Marshal, he's out of his depth. Time will tell, you suppose. [1-10 Saber, 11-40 Pistols, 41-70 Rifles, 71-85 Leadership, 86-100 Military Tactics: 29, 46. Both rolls are firearms, so he will focus entirely on the first.] [Learning roll: Martial, Breakpoints 20/50/80, 35+11=47.] [Teaching roll: Martial, Breakpoints 20/50/80, 69+16=85.] Your days are also filled with reading; both of the few as-yet-unread books of undead lore that the Colleges are willing to loan out, and of the very heavily encrypted spell-scrolls delivered directly to your hand by a harried apprentice with stern instructions to burn them after reading. They are densely packed with intricate and jargon-heavy instructions in the language of the Colleges, so it's doubtful any thief could even begin to understand them even if they could crack the code, but you take the warning to heart anyway. Take No Heed is in an interesting spell. Where Mindhole assaults the mind of your target, Take No Heed changes you in such a way that you slip right through the minds of all but the most attentive or the strongest of will. One morning, you're sitting in what may be the only quiet corner in Fort Redemption - the 4th has arrived, and though a number of tents have been set up outside the walls there's still nearly twenty-five thousand men inside them - when Gustav stumbles across you on his way to one of his innumerable other duties, and evidently finds himself curious enough to delay them. As he approaches and asks what's consuming your attention, you're grateful that you don't have to make up a lie about what you're reading - you left your other reading materials in Wurtbad. You pat the small pile of reading material beside you. "The scrolls are from my Master, instructing me in spells; the books are on the topic of the Undead, and how to destroy them." He looks torn between wariness and curiosity at that. "Spells, eh? Anything useful?" You close your eyes and let Ulgu flow into you, and take a pinch of nothing, and release it into the air, disturbing its fall with a few gestures and whispering a few mystical words. "Turn around and walk ten paces, then turn and return back to me." He gives you a quizzical look, but does so; when he turns back around, his eyes look back and forth, and rest on you for a moment before passing by. Then he frowns, thinks, shakes his head and looks back at you, then returns to you. "That was bloody odd," he says. "I could clearly see that there was a person there, but I didn't notice anything about them, and it didn't occur to me to pay any attention to them until I stopped and thought about it and reasoned that you must be that person." You smile. "It's not quite invisibility, and it fails if against the strong-willed and the determined, but it should prove useful." --- Burning Shadows is not so easily demonstrated on a live target, but you can practice on scrolls from your Master and reports from Julia that need destroying anyway. It's more complex than any spell you've ever attempted, and the typical material component is the poison known as Black Lotus, and is ruinously expensive and sourced from half a world away besides. And you don't know enough about pharmacology to find a local source you could harvest yourself. So you find yourself hunched over a candle night after night, trying to instil magic into the the shadows your hands cast. Doing so at all is easy - Ulgu needs little encouragement to fill the shadows - but to have it turn corrosive is an entirely new skill. It's only after long weeks of effort that the scrolls that you're targeting start to blacken where your shadow falls, but once you've learned the knack of it, it grows in effect by leaps and bounds, and soon the parchment is turning to liquid where your shadow falls, and leaving nasty stains and burns on your writing desk. The tricky part, both magically and mechanically, is distance. Within about twenty yards, it's simple enough to both cast the shadow and instil it with the required effect, but beyond that it takes a brighter light and greater concentration. You practice at night from the watchtowers of the Fort, where a shadow thrown by a torch can go for hundreds of yards; it takes commensurately more time and concentration to perform, but with enough time and concentration you manage to blacken the shape of your hand into a large patch of grass at just under two hundred yards. Now that could come in handy. [Learning Take No Heed: Learning, Req 60, 93+16=109.] [Learning Burning Shadows: Learning, Req 70, 58+16=74.] [Burning Shadows at a distance, Roll, 30+16+20 (Ranald's Blessing)+9 (rollover from Take No Heed)=75.] You also spend some time trying to recreate the bound spells back from the business with the infiltrators; sadly, with almost three years passed you spend most of your time trying to recall hazy details. Weeks of concentration and meditation refreshes the memory of the spell's structure in your mind, but your attempts to divine how it works so you can start to replicate it with Ulgu instead of Dhar are frustrated at every turn. You don't even have the enchantment vocabulary to keep notes. All you can do is hold a picture of the spell's structure in your mind, and you know it will fade with time. If you had more time or more general knowledge or if the memories were fresher, you know you could manage this, but with so many other priorities you eventually have to put it aside. More prosaic is your continued readings into the restless dead. With your upcoming excursion into Sylvania, your Master appears to have pulled some strings and had the College library send a few of their more restricted tomes, along with the usual dire warning as to what would happen if you were to lose them. Explanations into the magical side of the undead are conspicuously absent, but there's still a great deal of data, sometimes contradictory and pulled from a thousand sources though it may be. By the time you finish reading your way through the document, you're ready to put the finishing touch on the paperwork for your Intelligence Attachés, refining it down to a single page of twenty questions that, if answered accurately, would allow the knowledgeable - such as you - to identify the form of undead as reliably as if they had seen it themselves. You have the finished form delivered to Julia, who takes a moment away from her expansion of the Attachés into the 4th Division to commission some time from a printing press in Altdorf, and soon enough you have a stack of forms taller than you to be distributed to every officer in the Army of Stirland. [Bound Spell reverse engineering: Breakpoints 50/70, Learning, 58+16-20 (two full years passed)=54. Time penalty reset.] [Studying the Undead: Breakpoints 20/50/80, Learning, 86+16=102.] --- Before you threw yourself into training in earnest, you empowered the former leader of the Guild of Nightsoilmen and the de facto leader of the equivalent branch of the Watch to increase their ranks and scope, and now it is your unfortunate fate to have to read the report this produced; you really must see about getting a leader for it one of these days. The report says that recruitment was easier than expected; that it was on the government payroll meant that it was seen as a more stable and legitimate occupation than when it was an independent guild, though it was still necessary to offer slightly more pay than usual for unskilled labour to make up for the obvious downsides of the job. They also found no trouble expanding alongside the Watch, absorbing local guilds in Worden and Purgg and bringing new but badly needed services to the villages. The end result is impressive - it's still not close to making the Watch revenue-neutral but it is defraying a significant portion of the costs. And depending how the next few months go, Stirland might badly need every shilling. Your other reports make for easier reading, as information from all over Stirland flows to you: - The mood across Stirland is acceptable as rumour of the Purge's ambitions spread, split between those that think that Van Hal's ambition is going to lead to a lot of deaths and those that think that finally putting a Witch Hunter in charge might allow actual process in pushing back the Dead. - Morale in the 2nd is high, though only average in the 4th. - Events in the Stirhugel came to a head much faster than you expected, with the Watchmen in Ohlsdorf managing to pick up a trail of whatever it was that was preying on the sheep. To the relief of everyone involved, it turned out to be mere bandits; the Watchmen went back to Ohlsdorf, deputized a number of the burly locals with strong opinions about the theft of livestock, and led them into the camp with sword and bludgeon. Those that survived the assault were subjected to swift and merciless trial, and had already been hanged by the time a report had been prepared. The rural folk of Western Stirland take a very dim view of rustlers. - The Knights promised by Talabecland are on the way; when the report was written, they were in Wurtbad, so they're likely at least at Halstedt by now. - The Attachés to the 4th was mostly without problem, though with no retirees coming out of the Army of Stirland she had to cannibalize the Watch for recruits. Their numbers are now stretched worryingly thin, and they may be less effective until numbers are brought back up to a good place. In closer news, the would-be scribe that arrived from the University of Altdorf didn't manage to perform the duty expected of him; the banished Prince quickly grew sick of being asked to explain things every few minutes and sent the scholar packing. As a member in good standing of the University of Altdorf's longstanding rival, it pleases you to see one of them humbled, but as someone that was looking forward to reading the end result it's more than a little frustrating. A shame, but then, you have more pressing concerns than elf stories. --- Information Network: Intelligence Attaché attached to 4th Division. Stirland Watch: Gong Farmers have now expanded into every city the Watch has a presence in, and will continue to do so automatically if/when administrative staff or a Leader is acquired. Acquired skill - Pistols: Advanced. Take No Heed learned! Burning Shadows learned! Undead Lore proficiency achieved! Weapon acquired: pistol. --- Discretionary Income: +200g Regional informants: -90g Watch informants: -10g EIC informants: -20g Julia: -30g Townhouse staff: -20g Literacy lessons: -10g Attaché program: -120g --- Net: -100g Personal Income: +50g Estate Profit: +10g Tithe: -6g Student Loans: -35g --- Net: +19g --- There is no formal meeting of the council this month; there may not be one for quite some time. You've delivered written reports to Van Hal, though you're not sure if he's been able to read them - he's been entirely occupied with the finishing touches to the plans for the Purge, and in a rare minute you manged to snatch with him he said to use your judgement and then hurried off. You did manage to get informal updates on everyone's progress - Wilhelmina and Kasmir have the 1st provisioned and serviced by Chaplains, Gustav is happy with the preparedness of the men, and Schultz's road is long-finished and he's putting the last touches on a rather uninspired siege train. You even have a rare chance to talk to Anton as he returns from Zhufbar; they're apparently quite pleased, in their understated Dwarvish way, that the manlings are taking action against the blasted dead, but they're too engaged in battle with some sort of beastmen in their lower hold and the greenskins in their immediate surrounds to sally forth in the immediate future. Then he's off again to Averland. As thirty thousand men break camp and prepare to march, you consider your own path for the coming months. You itch to join them, though you're not sure if that's the best use of your time. Will the initial push into the Hills be more or less frantic than later on? Would it be useful for you to be personally present for every yard of five thousand square miles of purging? --- PLAN FOR THIS PURGE TURN ORGANIZATIONAL ACTIONS - pick ONE from the category 'Information Network' and NONE from 'Stirland Watch': The Stirland Watch actions can still be taken with personal actions; the action chosen for the Information Network will be their direction for the next three Purge Turns. Information Network - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [ ] Expand your information network into another province (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into another county or barony (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into the military (choose a Division) [ ] Expand your Intelligence Attaché program to another Division (choose one) [ ] Off the Leash: Let Julia handle the network without your micromanagement from now on. Information Network finances - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above. [ ] Attaché Paperwork: The Intelligence Attachés are your biggest expense by far - see if you can have them paid for by the Army of Stirland instead. [ ] Information Broker: Start selling tidbits of information, just enough for your information network to start paying for itself. [ ] Fixer: Work with the Wurtbad Thieves Guild, supplying them information in exchange for a portion of profits. [ ] Special Branch: Pull some financial trickery to get the information network classified as part of the Watch, so that their costs are covered by the Stirlandian treasury. [ ] Trade Delegation: Convince Wilhelmina and Markus to partner your network with the EIC based on the value of market information. Stirland Watch - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [o] Expand the ranks of the Watch, so that they're able to start covering even the poorer parts of their covered area. (cannot be taken until army retirement resumes in one year) [ ] Expand the Special Branch into areas already covered by the Watch, so you have an additional pool of manpower you can call upon to supplement the full-time Watchmen. [ ] Improve the training of the Watch, hiring trainers and dedicating paid time each week to sharpening skills. [ ] Integrate the Roadwarden network of covered areas into the Watch. [ ] Headhunt administrators from other organizations in Stirland. [ ] Seek out a new leader for the Watch. --- PERSONAL ACTIONS - CHOOSE BETWEEN TWO AND THREE. ANY CHOSEN BEYOND THE FIRST TWO WILL COME WITH RISKS - PLEASE SPECIFY THE 'ADDITIONAL' TASK: Genießt den Krieg - join the divisions entering Sylvania: [ ] Attach yourself to the general staff, so you can be present for anything interesting that might happen and keep a finger on the pulse of the war. [ ] Attach yourself to a specific regiment so you can spend some time in the thick of things. Miscellany: [ ] Financial Jargon: Everything with the EIC flew right over your head last time. Try again. Succeeding here will mean that you can take a more active hand in the company, adding it to the organizational actions; failing or not attempting means Mathilde will remain a silent partner. [ ] Hang Out A Shingle: Spymasters don't advertise, but wizards sometimes do. Make an official announcement that there's a wizard in residence, and see who comes out of the woodwork. [ ] Formal Proposal: Your idea for an undead research team was received poorly, but Van Hal is still open to the idea in theory. Write in details: Name, who it is technically a part of (Watch, Witch Hunters, Military, College, none), and whether it reports directly to you (becomes a new Organization you command) or, if not, who it would report to. [ ] Scribe: Altdorf's scribe did not get on well with the Prince. He's going to be rather busy with burning things, but maybe that'll put him in a better mood if you offer your own services. (NEW-ish) [ ] Gun Shopping: You're currently using a pistol that was a spare for the pistoliers. Visit Nuln to upgrade. (Choose: dueling pistols for accuracy and range, repeater pistols for weight of fire, dragons for hand shotguns. Choose: whether you will acquire and use two pistols at once or keep one hand free.) (NEW) [ ] Write up a proposal for Wilhelmina to approve a short-term increase in Discretionary Income, for the duration of the crisis. (NEW) Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. [ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills and internalize the lessons you've learned (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective if you've used the trait a lot lately). [ ] Tutoring: One of your fellow councillors may be willing to teach you in their chosen field (choose who; can choose which, or you can let them decide). [ ] Really Good Swords: You have achieved proficiency with the Greatsword. Future progress is possible, though it will take more effort to see results. [ ] Pistols at Dawn: You've taken some great strides in an entirely new form of combat, but you're still not entirely proficient. Finish your training. (NEW) [ ] Combat Training: You're virtually surrounded by armed warriors of various sorts. See if you can convince one to teach you (choose who). [ ] Combat Training, In The Free Market: You haven't made many heavily armed friends yet, but gold is good for that. Go out and buy some training. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. [ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Remixed: You're getting sick of having workmen tramping in and out of your abode. Recruit an entire team and personally oversee them to clear out all of the reachable portions of the Palace-Shrine and be done with it. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: You've finally got the equipment, now you've just got to unpack it all and set up your laboratory. [ ] Filled with Potential: You've got a room cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put there and get started on equipping it. (write in the purpose of the room) Research: [ ] Undead Research: You know the basics, now. Perhaps a great deal of effort will allow you to advance further. (NEW) [ ] Snooping: Van Hal gave you a key to his Study. He didn't specifically say not to poke around and see what you could find. [ ] Shyish-kebabs: The Shyish swords are hideously dangerous as weapons, but fascinating as a subject of study. Try to reverse-engineer the lost enchantments woven into them. [ ] Bound Spells: Though the corrosive Dhar made them high-maintenance, the design of the bound spells in the castle's infiltrators has fascinating possibilities. The memories had faded but you've managed to refresh them. Try to adapt it for use with Ulgu. (NEW-ish) [ ] Qhaysh Juice: Whatever it is, it's dripping out of the box at a steady rate. You've got two gallons of the stuff and it's still coming out. It's got to be good for something. [ ] Qhaysh Skunkworks: It would take careful study to unlock the secrets of the liquid. It would take considerably less time to find out if it can be made to burn, or explode, or do something militarily useful. (NEW) [ ] As a Journeywoman, the path to Magister is marked by mastering more than the two shadow spells you already know. Send to the Grey Order for the basics and work on figuring out one of the others. Influence: [ ] Thieves Guild: It's currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. If it could be expanded under your aegis, it could be a powerful tool. [ ] Biderhof: This village based on woodcutting and agriculture, has adopted you as one of it's own. Maybe you should adopt it as your own, in a literal sense. [ ] Non-Thief Guilds: Wurtbad, like all major cities, is home to a number of guilds. Reach out to them and enforce your will. Relations: [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with one of your fellow councillors or your liege, offering your help in their tasks and generally getting a feel for them (choose one). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: You've been given good reason to mistrust your fellow councillors. Perhaps you should see what they spent their time doing (choose one). [ ] Letters Home: You might be able to wring more information out of your Master, or you might just be able to get news, information and guidance in general from the Grey Order. [o] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (not possible during Purge Turns) --- FINANCES: NO ACTION POINT EXPENDITURE. Personal Income: 60 gold/turn Discretionary Income: 200 gold/turn Informer Payroll unlocked Currently paying Grey College tithe (-6 personal gold/turn) Currently paying Grey College student loans (-35 personal gold/turn) Not currently embezzling Currently funding regional informants (-90 discretionary gold/turn) Currently funding Watch informants (-10 discretionary gold/turn) Currently funding EIC informants (-20 discretionary gold/turn) Currently funding Intelligence Attaché program (-120 discretionary gold/turn) Currently employing Julia Massif (-30 discretionary gold/turn) Currently maintaining the staff of a townhouse in Wurtbad (-20 discretionary gold/turn) Totals: +19 personal gold/turn -90 discretionary gold/turn Bills will be paid every third Purge Turn. You can go into 'debt'; normally this would draw negative attention as you defer payments and take on loans in Stirland's name, but during the Purge it is to be expected; if you make good by the end of the turn immediately following the end of the War, all will be well. [ ] Begin plumping the informer rolls (choose ratio of real:fake informers. Almost impossible to detect, but also very difficult to increase or decrease the amount quickly) [ ] Change tithe payment/loan payment/embezzlement (specify) [o] These agents are getting expensive. Write up a proposal for your discretionary budget to be increased, instead of waiting for Van Hal to decide to increase it. (Van Hal does not have the attention to spare) - Welcome to the Purge. Each Purge Turn will be two months; you get two actions per turn and Julia will get an action every three turns. Feedback and oversight will be at best utterly minimal and more likely nonexistent; if there ever was a time for boldness, or to try to get away with something, it is now. - Size comparisons: the Haunted Hills, at about 5000 square miles, are about the size of Connecticut or Northern Ireland, and makes up about a quarter of Sylvania. While we're at it, Stirland (without Sylvania) is about 80k square miles, or the size of Kansas or Austria. Squinting at a map of the Empire gives me a figure of about 650k square miles - Alaska, or two and a half Texases, or two Germanies. - If you use a personal action to get a leader for the Watch, they'll be able to take actions on their own like the Information Network is during times like this. - If you venture into Sylvania, you will be accompanied at all times by your bodyguard platoon of 25 greatswords. - I didn't give you a Mastery for Take No Heed despite the crit because it didn't occur 'in the field' - you can't develop a deeper understanding of it while learning it by rote from scrolls. - What you learned of Gustav has already been added to the Dramatis Personae threadmark. - Ranald's Blessing will still be available, but will have a lesser effect during these turns. - Note that there's two sets of finances in the post, which could get confusing. The first set is the finances for this turn; the second is the projected income and costs for next turn.

Purge of the Haunted Hills - Nachgeheim, 2475

Winning Vote: [X] Plan The Front Don't Need Us Yet -[X][Intel] Information Broker: Start selling tidbits of information, just enough for your information network to start paying for itself. -[X][Personal] Seek out a new leader for the Watch. -[X][Personal] Scribe: Altdorf's scribe did not get on well with the Prince. He's going to be rather busy with burning things, but maybe that'll put him in a better mood if you offer your own services. (NEW-ish) --[X] Ranald's Blessing(if available) Click to expand... Click to shrink... --- It surprises you to find Wurtbad unchanged as you ride in. Thirty thousand men are marching to war and ten thousand more just outside the walls are prepared to join them, and Wurtbad is as it always was. The Watchmen at the gate salute as you pass, and your shadowhorse barely draws a glance from the citizenry, long accustomed as they are to your comings and goings. You allow your horse to dissipate as you enter the townhouse that is the public face of the Information Network of Stirland. Stirland's coffers are strained by the war, and so are your discretionary funds - at the current rate your funds will be exhausted within three to four months, and at that point you'll have to start dipping into your personal funds, which would negate the whole purpose of having embezzled them in the first place. "Madam," Julia greets you from her chaise longue, where she is skimming through files with an air of relaxed authority while tended to by a cloud of retainers she'd imported from Flensburg. She waves an air and in an instant all but one of them has left, who stands beside Julia, looking off to one side. "What news from the front?" You eye the remaining retainer, and Julia smiles. "This is Madeline, completely deaf and completely loyal. You can speak freely." You consider testing it, but then, you hired Julia so you didn't have to micromanage things like that. You take a seat across from her. "Let's talk finances." "Oh good," Julia says. "Gold has been flowing out like water and we're rapidly approaching a drought, I'm sure you're aware." She has mentioned it a time or two... in every single report to you for the past year. "I am. Information brokerage is the solution I want to discuss." She takes up a slate, scrawls on it with a piece of chalk, and then taps the girl on the elbow to get her attention; the girl peers at it and then disappears into the next room. "Hmm. It's not an immediate solution to our money troubles but it will at least put off the trouble for a few years - I've been collecting little bits and pieces for this eventuality. Limits?" "Nothing that hurts Stirland, of course. Nothing that would empower competitors to the EIC, for obvious reasons." You consider further. "Nothing that would destabilize Western Stirland - with Flensburg sorted out, Anton's father happy and Wolfsbach and Franzen occupied with the upcoming marriage and their joint riverine ventures, everything's just how Stirland wants it." She smiles at that - you wonder how well her family is doing of late. "I'll give you a free hand in the rest of Stirland - just don't destabilize Central and Southern Stirland at the same time. We will need supply lines to remain open." "Got it," she says, scribbling notes on the slate. "I take it that playing with internal Flensburg politics would be okay? I'd be propping up my own family, naturally, but also get a profit from playing the other families against each other." You nod, and she grins. "Shall we expand specifically for this? Our current agents aren't ideally placed to locate juicy gossip..." You think for a moment. "We need to be trending towards the black. If your collected information brings in enough of a lump sum, you can reinvest some of it in new agents, but otherwise work with what we've got." "Got it." Madeline comes back into the room, hands you a cool glass filled with some sort of... fruity-smelling cordial, and passes a folder to Julia, who skims through it with a smile. "Anything else I can help you with?" "Maybe. Do you know a good candidate for a leader for the Watch?" You take a sip of the drink - it's quite nice, some sort of sweetened apple cider by the taste of it. Very refreshing after a day spent on the road. Alcoholic, but not nearly as much as the brandy you share with Van Hal. "Hmm..." she nibbles her lip thoughtfully, still skimming through files. "If it weren't so important I'd probably try to talk you into one of my brothers, but to be honest they'd be thoroughly mediocre candidates. And it'd probably be a good idea to get at least one of the Hochschild boys out of the EIC, but they'd be terrible for the Watch." She pauses, then flips pages backwards. "Hand on. There's... here we go. The head of the castle guard at Steinbachthal is, by all accounts, wildly overqualified. And it just so happens that he's about to be out of a job, since someone is going to be selling information of his rather torrid affair with the Count's eldest daughter, who is supposedly a reclusive and respectable widow on the market for a new husband after her previous one passed away." "Have your people keep an eye on him after he's encouraged to seek work elsewhere, then. I'll meet him for an interview later in the month." [Martial candidate, Roll, Intrigue, 86+14=100.] --- With that taken care of, you bring your own efforts to bear in searching for a suitable candidate for the position. You briefly consider your own personal contacts, but none of them seem suitable. Those that you've trained with in the Army of Stirland... well, none of them worth hiring would leave it at such a crucial time. Anyone from your time in the Colleges? You mull that over for a while, but none of them seem even remotely suitable. Your brothers and sisters in Ranald's Faith? You can't help but laugh at the thought. Your only source of reasonable candidates you can think of is the mercenaries that Wilhelmina's been using to guard the EIC convoys between towns, and they're mainly the ones too cowardly or understrength to offer their services in proper wars. But then you have another idea. [Candidate search: Roll, Diplomacy: 10+7=17.] [Candidate search: Roll, Martial: 23+11=34.] [Candidate search: Roll, Stewardship: 38+13=51.] [Candidate search: Roll, Intrigue: 70+16=86.] [Candidate search: Roll, Piety: 6+16=22.] [Candidate search: Roll, Learning: 14+17=31.] --- High atop the streets of Wurtbad, a shadowed figure runs along the rooftops, leaping from one to the other, the evening fog muffling his sounds. The route was carefully mapped in advance, and he had timed it perfectly so that he could pass unnoticed. He reached his destination without trouble, a townhouse near the Castle - and far from the two townhouses that everyone in Wurtbad's criminal community knew not to touch. With a grin of triumph, he reached into the sheath at his belt for his trusty crowbar made of blackened steel- The window was already open. He hesitated, but stiffened his resolve, slipping the crowbar back into the sheath on his belt. After a moment of thought, he reached to the other sheath and confirmed the presence of his sword. He slowly bent down to peer into the room, searching for anyone standing guard. Clear - nobody waiting for him. He relaxed. A careless servant, perhaps. He slipped through the window soundlessly and into the sitting room, and suddenly, in full view of the window, where he knew he had looked and seen nobody, was a slight figure all in grey, wreathed in the evening fog that rolled in through the window to curl around her almost lovingly. --- "The Dämmerlichtreiter," the man breathes. You blink in surprise at him. "The what now?" You had been prepared for all sorts of reactions, but not calling you that. He stares, wild-eyed, pointing accusingly. "You! The Rider of Dusk! The woman who rides the coming of night across Stirland, bringing ruin to the enemies of the Hunter-Count!" You stare back, and a delighted smile spreads across your face. "I mean... gosh. I hadn't realized people had been noticing. The Rider of Dusk? That's... wow." You bask for a moment, but duty calls. "Anyway. Not why I'm here." The man's hand edged toward his sword, but an indecisive moment later away from it. "I will not resist the will of Stirland." "What? No, I mean, yes, technically, but I'm not here to arrest you or anything. In fact, go ahead and rob them, they haven't paid taxes since '62. I'm here to offer you a job." The man thinks that over, and relaxes somewhat. "Okay. What's the item?" "Oh, not that sort of job. Meet me at the Golden Eagle Inn at dawn tomorrow, and we can discuss it." You walk past the man, patting him on the shoulder as you go, and climb out the window. You can feel his eyes on your back as you climb down empty air like a flight of stairs, and can't keep from grinning at how thoroughly you nailed that dramatic exit. --- The man sits at your table as you work your way through your morning sausages. You glance across at him as you chew. Jack Albright, career thief and a damn good one at that. Originally of Marienburg, but attracted too much attention to himself and now on a protracted tour of the Empire. Charismatic, well-travelled, skilled in a variety of thieving arts and possessing of strong morals. You smile across at him. "Good morning. You look tired." "I didn't sleep well," he mutters. "The night before an interview," you nod understandingly. "Don't be too put out with your Fence. He would have warned you if he had remembered me." You smile at the wild-eyed look you get from him. "So, I take it you've heard of news with the Watch?" He looks around the inn nervously - it's usually crowded, but not this early, and there's nobody within earshot. He lowers his voice anyway. "You're fighting the War Below." "The War Below," you say musingly. Overly dramatic name for fighting against vermin and smugglers, but it has a nice ring to it. "The Watch is looking for a new leader. Ideally, someone with the creativity and inside knowledge to bring it success as it expands across Stirland." "You want me to betray those I work with," he mutters. "If I thought you would, you wouldn't be worth hiring. Besides, I envision the Watch as an organization with its attention elsewhere." As you talk, you dip a finger in your mug of small beer and draw an X on the table. Jack looks down at it thoughtfully as you wipe your mouth with a napkin, and then you place the napkin atop the X. "There are many threats to the good order of Stirland and the Empire, and a few thieves are the very least of them." "I... think I understand," he says. "Good. I'll give you some time to think it over - I've got to interview another candidate in Steinbachthal tomorrow morning, so if you're willing drop by my townhouse the day after, where I'll be receiving visitors." He stares at you, likely mentally calculating the distances, and you smile again. Being a wizard was so fun, sometimes. "Have a nice day." --- The candidate in Steinbachthal is another story entirely, much less awed and more morose. Jacques Seingalt sits in the tavern, already half-drunk despite it barely being lunchtime, and barely reacts when you introduce yourself. "And what," he says in the overly-clear diction of someone concentrating to keep from slurring, tinged with a faint Tilean accent, "does the Spymistress of Stirland want with a fired castle guard?" "To offer him a job," you say, and he perks up slightly at that. "The Stirland Watch is expanding, and needs a new leader. When I'd heard you'd been released from your duties, I decided to come see you for myself." He straightens himself in his seat. "Then you have fine taste in employees. I am Jacques Seingalt, duellist, doctor, and leader of men, famed across the Old World for my abilities." You'd heard similar. His career had begun in the mercenary bands of Tilea, before he befriended a travelling Bretonnian knight and went with him back to that strange land and led forces of men-at-arms against the greenskins ravaging the countryside in the unhappy aftermath of the disastrous Errantry War that wiped out a generation of Bretonnian knights. Since then he has travelled the length of the Old World, leading men of every nation against every enemy of mankind. It would be a mystery why he had settled for a lowly position as leader of a Count's household guard, if you didn't know well the full story. "I had heard as much. Would you be willing to perform this role?" He drains his tankard thoughtfully. "Normally I am dismissive of petty thief-takers, but rumour has spread of your ambitions for the Watch, how they spread across Western Stirland, how they protect even the smallest villages and ride forth to purge banditry from the countryside. This may be a suitable role for one of my skills; I will ride with you back to Wurtbad." You conceal a smile. "I think you will find it difficult to keep up." He scoffs. "No man, nor woman for that matter, can match me in the saddle." You end up impressed that it only takes him a week longer than you to arrive in the capital. --- You rejoin the army a month after the Purge has begun. Your information attachés had kept you well informed of their progress; or rather, their lack thereof. The first stage was to purge the Hills around Leicheberg and west of the river, but the projected two weeks had already turned into four and the job seemed no more than half done. The jagged countryside seemed to contain more nooks and crannies than should be possible, and any given stretch of land needed to be passed over in force a half-dozen times or more before things would stop appearing. It was hoped that as the troops and leadership learned, that this would be accelerated, but the fear was the opposite would be true - as they pressed deeper into Sylvania, it would only get worse. Still, at least Asarnil seems to be enjoying himself. He appears to be treating the operation as a massive hunt, with the armies acting as beaters to flush the undead out of wherever they were hiding so he could dive upon them - a symbiosis the troops are completely fine with. And the local shepherds who are flooding into the newly-cleansed hills with their herds have taken to sending sheep as tribute to Deathfang, the mighty jade-green dragon, who feasts on fresh mutton every evening surrounded by awed soldiers who play music on carved wooden pipes and kettledrums and crude mandolins in impromptu orchestras for him. Asarnil himself is less taken with the crowds, and broods in his massive tent alone each evening. He's occupied with buffing his armour with a cloth, but turns as you enter with a scowl and his mouth open to deliver a cutting rebuke, but upon seeing you he stops, surprised. "That manner of dress - why, you're one of Teclis' little ones!" You're rather taken aback at that. "I- well, I am part of the Colleges of Magic, yes-" "I'm so glad that you're still doing well. Which of them are you? Wait, don't tell me, you must be one of the Grey ones, right? Ulgu?" "Yes, I am of the Grey Order." "So few believed it would work, but Teclis proved them all wrong. And didn't Finubar hate that! He didn't even have the bravery to forbid one of those two brothers from doing what they pleased, but he predicted such ruin, and yet here you are." You're completely taken aback by this, but that last bit at least partially explains it - the tale of Asarnil's banishment from Ulthuan is well-known, and so something that tweaks the Phoenix King's nose would definitely please him. But you're starting to get the annoyed feeling that you're being treated like a child that has learned a particularly clever trick. "He taught you something of our language as well, didn't he? Is that still being passed down? Of course, not the proper thing, but a few words to use like we would use Anoqeyån." "Ulgunar kirior onai Tar-Eltharin, caladai-eldoir-kurn," you retort, and he stares at you, quite surprised. "I haven't heard-" he breaks off, and almost haltingly continues in Eltharin. "I have not heard the tongue of the True Elves in close to two centuries." "If it would please you, I would be happy to converse with you in it," you respond. "Of course!" he stops, and looks frustrated with himself. "Of course. I would like that very much." The two of you talk for some time on the progress of the campaign without touching on anything of any consequence, but the Elf seems to almost draw sustenance from hearing his language spoken, although he corrects your pronunciation a few times. And then you make your offer to him; though the scholar that was brought was inadequate for the task, you would be honoured to immortalize his campaigns in the Old World. He happily agrees - apparently it was Anton's unthinking comment of 'gosh, this should be written down so everyone could hear it' had planted the thought in him that some record of his acts should be made, to preserve his legacy in the unlikely event that he ever encounters something capable of striking him down. Week after week passes and parchment accumulates as one hundred and seventy-three years of battle are preserved in ink, beginning with the Battle of the Siren's Rocks that destroyed the entire naval fleet of Miragliano and ended them as a naval power and only growing from there, stopping only for you to sleep and for Asarnil to perform his duties in the Hills, though Deathfang takes to going off without him to keep himself occupied. The stories continue. A thousand battles, tens of thousands of skirmishes, hundreds of thousands dead by claw and flame and sword and lance, every one of which bought at an exorbitant price. He has fought for every realm of Man in the Old World from Kislev to Araby, for the mysterious elves of Athel Loren, for the lizard-people of the Southlands, and strangest of all, for dwarves. He shrugs at that. "I understand what it is to hold a grudge against the Phoenix King." Fair enough, you suppose. In the end, you've got an enormous and unruly pile of parchment containing the Dragonlord's account of every battle he has fought as a Mercenary. Asarnil claps you on the shoulder, dons his helm, and walks out of the tent to rejoin the campaign. [Purge progress: Roll, 30.] [Befriending the Elf: Req 70, Diplomacy, 93+7+10 (Likes Wizards)=110.] [Writing the stories: Roll, Learning, 51+17+10 (reader of tales)+10 (Ranald's Blessing=88.] --- CANDIDATE FOR LEADER OF THE STIRLAND WATCH - CHOOSE ONE [ ] Jack Albright, career criminal. [ ] Jacques Seingalt, wandering adventurer. [ ] Neither. WHAT DO YOU DO WITH THE TALES OF ASARNIL? CHOOSE ANY NUMBER. [ ] Hand them over to him in their current form; he would be fine with this, and would take his own actions with them. [ ] Have a scribe transfer them into book form - one copy for you, one for the Imperial College, one for Asarnil. [ ] Hire some printing press time and a translator, and start selling Reikspiel versions to anyone who's interested. [ ] Hire some printing press time and find a merchant willing to ship and sell as many copies as they can to Ulthuan. --- PLAN FOR THIS PURGE TURN ORGANIZATIONAL ACTIONS - pick NONE. For reference only, as actions can be taken as Personal Actions. Information Network - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [ ] Expand your information network into another province (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into another county or barony (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into the military (choose a Division) [ ] Expand your Intelligence Attaché program to another Division (choose one) [ ] Off the Leash: Let Julia handle the network without your micromanagement from now on. Information Network finances - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above. [ ] Attaché Paperwork: The Intelligence Attachés are your biggest expense by far - see if you can have them paid for by the Army of Stirland instead. [ ] Fixer: Work with the Wurtbad Thieves Guild, supplying them information in exchange for a portion of profits. [ ] Special Branch: Pull some financial trickery to get the information network classified as part of the Watch, so that their costs are covered by the Stirlandian treasury. [ ] Trade Delegation: Convince Wilhelmina and Markus to partner your network with the EIC based on the value of market information. Stirland Watch - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [o] Expand the ranks of the Watch, so that they're able to start covering even the poorer parts of their covered area. (cannot be taken until army retirement resumes in one year) [ ] Expand the Special Branch into areas already covered by the Watch, so you have an additional pool of manpower you can call upon to supplement the full-time Watchmen. [ ] Improve the training of the Watch, hiring trainers and dedicating paid time each week to sharpening skills. [ ] Integrate the Roadwarden network of covered areas into the Watch. [ ] Headhunt administrators from other organizations in Stirland. [ ] Neither candidate is suitable - continue to seek out a new leader for the Watch. --- PERSONAL ACTIONS - CHOOSE BETWEEN TWO AND THREE. ANY CHOSEN BEYOND THE FIRST TWO WILL COME WITH RISKS - PLEASE SPECIFY THE 'ADDITIONAL' TASK: Genießt den Krieg - join the divisions entering Sylvania: [ ] Attach yourself to the general staff, so you can be present for anything interesting that might happen and keep a finger on the pulse of the war. [ ] Attach yourself to a specific regiment so you can spend some time in the thick of things. Miscellany: [ ] Financial Jargon: Everything with the EIC flew right over your head last time. Try again. Succeeding here will mean that you can take a more active hand in the company, adding it to the organizational actions; failing or not attempting means Mathilde will remain a silent partner. [ ] Hang Out A Shingle: Spymasters don't advertise, but wizards sometimes do. Make an official announcement that there's a wizard in residence, and see who comes out of the woodwork. [ ] Formal Proposal: Your idea for an undead research team was received poorly, but Van Hal is still open to the idea in theory. Write in details: Name, who it is technically a part of (Watch, Witch Hunters, Military, College, none), and whether it reports directly to you (becomes a new Organization you command) or, if not, who it would report to. [ ] Gun Shopping: You're currently using a pistol that was a spare for the pistoliers. Visit Nuln to upgrade. (Choose: dueling pistols for accuracy and range, repeater pistols for weight of fire, dragons for hand shotguns. Choose: whether you will acquire and use two pistols at once or keep one hand free.) [ ] Write up a proposal for Wilhelmina to approve a short-term increase in Discretionary Income, for the duration of the crisis. Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. [ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills and internalize the lessons you've learned (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective if you've used the trait a lot lately). [ ] Tutoring: One of your fellow councillors may be willing to teach you in their chosen field (choose who; can choose which, or you can let them decide). [ ] Really Good Swords: You have achieved proficiency with the Greatsword. Future progress is possible, though it will take more effort to see results. [ ] Pistols at Dawn: You've taken some great strides in an entirely new form of combat, but you're still not entirely proficient. Finish your training. [ ] Combat Training: You're virtually surrounded by armed warriors of various sorts. See if you can convince one to teach you (choose who). [ ] Combat Training, In The Free Market: You haven't made many heavily armed friends yet, but gold is good for that. Go out and buy some training. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. [ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Remixed: You're getting sick of having workmen tramping in and out of your abode. Recruit an entire team and personally oversee them to clear out all of the reachable portions of the Palace-Shrine and be done with it. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: You've finally got the equipment, now you've just got to unpack it all and set up your laboratory. [ ] Filled with Potential: You've got a room cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put there and get started on equipping it. (write in the purpose of the room) Research: [ ] Undead Research: You know the basics, now. Perhaps a great deal of effort will allow you to advance further. [ ] Snooping: Van Hal gave you a key to his Study. He didn't specifically say not to poke around and see what you could find. [ ] Shyish-kebabs: The Shyish swords are hideously dangerous as weapons, but fascinating as a subject of study. Try to reverse-engineer the lost enchantments woven into them. [ ] Bound Spells: Though the corrosive Dhar made them high-maintenance, the design of the bound spells in the castle's infiltrators has fascinating possibilities. The memories had faded but you've managed to refresh them. Try to adapt it for use with Ulgu. [ ] Qhaysh Juice: Whatever it is, it's dripping out of the box at a steady rate. You've got two gallons of the stuff and it's still coming out. It's got to be good for something. [ ] Qhaysh Skunkworks: It would take careful study to unlock the secrets of the liquid. It would take considerably less time to find out if it can be made to burn, or explode, or do something militarily useful. [ ] As a Journeywoman, the path to Magister is marked by mastering more than the two shadow spells you already know. Send to the Grey Order for the basics and work on figuring out one of the others. Influence: [ ] Thieves Guild: It's currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. If it could be expanded under your aegis, it could be a powerful tool. [ ] Biderhof: This village based on woodcutting and agriculture, has adopted you as one of it's own. Maybe you should adopt it as your own, in a literal sense. [ ] Non-Thief Guilds: Wurtbad, like all major cities, is home to a number of guilds. Reach out to them and enforce your will. Relations: [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with one of your fellow councillors or your liege, offering your help in their tasks and generally getting a feel for them (choose one). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: You've been given good reason to mistrust your fellow councillors. Perhaps you should see what they spent their time doing (choose one). [ ] Letters Home: You might be able to wring more information out of your Master, or you might just be able to get news, information and guidance in general from the Grey Order. [o] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (not possible during Purge Turns) - You will find out the financial effect of the Information Network decision at the end of the Purge Turn after this coming one. - There are three votes - Watch Leader, the elf stories, and the turn proper. - Don't forget Ranald's Blessing. --- Added to this threadmark for posterity: -[*] Attach yourself to a specific regiment so you can spend some time in the thick of things. Click to expand... Click to shrink... ...I could have sworn this said 'specify which'. Though it might be better to have it be an informed decision. Okay, minivote time. Empire tactics 101: spears receive the charge, swords countercharge. Each Division has two spear regiments, one sword regiment, and one crossbow regiment. The Regiment you choose will determine what sort of action, if any, you find yourself in. You can also attempt to join one of the other presences on the battlefield. - Herr Schultz with the 2nd Division will be pushing up the Hilltop Road about halfway to Vanhaldenschlosse. Once there, they will find a hilltop close to the road and fortify it, to be used as a fallback position and supply depot. They will also be scouting the nearby area as well as standing ready to support the 3rd or 4th if needed. - Gustav with the 3rd Division will be circling around the outside of the Hills to approach one of the tallest peaks in the range, home to many a local legend, most of which are worrying light on details but something called a 'Blasphemy of Blood' keeps coming up. Gustav is confident that whatever it is, it will prove vulnerable to at least one of steel, cannonballs, or dragonfire. - Van Hal with the 4th Division will be scouring the hills between the two upper forks of the river, northwest of Naubonum. This is expected to be business as usual, though Van Hal will be intending to examine the problem of why any patch of given land needs to be scoured several times to be free of undead. From the preliminary results of processing all the reports and paperwork coming in, most of what has been faced has been the restless dead - zombies, skeletons, and the occasional wight. Ghouls have been spotted, but not in any great number and most have been seen scampering away at high speed, and they've only been rode down when knights or pistoliers were close at hand. Spoiler: Campaign map 2nd Division [ ] Flensburg Spear Regiment [ ] Franzen Spear Regiment [ ] Flensburg Sword Regiment [ ] Blutdorf Crossbow Regiment [ ] 1st Pistolier Cohort [ ] 2nd Pistolier Cohort [ ] Talabeclander Knights 3rd Division [ ] Steinbachthal Spear Regiment [ ] Schramleben 1st Spear Regiment [ ] Halstedt Sword Regiment [ ] Marburg Crossbow Regiment [ ] Artillery battery (10 cannon, 10 mortar) [?] Asarnil the Dragonlord 4th Division [ ] Schramleben 2nd Spear Regiment [ ] Sigmaringen Spear Regiment [ ] Leicheberg Sword Regiment [ ] Hornau Crossbow Regiment [ ] Knights of Morr

Purge of the Haunted Hills - Brauzeit, 2475

Winning vote: [*] Jack Albright, career criminal. [*] Have a scribe transfer them into book form - one copy for you, one for the Imperial College, one for Asarnil. [*] Hire some printing press time and a translator, and start selling Reikspiel versions to anyone who's interested. [*] Hire some printing press time and find a merchant willing to ship and sell as many copies as they can to Ulthuan. [*] Plan Get Stuck In -[*] Bound Spells: Though the corrosive Dhar made them high-maintenance, the design of the bound spells in the castle's infiltrators has fascinating possibilities. The memories had faded but you've managed to refresh them. Try to adapt it for use with Ulgu. --[*] Ranald's Blessing -[*] Attach yourself to a specific regiment so you can spend some time in the thick of things. --[*] Leicheberg Sword Regiment Click to expand... Click to shrink... --- Forewarned by Van Hal's stern instruction to make you welcome, the Colonel in charge of the Leicheberg Swords stands still long enough to acknowledge your status and inform you that his men have been instructed to make you welcome and obey all reasonable requests, before hurrying off to see to the last minute arrangements of getting thousands of men back on the march. Having been posted in Steinbachthal and therefore out of the nexus of activity that Fort Redemption has become, the 4th are apparently still finding their feet - which may be why Van Hal is taking charge of them personally. You get in touch with the members of your attaché, and have a look over the paperwork that has yet to be sent on its way to Wurtbad. The forms are proving their worth; the details are recorded while memories are still fresh, and instead of having to wonder whether vague reports of 'walking skeletons' could refer to the rare and dangerous wights, one only needs to refer to the entry for 'Colour of Glow of Eyes or Eye Sockets'. There's even inferences that can be drawn that didn't occur to you when you made the forms. The entries for 'armament' and 'substance said armament is formed from' reveals that the skeletons are wielding an eclectic mix of modern steel, older iron and much older bronze, which implies that the undead are not sourced from any one battlefield but rather the result of thousands of years of accumulated restless dead. Back in Wurtbad, Julia is probably working on an organizational system to index this information - you hadn't asked her to, but it's the sort of thing she does. Hours later the army is finally ready to leave, and off they march at something of a relaxed stroll. You summon your shadowsteed and join the head of the column, where the General and four Colonels - part of an endless cloud of military men whose names you're glad you never have to learn - are planning the day's march, or as best they can with the map pinned over the horn of Van Hal's saddle and the wind doing its best to pluck the map free and carry it off. As far as you can tell, the full day's march will take the troops about as far as you could go in twenty minutes. You're starting to regret your decision to join the rank and file. --- Two agonizingly dull days later, the army finally reached the bridge that leads to Naubonum. Another day of organizing later, and the army disintegrated; five companies stayed in place to maintain and guard the camp while twenty plunged into the hills to start performing their task. You pick the first one where nobody makes the sign of the hammer as you approach and introduce yourself to the Captain, who's name you honestly tried to remember, and the Lieutenant of the swords contingent of the company, whose name you might be able to remember if you thought about it for a moment. You also introduced yourself to the Knight of Morr that would be accompanying you, though of course you received no reply. And with that, fifty spearmen, twenty-five swordsmen, twenty-five crossbowmen, one Knight of Morr and a wizard ventured off into the hills, and it takes you less than an hour to realize the insurmountable problem that this campaign faces. It is, unfortunately, not one you are qualified to solve. The cause of these seemingly regenerating undead is not mystical, but geographical. You had pictured softly rolling hills, covered in grass, perhaps of a sickly colour due to the Sylvanian atmosphere. Instead the landscape is jagged, like it had been sliced apart by some enormous blade, and covered in impenetrable scrub and unnaturally still lakes and fathomless caves. The Leichebergian troops, native to these lands, are happy to share with you an all-new vocabulary of the land they call the Wold. Combes, steep, narrow valleys without watercourse, almost always impassably filled with thorned scrub. Scarps, the sheer cliffs separating two otherwise level pieces of land, as if the land had been broken apart and then put back together off-center. Dew-ponds, artificial hilltop lakes built longer ago than man remembers, that somehow remain full without being fed by spring or river. Karst, the bizarrely smooth caves that absolutely riddle the hills. Doline, when the land atop the aforementioned caves has surrendered to the pull of gravity, creating enormous depressions like the impact of some unbelievably enormous missile - and, they warn, sometimes the land is just waiting to collapse in on a karst cave and form a doline, so never march in time atop the Wold. And compounding the geographic terrors, there are the botanical ones. Mother-die, the horrifically-named tree that grows out rather than up, with soft white flowers and shiny red berries and jagged thorns as long as a man's hand. Spined Spurge, a sprawling climbing shrub with every stem festooned with barbed spines - they say that if a man dies touching a Spurge, it will envelop his corpse and never let it rise, which makes it popular among villages unsupervised by the Morrites. The Brambles, a variety of dense shrubs with tasty berries that can grow as fast as a man can walk, or so they say, and are - inevitably - covered in thorns. They also speak of ancient tales, though none can agree if those that feature in them were the Fennone or the Asoborn - you privately theorize that it was both, and the Southern Stirlanders have always been a blend of Sylvanians and Stirlanders. The tale tells of hills covered in dense, choking woodland that jealously covered the sky so that nothing below could live, and how the people of prehistory fought it over generations with axe and saw until the forest was killed and life returned to the hills. For millennia the Wold was host to grass and grazers and shepherds, tamed and peaceful and quiet... until, of course, it became just one victim among countless others, when Sylvania fell to plague and beastman and necromancy in the time of Van Hal's infamous ancestor. All very interesting in a bucolic sort of way, you suppose, but the end result is a land that can't be easily searched. Any given hour's walk will find an impassable cliff, an impenetrable valley, the entrance to a cave network of unmappable complexity, and acre after acre of dense, thorned scrubland. One doesn't clear such a land - one just marches back and forth along the few passable routes until they stop finding enemies to kill. You wonder what Van Hal is going to make of all this. --- Weeks pass atop the Wold. Each morning you emerge from your tent, cursing the late autumn chill, and try to find solace in the dawn mist. Each day you march, and you inevitably find something; usually skeletons, sometimes zombies, and once a wight, that might have broken up the monotony if your pistol shot, trailing Ulgu, hadn't punched right through its skull and dispersed the fell magic holding it together. You have the opportunity to watch the forms you designed in action, and are pleased to see the diligence with which the officers fill them out, and the odd air of satisfaction with which they do so. As if performing a final tally of the dead - they're slain, they're given rites by the silent Knight, their details are taken down, and all the forms will be sent off to the capital all nice and neat and that's that undead beastie dealt with for good, nice and neat and official. Only once did you or the Swords see proper combat, when you stumbled across the entrance to some vast underground chamber filled with milling dead. Without a good open battlefield to form neat units, the swords and spears stood side by side at the opening to the cave, and your pistol barked once before they were upon your lines, and your flamberge rose and fell in time with the swords of those at your side until finally no more emerged. Forty of them, all told, four of whom were slain by your hand; six injuries among the ranks of the living, none serious. Over the course of the month, you claim another dozen, all from pistol-shot and all just before the crossbows would have achieved the result anyway. The task at hand is thoroughly lacking in glory - if anything, it's a chore. A chore with a small but significant chance of getting you killed, and not even in any interesting, glorious way. You're relieved when the month draws to an end and the army reassembles to head back to Fort Redemption before winter settles in. --- Before fleeing to the comforts of home, you sat in on the council of war that convened in the usual council room at Fort Redemption. Van Hal was... well, if it was anyone else you'd say they were sulking. He had clearly been expecting some sort of horrible necromantic curse to unravel, and instead it was just a matter of geography. Gustav had greater luck with his adventure; what was once the tallest peak in the western Wold is now very much not so, and he's quite pleased to add 'killing a mountain' to his list of deeds. The 'Blasphemy of Blood' had turned out to be some sort of bizarre cursed spring in a cave atop the peak. It burbled blood-red water, which local vermin drank and drank and drank from, growing bloated and sloshing, and the only thing they thirsted for more than the liquid of the spring was the true blood that ran in the veins of men. Sadly for the creatures, it turns out that in this case water does not beat fire, and Deathfang had dealt with most of their population in a single contemptuous exhalation. The problem of what to do with the spring was puzzling for a while, and then he'd apparently decided that thinking was for other people and decided to hit it until it went away, and to do that he had roped in the 3rd Division and their siege train. For three weeks boulders the size of cows had been flung at the peak, and though at first it just caused the cursed spring to overflow its pool and run down in a crimson waterfall, he'd persevered until one day, finally, against all reason, the waterfall ran clear. He produced a flask of water, which he'd said the chaplains had already inspected; you give it a close examination, but there's absolutely nothing to indicate it's anything but completely normal water. You're slightly annoyed that 'hit it until it stops doing evil magic stuff' has proven effective even against inanimate objects. --- It is the aptly-named Kaldezeit and you are incredibly glad to be back in Wurtbad, and especially Wurtbad's hot springs. Once a vibrant tourist attraction, the misrule of the Haupt-Anderssens had rendered them little more than a local luxury, but such a luxury they were. You idly consider the possibility of getting one piped in to your buried palace. Once you get that out of your system, you check in with Jack, who appears to be settling in quite well to his position - he's been taciturn about his previous experience and the Watchmen have, understandably, reached the conclusion that he's a former spy. You check in with Julia, who's busily distilling thousands of freshly filled-out forms from the front into usable information. You check in with the printers, who assure you that they'll get to it when they get to it and to please stop breathing down their necks about your elf story; the scribe you hired for the three properly scribed copies says something similar. Then, satisfied that everything is ticking over nicely without you, you turn to magical experimentation. With your memory of the lattice of Dhar that had ensorcelled the infiltrators refreshed, you try your damnedest to adapt it for Ulgu. It's a great deal trickier than you first thought; it could be said to be similar to trying to achieve with ice what someone else had done with water, except magic has ten forms instead of the three of matter. Dhar has an inherent tendency to degenerate, so your hope is that the same trick done with Ulgu will lack the tendency to break down and unleash the held effect; but Dhar also has a tendency to stick to people, where Ulgu does not. Weeks pass in experimentation. Theory turned to practice, and now a corner of your spare room has been fenced off and is now the temporary home of a half-dozen chickens. On a piece of wood you've set up as a workbench, one has been sent to Sleep while you hunch over it, weaving Ulgu into its tiny feathered frame. You've been at it for hours, and this is the third time you've tried today - over in the pen one chicken is clucking distressingly as fog spills from its beak, and another is confusedly preening its newly-grey feathers. It's like trying to build a spiderweb inside of a soap-bubble, and then building a model ship inside the spiderweb. The framework for the spell is built inside the physical body of the creature - without, obviously, being able to physically interact with where the metaphysical framework is being built - and then the spell needs to be cast inside that framework. It is, in short, hideously fiddly. Finally, finally, it is done. You pull away from the chicken with your breath held, and observe. The spell is there, glowing softly to those with the eyes to see, but frozen as if in amber at the moment of culmination. You shift in your seat, a little awkwardly. There was really only one suitable spell for testing this - Drop would rarely have an effect on a chicken and as for Mindhole, how did you even tell if a chicken remembered you? So the spell you had woven inside the chicken was Sleep. You poke it, gingerly, your breath held and watching for any sign of destabilization from the lattice inside the bird. But it holds firm even as it stirs, and then it takes one look at you and dashes off the surface of the bench, flapping its way to the floor as it clucks in distress. "Test," you say, and the chicken continues scampering away from you. "Balderdash." Still nothing untoward; it apparently decides the distance is now safe and starts scratching at the floor. "Danoi," you say, and the chicken instantly collapses forwards onto its feathered breast, eyes closed. You step forward and pick up the bird gingerly, examining it closely. Sure enough, the spell that had been held within it was gone, the once-frozen magic having fulfilled its purpose and dispersed. But, to your surprise, the framework that once held the spell remains. Interesting. And potentially useful. You once again begin weaving Ulgu into the hapless bird. [Bound Spell research: 93+17+10 (Ranald's Blessing)=120.] --- Spoiler: Campaign progress Pistol proficiency acquired! 'Bound Spells' adapted for Ulgu. Jack settling in to the Watch - 'free' Watch action will be available after next turn. 70g spent on books - 10g for personal copies, 40g for printing plates for the books, 20g for the initial print run --- PLAN FOR THIS PURGE TURN ORGANIZATIONAL ACTIONS - pick NONE. For reference only, as actions can be taken as Personal Actions. Information Network - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [ ] Expand your information network into another province (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into another county or barony (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into the military (choose a Division) [ ] Expand your Intelligence Attaché program to another Division (choose one) [ ] Off the Leash: Let Julia handle the network without your micromanagement from now on. Information Network finances - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above. [ ] Attaché Paperwork: The Intelligence Attachés are your biggest expense by far - see if you can have them paid for by the Army of Stirland instead. [ ] Fixer: Work with the Wurtbad Thieves Guild, supplying them information in exchange for a portion of profits. [ ] Special Branch: Pull some financial trickery to get the information network classified as part of the Watch, so that their costs are covered by the Stirlandian treasury. [ ] Trade Delegation: Convince Wilhelmina and Markus to partner your network with the EIC based on the value of market information. Stirland Watch - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [o] Expand the ranks of the Watch, so that they're able to start covering even the poorer parts of their covered area. (cannot be taken until army retirement resumes in one year) [ ] Expand the Special Branch into areas already covered by the Watch, so you have an additional pool of manpower you can call upon to supplement the full-time Watchmen. [ ] Improve the training of the Watch, hiring trainers and dedicating paid time each week to sharpening skills. [ ] Integrate the Roadwarden network of covered areas into the Watch. [ ] Headhunt administrators from other organizations in Stirland. --- PERSONAL ACTIONS - CHOOSE BETWEEN TWO AND THREE. ANY CHOSEN BEYOND THE FIRST TWO WILL COME WITH RISKS - PLEASE SPECIFY THE 'ADDITIONAL' TASK: Genießt den Krieg - join the divisions entering Sylvania: [o] Attach yourself to the general staff, so you can be present for anything interesting that might happen and keep a finger on the pulse of the war. (army is bunked down for the winter) [o] Attach yourself to a specific regiment so you can spend some time in the thick of things. (army is bunked down for the winter) [ ] By all accounts the entire general vicinity it was in has been pulverized, but there could be a shadow of a ghost of a chance that something might remain of the Blasphemy of Blood that could be studied? Maybe? (NEW) Miscellany: [ ] Financial Jargon: Everything with the EIC flew right over your head last time. Try again. Succeeding here will mean that you can take a more active hand in the company, adding it to the organizational actions; failing or not attempting means Mathilde will remain a silent partner. [ ] Hang Out A Shingle: Spymasters don't advertise, but wizards sometimes do. Make an official announcement that there's a wizard in residence, and see who comes out of the woodwork. [ ] Formal Proposal: Your idea for an undead research team was received poorly, but Van Hal is still open to the idea in theory. Write in details: Name, who it is technically a part of (Watch, Witch Hunters, Military, College, none), and whether it reports directly to you (becomes a new Organization you command) or, if not, who it would report to. [ ] Gun Shopping: You're currently using a pistol that was a spare for the pistoliers. Visit Nuln to upgrade. (Choose: dueling pistols for accuracy and range, repeater pistols for weight of fire, dragons for hand shotguns. Choose: whether you will acquire and use two pistols at once or keep one hand free.) [ ] Write up a proposal for Wilhelmina to approve a short-term increase in Discretionary Income, for the duration of the crisis. Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. [ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills and internalize the lessons you've learned (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective if you've used the trait a lot lately). [ ] Tutoring: One of your fellow councillors may be willing to teach you in their chosen field (choose who; can choose which, or you can let them decide). [ ] Really Good Swords: You have achieved proficiency with the Greatsword. Future progress is possible, though it will take more effort to see results. [ ] Combat Training: You're virtually surrounded by armed warriors of various sorts. See if you can convince one to teach you (choose who). [ ] Combat Training, In The Free Market: You haven't made many heavily armed friends yet, but gold is good for that. Go out and buy some training. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. [ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Remixed: You're getting sick of having workmen tramping in and out of your abode. Recruit an entire team and personally oversee them to clear out all of the reachable portions of the Palace-Shrine and be done with it. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: You've finally got the equipment, now you've just got to unpack it all and set up your laboratory. [ ] Filled with Potential: You've got a room cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put there and get started on equipping it. (write in the purpose of the room) Research: [ ] Undead Research: You know the basics, now. Perhaps a great deal of effort will allow you to advance further. [ ] Snooping: Van Hal gave you a key to his Study. It's been a while since he's been in Wurtbad; he probably forgot he did so, and won't remember until he returns. And he didn't specifically say not to poke around and see what you could find. [ ] Shyish-kebabs: The Shyish swords are hideously dangerous as weapons, but fascinating as a subject of study. Try to reverse-engineer the lost enchantments woven into them. [ ] Publish Or Perish, Part 1: Though it's currently of limited utility to you personally, sharing your discovery might bring it to the attention of hundreds of wizards who could put it to great effect. Though before you do that, you'll need to learn the vocabulary to communicate exactly what it is you're doing, since you can't exactly submit the poor chicken as part of your paper. (NEW) [ ] Qhaysh Juice: Whatever it is, it's dripping out of the box at a steady rate. You've got two gallons of the stuff and it's still coming out. It's got to be good for something. [ ] Qhaysh Skunkworks: It would take careful study to unlock the secrets of the liquid. It would take considerably less time to find out if it can be made to burn, or explode, or do something militarily useful. [ ] As a Journeywoman, the path to Magister is marked by mastering more than the two shadow spells you already know. Send to the Grey Order for the basics and work on figuring out one of the others. Influence: [ ] Thieves Guild: It's currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. If it could be expanded under your aegis, it could be a powerful tool. [ ] Biderhof: This village based on woodcutting and agriculture, has adopted you as one of it's own. Maybe you should adopt it as your own, in a literal sense. [ ] Non-Thief Guilds: Wurtbad, like all major cities, is home to a number of guilds. Reach out to them and enforce your will. Relations: [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with one of your fellow councillors or your liege, offering your help in their tasks and generally getting a feel for them (choose one). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: You've been given good reason to mistrust your fellow councillors. Perhaps you should see what they spent their time doing (choose one). [ ] Letters Home: You might be able to wring more information out of your Master, or you might just be able to get news, information and guidance in general from the Grey Order. [o] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (not possible during Purge Turns) - Finance details will be at the end of the next Purge Turn. - Don't forget Ranald's Blessing. - Any questions you have about the undead statistics, ask - though keep it general, because I'm not going to calculate and detail exact casualty figures. - Before anyone tries - no, you can't wield a greatsword in one hand and a pistol in the other and get a total of +6 martial.

Turn 11: Shedding Blood

Spoiler: Voted Upon Plan

[X]Plan Youth is the Future
-[X] Target An Aerus Daemonforge - One of the tainted manufactorums which continually spill out a mixture of random possessed machinery, horrific cybernetic monstrosities, etc. behind the ‘enemy lines’ which are currently fighting against the streaming hordes of Skitarii. Marcus is planning to lead the 1st Company in a strike deep into enemy lines to destroy the closest to the Skitarii Lines.
--[X]Have Justinius Probalis scry the Daemonforge, find us the best way in to the heart of the damned place)
--[X]Gabriel + Apollo, Rogal's Fist to Apollo, Pistol of Baal to Gabriel
--[X]5th Company w/ 6x Meltaguns, 4x Plasma Guns, 4x Flamers, 4x Stormbolters, 30x Combat Shields, Gift of the Seraphim to Kaius Jacobus
--[X]Vindicator, 2 Predators, All the Razorbacks (we should have 3 of the Twin-linked plasma cannon + Lascannon variants now), Rhinos, Litany of Purgation and enough assault bikes so everyone coming is mounted.
--[X]Marcus remains in command of the overall force
-[X] Patrol the Reclaimed Zone - Is subject to regular ambushes, machine creature infiltrators, mutated creatures appearing through ruined sewers and pipes. This will free up the 1stMeridian, while allowing the Mechanicus to work with better ease at restoring the area, building up their own defenses, etc.
--[X]Assign unused Tarantula turrets to support the 1st Meridian, to be deployed where they see fit.
-[X] Assign Ares Actus, your newest Chaplain, to a Company. (1st)
-[X] Search amongst the neophytes and scouts for any with the potential to become an Apothecary.
-[X] Search amongst the neophytes and scouts for any with the potential to become a Techmarine.
-[X] Search amongst the neophytes and scouts for any with the potential to become a Chaplain.
-[X]Find out how dangerous the Hrud infestation has become. Go personally if needed.
-[X] Agility
-[X] Toughness
--[X] Tarkus
-[X] Implant all 45 late-stage Neophytes with gene-seed
-[X] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest in 5 years. [11]
-[X] Build Order (250 BP Available)
--[X]2x Thunder Hammers (230)
--[X]6x Power Fists(200)
--[X]Land Raider Crusader [200/400 BP] (0)
-[X] Set up the world of Junius to be a proper Recruiting World for the Chapter. Further train the 10th Company while there, in the hopes of advancing them further. This is required for Blood Trials in the future.

Shedding Blood
+007.M42+
+Honor The Imperium+

“It is…disgusting,” Justinius finally grunts out as he slowly rises from the ritual circle, surrounded by the pitifully few numbers of the once many fierce Librarians that your Chapter once boasted. “Daemons of spite and fury have infected its very bones down to the steel and foundations, even the electricity that courses through its veins are tainted.”

The Librarius of the Omnis Arcanum was once the grandest in the Chapter, and you suppose it still might, but there is the lingering suspicion of pitfalls left behind in both the real and unreal by its long association with Kyras. As it is, your Chief Librarian has gathered almost all of the Librarians left to the Chapter to assist him in scrying into the surface of a world blanketed in Chaotic energies where the stark and cool presence of the Adeptus Mechanicus remains.

“But we see a path,” the newest Codicier speaks up from where he remains kneeling, hands pressed against the deck plates. “Both for us and the first company to push through. The parts of the world that are uncleansed, some of it is corrupted by things simply mundane. Fierce enough to fight off encroaching metal beasts with minds they should never have had, but not so much for the mailed fist of the Emperor’s fury.”

“Nero is correct,” Justinius nods in the direction of the blind yet seeing Librarian. “It will nonetheless be hard, and the very nature of this world’s tainted territories make it difficult to pierce the veil perfectly.”

“It will have to be enough,” you say as you turn towards the doors. “We shall return to the planet post-haste, then to join up with Captain Marcus.”

=========================

“Burn you mongrel creatures! BURN!” you hear the telltale voice of Jacobus bellowing as the marines of the 5th company spew fire of literal, melta, and bolter varieties down the throats of the charging beasts.

There are too many to even properly describe, so varied are the mutants that burst from the metallic wilderness all around you. From ancient sewer pipes that have become filth choked dens for these nesting beasts they erupt from all around you, only to run up against the steely fury of the Blood Ravens. Few even get close enough to be granted the dubious honor of melee combat against the Angels of Death, and of those even fewer survive contact with yourself, Apollo, or others who bear weapons for such work rather than the noble bolter.

From up ahead, the bellowing and yet comforting hate-filled voice of Ares Actus booms out as he smashes a creature that looks to be a mix between ancient terran ursine and bovine put together with far too many horns and legs. The 1st Company rallies around he and their Captain both as they push forward through organic muck mixing with the rusting floor of the Forgeworld’s ancient pockmarked skin. To be sure, the blasting beams of searing light that erupt from the Litany of Purgation do even more damage to the creatures, but that does not stop you from seeing one of the newest members of the 5th Company, arriving from the ministrations of Cyrus, from being leapt upon by a simply massive pile of smaller creatures that only come up to a knee individually.

Roaring defiance, you push forward, smashing away the creatures with each blow of Godsplitter, but by the time you have cleared them out the marine is most certainly mortally wounded. As if summoned by some unseen signal, the gore slathered Constantius appears from out of the melee of combat, the white of his armor almost invisible beneath it all. There are no words to be said, save that the Apothecary clucks his tongue once in annoyance as he begins to go about his own surgical ministrations. You are turning away to guard over him even as his saw begins to whir and the shunting hiss of his sacred device activates.

“Will he live?” you grunt as you batter into a nondescript thing with armor plates that could have been a combat shield on their own.

“In a dreadnought shell, yes,” the Apothecary of the 1st Company replies tersely, “But his wounds are too severe otherwise, not with his spinal cord and the brain’s tissues…,” he mutters something that you cannot hear beneath his breath, “Went in straight through the eyes, both of them…into the….no, I am sorry Chapter Master, but these are his last moments outside of a shell.”

“Damnation,” you roar before pushing forward and utilizing the incredible strength granted by the terminator armor you wear to simply lift up one of the creatures and slam it down so that you can stomp it to death.

It is then that your comm bead crackles.

“Chapter Master, the daemonforge is up ahead! We are moving towards it, can you guard our rear and flanks!?” Marcus calls out, the sounds of battle echoing now twice as loud in your head.

“Of course, Captain. Good hunting,” you call back before returning to your own work.

All around you, ‘The Fated’ fight gloriously, and all the same slowly begin to pull back to form a static defense. Why Boreale, your own student, would fail to accept the utility of such things, is beyond you. Yet the anger and shame at what your failure as a teacher, in creating such a student, is a cold one by now. You cannot allow such doubt to cloud your mind, and so put it aside so that you can continue to fight alongside your brothers.

“You…shall…all…die!” a more welcome voice intrudes upon your morose thoughts, focusing you just as well.

Davian Thule’s mind was worried to be forever clouded by the toxins of the tyranids. But in the years since the purge it had slowly recovered more and more as time went on. By now, fighting alongside the rest of the 5th Company as they formed up into a loose shield against the enraged creatures that stomped, twisted, slithered, and bounced out to face you. It is such a sight that heartens you further as he uses his great bulk to shift such that it blocks a series of acid-dripping spines launched by some snake-like creature or another before it screams as it is set aflame by the relic flamer born by Kaius. Indeed, perhaps ironically, the stretch of Aerus that you worked to push through in order to reach the daemonforge at all had managed to fight off the more mechanical denizens of this place, but you crashed through them in a tide of metal that would do even the Iron Hand proud.

A land raider, the vindicator, your razorbacks and two predators, as well as far more assault bikes. Though you cannot ride atop one, many more can, able to weave in and out of danger as they unleash the righteous cleansing death that you have brought to this place. All is not perfect, of course. As one small formation of the assault bike ride past you, some bearing members of the 1st Company and others of the 5th Company, a twin-tailed scorpion creature pushes to the fore amongst the more porcine squealing creatures ahead of it. With a stab forward that defies natural evolution with its speed, one of the assault bikes is stabbed through the middle and tearing into the rider’s leg at the same time – piercing so deep as to hit the second as well through the bike itself. With a grunt, you watch – busied with a trio of charging primate-esque monsters almost reminding you of jakaero – as the marine instead merely roars with fury and a cry to the Emperor before stabbing his combat knife into the tail itself, letting it drag him up into the air and towards it as it pulls bike and prey towards its gullet.

An instant passes, as you sweep your hammer forward to obliterate the chest of another creature, and when you look back again the now legless marine has hacked off the impaled appendages and falls forward into its chittering mouth, a bandolier of grenades held in one hand. It is to your surprise, then, when he twists so that only said arm is delivered into its mouth. The resulting explosion shreds both the head and thorax of the creature and sends the marine flying now sans that same arm into a heap nearby, landing atop another pile of scrap, a broken shard of some sort of metal stabbing up and through his ceramite armor to impale him through the stomach.

Then he sits up, grasps the metal spike, and snaps it.

“APOTHECARY!” the marine bellows, more anger than pain in his voice.

Up ahead, there is the sound of a daemonic bellow which echoes so far back that you can hear it, as well as the responding scream of Marcus and all those who he leads. Another blink, another slain beast, bolters booming all around you, and Constantius has returned to your sight, at the side of the marine who you find yourself observing with a fraction of your attention while the rest remains concerned with the battle at hand.

“Brother Ateren,” the apothecary greets, “How may I-,”

“SEAL MY WOUNDS! THE EMPEROR’S FURY REQUIRES YET MORE DELIVERING UNTO THE FOE!”

With but one limb remaining, Ateren is thus dragged into the line, holding a bolter in one hand as he hops forward to find a better position amongst those that bear combat shields and bolters in a quasi-shield wall to prevent more of the enraged abominations from charging into the rear of Marcus’ task force. All the while he screams utter obscenities towards the enemy, besmirching their honor, existence, lack of souls, and appearance in one almost ceaseless stream of hatred.

In point of fact, he is not the only marine that you have paid attention to throughout this fight. For it is true more often than not that in the crucible of battle that many things can be discerned that more ‘peaceful’ observation cannot quite match. For one, this Brother Ateren, of the 1st Company. In another moment, a Brother Caesar who angrily yet quickly managed to stabilize one of his brothers from what would surely have been a crippling injury without any aid from Constantius. Of the 5th Company, one of the newest recruits from Cyrus demonstrated a bolter of higher than average firing rate, something quietly noted to you by Apollo as he bore the noble Rogal’s Fist to punch his way through the enemy with high speed. A moments interrogation mid-fight during one breath from the next brings you the knowledge that he modified it himself, though he paled at the thought of having committed tech-heresy in doing so. Apparently the boy was once a blacksmith’s apprentice on his homeworld before attending the Blood Trials.

Here, now, upon Aerus, you scour your own Chapter for those vital members for filling ranks beyond that of a battle brother. And here, now, upon Aerus, you have found them. These, along with those that Cyrus tells you of, grants a sliver of hope for the future of the Blood Ravens.

“For the Emperor!” the vox crackles once more, and you feel the earth around you tremble as a great many explosives go off, one after another at the site of the daemonforge.

Smoke stacks that forever plumed out acrid smoke whose color changed daily and by the minute begin to crumple in amongst themselves. While the 5th Company held the line, the 1st Company plunged deep into the belly of the most certainly sentient beast that was the daemonforge, and from the sheer amount of explosives you can feel still rippling outward, they succeeded in their course to destroy the thing.

Of course, the issue then, is punching your way back towards the Mechanics lines. Luckily, you have already torn to shreds much of the route that you passed through and shall now pass through once again.

=====================================
[Training With Apollo – Agility From 4 to 5: 419+5+Apollo(29)+(Turn 8/9 Apollo Retroactive of 29+29)=511/600]
[Chapter Training – Toughness: 445+12+Tarkus(25)= 482/600]

The tale of fighting endless waives of mutated and possessed servitors, animalistic machines given unholy life, and more, is one that is proudly enshrined within the annals of the 1st Company. At the same time, the noble holding action of the 5th Company which allowed their brothers to commit all of their strength at once is held with equal regard. All are proud of the work that was done, even at the injuries and casualties taken by very many in the fight. Of them all, only one was reduced to being interred within a dreadnought, but of that there are still injuries aplenty which remain. Your much reduced apothecarium certainly is in dire need of repopulation, and it is now that you focus your efforts upon it.

While you spar and train, the Chapter along with you, much work is done within the hands of your apothecaries. The greatest implantation of all your gene-seed is done, and you find yourself remarkably calm about the fact that you in doing so have removed the vast majority of your remaining gene-seed from being used for any other purpose. It is a dangerous gamble, and yet at the same time you can take heart in the test-slave cloning chambers that you are making access of. While the gene-seed they produce will be unseasoned, for lack of a better word, you know well that the galaxy will happily provide foes for such things to be dealt with by blood and war.

The remainder are equally put once more into the Test-Slaves, another half a decade to pass before harvesting is possible.

=========================================

Martellus quietly chanted to himself as he began to fit the chassis together, each part of the holy vehicle who he had been bid to construct requiring ritual purification and blessings before being fit together. Yet it was something that he was more than glad to partake in. To craft such a vehicle for the service of the Omnissiah, the Emperor, and truly the Imperium as a whole, was not just a duty, it was an honor. And so he continued to go about his work. While his personal affection for the wondrous protection that a few good turrets could create was strong, he could not afford even the slightest of failure when producing this vehicle. Too much was lost thanks to the traitors, and what could not be recovered would have to be rebuilt or built anew entirely.

And so Martellus went about his holy work, finished with his other orders far sooner than any others might have expected.

==================================================

“And this shall be the place where the Blood Trials take place,” Cyrus murmured, pressing a few more buttons into the data-slate before placing it back onto its clip at his side. “Begin the construction,” he swept his hands out, and from behind him the servitors and serfs moved forward.

The world was a strong one, tough. Its population was pure, as near as he could tell, though any who came from here would require of course strong testing by the apothecaries. They could not have passed all this time with a world filled with daemons and tainted by the warp within the same solar system without some taint that even he could not see. Across the world, the 10th Company had already spread out, testing themselves against its brutal and icy environment while observing the denizens of the planet already for potentials to refill the ranks. Some might have accepted laxer standards, but he would not compromise on them.

Never again.

===================

Acquiring information on the nearby Hrud threat is not hard. The Imperial Guard and Navy of the Sector are not quite used to dealing with such a threat in such numbers. Yet they fight well, as far as the reports go. Astropaths carrying discrete communications as you go through what channels you can inform you quite well of the lumbering yet admittedly powerful movements and assaults of the Guard as they land in the infested area. The short lives of thousands of Guardsmen have already been snuffed out not by the uncanny weaponry of the vile xenos but by the strange entropic energies that they carry with them, yet they push on. For a moment you thought that the Blood Ravens might have been required to give aid in some measure or another, but whether by due to the great stain on your honor and reputation that you still carry with you or some other reason, they have instead asked and received the aid of the Order of the Lost Rosetta. With them on the battlefield it is vastly unlikely that your aid would be accepted whatsoever. Nevertheless, the infestation grew strong without much intervention, and if the Imperials and Sisters of Battle should fail or falter, you must be ready to purify the xenos if need be.

006.M42 Into 007.M42 Results:
- 1 Marine of 5th Company interred in dreadnought frame. Brother Nathan. +1 Gene-Seed Recovered/-1 Dreadnought Chassis
- 1st Company Veteran Brother Ateren shows Chaplain Potential, 1st Company Veteran Brother Caesar shows Apothecary Potential, 5th Company Brother Hestior shows Techmarine Potential
- 4 Apothecary-Potential Scout [2nd Stage] located, 1 Techmarine-Potential Scout [2nd Stage] located, No Chaplain Potentials located within Scouts/Neophytes
- 10 1st Company Veterans badly injured. Wounds Healed By Start Of Turn 008.M42
- 20 Scout Marines [1st Stage] advance, 15 to [2nd Stage], Remainder expired. +5 Gene-Seed Recovered
- Psyker Neophytes [2nd Stage] advance to Lexicani x2 within Librarium.
- Psyker Neopytes [1st Stage] advances to [2nd Stage]
- 1 Aerus Daemonforge destroyed.
- 45 Neophytes [1st Stage] implanted with Gene-Seed, allowing advancement to [2nd Stage]. 9 Expire. 4 Neophytes began displaying psyker talents upon full implantation to [2nd] Stage, transforming to Psyker Neophytes [2nd Stage]. -45/+9 Gene-Seed Lost/Recovered.
- 11 Test-Slaves implanted for harvesting at a later date. -11 Gene-Seed. Test-Slave Harvest In 012.M42
- 002.M42 Test-Slave Batch Finishes Gestation! +34 Gene-Seed Acquired, Remainder Failed/Degenerated/Mutated/Etc.
- Brother Tarion, Augustine, Ravias, and Antonius have all completed their Chaplain training. They may now be assigned as you see fit.
- Brother Medici has completed his Apothecary training. He can be assigned as you see fit.

Aerus Warfare Decisions (45% of Aerus Reclaimed/Reclaimed Area rated as Extremis-grade Defenses By Mechanicus/Orbital Drop,Thunderhawk Transport Allowed Within Reclaimed Territory Due To Lack of Daemon-slaved AA Batteries):
[] Patrol the Reclaimed Zone - Is subject to semi-regular ambushes, machine creature infiltrators, mutated creatures appearing through ruined sewers and pipes. Recent aid by way of the numerous turrets of the Chapter's forges being put to use has greatly assisted in this. The 1stMeridian's morale is on the rise, as it can patrol without assured casualties every single hour now. The Mechanicus has been able to work with better ease at restoring the area, building up their own defenses, etc. Marcus is planning to lead half of the 1st Company in a thorough patrol through this area instead of heading out otherwise, due to the casualties that his forces took already. (Write-In Forces)
[] Target An Aerus Daemonforge - One of the tainted manufactorums which continually spill out a mixture of random possessed machinery, horrific cybernetic monstrosities, etc. behind the ‘enemy lines’ which are currently fighting against the streaming hordes of Skitarii. (Write-In Forces)
[] Break Mad Machine Mass, a grouping of insane tanks and armored carriers whose Machine Spirits have gone mad and are traveling as one mass and attacking everyone and everything they can, heading straight for the Skitarii Lines. One that spawned from seemingly nothing deeper within the hostile territory of Aerus is driving ever closer to the Skitarii Lines. (Write-In Forces)
[] Attack Abominable Quasi-Titan – Aerus did not have a Titan Legion on its own, but apparently it’s twisted ghosts are determined to produce their own. Out of daemonflesh, rusted cable, and random scrap and weaponry scattered across the land, are titan-sized creatures crafted by mad machine spirits and corrupted programming. They are rare, but especially dangerous. (Write-In Forces)
[] Join The Lines - The Skitarii are currently in a seemingly endless back and forth with the rest of Aerus. While the penetrating spearhead strikes of the Blood Ravens have prevented the stalemate from falling in the wrong direction, some front-line assistance for properly equipped dreadnoughts and terminators could likely assist the Mechanicus forces in pushing further forward in general. With your own vehicles, and heavy weaponry, this could be made possible. The further the line stretches and expands, the better it will be for all. And at the least, you would not be sending astartes into enemy territory and instead they would be fighting alongside allies. Another half of the 1st Company led by Ares Actus is shifting towards this theater of the battlefield to slay and fight. (Write-In Forces)

Lead Your Chapter (All Technically Available):
[] Further Black Crusade Contributions – Send forces to aid in the Black Crusade, even though Aramus’s presence apparently counts enough for some. (Write-In)
[] Recall Brothers In The Deathwatch
- (Specify In Write-In)
[] Assign one of your new Chaplains to 5th and 10th Company.
[] Shift 1st Company Veteran Brother Ateren into Chaplain training, 1st Company Veteran Brother Caesar into Apothecary training, 5th Company Brother Hestior into Techmarine training.
[] Promote the 4 Apothecary-Potential Scouts [2nd Stage] into Apothecarium training and the 1 Techmarine-Potential Scout [2nd Stage] into Techmarine training.
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Training With Apollo
Select One Of The Below To Train With Apollo’s Aid
[] Weapon Skill
[] Ballistic Skill
[] Agility

Train Your Chapter
The Blood Ravens have lost so many, both fresh blood and veteran. It may aid in the rebuilding of the Chapter for you to work upon them and try to impart the skill and experience that the Blood Ravens of the past once possessed.

[] Select Main Characteristic (1d100+Trainer)
- [] Specify Teacher

[] Select Two Secondary Characteristics (1d50+Trainer Each)
- [] Specify Teacher(s)

Things To Consider – Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
- Remember that Chapter Master Angelos, Chief Librarian Probalis, and Apollo are mighty champions and can be deployed on operations. They need not remain in their ships doing nothing. To have them participate in an operation, it must be specified that they do so.
- You have access to a number of veterans who could impart their knowledge and skills upon your ranks, an especially important thing now that it is likely that many scouts will soon be promoted to full battle brothers. Not just in one way, but more. You have the exceptional battle brothers for it, after all.

Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary (Choose 1):
[] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest in 5 years. Write-In the amount of Gene-Seed you wish to use.
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Nero Gracchus
- The Apothecarium really does need more, well, Apothecaries. The Companies we have should not be without! Especially on Aerus!
- In 112.M42, 22 Gene-Seed should be available from the Test-Slaves.
- Gracchus is currently studying the gene-seed of the Blood Ravens, to perhaps improve survival rates for implantation.

Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (Choose 1):
[] Build Order (250 BP Available)

Things To Consider – Master of the Forge Ravias
- I could use a few more peers in the forges. Or at least subordinates.
- We need a bit of everything when it comes to equipment these days.
- Some of our most constant foes are the most numerous - orks, tyranids, the denizens of Chaos. Further firepower could surely assist, and one of the best examples of this are the Tarantula Turrets.

Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits (Choose 1):
[] Set up Blood Trials upon the world of Junius, to recruit Aspirants so that your Chapter may one day be replenished fully.
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Master of Recruits
- The only thing that can truly help the 10th Company is time, dedicated time, to train your initiates, neophytes, and scouts.

Purge of the Haunted Hills - Nachexen, 2476

Winning vote: [*] Plan Intellectual Arts -[*][Info] Gossipmongers: Hire a number of informers specifically for their ability to pass on saleable information. -[*][Watch] Try to soothe those in the watch upset by recent changes. -[*][Personal] Publish Or Perish, Part 2: With a mindful of trigonometry, it's time to formally record the process for creating 'Bound Spells'. And, optionally, pick a catchier name for it than that. (Optional: Write in name) (NEW) --[*] Name: Mathilde's Matrix --[*] Ranald's Blessing -[*][Personal] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills and internalize the lessons you've learned (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective if you've used the trait a lot lately). Click to expand... Click to shrink... --- Julia receives your instructions with barely-concealed glee and practically skips off to begin the arrangements to expand her network of gossipmongers; Jack is more reserved when you give him his instructions, though you can see the wheels begin turning in his head as he begins to work on a plan. The problem's in his hands now, and in six months you can come back and either harvest the credit for yourself or dump the blame on him. You're starting to understand why so many seek power. With that organized, you secret yourself away in the Buried Palace. You seek no less than to wrest a weapon from the hands of the enemies of mankind and spread it to every Wizard that served Sigmar's Empire, and all around you are the weapons you will use to that end. The dense tomes of dry formulae of the Gold Alchemists, the slim books of metaphor and wordplay from the Celestial Astromancers, transcribed oral tradition from the Jade Druids and the collected snippets of deeply personal wisdom from the Amber Shamans. Even a few scraps from the Amethysts, who you'd regard as secretive if you were from any other Order, and some typically bombastic words on the subject from the Pyromancers of the Bright Order. The only orders to have not chimed in on the subject are the Light, who are more the 'fill it with holy radiance and see what happens' sort, and your own order, and you aim to change the latter. It's rough going. Incredibly so. A dozen times you run into 'I did it this way because it collapsed in on itself if I didn't' and you have to either investigate further or codify the workaround. You're tempted, oh so tempted, to just leave it be, but this is to be your first true contribution to the realm of the Empire's knowledge of magic, and you refuse to give short thrift. So day after day you weave Ulgu again and again, dispelling and reapplying the bindings (the Matrix? 'Mathilde's Matrix' does have a ring to it...) to see how you can and can't anchor the bindings to the inside of the creature - first your test chickens, and then a lamb and a small pig to ensure that the size and species makes no difference, and finally a volunteer from the castle staff who was now enjoying some paid time off to visit their family in exchange for their cooperation. As you expected, species made no difference, only the physical dimensions of the host, but now you knew for sure. And it slightly helped to have a scaled-up host to work with, as it allowed you to measure angles with greater fidelity - if the word fidelity can be used at all, when you hold up a protractor against a pig's stomach and try to measure the angle of a lattice of energy on an entirely separate physical plane. Hundreds of different ways to suspend the energy later, you find a pattern, and test it again and again until you hammer that pattern into a set of rules for how the matrix must be formed. Weeks pass in the spell-lit underground gloom, emerging only to forage for food for yourself and your test subjects and blinking owlishly in the sunlight. You send off for more and more books, until copies of every single tome the College Libraries are willing to share on the topic of magical lattices are surrounding you, and you persevere gamely against each and every one of them. Every wizard has their own view of how magic works, so every book requires the reader to learn a new set of fundamentals to begin to understand what is being said. But the more you read, the more you detect a common thread, perhaps even a harmony underneath it all. You're reminded of a parable of the Blind Man and the Elephant from the Kingdoms of Ind, oft applied to fieldcraft in the lessons of the Grey Order but more relevant now than ever. A group of blind men encounter an elephant, or so the tale goes, and they seek to learn of it. One grasps it by the tail, and exclaims that an elephant is like a snake; another by the leg, and says that an elephant is like a tree-trunk, another finds the elephant's side, and says that an elephant is like a wall, and so on, and they end up quarreling, each insisting the small glimpse they had gotten of the whole was the truth of the matter. You read the books through fresh eyes, seeking not to interpret what each of them are saying into terms you intuitively grasp, but instead accepting them as equally valid glimpses of magic. And it feels very much like you're trying to work out the shape of an elephant from the reports of those blind men, but you soon grasp that there's a finite amount of parts to it - though tragically, it's not limited to the eight traditional Winds. You find it breaking down, more or less, into an axis between two points. On one side, the Elemental, who draw meaning from the physical manifestations that the wind is drawn to - such as those that would see fire as burning. On the other, the Mystical, who deal more in metaphor - those that see fire as passionate, or as cleansing. You consider Ulgu. Taken elementally, it is the interplay between light and dark. Taken mystically, it is the coming of dawn and dusk, of revelation and concealment. You consider your own magical repertoire, and find that you've drawn almost entirely from the latter. Your spells owe little to the elemental nature of Ulgu - no Invisibility or Shadowcloak, for instance. Your spells draw more from the mystical significance of shadows - the sudden plunge into darkness of Mindhole, the tireless advance of the dusk and dawn of Shadowsteed. Both directions are correct, or at least no more incorrect than each other. You emerge from your months of solitude with a greatly deepened understanding of man's relation with magic. But, sadly, not with a completed paper on the subject of Mathilde's Matrix. ...name possibly pending. [Writing the paper: Roll, Learning, 16+17+10 (Ranald's Blessing)=43.] [Improve Learning: Learning, breakpoints 60/90, 79+17=96.] +2 Learning Gained! --- You stumble into Julia's townhouse and start devouring equal parts reports, gossip, and marmalade toast one of the house staff brings you. The 1st Division is on the march to join the rest of the Army on the campaign, and news from said army is all positive - Vanhaldenschlosse was found to be entirely inoffensive, and the divisions separated to clear the largest segment of the Haunted Hills yet. You estimate about a fourth of the Hills have now been cleared; you skim the reports from the Attachés, and find that the undead found have remained largely the same, with a higher proportion of ghouls closer to the Hunger Woods on the northern edge of the Hills. Next stop on the army's agenda is to push on along the Old Road to Nachthafen, home of the only noble of Sylvania to pay even technical fealty to the Elector Count of Stirland, Countess Gabriella von Bundebad, which should prove interesting. What little gossip that flows from Ostermark indicates that they're faring about as well in the Dead Woods as Stirland is in the Haunted Hills, but at least they show no sign of stopping. Even scanter gossip from the mountains tells that Zhufbar has gained the upper hand in the three-way war between subterranean beastmen and besieging greenskins; hopefully that means they'll be able to join in against Sylvania. No news from Averland, as sadly Anton was unable to convince them to contribute to the campaign, occupied as they were with greenskins in their own lands. No other news of note from the rest of the Empire, but then, your ears are mostly internal. --- PLAN FOR THIS PURGE TURN ORGANIZATIONAL ACTIONS - these are LOCKED IN for the next two purge turns, but personal actions can still be spent on them. Spoiler: Organizational Actions Information Network - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [ ] Expand your information network into another province (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into another county or barony (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into the military (choose a Division) [ ] Expand your Intelligence Attaché program to another Division (choose one) [ ] Off the Leash: Let Julia handle the network without your micromanagement from now on. Information Network finances - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above. [ ] Attaché Paperwork: The Intelligence Attachés are your biggest expense by far - see if you can have them paid for by the Army of Stirland instead. [ ] Fixer: Work with the Wurtbad Thieves Guild, supplying them information in exchange for a portion of profits. [ ] Special Branch: Pull some financial trickery to get the information network classified as part of the Watch, so that their costs are covered by the Stirlandian treasury. [ ] Trade Delegation: Convince Wilhelmina and Markus to partner your network with the EIC based on the value of market information. Stirland Watch - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [o] Expand the ranks of the Watch, so that they're able to start covering even the poorer parts of their covered area. (cannot be taken until army retirement resumes in six months) [o] Expand the Watch into a new county or barony (choose which) (cannot be taken until army retirement resumes in six months) [ ] Expand the Special Branch into areas already covered by the Watch, so you have an additional pool of manpower you can call upon to supplement the full-time Watchmen. [ ] Improve the training of the Watch, hiring trainers and dedicating paid time each week to sharpening skills. [ ] Integrate the Roadwarden network of covered areas into the Watch. [ ] Investigate the possibility of adding a River Warden branch of the Watch. [ ] Headhunt administrators from other organizations in Stirland. [ ] Attempt to hire administrators and clerks from Altdorf and Nuln. Stirland Watch finances - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above. [ ] Formalize and organize the payments people make for the Gong Farmers to perform their service, as well as having the Watch start enforcing existing laws against dumping human waste in the street or the Stir. [ ] Currently, solid waste is sent by cart and wagon out to the fields for a pittance. It could instead be used to create market gardens along the banks of the Stir (hopefully downwind) and increase revenue and provide jobs for the desperate by growing a variety of cash crops. [ ] Tanneries have a seemingly limitless demand for urine, which explains a lot about the smell. A bit of fragrant research would allow you to identify how much demand there is and how much of a profit you can wring from this. [ ] In Wissenland, there are a number of techniques in use to derive saltpeter from urine. It would take a great deal more effort than selling to tanneries, but saltpeter could be exported to Nuln for fantastic profit, or used to start gunpowder production in Stirland. --- PERSONAL ACTIONS - CHOOSE BETWEEN TWO AND THREE. ANY CHOSEN BEYOND THE FIRST TWO WILL COME WITH RISKS - PLEASE SPECIFY THE 'ADDITIONAL' TASK: Genießt den Krieg - join the divisions entering Sylvania: [ ] Now that the land is cleared between Stirland proper and Nachthafen, spend some time in the court of the only Sylvanian noble to recognize and be recognized by the Empire, Countess Gabriella von Bundebad. [ ] If you're feeling nosy, Vanhaldenschlosse is apparently free of anything that would object to you poking around in what was once the proud ancestral home of the Van Hals. [ ] Something apparently quite similar to the Purge of the Haunted Hills is going on in Ostermark's southern regions; you could inspect goings-on up there yourself. [ ] Attach yourself to the general staff, so you can be present for anything interesting that might happen and keep a finger on the pulse of the war. [ ] Attach yourself to a specific regiment so you can spend some time in the thick of things. Miscellany: [ ] Hang Out A Shingle: Spymasters don't advertise, but wizards sometimes do. Make an official announcement that there's a wizard in residence, and see who comes out of the woodwork. [ ] Formal Proposal: Your idea for an undead research team was received poorly, but Van Hal is still open to the idea in theory. Write in details: Name, who it is technically a part of (Watch, Witch Hunters, Military, College, none), and whether it reports directly to you (becomes a new Organization you command) or, if not, who it would report to. [ ] Gun Shopping: You're currently using a pistol that was a spare for the pistoliers. Visit Nuln to upgrade. (Choose: dueling pistols for accuracy and range, repeater pistols for weight of fire, dragons for hand shotguns. Choose: whether you will acquire and use two pistols at once or keep one hand free.) [ ] Write up a proposal for Wilhelmina to approve a short-term increase in Discretionary Income, for the duration of the crisis. Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. [ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills and internalize the lessons you've learned (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective if you've used the trait a lot lately). [ ] Tutoring: One of your fellow councillors may be willing to teach you in their chosen field (choose who; can choose which, or you can let them decide). [ ] Really Good Swords: You have achieved proficiency with the Greatsword. Future progress is possible, though it will take more effort to see results. [ ] Combat Training: You're virtually surrounded by armed warriors of various sorts. See if you can convince one to teach you (choose who). [ ] Combat Training, In The Free Market: You haven't made many heavily armed friends yet, but gold is good for that. Go out and buy some training. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. [ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Remixed: You're getting sick of having workmen tramping in and out of your abode. Recruit an entire team and personally oversee them to clear out all of the reachable portions of the Palace-Shrine and be done with it. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: You've finally got the equipment, now you've just got to unpack it all and set up your laboratory. [ ] Filled with Potential: You've got a room cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put there and get started on equipping it. (write in the purpose of the room) Research: [ ] Undead Research: You know the basics, now. Perhaps a great deal of effort will allow you to advance further. [ ] Snooping: Van Hal gave you a key to his Study. It's been a while since he's been in Wurtbad; he probably forgot he did so, and won't remember until he returns. And he didn't specifically say not to poke around and see what you could find. [ ] Shyish-kebabs: The Shyish swords are hideously dangerous as weapons, but fascinating as a subject of study. Try to reverse-engineer the lost enchantments woven into them. [ ] Publish Or Perish, Part 3: You spent a month running into roadblocks; hopefully that means that you got them all and now there's nothing between you and actually writing the damn paper. (NEW) [ ] Qhaysh Juice: Whatever it is, it's dripping out of the box at a steady rate. You've got several gallons of the stuff and it's still coming out. It's got to be good for something. [ ] Qhaysh Skunkworks: It would take careful study to unlock the secrets of the liquid. It would take considerably less time to find out if it can be made to burn, or explode, or do something militarily useful. [ ] There's always room for more shadow spells in your repertoire. Send off to the Grey College for the basics on one of the others and get started on trying to learn it. Influence: [ ] Information Network: Work alongside to Julia to administer the network. Choose another Organizational Action for the Network. [ ] Stirland Watch: Work alongside Jack to administer the Watch. Choose another Organizational Action for the Watch. [ ] Financial Jargon: Everything with the EIC flew right over your head last time. Try again. Succeeding here will mean that you can take a more active hand in the company, adding it to the organizational actions; failing or not attempting means Mathilde will remain a silent partner. [ ] Thieves Guild: It's currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. If it could be expanded under your aegis, it could be a powerful tool. [ ] Biderhof: This village based on woodcutting and agriculture, has adopted you as one of it's own. Maybe you should adopt it as your own, in a literal sense. [ ] Non-Thief Guilds: Wurtbad, like all major cities, is home to a number of guilds. Reach out to them and enforce your will. Relations: [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with one of your fellow councillors or your liege, offering your help in their tasks and generally getting a feel for them (choose one). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: Though you no longer mistrust them, perhaps you should see what your fellow councillors spend their time doing anyway (choose one). [ ] Letters Home: You might be able to wring more information out of your Master, or you might just be able to get news, information and guidance in general from the Grey Order. [o] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (not possible during Purge Turns) --- SEPARATE VOTE: What is to be the name of the bound spell matrix? - Apologies for not having the name vote be separate last time around; towards the end of things I'm itching to just hit the 'submit' button and be done with it and sometimes don't think things through properly. - I've not formalized the rules for attribute advancements but as a general rule of thumb: the higher your base score is, the harder it is to advance, and if you've been using it a lot recently it improves your chances and can unlock the possibility of multiple levels of advancement at once.

Purge of the Haunted Hills - Pflugzeit, 2476

Winning vote: [*][Action] Plan Is Bundebad Good Or Bad -[*][Personal] Now that the land is cleared between Stirland proper and Nachthafen, spend some time in the court of the only Sylvanian noble to recognize and be recognized by the Empire, Countess Gabriella von Bundebad. --[*] Ranald's Blessing -[*][Personal] Publish Or Perish, Part 3: You spent a month running into roadblocks; hopefully that means that you got them all and now there's nothing between you and actually writing the damn paper. (NEW) [*][Name] Mathilde's Mystical Matrix Click to expand... Click to shrink... --- As spring arrives and the armies of Stirland march, you remain underground. You've finally gathered together all the knowledge you require to properly record Mathilde's Mystical Matrix in such a way that it can be shared among all present and future wizards of the Empire. Or so you thought. Weeks pass in a haze of frustration as words emerge like blood squeezed from a stone. The sentences drip out of you like tar from a barrel, describing the ways to anchor a matrix of mystical energy within a living creature. Every trigonometric detail is checked and double-checked and laid down in the correct place. Every single sentence is an effort, and there's more than you could begin to imagine as you find no elegant way to describe what you can picture so easily, and so you have to describe every facet of it individually in agonizing detail, then go even further in the descriptions of how they all connect together. The only thing more painful than writing it is rereading it, except more painful still is trying desperately to edit it into something slightly easier to understand. The end result is, technically, an accurate guide to constructing Mathilde's Mystical Matrix. It's not even misleading. But it is incredibly dry and difficult to grasp and far longer than it has any right to be, and if you have to look at it one more time you might scream and set it on fire. You storm out of your buried palace, summon a horse, and ride at considerable speed for Sylvania. You'd rather face the undead than that bloody paper right now. [Writing the papar again: Learning, Roll, 31+19=50.] --- As you approach the only county in Sylvania to recognize Stirlandian rule, you reflect on the progress of the Purge. It was discovered, at least in part, why the army had met so little resistance in the northwestern Hills; because they were all laying siege to Nachthafen, or at least were encircling it; there was no indication that anything like a guiding mind was directing things, and all that caused the siege was mob mentality, and sometimes not even that. Fresher zombies were preyed upon by ghouls, who were in turn preyed upon by wolves - not, it appears, the undead 'dire wolves', but living giant wolves who loafed around the edges of the siege, shattering the occasional skeleton to gnaw upon its bones and on the lookout for anything close to living for them to fall upon. But the advance of three divisions of the Army of Stirland shattered the siege, some twenty thousand undead were put to the fire and steel as members of five Knightly Orders contemptuously smashed their way to and fro through the ranks of the unguided dead - with nary a spearwall to be seen they were in their element, and accounted for near half the enemy dead themselves. By the time you arrived, the dead had been given their final rites but most were still awaiting the pyres, with wood having to be cut and transported from the Hunger Wood. Everywhere you looked, a local was looking back - not, as far as you could tell, with any ill intent, but with the air of a tiny prey animal who knows very well to watch even the slightest rustle in the undergrowth. Each local was accompanied by small herds of sheep or goats, but these were the most obedient herds you'd ever seen, staying within a few yards of their overseer and following along obediently every time he moved. Nachthafen itself, when you reached it, was no less strange. Not even a quarter the size of Wurtbad in population, it rivalled it in area and beat it in the height of its walls. You had papers to prove your identity, but the guard at the gate, armoured from head to toe in rusted chainmail with only a narrow slit in his coif to peer through, barely glanced at them, instead peering suspiciously at your pupils and then clumsily removing a chainmail mitten to feel the pulse in your wrist and then waving you inside. Inside, you saw that most of the space inside the walls was empty livestock pens, though from the state of things, you easily deduce that all the livestock of the herdsmen outside the walls were kept in here during the siege. The buildings, clustered together around a modest keep, were of sturdy construction and built so that there was no space between them, with no windows at ground level and small shuttered ones above, effectively presenting a second wall inside the first. The streets were mostly empty, with a few street merchants standing by their stalls in silent judgement of a world where nobody buys their stock - their eyes follow you as you pass, each judging whether you could be convinced to buy some sort of severely boiled sheep product and deciding against the attempt. You've been in villages louder than this town, and tombs more welcoming. You arrive at the castle, and this time your papers are given close scrutiny by a man who peers and moves his lips as he struggles his way through the words, though he does check your pulse and pupils as well. He leads you through the gatehouse, through a courtyard smaller than your bedroom, and into a great hall packed with the busy silence of dozens of people silently waiting. A line stretches from the throne and wraps around the wall until the tail folds in on itself in a mob of silent confusion, and the only ones speaking are the peasant at the head of the line, who seems to be deep in some sort of explanation of how something went terribly wrong with goat husbandry, and the pale young woman on the throne wearing clothes only half a decade out of fashion and seemingly engrossed in the conversation. The woman glances up as you approach, and the conversation accelerates to a conclusion; a single golden coin is placed in the peasant's hand, and instructions are given that the hapless goat who seems to have failed in some required task is to be presented to the keep's kitchen. Then the woman on the throne stands, smiles at you, and beckons at you to follow her into a side-room; the peasants lined up make no reaction to this, seemingly content to wait. Since this is Sylvania, and you are not an idiot, the first thing you do is carefully scrutinize the woman with your mage sight as you follow, and are relieved to find that she's no more tainted by Dhar and stained by Shyish than anyone else in Sylvania. She leads you to what appears to be a sunroom built by someone who quite missed the point, with cozy chairs around a small table and packed bookshelves lining the walls and the only sun being a thin, faint beam squeezing its way through an arrow slit. Following her lead, you take a seat across a small table. "So," she says brightly. "The famous Spymistress of Stirland; an honor to meet you in the flesh at last. We have heard so much about you." "And I of you," you reply politely, and she grins. "So, here to take a look at the most far-flung corner of Stirland's demesne?" "And the citizens of the Empire within it," you reply. "I'm glad we were able to lift the siege, though it's quite strange that we knew nothing of it until we arrived." "We're quite used to being an island of civilization in a sea of terror, I'm afraid," she explains vaguely. "By the time it occurred to anyone to send for help, we had already been encircled." "Messenger pigeons?" you suggest, but she's shaking her head before you even finish the words. "That's a boondoggle one only has to sink money into once to learn their lesson. It's the bats, you see. They've got quite an appetite for blood, which tragically extends to that of birds." "So has this sort of thing happened before?" you ask, changing tack. "Impromptu, unguided sieges? Oh, yes. There's some sort of rudimentary herding instinct in them, so every now and then enough accumulate at the walls to start attracting more and from there it just accumulates." "And how do you usually solve it?" "Winter comes eventually; the ghouls and wolves seek shelter and the zombies freeze, while the skeletons are buried in snow. We spend the winter months digging them up one by one and smacking them over the head until they stop moving. Inconvenient when a siege begins in spring, but such is life in Sylvania." Your eyes narrow at her in thought; by all appearances she's younger than you, but she talks with the confidence and experience and world-weariness of a woman with a decade on you. You're sure that Countess Gabriella has ruled here for as long as you've been Spymistress, which must mean she was merely a teenager when she became Countess; not unheard of, and it could explain her acting older than her years, but... But your suspicions must be visible on your face, because her smile suddenly widens. "I know that look," she says suddenly. "It's an 'I'm going to check the records when I get back home and see how long there's been a Countess Gabriella in Nachthafen' sort of look." You stare at her again, both at her person and at the mystical energy flowing within her, and to both she seems absolutely normal. "You get that look a lot?" you manage, shifting in your seat slightly so you could leap to your feet without trouble, if necessary. "Every now and then. Let me spare you some trouble: since just before the turn of the millennium. The nineties were a good time to put down roots." Too obvious. Too obvious. She's giving it away for free. Why? What reaction is she trying to get? Remember your teachings. Game it out. She all but tells you she's a vampire. You... do you attack her? If she knows you by reputation, she has to be at least prepared for the possibility, and you have an enormous sword on your back, for crying out loud. Witnesses? Is she prepared to fend off an attack and then have witnesses tell of your 'unprovoked' assault on her? Otherwise... well, you'd go straight to Van Hal. Van Hal would investigate himself. Is she trying to draw him in for something? To discredit you? To spring a trap on him? Is she even telling the truth about being a vampire? Why would someone lie about that? But then, why would someone be honest about that? Then... do you do nothing? That might be the play. She's revealing this to inspire some sort of reaction in you; to do nothing counters that. It leaves her free to act, but no freer than if she had just said nothing. What's she trying to do? How do you prevent it? She's been watching you as your thoughts race, her smile widening. "Oh, it's so nice to have a thinker in Eagle Castle. The last fellow was so tedious - wouldn't think about what to have for breakfast unless someone was bribing him to do so. Have you found him?" "Hasn't been a priority," you say cautiously. Keep her talking. If she's talking, she's not doing anything else. "Smart. He was a piece, not a player." "And who moved him?" "Anyone with money, of course." She smiles as you stare at her. "You know who one of them was. Everyone with the senses to feel it knows the spell that girl in Drakenhof hurled at you." She tuts, and fussily rearranges her hands in her lap. "So much raw power, so little control. Little wonder she's stark raving mad." "Countess von Carstein," you venture, and she scowls. "So she calls herself. Incorrect on all three counts - if you'll excuse the pun. No more spurious a claim has ever been made, I assure you." "What are your plans in this campaign?" you ask. "Plans? Why would I have plans? The hills are safer for my subjects to graze their herds in, and my neighbour to the east is soon to get a rude visitation they thoroughly deserve. Doing nothing is serving me quite splendidly." You can't think of any other questions to ask; you need to digest what has already been said, or at least hinted at. "If you'll excuse me," you ask politely. "Of course," she says graciously as you rise to your feet; at the door, apparently unsummoned, the man who led you in appears to lead you back out. "This was such fun. Come by again some time. Give my best to Abelhelm," she says, smug as a cat with a full belly. You make your way out, your nerves screaming, but everything is normal. The peasants in the hall continue to wait patiently, the only change being a few more at the end of the line. You soon find yourself back on the streets of Nachthafen, with no more answers and a great deal more questions than when you first arrived. But you'll not let yourself be so easily driven off, though. You linger in the area for a couple of weeks, and find a score of locals willing to pass on information for silver. Chances are at least some of them will be feeding you false information, but one can often derive truths from the lies someone tells. Spoiler: Purge Progress --- PLAN FOR THIS PURGE TURN ORGANIZATIONAL ACTIONS - these are LOCKED IN for the next purge turn, but personal actions can still be spent on them. Spoiler: Organizational Actions Information Network - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [ ] Expand your information network into another province (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into another county or barony (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into the military (choose a Division) [ ] Expand your Intelligence Attaché program to another Division (choose one) [ ] Off the Leash: Let Julia handle the network without your micromanagement from now on. Information Network finances - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above. [ ] Attaché Paperwork: The Intelligence Attachés are your biggest expense by far - see if you can have them paid for by the Army of Stirland instead. [ ] Fixer: Work with the Wurtbad Thieves Guild, supplying them information in exchange for a portion of profits. [ ] Special Branch: Pull some financial trickery to get the information network classified as part of the Watch, so that their costs are covered by the Stirlandian treasury. [ ] Trade Delegation: Convince Wilhelmina and Markus to partner your network with the EIC based on the value of market information. Stirland Watch - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [o] Expand the ranks of the Watch, so that they're able to start covering even the poorer parts of their covered area. (cannot be taken until army retirement resumes in six months) [o] Expand the Watch into a new county or barony (choose which) (cannot be taken until army retirement resumes in six months) [ ] Expand the Special Branch into areas already covered by the Watch, so you have an additional pool of manpower you can call upon to supplement the full-time Watchmen. [ ] Improve the training of the Watch, hiring trainers and dedicating paid time each week to sharpening skills. [ ] Integrate the Roadwarden network of covered areas into the Watch. [ ] Investigate the possibility of adding a River Warden branch of the Watch. [ ] Headhunt administrators from other organizations in Stirland. [ ] Attempt to hire administrators and clerks from Altdorf and Nuln. Stirland Watch finances - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above. [ ] Formalize and organize the payments people make for the Gong Farmers to perform their service, as well as having the Watch start enforcing existing laws against dumping human waste in the street or the Stir. [ ] Currently, solid waste is sent by cart and wagon out to the fields for a pittance. It could instead be used to create market gardens along the banks of the Stir (hopefully downwind) and increase revenue and provide jobs for the desperate by growing a variety of cash crops. [ ] Tanneries have a seemingly limitless demand for urine, which explains a lot about the smell. A bit of fragrant research would allow you to identify how much demand there is and how much of a profit you can wring from this. [ ] In Wissenland, there are a number of techniques in use to derive saltpeter from urine. It would take a great deal more effort than selling to tanneries, but saltpeter could be exported to Nuln for fantastic profit, or used to start gunpowder production in Stirland. --- PERSONAL ACTIONS - CHOOSE BETWEEN TWO AND THREE. ANY CHOSEN BEYOND THE FIRST TWO WILL COME WITH RISKS - PLEASE SPECIFY THE 'ADDITIONAL' TASK: Spoiler: Personal Actions Genießt den Krieg - join the divisions entering Sylvania: [ ] Countess Gabriella von Bundebad implied quite a lot, and in such a way that it's clear she's trying to needle you into action. But you don't know what. If inaction isn't the correct move, what is? (write in; may take an action) (NEW) [ ] If you're feeling nosy, Vanhaldenschlosse is apparently free of anything that would object to you poking around in what was once the proud ancestral home of the Van Hals. [ ] Something apparently quite similar to the Purge of the Haunted Hills is going on in Ostermark's southern regions; you could inspect goings-on up there yourself. [ ] Attach yourself to the general staff, so you can be present for anything interesting that might happen and keep a finger on the pulse of the war. [ ] Attach yourself to a specific regiment so you can spend some time in the thick of things. That Bloody Paper: (NEW) [ ] Sod it. Submit the paper as it is now, and let whoever may be interested slog their way through a few hundred pages of densely-packed trigonometric formulae. (does not take an action) [ ] Send it off to our Master and ask that he passes it on to someone with the skills to distil it into something resembling elegance; though it will mean that they will get co-author status, and may fight you on the name. (does not take an action) [ ] Throw yourself back into reclusion and goddamn stay there until the job is bloody well done. (takes two actions) [ ] Wurtbad was once famous for hospitality, and it still has a wonderful selection of high-class inns with actual hot running water. Book yourself into the Golden Eagle Inn and allow yourself to be pampered in the hopes that it will let the words flow. (costs personal funds) [ ] Get atop your horse, find a place rich in Ulgu, and play hermit for a month while hoping that the energies you're so familiar with will inspire you. (???) Miscellany: [ ] Hang Out A Shingle: Spymasters don't advertise, but wizards sometimes do. Make an official announcement that there's a wizard in residence, and see who comes out of the woodwork. [ ] Formal Proposal: Your idea for an undead research team was received poorly, but Van Hal is still open to the idea in theory. Write in details: Name, who it is technically a part of (Watch, Witch Hunters, Military, College, none), and whether it reports directly to you (becomes a new Organization you command) or, if not, who it would report to. [ ] Gun Shopping: You're currently using a pistol that was a spare for the pistoliers. Visit Nuln to upgrade. (Choose: dueling pistols for accuracy and range, repeater pistols for weight of fire, dragons for hand shotguns. Choose: whether you will acquire and use two pistols at once or keep one hand free.) [ ] Write up a proposal for Wilhelmina to approve a short-term increase in Discretionary Income, for the duration of the crisis. Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. [ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills and internalize the lessons you've learned (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective if you've used the trait a lot lately). [ ] Tutoring: One of your fellow councillors may be willing to teach you in their chosen field (choose who; can choose which, or you can let them decide). [ ] Really Good Swords: You have achieved proficiency with the Greatsword. Future progress is possible, though it will take more effort to see results. [ ] Combat Training: You're virtually surrounded by armed warriors of various sorts. See if you can convince one to teach you (choose who). [ ] Combat Training, In The Free Market: You haven't made many heavily armed friends yet, but gold is good for that. Go out and buy some training. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. [ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Remixed: You're getting sick of having workmen tramping in and out of your abode. Recruit an entire team and personally oversee them to clear out all of the reachable portions of the Palace-Shrine and be done with it. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: You've finally got the equipment, now you've just got to unpack it all and set up your laboratory. [ ] Filled with Potential: You've got a room cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put there and get started on equipping it. (write in the purpose of the room) Research: [ ] Undead Research: You know the basics, now. Perhaps a great deal of effort will allow you to advance further. [ ] Snooping: Van Hal gave you a key to his Study. It's been a while since he's been in Wurtbad; he probably forgot he did so, and won't remember until he returns. And he didn't specifically say not to poke around and see what you could find. [ ] Shyish-kebabs: The Shyish swords are hideously dangerous as weapons, but fascinating as a subject of study. Try to reverse-engineer the lost enchantments woven into them. [ ] Qhaysh Juice: Whatever it is, it's dripping out of the box at a steady rate. You've got several gallons of the stuff and it's still coming out. It's got to be good for something. [ ] Qhaysh Skunkworks: It would take careful study to unlock the secrets of the liquid. It would take considerably less time to find out if it can be made to burn, or explode, or do something militarily useful. [ ] There's always room for more shadow spells in your repertoire. Send off to the Grey College for the basics on one of the others and get started on trying to learn it. Influence: [ ] Information Network: Work alongside to Julia to administer the network. Choose another Organizational Action for the Network. [ ] Stirland Watch: Work alongside Jack to administer the Watch. Choose another Organizational Action for the Watch. [ ] Financial Jargon: Everything with the EIC flew right over your head last time. Try again. Succeeding here will mean that you can take a more active hand in the company, adding it to the organizational actions; failing or not attempting means Mathilde will remain a silent partner. [ ] Thieves Guild: It's currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. If it could be expanded under your aegis, it could be a powerful tool. [ ] Biderhof: This village based on woodcutting and agriculture, has adopted you as one of it's own. Maybe you should adopt it as your own, in a literal sense. [ ] Non-Thief Guilds: Wurtbad, like all major cities, is home to a number of guilds. Reach out to them and enforce your will. Relations: [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with one of your fellow councillors, your liege, or any of the other important figures you've come to know, offering your help in their tasks and generally getting a feel for them (choose one). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: Trust, but verify. Spend some of your time seeing what a certain person spends their time doing (choose one). [ ] Letters Home: You might be able to wring more information out of your Master, or you might just be able to get news, information and guidance in general from the Grey Order. [o] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (not possible during Purge Turns) - Something to keep in mind: I only show a roll when it's obvious that a roll is being made, and obvious what the results are. That there is a roll at all can reveal a lot in the meta sense, as can the difficulty of the roll, and the modifiers opposing it, and how well the results line up with the roll; and often what would be revealed is information you have no access to in character, so I err on the side of not showing those rolls. In this case, one of those 'hidden' rolls used your Blessing, I didn't forget it (this time). - For the write-in for Countess Gabriella, simply telling someone won't take an action, but performing an in-depth investigation will; if in doubt, ask, and don't try to get cheeky with how much you can achieve without 'counting' as an action.

Purge of the Haunted Hills - Sommerzeit, 2476

Spoiler: Winning Vote [*] Plan Wait and Listen -[*] Countess Gabriella von Bundebad implied quite a lot, and in such a way that it's clear she's trying to needle you into action. But you don't know what. If inaction isn't the correct move, what is? (write in; may take an action) (NEW) --[*] Write in: Tell Van Hal about the conversation. Advise that, as the situation is apparently stable and we have ears in the city, it can probably wait until the purge is done and we have time to investigate properly. -[*] Wurtbad was once famous for hospitality, and it still has a wonderful selection of high-class inns with actual hot running water. Book yourself into the Golden Eagle Inn and allow yourself to be pampered in the hopes that it will let the words flow. (costs personal funds) [*] Get atop your horse, find a place rich in Ulgu, and play hermit for a month while hoping that the energies you're so familiar with will inspire you. (???) --[*] Ranald's Blessing Sometimes, you feel the burden of your allegiances as a physical weight upon your shoulders. The allegiances of a wizard are lain down in stone in the Articles of Imperial Magic. To the Empire and the Emperor, first and foremost - easy enough. Next, theoretically, to the Supreme Patriarch, but you've yet to have any allegiance to any Supreme Patriarch play a part in your life. Then to the laws and ideals of the Grey Order, which, well... you've always cleaved closer to the ideals than the letter of the actual laws. Then to the Patriarch, which might become relevant one day should you learn who the Patriarch actually is. Then to the 'authorities you serve in the course of your duties': to wit, Van Hal. And, finally other superiors within the Grey Order - most specifically, your Master. Then, either parallel or subordinate to those, are your loyalties as Spymistress, as a Knight, as a citizen of the Empire, and as a person. You owe Van Hal your fealty at least five times over. But none of them, you eventually conclude, supersedes your duty to the Colleges. --- In the scant privacy of a tent pitched outside the walls of Nachthafen, Van Hal nods as you give your report on the Countess. "It fits what we know - 'we' being the Witch Hunters. She's been under suspicion for quite some time, but by chance or artifice she's always been far down the list of priorities. It's not like there's any shortage of targets in Sylvania." "So do you think she's a vampire?" He waves a hand vaguely. "Impossible to say. The possible reasons for her lying are as devious as those for revealing the truth. Whatever she is, she's cooperating, and said cooperation cuts half a year of our timetable for marching on Drakenhof." "Lesser evil," you note. "Very much so. I'd like to know exactly what kind of evil she is, but either she keeps playing along and lends her aid to the destruction of Drakenhof or she plays her hand when I've got forty thousand men and fourteen hundred knights at my back. Both possibilities bode well for Stirland." He turns to you, raising a questioning eyebrow. "Though if you've got a better course of action in mind, I'm open to suggestion." You've got ideas. A lot of ideas. A dozen different ways to burrow into Nachthafen and start watching for whatever may be rotting at its heart leap to mind immediately, and more would appear with thought. But all would take time, and effort, and attention that is needed elsewhere. So instead you open your mouth and say, "the situation is apparently stable, and we have ears in the city. Whatever she is, she can wait until the Purge is done and we have time to investigate properly." He nods, not questioning it for a second and already turning back to the map of the hills he was studying when you came in. You feel something twist in your stomach at the trust he has in you. "If all goes well, in three to four months I will call a final council meeting before the advance on Castle Drakenhof. Until then, continue as you have been." Within the minute, you've summoned your horse and are on your way back to Wurtbad. --- In a city filled with quality inns, the Golden Eagle Inn stands far above the rest. They claim to have served visiting dignitaries in the time of Emperor Dieter IV and his forebears, and that they haven't dropped a notch in standards since, and you believe them. The beds are soft and clean and the option exists for breakfast to be served in them. There's a tangle of metal pipes to deliver hot water to the room for use with the brass tub tucked into a corner, as well as hot spring baths around the back should one prefer. The food is straightforward, no Halfling nonsense or Bretonnian pretension to be found, just quality meat cooked to perfection and served with fresh bread and plentiful gravy, and seconds are always available should they be desired. The servants are always at hand when desired and never to be seen when not. By your third day there, you're starting to wonder if you can fit an indefinite stay into your budget. Each morning, you rise early and take your notes and a breakfast with you to a tower on the walls, where the coming dawn illuminates the mists rolling over the trees and lapping at the base of the walls like waves against the shore. Every time frustration rises in you, you lift your head and take in the sight of a world awash in Ulgu and are able to find some measure of peace once more. As the sun rises in the sky you return to the Inn, where you continue your revisions in the comfortable quiet of the reading room, the only sound being the crackle of the fire and the soft noises of paper and parchment as the other guests turn pages or roll scrolls. Then you return to the walls, this time on the opposite side of Wurtbad, and watch the sun fall below the horizon, and return to the Inn in time for supper. If it weren't for what you were doing, this may be the most idyllic period of your life to date. As it is, it's a counterweight keeping your mood from plummeting as every day you chip away at the opacity of your past words, hoping to reveal the shape of elegant truth within. Weeks pass. Spring turns to summer. Dawn comes ealier and dusk later every day, and just as eternal as the sun is the task at hand. You have to think hard to remember that anything but this damnable paper still exists. But progress is made, paragraph by agonizing paragraph. When you finally lift your pen for the final time, you feel both empty and free. The end result is... you ache to call it outstanding. Or elegant. Or any sort of word to justify the amount of time spent, to match the profundity of the dawn and dusk you witnessed every day for two months. But it's... it's competent. It's readable, it's understandable, it's legible, and all sorts of things ending in -ble. It's... it's stolid. It's a medium for communicating the structure and creation of Mathilde's Mystical Matrix and it does exactly that, and no more. The only thing that hurts more than the unexceptionalness of the paper you've produced is the idea of spending another minute on it. [Appreciating Ulgu: 28+19+10(Ranald's Blessing)=57] [Time at the Golden Eagle Inn: 52+19=71] --- You meet with your two lieutenants in a conference room in Julia's townhouse, over a highly annotated map of Greater Stirland. Their reports to you are short and to the point. Jack has mollified the worst of the grumblers, and though the mood of the Watch's long-term veterans is no better than it was they've been convinced to wait and see rather than reflexively pining for the nostalgia-tinted past. Julia's news is less positive: her attempts to expand the Network to start soaking up saleable information went terribly, and badly-needed funds vanished into Flensburgian society like stones thrown into a bog. You're not sure whether Julia was outmanoeuvred, got unlucky, or is just unsuited for this facet of her role, but at least she pulls no punches in her evaluation of how badly it went. Julia also passes on information from the front lines: the central Hills proved to be as terrible as Van Hal had feared. The army stumbled into a vast natural valley within the Hills that proved to be the home of innumerable ghouls led by what the troops are calling the Singing King: an enormously muscled vampire mounted atop some sort of hideous dragon-bat that directed his gathered horde with long, wordless cries. The fighting was long and bloody, and near a fifth of the army are now dead, wounded, or otherwise out of action - including Gustav's Pistoliers, whose horses were driven wild by the singing of the Ghoul King, and ended up bucking their riders and escaping into the questionable safety of the Hills. In the end the back of the ghoulish army was broken and the majority of the creatures were ridden down by the Knights as they tried to flee along ancient dirt roads weaving through the hills towards the Ghoul Wood. Their King, however, remains at large - though without a mount, as Deathfang apparently took umbrage at a counterfeit dragon sharing a battlefield with him. In a grim silver lining, Jack notes, the massive amount of those retired from the Army due to injuries are filling the ranks of the Watch nicely. News from the other two 'fronts' are better. Ostermark's progress continues, advancing slowly but steadily through the Dead Wood. The first of their troops have reached the dead city of Mordheim, and have reported chasing off small numbers of beastmen calling the city home. Down south, Zhufbar has finally broken their twin sieges, and greenskins are flooding out of the mountains pursued by the Throng of Zhufbar, seeking shelter in the greenskin shelter of Fang Island... deep within Ghoul Wood. Grins are shared over the table as the image of a greenskin army running headfirst into a ghoulish one fills your heads. In other news, tensions are higher than ever in the Hochschild household as Wilhelmina chooses keeping the army amply supplied over outrageous profits; the EIC is currently operating practically at cost, to the protest of absolutely none of its shareholders. There'll be time enough for profit after the war is over, the three of you feel - but Wilhelmina's sons definitely do not feel the same way. Further afield, Van Hal apparently gave Anton a discretionary budget again. Anton, it seems, mentioned to the Master Engineers of Nuln that Van Hal was going to kill the infamous Castle Drakenhof, but due to lack of cannon and powder he was going to have to do so with catapults. The thought of such a magnificent feat being accomplished in such a Bretonnian way went against everything the Imperial Gunnery School stood for, and now two score cannon were travelling up the river Aver to Sylvania, with all but the down payment still outstanding on them. All in all, though the Army of Stirland has lost eight thousand of its number and the pistoliers have been turned into infantrymen, the war seems to be going well. Spoiler: Campaign Map --- VOTE: Do you submit the paper as it exists now? [ ] Yes. Don't be unrealistic. The paper communicates the concept and construction of Mathilde's Mystical Matrix without inducing unconsciousness or migraines. That's a win. Take the win. Paper is sent to Altdorf to be published, gain trait: Practical - Long exposure to scholarship has given her an appreciation for literally everything else. +1 Diplomacy, +1 Stewardship, +1 Martial, +1 Intrigue, -1 Learning. [ ] No. Mathilde's Mystical Matrix is worthy of a paper of sublime profundity, that communicates the earthshaking possibilities of the spell with elegance. Continue work on paper, ???. --- PLAN FOR THIS PURGE TURN ORGANIZATIONAL ACTIONS - new ones to be chosen now; these will be LOCKED IN for the next three purge turns. Spoiler: Organizational Actions Information Network - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [ ] Expand your information network into another province (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into another county or barony (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into the military (choose a Division) [ ] Expand your Intelligence Attaché program to another Division (choose one) [ ] Off the Leash: Let Julia handle the network without your micromanagement from now on. Information Network finances - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above. [ ] Gossipmongers: Julia's previous attempt had no result but the enrichment of various hangers-on of the Flensburg courts. Perhaps this was just poor luck; perhaps she should try again. (NEW-ish) [ ] Attaché Paperwork: The Intelligence Attachés are your biggest expense by far - see if you can have them paid for by the Army of Stirland instead. [ ] Fixer: Work with the Wurtbad Thieves Guild, supplying them information in exchange for a portion of profits. [ ] Special Branch: Pull some financial trickery to get the information network classified as part of the Watch, so that their costs are covered by the Stirlandian treasury. [ ] Trade Delegation: Convince Wilhelmina and Markus to partner your network with the EIC based on the value of market information. Stirland Watch - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [ ] Expand the ranks of the Watch, so that they're able to start covering even the poorer parts of their covered area. [ ] Expand the Watch into a new county or barony (choose which) [ ] Expand the Special Branch into areas already covered by the Watch, so you have an additional pool of manpower you can call upon to supplement the full-time Watchmen. [ ] Improve the training of the Watch, hiring trainers and dedicating paid time each week to sharpening skills. [ ] Integrate the Roadwarden network of covered areas into the Watch. [ ] Investigate the possibility of adding a River Warden branch of the Watch. [ ] Headhunt administrators from other organizations in Stirland. [ ] Attempt to hire administrators and clerks from Altdorf and Nuln. Stirland Watch finances - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above. [ ] Formalize and organize the payments people make for the Gong Farmers to perform their service, as well as having the Watch start enforcing existing laws against dumping human waste in the street or the Stir. [ ] Currently, solid waste is sent by cart and wagon out to the fields for a pittance. It could instead be used to create market gardens along the banks of the Stir (hopefully downwind) and increase revenue and provide jobs for the desperate by growing a variety of cash crops. [ ] Tanneries have a seemingly limitless demand for urine, which explains a lot about the smell. A bit of fragrant research would allow you to identify how much demand there is and how much of a profit you can wring from this. [ ] In Wissenland, there are a number of techniques in use to derive saltpeter from urine. It would take a great deal more effort than selling to tanneries, but saltpeter could be exported to Nuln for fantastic profit, or used to start gunpowder production in Stirland. --- PERSONAL ACTIONS - CHOOSE BETWEEN TWO AND THREE. ANY CHOSEN BEYOND THE FIRST TWO WILL COME WITH RISKS - PLEASE SPECIFY THE 'ADDITIONAL' TASK: Spoiler: Personal Actions Genießt den Krieg - join the divisions entering Sylvania: [ ] If you're feeling nosy, Vanhaldenschlosse is apparently free of anything that would object to you poking around in what was once the proud ancestral home of the Van Hals. [ ] Something apparently quite similar to the Purge of the Haunted Hills is going on in Ostermark's southern regions; you could inspect goings-on up there yourself. [ ] The Dwarves have crossed into the Empire, pursuing the greenskins into the woods. Perhaps you could tag along. (NEW) [ ] Attach yourself to the army so you can join the hunt for the Singing King (specify which regiment to join, or general staff to avoid the thick of the fighting). (NEW-ish) That Bloody Paper: (If further revision was chosen) [ ] Send it off to our Master and ask that he passes it on to someone with the skills to distil it into greater elegance; though it will mean that they will get co-author status, and may fight you on the name. (does not take an action) [ ] Throw yourself back into reclusion and goddamn stay there until the job is bloody well done. (takes two actions) [ ] Spend some more time in the Golden Eagle Inn. It's such a lovely place, there's plenty of room. (costs personal funds) [ ] The watchtowers on the walls was an uninspired choice for watching the Ulgu in the world, perhaps you can think of something different. (???) Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. [ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills and internalize the lessons you've learned (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective if you've used the trait a lot lately). [ ] Tutoring: One of your fellow councillors may be willing to teach you in their chosen field (choose who; can choose which, or you can let them decide). [ ] Really Good Swords: You have achieved proficiency with the Greatsword. Future progress is possible, though it will take more effort to see results. [ ] Combat Training: You're virtually surrounded by armed warriors of various sorts. See if you can convince one to teach you (choose who). [ ] Combat Training, In The Free Market: You haven't made many heavily armed friends yet, but gold is good for that. Go out and buy some training. (-personal gold) [ ] Gun Shopping: You're currently using a pistol that was a spare for the pistoliers. Visit Nuln to upgrade. (Choose: dueling pistols for accuracy and range, repeater pistols for weight of fire, dragons for hand shotguns. Choose: whether you will acquire and use two pistols at once or keep one hand free.) [ ] Enchantment: You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. [ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Remixed: You're getting sick of having workmen tramping in and out of your abode. Recruit an entire team and personally oversee them to clear out all of the reachable portions of the Palace-Shrine and be done with it. (-personal gold) [ ] Enchantment: You've finally got the equipment, now you've just got to unpack it all and set up your laboratory. [ ] Filled with Potential: You've got a room cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put there and get started on equipping it. (write in the purpose of the room) Research: [ ] Undead Research: You know the basics, now. Perhaps a great deal of effort will allow you to advance further. [ ] Snooping: Van Hal gave you a key to his Study. It's been a while since he's been in Wurtbad; he probably forgot he did so, and won't remember until he returns. And he didn't specifically say not to poke around and see what you could find. [ ] Shyish-kebabs: The Shyish swords are hideously dangerous as weapons, but fascinating as a subject of study. Try to reverse-engineer the lost enchantments woven into them. [ ] Qhaysh Juice: Whatever it is, it's dripping out of the box at a steady rate. You've got several gallons of the stuff and it's still coming out. It's got to be good for something. [ ] Qhaysh Skunkworks: It would take careful study to unlock the secrets of the liquid. It would take considerably less time to find out if it can be made to burn, or explode, or do something militarily useful. [ ] There's always room for more shadow spells in your repertoire. Send off to the Grey College for the basics on one of the others and get started on trying to learn it. Influence: [ ] Information Network: Work alongside to Julia to administer the network. Choose another Organizational Action for the Network. [ ] Stirland Watch: Work alongside Jack to administer the Watch. Choose another Organizational Action for the Watch. [ ] Financial Jargon: Everything with the EIC flew right over your head last time. Try again. Succeeding here will mean that you can take a more active hand in the company, adding it to the organizational actions; failing or not attempting means Mathilde will remain a silent partner. [ ] Thieves Guild: It's currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. If it could be expanded under your aegis, it could be a powerful tool. [ ] Biderhof: This village based on woodcutting and agriculture, has adopted you as one of it's own. Maybe you should adopt it as your own, in a literal sense. [ ] Non-Thief Guilds: Wurtbad, like all major cities, is home to a number of guilds. Reach out to them and enforce your will. Relations: [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with one of your fellow councillors, your liege, or any of the other important figures you've come to know, offering your help in their tasks and generally getting a feel for them (choose one). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: Trust, but verify. Spend some of your time seeing what a certain person spends their time doing (choose one). [ ] Letters Home: You might be able to wring more information out of your Master, or you might just be able to get news, information and guidance in general from the Grey Order. [o] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (not possible during Purge Turns) --- Discretionary Income: +200g Information Brokerage: +40g Regional informants: -90g Watch informants: -10g EIC informants: -20g Julia: -30g Townhouse staff: -20g Attaché program: -120g Attempted expansion: -50g --- Net: -100g Personal Income: +50g Estate Profit: +10g Tithe: -6g Student Loans: -35g Golden Eagle Inn stay: -20g --- Net: -1g --- - Mathilde's time spent working on the paper has twisted her perception of things. As it exists now, it is a perfectly acceptable means of communicating Mathilde's Mystical Matrix, and a solid foundation for a Magisterial bid. What it isn't, thanks to your uncharacteristically mediocre rolls, is the source of the amazing mystical trait I know that some of you are hoping for. - Note that the paper vote is separate to the plan vote. - The perils of subordinates: you can't see Julia's dice or full charsheet, so you can't see for sure whether she just glitched the roll, whether there's traits that make it a poor fit for her, or whether there's something untoward going on. - Don't forget Ranald's Blessing. - Currently it seems like the Purge will last another six months before the final assault on Castle Drakenhof (which I've been using interchangeably with just Drakenhof, though they're two different albeit nearby places - sorry about that). Your accumulated discretionary funds can just last that long with no additional spending, but if it goes even a single Purge Turn longer than that you'll be in the negatives; if the Purge is still going when your budget is about to hit zero you'll be given the option of accumulating debt (which is acceptable, though hardly ideal, under wartime conditions) or the emergency measures you can take to plump your finances.

Purge of the Haunted Hills - Nachgeheim, 2476

Spoiler: Voting results [X] Yes. Don't be unrealistic. The paper communicates the concept and construction of Mathilde's Mystical Matrix without inducing unconsciousness or migraines. That's a win. Take the win.3 [X] Plan Singing King Hunt + Enchantment -[X][Intel] Gossipmongers: Julia's previous attempt had no result but the enrichment of various hangers-on of the Flensburg courts. Perhaps this was just poor luck; perhaps she should try again. (NEW-ish) -[X][Watch] In Wissenland, there are a number of techniques in use to derive saltpeter from urine. It would take a great deal more effort than selling to tanneries, but saltpeter could be exported to Nuln for fantastic profit, or used to start gunpowder production in Stirland. -[X][Personal] Attach yourself to the army so you can join the hunt for the Singing King (specify which regiment to join, or general staff to avoid the thick of the fighting). (NEW-ish) --[X] General Staff --[X] Ranald's Blessing -[X][Personal] Enchantment: You've finally got the equipment, now you've just got to unpack it all and set up your laboratory. You agonize for hours over the decision, balanced almost exactly between practicality and perfection, but in the end practicality and the burning desire to be done with it win out. As the copy of your paper makes its way to Altdorf, you feel an almost physical weight lift from your shoulders. It's done; Mathilde's Mystical Matrix has been unleashed upon an unexpecting world. And if anyone overlooks it because the paper itself is merely good instead of amazing, then more fool they. Julia's been ordered to try to expand her gossipmonger network once more, while Jack is to look into producing saltpeter in industrial quantities from all the waste the gong farmers are collecting. You're not sure how suited he'll turn out to be for that sort of task, or how well the already-disgruntled watchmen will take it, but you suppose there's only one way to find out. You know that the Army of Stirland is going to be advancing on the woods where the Singing King has fled to with his court only after clearing the hills between the valley and the woods, so you've time to finally set up the enchantment equipment you spent so long searching for. Box after box of delicate glass and crystal components are unpacked from the straw that cushioned them for their journey to Wurtbad, and has been mouldering ever since. You're forced to gently transfer a mother cat and her kittens from the nest she had made among your crystal lenses, and she glares at you sullenly as you work from her new home in an emptied box the entire time. One unversed in the strange and subtle art of enchantment may think that this work could be completed in an afternoon, but they'd be very thoroughly convinced otherwise the first time their sloppy work exploded in their face. Prisms need to be angled exactly correctly to concentrate light at the correct angles - and natural light, too, since magical light would taint whatever you were trying to work with. Which means finding a source of high-quality candles - beeswax is the only local source, but oils found in certain trees in the Southlands or carved out of enormous creatures found in the seas were even better. And for times when no artificial light was suited, a series of mirrors needed to be set up to reflect sunlight into the laboratory, which also need careful measuring, and to be solidly fixed in place so the damn cats can't knock them out of alignment. Also necessary is to track down local sources for a whole range of substances standing on the intersection between chemistry and alchemy, necessary not for their action on physical matter but on how they can alter a substance to be better able to play host to the winds of magic. One could, through effort or skill, force the winds into any item, but it is far easier to first make an item a slightly less unnatural home for it. For those useful substances you can't find local sources for, you send off to Altdorf for the processes for creating them from more-common ingredients. A thousand little preparations that combine to take the onerous task of forcing winds into an inanimate object from nigh impossible down to merely very difficult. You hope you find the time to make the effort worth it. --- When you're finally done in Wurtbad and make your way to join the army, they're in the final stretch of their advance towards the Ghoul Woods. Van Hal glances up from the map of the hills he's poring over to greet you with a smile as you join him in his command tent, and Gustav and Kasmir give you nods, but the generals ignore you in favour of the map. "We ignore the dirt road the ghouls were using," Van Hal is saying. "The ghouls may be mindless creatures, but it's a fatal trap to think the same of the Strigoi ruling them, and even without him they have the animal cunning to set an ambush. Especially since our scouting force is no longer effective as such. Speaking of-" he glances over to Gustav. "They should be remounted in time for the march on Drakenhof," he reports. There's a near-permanent scowl on his face recently - he didn't take his pet cohorts being turned into pedestrians well at all. "That's something, at least," Van Hal notes distractedly. "So we push along the hills, as we have been doing all this time. It's slower but we can't afford many more losses, and the ghouls aren't going anywhere. The Aver has them hemmed in from the south and the west and the Throng of Zhufbar is advancing into the woods from the east." "The men are briefed," one of the generals comments. "They're prepared for whatever they face, whether it be ghoul or greenskin." "Let us hope so," Van Hal murmurs. "We've had ample practice in coordinated sweeps through difficult terrain, the only difference is this time it's forest instead of hills. We push forward on a wide front until we meet serious resistance and then we draw in to crush it, just as we've done a hundred times over by now." Gustav and the generals salute and hurry off to put the orders into action, leaving you with Van Hal and Kasmir. "Strigoi," he says. "Given the option, there's no type of vampire I'd rather fight. No politics, no plots, no hiding. Just the terrible monster they all are, visible for any to see." "It could have lurked in these hills for generations," Kasmir notes. "Feeding on wildlife and the innumerable dead of Sylvania. Until its vile court grew to where the Hills couldn't sustain it, and then they would have burst forth upon Southern Stirland." "A stroke of luck we caught it now, I suppose," Van Hal says, though he doesn't sound convinced, and you can understand why. A heavy price has already been paid, and the Singing King isn't even slain. --- Days of feverish activity pass, with Van Hal at the middle of it all like a particularly restless spider in a web. Forty thousand men - well, closer to thirty now - reporting to him, and he needs only speak to Gustav. Gustav speaks to the four generals, the generals speak to their four colonels apiece. Each colonel has five majors, each major five captains, each captain four lieutenants, and then sergeants and corporals manage individual squads. An operation of tens of thousands and not a single officer is directly responsible for more than a half-dozen men. You make mental notes at the masterpiece of delegation that is the modern army as the machine ticks away frantically in front of you. Information flows in, orders flow out, and paperwork accumulates. Some confused lieutenants have taken to filling in the contact reports for the greenskins they face, which... well, no reason to discourage that, you suppose - it can be filtered out later, or you could just add it to the enormous archive of information back in Wurtbad. Also accumulating are casualties, as there appear to be more enemies to face in the Ghoul Woods than there was in the entirety of the Hills that have been swept to date. Every yard is purchased in blood, whether it be that of human, ghoul, or greenskin, and with every casualty report Van Hal's temper shortens. Then, finally, the wretched singing is found once more, and the army closes on it like the steel jaws of a trap. Van Hal races to join the front, with you and Kasmir at his side, and when you all arrive you're presented with the sight of the Singing King's new court: Fang Island, a ramshackle greenskin fortress construction of wood and bone formed to resemble a massive set of jaws emerging from the ground. And now it looked as if someone had given those jaws a few solid blows, as one side of the fortress had been demolished, with greenskin corpses littered around showing where they fought to the last in the defence of their stronghold against an endless tide of hunger-crazed ghouls, which even now were swarming the fortress like ants from a kicked hive, stripping the flesh from the fallen. "He's within, I'm sure of it," Gustav reports as he hurries up. "I caught a glimpse of him through my spy-glass." "Then we flush him out," Van Hal replies shortly. "Where are the cannon?" The four of you look around for Schultz, who has been handling logistics, but he's nowhere to be found - the sudden concentration of forces had been a confusing mess, and a great deal of the strength Stirland had brought to bear was still scattered across the Woods - including, unfortunately, Asarnil. "No matter. Bring the crossbowmen together and start firing volleys into the fortress. Either they emerge and face us, or they don't and die in droves. Gather what knights we have, they can fight unmounted among the spearwall. Kasmir, Mathilde, will you join me in the lines?" "Yes, your Grace," Kasmir replies saluting. "Of course," is your reply as you double-check your sword is still strapped to your back. "Then let us finish this damned distraction." --- Thunk. As one, three thousand mechanisms send three thousand bolts skywards. Crash. As one, two thousand swords ring against two thousand shields. Crash. Again, every few heartbeats. The taunting tattoo of the battlefield. Here we are, it says. Come and get us. Crash. Thunk. Another volley. Almost drowned out by the beating rhythm of the infantry, the inhuman cries from a hundred throats as their tainted lives bleed out onto the ground. Crash. You heard somewhere that ghouls were once humans that turned to cannibalism and were twisted by it. Crash. You doubt it, personally; you suspect that whatever mechanism transforms one into the creatures known as ghouls, Crash, possibly related to that which transforms people into beastmen? Thunk. That it has a side-effect in its early stages of a ravenous hunger for fresh meat, and the closest fresh meat to the average person is other people. Crash. You wonder if the Amethyst Order has ever studied the matter. Crash. You wonder if such study would even be allowed, or whether it would be considered too close to necromancy. Crash. You wonder if it's even a question worth answering, when the only answer truly needed is that of steel. Thunk. And a cry even more inhuman than the others arises, as the Singing King finally accepts the invitation that so many bolts have been sending to him. A hundred sergeants raise a hundred cries, and thousands of shields lock into place at the front of the lines just outside the ruined portion of the fortress walls. Any one man here would be no match for even the least of the terrors within these walls, but no one man is alone. They stand not only with those by their sides, but with the blacksmiths that forged their weapons, with the trainers that taught them the arts of war, with the chaplains that stoked the fires of their faith. And as if summoned by your thoughts, at the other side of Van Hal, Kasmir voice somehow pierces the din of battle. Lord Sigmar, Hear My Prayer, his cry goes up, and is joined by ten thousand more. Let not my weapon fail me, as a thousand skulking hungry horrors boil out of the fortress. But strengthen it against the foe, as the worst of them all emerges, his terrible voice drowned out by the call of the faithful. Give my blade your wisdom, and voices rise from prayer into a wordless cry as the foremost of the ghouls throw themselves against the spearline. For a moment it seems the line will hold, but then the weight of the rest of the forces are thrown at the backs of those impaled upon spears, and human muscle cannot stand against inhuman hunger. A step is taken back, and then two, as the only other option was to break under the terrible strength of the ghouls, and plenty had no opportunity to make those choice as their spears were torn away and claws and teeth tore into the flesh of far too many of the spearmen. But then the second line steps forward. The swordsmen of the Empire are a much romanticized lot, by nobody more than themselves, but you've learned from your times with the Greatswords that they barely scratch the surface of what is possible with a blade. All they are good for is wielding the steel of the Empire like a bludgeon, battering away at the enemy without artifice or any real skill. But these swordsmen have been campaigning for over a year against everything Sylvania could throw at them, and those that remain have been forged by adversity into an army worthy of the name. If that was all that stood in the second line, it would have been barely sufficient to halt the charge. But it was not all, for the Knights of the Empire stood with them. The Knights Panther. The Knights of Sigmar's Blood. The Order of the Black Rose. The Order of the Blazing Sun. And outnumbering them all, the Black Guards of Morr. Four warcries of four Knightly Orders sound, and a fifth remains silent as they swing as one with the Swordsmen of the Empire, and in a bloody instant a thousand creatures of the night perish, drowning out the cries of the dying spearmen. As if personally offended, the creature commanding the ghouls strides forward, pushing through the charging masses with ease. By chance or low cunning or just because he was the tallest figure on the battlefield and standing on an elevated point besides, his burning eyes lock onto Van Hal, and his eyes glow with dark hunger, his distended muscles bulging with strength that no mortal could withstand. But in doing so, he overlooked the two figures standing at the side of the Elector Count. With a chanted prayer that you faintly realize is a continuation of the one that began the battle, the Priest of Sigmar glows, literally glows, with what you cannot help but know is the manifestation of the truest faith in the Champion of Mankind. The gloom of the forest is driven back as a mirror to the sun in the sky bursts forth from the armoured priest, and the courage of every true servant of the Empire is bolstered as- you shake your head, trying to regain your concentration. Something about whatever it is Kasmir was doing (was it magic? was it divine? was there a difference?) seemed to twist your thoughts into grandiose purple prose, and you can't afford to be distracted. Because as the terrible creature advances, undeterred by the beacon of faith that Kasmir has become, you step between the two of them. Since the first pull of a trigger of this battle, you've been drawing the Ulgu that lies thick in the shadows of these woods into you, and shaping it into the most difficult and potent spell of Grey Magic you know. And as your silhouette falls upon the tide of the dead, you let the magic within you burst forth. And in an instant, holy light and caustic Ulgu woven by the combined will of a priest and a wizard slam against the packed ranks of the creatures and they melt. Literally. The terrible cries of the Singing King are nothing compared to the hundreds of agonized screeches torn from the throats of those between you and the King, and the air is filled with their cries and the smell of boiling flesh and a horrible fog of vapourized skin. In instants the creatures have either literally or figuratively melted away and there's nothing between you and the Strigoi, and the worst cry yet fills the air, as the set of lungs that commanded a battlefield is given over to nothing but the expression of pure agony as the creature's skin boils away to reveal blackening muscle and yellowing bone, until they, too, begin to liquefy... The legendary resilience of the grave might have been enough to counter even that, had Van Hal not chosen that moment to raise his repeater rifle and unload every single blessed bullet into the hideous creature. For an instant, your shadow stretches across a portion of the battlefield filled only with the bubbling corpses of the rightfully dead, until Kasmir's beacon of light blinks out and shadow rushes back in to fill the void. [Spearline holds against the charge: 35 vs 84] [Swords advance: 95+20 (Knights) vs 86] [Kasmir interrupt 92+??] [Mathilde interupt 95+18] [Van Hal fires: 66+24] [Strigoi rolls to not die: 22+20 (vampiric resilience)] --- After that, the battle was over; all that remained was cleaning up. Whatever terrible hold the Strigoi vampire held over the ghouls was shattered, and they reverted to mindless instinct and fled; unfortunately for them, they fled into the fortress, so the only escape from the Empire's steel was to throw themselves from the battlements upon the spikes of wood and bone crafted by the greenskins the ghouls had slaughtered and feasted upon. If greenskins had souls, you reflect, that would give theirs succour. The final tally is more brutal than you had expected; a full quarter of the spearmen died in the initial terrible charge of the ghouls, and many more are injured, and there's much damage done to the swordsmen, too. Combined with the previous losses, as much as a third of the Army of Stirland is no longer fit for combat, and you see Van Hal brooding over those figures time and time again. Weeks more pass in busy work, as the Purge is expanded to cover the Woods since you're there already and the greenskins have been all but exterminated. When the Throng of Zhufbar arrives, having decided to follow up their hard-won victory over the greenskins by destroying their fort, they find it already far advanced in deconstruction, with a single tent standing in the middle of it all, and within it Van Hal is carefully scrubbing the last vestiges of flesh from the skull of what had once been a Strigoi vampire. His gift to you, he had said, and you suppose you could always use a terrifying paperweight for the laboratory. Sitting beside Van Hal as the dwarves enter is you, staring in troubled thought at the candle that flickers away almost to nothing whenever you draw near to it. [Arcane Mark gained: Flicker] [Title gained: Sängerkritisch] --- PLAN FOR THIS PURGE TURN ORGANIZATIONAL ACTIONS - these have been LOCKED IN for the next two purge turns. Spoiler: Organizational Actions Information Network - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [ ] Expand your information network into another province (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into another county or barony (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into the military (choose a Division) [ ] Expand your Intelligence Attaché program to another Division (choose one) [ ] Off the Leash: Let Julia handle the network without your micromanagement from now on. Information Network finances - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above. [ ] Attaché Paperwork: The Intelligence Attachés are your biggest expense by far - see if you can have them paid for by the Army of Stirland instead. [ ] Fixer: Work with the Wurtbad Thieves Guild, supplying them information in exchange for a portion of profits. [ ] Special Branch: Pull some financial trickery to get the information network classified as part of the Watch, so that their costs are covered by the Stirlandian treasury. [ ] Trade Delegation: Convince Wilhelmina and Markus to partner your network with the EIC based on the value of market information. Stirland Watch - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [ ] Expand the ranks of the Watch, so that they're able to start covering even the poorer parts of their covered area. [ ] Expand the Watch into a new county or barony (choose which) [ ] Expand the Special Branch into areas already covered by the Watch, so you have an additional pool of manpower you can call upon to supplement the full-time Watchmen. [ ] Improve the training of the Watch, hiring trainers and dedicating paid time each week to sharpening skills. [ ] Integrate the Roadwarden network of covered areas into the Watch. [ ] Investigate the possibility of adding a River Warden branch of the Watch. [ ] Headhunt administrators from other organizations in Stirland. [ ] Attempt to hire administrators and clerks from Altdorf and Nuln. Stirland Watch finances - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above. [ ] Formalize and organize the payments people make for the Gong Farmers to perform their service, as well as having the Watch start enforcing existing laws against dumping human waste in the street or the Stir. [ ] Currently, solid waste is sent by cart and wagon out to the fields for a pittance. It could instead be used to create market gardens along the banks of the Stir (hopefully downwind) and increase revenue and provide jobs for the desperate by growing a variety of cash crops. [ ] Tanneries have a seemingly limitless demand for urine, which explains a lot about the smell. A bit of fragrant research would allow you to identify how much demand there is and how much of a profit you can wring from this. PERSONAL ACTIONS - CHOOSE BETWEEN TWO AND THREE. ANY CHOSEN BEYOND THE FIRST TWO WILL COME WITH RISKS - PLEASE SPECIFY THE 'ADDITIONAL' TASK: Spoiler: Personal Actions Genießt den Krieg - join the divisions in Sylvania: [ ] If you're feeling nosy, Vanhaldenschlosse is apparently free of anything that would object to you poking around in what was once the proud ancestral home of the Van Hals. [ ] Something apparently quite similar to the Purge of the Haunted Hills is going on in Ostermark's southern regions; you could inspect goings-on up there yourself. [ ] The Dwarves have crossed into the Empire and joined up with the Empire forces. Perhaps you could spend some time with the general staff as the two of them start to work together. [ ] Attach yourself to the army so you can join in the Purge of the Ghoul Woods. (specify which regiment to join). Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. [ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills and internalize the lessons you've learned (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective if you've used the trait a lot lately). [ ] Tutoring: One of your fellow councillors may be willing to teach you in their chosen field (choose who; can choose which, or you can let them decide). [ ] Really Good Swords: You have achieved proficiency with the Greatsword. Future progress is possible, though it will take more effort to see results. [ ] Combat Training: You're virtually surrounded by armed warriors of various sorts. See if you can convince one to teach you (choose who). [ ] Combat Training, In The Free Market: You haven't made many heavily armed friends yet, but gold is good for that. Go out and buy some training. (-personal gold) [ ] Gun Shopping: You're currently using a pistol that was a spare for the pistoliers. Visit Nuln to upgrade. (Choose: dueling pistols for accuracy and range, repeater pistols for weight of fire, dragons for hand shotguns. Choose: whether you will acquire and use two pistols at once or keep one hand free.) [ ] Enchantment: You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. [ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Remixed: You're getting sick of having workmen tramping in and out of your abode. Recruit an entire team and personally oversee them to clear out all of the reachable portions of the Palace-Shrine and be done with it. (-personal gold) [ ] Filled with Potential: You've got a room cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put there and get started on equipping it. (write in the purpose of the room) Research: [ ] Undead Research: You know the basics, now. Perhaps a great deal of effort will allow you to advance further. [ ] Snooping: Van Hal gave you a key to his Study. It's been a while since he's been in Wurtbad; he probably forgot he did so, and won't remember until he returns. And he didn't specifically say not to poke around and see what you could find. [ ] Shyish-kebabs: The Shyish swords are hideously dangerous as weapons, but fascinating as a subject of study. Try to reverse-engineer the lost enchantments woven into them. [ ] Qhaysh Juice: Whatever it is, it's dripping out of the box at a steady rate. You've got several gallons of the stuff and it's still coming out. It's got to be good for something. [ ] Qhaysh Skunkworks: It would take careful study to unlock the secrets of the liquid. It would take considerably less time to find out if it can be made to burn, or explode, or do something militarily useful. [ ] There's always room for more shadow spells in your repertoire. Send off to the Grey College for the basics on one of the others and get started on trying to learn it. Influence: [ ] Information Network: Work alongside to Julia to administer the network. Choose another Organizational Action for the Network. [ ] Stirland Watch: Work alongside Jack to administer the Watch. Choose another Organizational Action for the Watch. [ ] Financial Jargon: Everything with the EIC flew right over your head last time. Try again. Succeeding here will mean that you can take a more active hand in the company, adding it to the organizational actions; failing or not attempting means Mathilde will remain a silent partner. [ ] Thieves Guild: It's currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. If it could be expanded under your aegis, it could be a powerful tool. [ ] Biderhof: This village based on woodcutting and agriculture, has adopted you as one of it's own. Maybe you should adopt it as your own, in a literal sense. [ ] Non-Thief Guilds: Wurtbad, like all major cities, is home to a number of guilds. Reach out to them and enforce your will. Relations: [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with one of your fellow councillors, your liege, or any of the other important figures you've come to know, offering your help in their tasks and generally getting a feel for them (choose one). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: Trust, but verify. Spend some of your time seeing what a certain person spends their time doing (choose one). [ ] Letters Home: You might be able to wring more information out of your Master, or you might just be able to get news, information and guidance in general from the Grey Order. [o] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (not possible during Purge Turns) - This turn the Purge will be finishing off the Ghoul Woods; next turn is the southern Hills. After that is the final preparations before the attack on Drakenhof, which will have separate options for last-minute preparations (including hiring battle wizards). So you have two 'proper' purge turns left until the climax of the Purge. - Because I know what to expect: don't, repeat DON'T, expect Burning Shadows to always be this effective. This was a double crit. Tune your expectations accordingly.

Purge of the Haunted Hills - Brauzeit, 2476

Spoiler: Winning Vote [X] Plan Train The Watch, or How To Not Have A Watch Revolt On Our Hands -[X] The Dwarves have crossed into the Empire and joined up with the Empire forces. Perhaps you could spend some time with the general staff as the two of them start to work together. --[X] Enquire about arranging for some Tunnel Fighting trainers for the future “War Below” (after the Purge), or at least make some contacts. Not hired right now, we can’t afford them. -[X] Stirland Watch: Work alongside Jack to administer the Watch. Choose another Organizational Action for the Watch. --[X] Improve the training of the Watch, hiring trainers and dedicating paid time each week to sharpening skills. ---[X] A formal program of a few old-timer veterans with the right attitude and aptitude being paid to train and pass local knowledge to newcomers. Perhaps injured Greatswords or officers provide some candidates to sharpen fighting skills? Jack might know some trainers in the arts of avoiding notice. Watchmen who arrived prior to us probably can’t read. Does Van Hal know a retired Witch Hunter who could pass on some investigation and Corruption-spotting skills? Maybe Julia can suggest an Agent particularly skilled at ferreting out information and sifting useful leads from bad. Anything that comes up from the meeting with the senior Watchmen below? ---[X] Meet with some and gain a better understanding of the senior Watchmens’ grievances and discuss our shared hopes for the future of the Watch. We really respect the Watch and want to address their concerns, we owe our life to a brave and dedicated village Watchman. Shouldn’t every child in Stirland have the same protection, and more? -- [X] Ranald's Blessing "So!" states the apparent leader of the dwarves, who when viewed from the front appeared to be made entirely of neatly-braided, fiery-red beard. "You're the manling out to try his luck against the bloodsuckers!" Van Hal smiles and glances pointedly down at the skull he's scraping the last traces of flesh off, and the dwarf chuckles. "Point well made. Our rangers are of the opinion that the grobi that besieged Zhufbar sought shelter in that pathetic excuse for a fortress, only to be eaten by the lot you were chasing. Not the best end to the tale, but the extinction of the Crooked Eye tribe will settle a fair few Grudges, I dare say." "Glad that Stirland could be of service," Van Hal says, placing the skull atop the table and rising to his feet. "That lad of yours did say that you wanted to be friends," the dwarf says. "Time will tell if anything will come of that, but you're off to a damn fine start." A stubby hand extends from the beard, and Van Hal shakes it. "Thorri, of clan Stoneheart, Thane of Zhufbar." "Abelhelm Van Hal, Elector Count of Stirland." "I suspected as much." He looks over at you, and looks you up and down with a critical eye. "This the lass that did such a number on the creatures at the breach?" He stumps over to you and extends his hand, and you shake it gingerly, expecting a rock-crushing grip and surprised at the carefulness with which his fingers close around yours. "You did a day's work there. Nothing a few flame cannon couldn't have done, but I daresay you're more portable than they would be." "Thank you," you reply uncertainly. "Since we're on the warpath already," he grins suddenly, "Khazukan Kazakit-ha!" The cry is picked up by a dwarf outside, and in seconds has spread to the rest of the throng in the distance. "I decided we would coordinate to better exterminate the grobi and the despoilers of the dead. What's your plans?" Van Hal leads the dwarf over to the table where the map of the Hills sits, and Thorri pulls a tube from a pocket and unrolls his own map, and they start comparing, with a great deal of complaints about how impossible it is to find one's way around without good solid mountains around to act as reference points. "Right," he decides as last. "We'll hang about here for a season and make sure the Crooked Eye are extinct for good, and then we'll join you on the march against Drakenhof. About time that particular peak was removed from the range, I daresay." He claps Van Hal on the back, and with that the partnership was struck. --- Your attempt at mingling with the dwarves gets off to a rocky start at first. It takes you some time to get to the bottom of why they're so standoffish, but eventually you start piecing together the dwarf mindset. To them, magic was to be nailed down properly and used only through the medium of their strange pseudo-enchantment runes; wizardry was, to their mind, something like taking the gunpowder one would use in a rifle, throwing it in an enemy's face, and then trying to hit them with a torch - potentially effective, but clumsy, wasteful, and certain to end in disaster all around and your beard burnt off. Nevertheless you persevere, and end up spending time with the only one that seems unbothered by your presence - a short-bearded begoggled dwarf engineer named Narfi, who is apparently in charge of the scant few war machines the Throng has brought with them in their pursuit and as such is used to spending times around things that are likely to explode in everyone's faces. "A dwarf with his back against the wall can sell his life very dearly indeed," he says to you one evening as you try your best to contribute to a combined plan for the artillery of Zhufbar and Stirland. "But scaled up, there's very few dwarfholds that can be said to have anything solid at their back. Each is an island in a sea of enemies, and every dwarf born for the past four thousand years comes out of the womb with an uncomfortable itch between their shoulderblades." "So for Zhufbar..." "To the north, your land of Sylvania. To the east, endless mountains of greenskins, ever since Gunbad fell. To the south, Varn Drazh - the Black Water. A thousand mineshafts lost to us and crawling with foes. And to the west, Karak Varn, that once produced the metal that Zhufbar smelted, long lost to the thaggoraki." "Thaggoraki?" you ask. "I believe you know them as 'beast men'." "I didn't realize beastmen tormented the dwarves so," you comment, frowning. "Some days it seems that there's little that doesn't torment us, lass." He frowns, thinking. "The point... I believe I had a point, somewhere." "Backs against walls," you prompt. "Ah, yes. Stirland has been an adequate friend to Zhufbar, in matters of trade and such. If you could take Sylvania in hand, and be the wall that we of Zhufbar could put our backs to..." He sighs, long and heartfelt. "A manling state, being the best our hold could hope for. Such are the times we live in." Most of you is busy with trying to keep from being offended, but part of you feels the utmost pity for a race that sees a good death as the best they could hope for. In the end your contributions are of questionable utility, but given the backhanded compliment of being adequate when one accounts for the fact that you've yet to finish your third decade, which makes you still a child in dwarf terms. And you've become at least acquaintances with Narfi. [Making friends with dwarves: Req 50, Diplomacy, 21+8=29] [Contributing to military matters: Req 60, Martial, 42+13=55] --- Having failed to capitalize on the good impression you had made on the dwarves, your mood as you retreat back to Wurtbad is far from positive. It is, however, slightly improved when you check in with Jack, who has apparently acquired through unspecified means the details of a few varying but universally disgusting techniques to derive saltpeter from human and animal waste. And then it's right back to misery when you learn that the mood of the Watch has plummeted further when they learned that their new leader is quite literally pissing his time away instead of doing anything to improve their lot. It may, you reflect, have been a tad tone-deaf to begin the saltpeter operations when moods were already soured. Oh, you could tell them of budgetary concerns and such, but as far as they're concerned their pay comes from the Treasury of Stirland and any deviation from that is inherently suspicious. A soldier's career begins when they ceremonially take the Count's shilling from the recruiter, and the Paymasters of the army play a very pivotal role in the military psyche, and as such they are annoyingly preoccupied with the legitimacy of their pay. Nevertheless, one must press on. There is, tragically, a deluge of potential new recruits as the wounded filter back to Wurtbad; you spend days filtering through them all, and eventually find a few solid candidates: one of Gustav's pistoliers, a crackshot who unfortunately can no longer sit astride a horse due to damage to his back, a spearman sergeant who lost a hand to the jaws of a ghoul in the Battle of Fang Island, and a swordsman who left both legs in the Haunted Hills. You ask Jack and Julia for candidates, and they produce them: Jack has two names in mind, one a former smuggler who claims knowledge of every tunnel from here to Salzenmund and the other a Hochland poacher, and Julia a former tutor in horsemanship and swordplay run out of Flensburg for a habit of being seduced by the young women he taught, which hopefully won't be a problem with the grizzled veterans of the Watch. You push further afield; Van Hal has every man he can call upon focused on the Purge, Kasmir says the same, and Wilhelmina and Schultz can't think of anyone suited for the task. Gustav gives you the name of an old friend who used to lead a company of Nordland Marines. Anton, who appears in Wurtbad only briefly before hurrying off in the direction of Reikland, gives you the name of a man who he says is the only name worth knowing when it comes to the breeding of Stirland Terriers. Markus, of course, can't spare a single one of his able-bodied greatswords, but does pass on the name of a field doctor who he claims is actually capable of improving a wounded man's chances of survival. You're left with a diverse pool of candidates to choose from, but sadly, only two of them can be hired at this time. And you might have to take into account how the Watch will feel about your choices... [Trainer hunt - Diplomacy: Req 60, 14+8=22] [Trainer hunt - Intrigue: Req 60, 70+17+10(Ranald's Blessing)=97] [Trainer hunt - Martial: Req 60, 68+13=81] [Trainer hunt - Stewardship: Req 60, 30+14=44] [Trainer hunt - Learning: Req 60, 14+18=32.] [Trainer hunt - Piety: Req 60, 9+16=25] --- Watch Trainers: Pick TWO. Conventional Candidates: [ ] Promote Internally - Best for morale, but brings nothing new to the table [ ] Spearmen - Watchmen become proficient in the spear, can form spearwalls [ ] Swordsman - Watchmen become proficient with swords and shields [ ] Pistolier - Watchmen become proficient with pistols, carry them on patrol Unconventional Candidates: [ ] Dog Breeder - Stirland Terriers become part of the Watch [ ] Smuggler - Watchmen become much better at operating underground [ ] Poacher - Watchmen learn woodsmanship and archery [ ] Tutor - Watchmen learn advanced swordsmanship and horsemanship [ ] Marine - Watchmen learn marine combat and non-lethal subdual techniques [ ] Doctor - Watchmen learn first aid --- PLAN FOR THIS PURGE TURN ORGANIZATIONAL ACTIONS - these have been LOCKED IN for the next purge turn. Spoiler: Organizational Actions Information Network - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [ ] Expand your information network into another province (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into another county or barony (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into the military (choose a Division) [ ] Expand your Intelligence Attaché program to another Division (choose one) [ ] Off the Leash: Let Julia handle the network without your micromanagement from now on. Information Network finances - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above. [ ] Attaché Paperwork: The Intelligence Attachés are your biggest expense by far - see if you can have them paid for by the Army of Stirland instead. [ ] Fixer: Work with the Wurtbad Thieves Guild, supplying them information in exchange for a portion of profits. [ ] Special Branch: Pull some financial trickery to get the information network classified as part of the Watch, so that their costs are covered by the Stirlandian treasury. [ ] Trade Delegation: Convince Wilhelmina and Markus to partner your network with the EIC based on the value of market information. Stirland Watch - pick ONE (no action expenditure required), currently at +1 Budget Points: [ ] Expand the ranks of the Watch, so that they're able to start covering even the poorer parts of their covered area. (-1 Budget Point) [ ] Expand the Watch into a new county or barony (choose which) (No Budgetary Impact due to expanded Gong Farming) [ ] Expand the Special Branch into areas already covered by the Watch, so you have an additional pool of manpower you can call upon to supplement the full-time Watchmen. (-1 Budget Point) [o] Improve the training of the Watch, hiring trainers and dedicating paid time each week to sharpening skills (LOCKED until administrative staff acquired) (-1 Budget Point) [ ] Solve the current morale problem by brute force: throw time, effort and money at it until it goes away. (-1 Budget Point) [ ] Integrate the Roadwarden network of covered areas into the Watch. [ ] Investigate the possibility of adding a River Warden branch of the Watch. [ ] Headhunt administrators from other organizations in Stirland. [ ] Attempt to hire administrators and clerks from Altdorf and Nuln. Stirland Watch finances - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above, will yield an unknown number of Budget Points. [ ] Formalize and organize the payments people make for the Gong Farmers to perform their service, as well as having the Watch start enforcing existing laws against dumping human waste in the street or the Stir. [ ] Currently, solid waste is sent by cart and wagon out to the fields for a pittance. It could instead be used to create market gardens along the banks of the Stir (hopefully downwind) and increase revenue and provide jobs for the desperate by growing a variety of cash crops. [ ] Tanneries have a seemingly limitless demand for urine, which explains a lot about the smell. A bit of fragrant research would allow you to identify how much demand there is and how much of a profit you can wring from this. PERSONAL ACTIONS - CHOOSE BETWEEN TWO AND THREE. ANY CHOSEN BEYOND THE FIRST TWO WILL COME WITH RISKS - PLEASE SPECIFY THE 'ADDITIONAL' TASK: Spoiler: Personal Actions Genießt den Krieg - join the divisions in Sylvania: [ ] If you're feeling nosy, Vanhaldenschlosse is apparently free of anything that would object to you poking around in what was once the proud ancestral home of the Van Hals. [ ] Something apparently quite similar to the Purge of the Haunted Hills is going on in Ostermark's southern regions; you could inspect goings-on up there yourself. [ ] Attach yourself to the army so you can join in the final push of the Purge of the Haunted Hills. (specify which regiment to join; can join the artillery under Narfi of the Throng of Zhufbar). (NEW-ish) Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. [ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills and internalize the lessons you've learned (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective if you've used the trait a lot lately). [ ] Tutoring: One of your fellow councillors may be willing to teach you in their chosen field (choose who; can choose which, or you can let them decide). [ ] Really Good Swords: You have achieved proficiency with the Greatsword. Future progress is possible, though it will take more effort to see results. [ ] Combat Training: You're virtually surrounded by armed warriors of various sorts. See if you can convince one to teach you (choose who). [ ] Combat Training, In The Free Market: You haven't made many heavily armed friends yet, but gold is good for that. Go out and buy some training. (-personal gold) [ ] Gun Shopping: You're currently using a pistol that was a spare for the pistoliers. Visit Nuln to upgrade. (will trigger a subvote next turn for what type and how many) [ ] Enchantment: You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. [ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Remixed: You're getting sick of having workmen tramping in and out of your abode. Recruit an entire team and personally oversee them to clear out all of the reachable portions of the Palace-Shrine and be done with it. (-personal gold) [ ] Filled with Potential: You've got a room cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put there and get started on equipping it. (write in the purpose of the room) Research: [ ] Undead Research: You know the basics, now. Perhaps a great deal of effort will allow you to advance further. [ ] Snooping: Van Hal gave you a key to his Study. It's been a while since he's been in Wurtbad; he probably forgot he did so, and won't remember until he returns. And he didn't specifically say not to poke around and see what you could find. [ ] Shyish-kebabs: The Shyish swords are hideously dangerous as weapons, but fascinating as a subject of study. Try to reverse-engineer the lost enchantments woven into them. [ ] Qhaysh Juice: Whatever it is, it's dripping out of the box at a steady rate. You've got several gallons of the stuff and it's still coming out. It's got to be good for something. [ ] Qhaysh Skunkworks: It would take careful study to unlock the secrets of the liquid. It would take considerably less time to find out if it can be made to burn, or explode, or do something militarily useful. [ ] There's always room for more shadow spells in your repertoire. Send off to the Grey College for the basics on one of the others and get started on trying to learn it. Influence: [ ] Information Network: Work alongside to Julia to administer the network. Choose another Organizational Action for the Network. [ ] Stirland Watch: Work alongside Jack to administer the Watch. Choose another Organizational Action for the Watch. [ ] Financial Jargon: Everything with the EIC flew right over your head last time. Try again. Succeeding here will mean that you can take a more active hand in the company, adding it to the organizational actions; failing or not attempting means Mathilde will remain a silent partner. [ ] Thieves Guild: It's currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. If it could be expanded under your aegis, it could be a powerful tool. [ ] Biderhof: This village based on woodcutting and agriculture, has adopted you as one of it's own. Maybe you should adopt it as your own, in a literal sense. [ ] Non-Thief Guilds: Wurtbad, like all major cities, is home to a number of guilds. Reach out to them and enforce your will. Relations: [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with one of your fellow councillors, your liege, or any of the other important figures you've come to know, offering your help in their tasks and generally getting a feel for them (choose one). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: Trust, but verify. Spend some of your time seeing what a certain person spends their time doing (choose one). [ ] Letters Home: You might be able to wring more information out of your Master, or you might just be able to get news, information and guidance in general from the Grey Order. [o] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (not possible during Purge Turns) - You currently have one (1) Dwarf Rep, gained from your showing in the Battle of Fang Island, and, sadly, none from the time you spent with them. Dwarf Rep is not the out-of-ten scale that your relations have used so far - it starts at zero and increments (or decrements) as you perform acts that have an impression on them. This is the currency one could use, for instance, for attempting to hire a dwarven teacher for the Watch; there will be opportunities to gain more in the combined campaign against Drakenhof. - It's been hashed out already, but for posterity and those that skip to the update: trying to write in every single step that Mathilde might take to perform a task will not help you. This is not a quest where you have to write in to keep breathing or Mathilde will keel over and suffocate. - Before anyone asks: any trainers not chosen now are lost. You can't offer them any other roles, you can't save them for later; they're either one of the two picks you make this turn or they're gone. - You will be able to expand the training staff further after administrative staff and a new headquarters are acquired. - The Trainer Vote will be separate to the vote on Personal Actions. - I've further formalized the Watch's budget system; 'Budget Points' are gained and lost based on actions taken. The 'status quo' before you took over was 0; it's up to you whether you think that's a good balance to aim for under your stewardship. - This is the last Purge Turn before the assault on Drakenhof. Just saying. - Don't forget Ranald's Blessing!

Purge of the Haunted Hills - Ulriczeit, 2476

Spoiler: Winning Vote [*] Dog Breeder - Stirland Terriers become part of the Watch [*] Promote Internally - Best for morale, but brings nothing new to the table [*] Plan Sword-wizard -[*] Really Good Swords: You have achieved proficiency with the Greatsword. Future progress is possible, though it will take more effort to see results. -[*] There's always room for more shadow spells in your repertoire. Send off to the Grey College for the basics on one of the others and get started on trying to learn it. -[*] Shroud of Invisibility -[*] Ranald's Blessing Ideally, you'd like to hire pretty much every candidate for the training positions. But the Watch is held back by budgetary constraints, by lack of skilled administrators, by the grumbling of the veterans, and by the limited number of hours in a day. You brood over the decision for days, balancing utility against morale against practicality against cost. The swordman and spearman are discarded early; they'd be safe choices morale-wise, but neither bring anything new to the Watch nor would outright please its members - neither one thing nor t'other. The tutor and poacher, too, are discarded, as their skills are outside the current remit of the Watch. That ends the easy choices, and from here on every attempt to par down the list hurts. The marine goes early; the non-lethal techniques of Nordland's infamous press gangs may have proven useful, but not enough to justify a full-time trainer. The doctor too; the Watch, you daresay, would not appreciate attempts to teach them the mistrusted art of medicine. The smuggler would be hugely useful, but potentially disastrous considering the current mood of the watch. And, with deep reluctance, you finally admit that the cost of arming the entire Watch with pistols could very well prove prohibitive. A decision, at last, is made. Lower Hans presents a series of his most skilled and personable veterans of the Sewer Jacks to rotate through the Watch's training ground, which goes over well among the grumblers of the Watch. And Anton's friend, the breeder of the Stirland Terrier, is brought onto the payroll of the Watch. The choice is unconventional, and for a moment it seems like the Watch could take it either way, but in the end it is the terrier itself wins over those who were unsure. Bred specifically for rat-baiting, it is larger and nobler-looking than the mongrels favoured by the rat catchers, and the breeder promises that the breed's watchfulness and intelligence would make them an asset in a number of situations, not just in killing rats. The Watch is pleased, and distracted from Jack's exploration of saltpeter derivation, defusing what was shaping up to be a nasty morale crisis. --- With the final stage of the Purge underway, you join Markus and the Greatswords once more. As they've stayed by the sides of those they're sworn to protect, they've missed most of the fighting in the past year, but you've heard they made a good showing of themselves in the Battle of the Valley of the Singing King. Markus welcomes you gruffly back to the training grounds, and puts you through a series of drills to determine whether you've dropped a step. At your level of proficiency, training is with blunted steel instead of the wooden swords you trained with, and the ringing of steel on steel is very different to the blunt impact of wood on wood. The next few weeks are punishing; not only are you training from dawn to dusk, but you're also following the army as it marches across the Hills, and with a pack loaded with rocks on foot. Markus is a great believer in the importance of fitness, and when you grumble, he throws on a pack twice the size of yours and literally runs circles around you for the entire day's march, which forces you to shut up. In the end, the results speak for themselves. You've always been somewhat on the small side and you doubt anything will change that, but beneath your robes the lean muscle of a warrior has replaced the soft flesh of a sheltered academic. [Fitness training: Req 60, Martial, 64+13=77] [Greatsword training: Req 80, Martial, 86+13=99] Your training allows you to be on hand for the penultimate major battle of the campaign, as the expected resistance finally materializes and the 'wild' undead suddenly begin acting in unison. Unfortunately for the enemy, they vastly underestimated the Army of Stirland, which if anything are delighted that the enemy are coming straight to them instead of being tucked away in the nooks and crannies of the Hills. A series of devastating skirmishes later, the enemy is hemmed in and tracked down to their base of operations - an ancient, ruined hillfort. While once the fort would have proven a difficult obstacle, that time was thousands of years ago, and seventy cannon speak as one to tear the defences asunder. If anything, they're too effective, and all there is to investigate is fresh blood and scraps of flesh and splinters of bone, proving that a living necromancer was foolish enough to try to stand in the way of the artillery of Stirland. The Throng of Zhufbar nod to themselves and gruffly mutter that it may have been a good decision to grant mankind the secret of gunpowder. The Hillfort proves to be the entrance into a network of natural caves that were converted in ancient times into what could be the largest pre-Sigmar tomb complex you've ever heard of. Shyish is thick in the air, skittering in the depths proves the presence of ghouls and possibly worse things, and the dead stir uneasily at the trespass of man into their graves. Stairs carved into steep rock slopes seem to descend forever into the darkness, and your brief attempts at sketching out a map ends with more unexplored tomb stretching out in every cardinal direction, plus downwards. You itch to plumb the depths of the unknown, but the army is already breaking camp to finish as much of the Purge as possible before winter sets in once more and forces them to seek shelter in Nachthafen. Still, it's been sitting there for at least three thousand years, it's not going anywhere. --- To shroud oneself in Ulgu is easier said than done; it has a natural tendency to gravitate towards those attuned to it, but to get it to do more than to curl around your ankles is like trying to grab mist. It requires a completely different set of techniques than the simple one every wizard knows to draw magic in, and the technique is wholly alien to anything you've ever tried - like reading a treatise on how to grow hands on every inch of your skin and grasp at the air with them. You pass weeks in meditation, trying to grasp the techniques laid out in the encrypted scrolls. Progress is infuriating slow but is being made, every morning spent shrouded in the morning mist atop one hill or another, until one morning you're grasping and you feel the sensation every wizard dreads - that of magic tearing itself free of your grasp. Though it has been long years since Ulgu has fought your control, the reactions were taught so deeply that they are still automatic - the releasing of the spell, the purging of magical energies from your body, throwing yourself as far from the spot you had stood as possible in the instant you have to react, the grounding of bare flesh against soil, the desperately mumbled prayers to any god that may be listening... The Ulgu that had seconds before been coiled around you is suddenly pulled taut, like a fishing line that just snared a shark, and the very air resonates with the energy in it. The mist around you grows darker, deeper, and glimpses of alien colours can be seen within it- And then, as suddenly as it had appeared, the energies ground themselves. Without moving, you cast your eyes around, dreading what you'll find. When magic tears itself free and starts to draw on the hellish dimension it originated from, the possibilities are literally endless, and invariably bad... The hill. It had been covered with soft, green grass, tinged white with the frost of winter, and now was just the brown of soil. But undisturbed, as if... You run your hand over the bare ground nearest to you, and feel blades of grass tickle your fingers, and thank Ranald that the only victims of your spell are innumerable blades of grass that are now completely cut off from life-giving sunlight. Though that's the least of their troubles, because you're going to cover this entire hilltop in lamp oil and set it alight, just in case. [Learning Shroud of Invisibility: Req 70, Learning, 11+18+10(Ranald's Blessing)=39] --- Advanced Greatsword (Beginner) acquired. Fitness Proficiency achieved! --- The Army of Stirland and the Throng of Zhufbar gather at Nachthafen to ride out the worst of winter. When the human army started putting up tents, the dwarves had snorted and set to work, and in days a fortified wooden barracks has been erected outside Nachthafen, complete with stone chimneys in every room and firing slits for the cannon. Ostermark continues to be bogged down in their campaign, projecting another year until the woods around Mordheim are cleared, dashing any last hopes that they would open the second front they spoke of. The forces present will have to suffice, and such a force it is. On the human side: thirty thousand infantry, fourteen hundred knights, seventy cannon, thirty mortars, one wizard, and an elven prince atop a dragon. For the dwarves: six thousand warriors, four thousand rifle-armed and aptly-named Thunderers, ten cannon, and ten multi-barrelled 'organ guns' of seeming similarity to the Empire's Helblasters. And, they say, they're calling for reinforcements from Zhufbar, apparently unwilling to let manlings so outdo them in heavy artillery. Possibly sufficient, possibly. But there is always room for more firepower, and Van Hal is calling a meeting of the council to discuss last-minute preparations, mostly consisting of requests for aid. FINAL PREPARATIONS FOR THE ASSAULT ON DRAKENHOF. Pick between two and three to assist with personally. A third, if chosen, will count as Overwork and come with risks. Optionally, pick three more to argue in favour of though you cannot take care of them yourself, as Van Hal values your opinion. [ ] Averland's army is currently mobilized to mop up the last vestiges of a defeated Waagh; perhaps they can be convinced to contribute. [ ] Hochland's famous snipers could come in useful in a prolonged siege. [ ] The forests of Mordheim will keep. Invite Ostermark to bring their armies into Sylvania, so that they might actually achieve something for a change. [ ] Anton is already in Reikland seeking assistance from the Emperor, but perhaps a greater focus here could pay dividends. [ ] Talabecland's knights appear to be having a grand time, perhaps they could convince more of their fellows to join in. [ ] More cannon. More cannon. Send to Wissenland. [ ] There's one neighbour that hasn't been asked for help. Maybe the Moot could contribute somehow? [ ] Send for Battle Wizards from a College of Magic (pick which, can be taken multiple times). [ ] What purpose could be more holy than this? Request aid from the Grand Theogonist. [ ] Surely Van Hal has a lifetime of contacts and favours to draw on. Bring the Witch Hunters in. [ ] The Cult of Ulric are no friends to the undead. Call them to battle. [ ] The Fellowship of the Shroud are technically Tilean, but their enmity of vampires is unquestionable. Extend an invitation. [ ] The Throng of Zhufbar is already seeking reinforcements, perhaps the backing of an official request from Stirland could help. [ ] The Slayer Keep, Karak Kadrin, is close enough to Sylvania to inspire a dislike for it. Ask if they'd be willing to join in. [ ] The dwarvern hold of Karak Angazhar in the Black Fire Pass is small compared to Zhufbar or Karak Kadrin, but they've closer ties with man and a greater interest in trade; perhaps they'd be easier to convince to join in. [ ] Apparently there's dwarves gathering for some sort of revanchist crusade into the Badlands. Perhaps they could hone their edge against this fortress. [ ] Drakenhof is very close to one of the utmost reaches of the Stir; perhaps the riverine forces of the Empire could contribute to the fight. [ ] Sylvania is technically part of Stirland, so this could be considered defensive. Raise the militia. (pick which segment of the militia, can be taken multiple times, check the Military of Stirland threadmark for militia details) [ ] Seeking mercenaries has, to put it mildly, gone rather well so far. Seek out more. [ ] It seems Countess Gabriella is content to sit back and watch events unfold. If your suspicions are correct, and you don't mind dabbling in what might be considered heresy, her personal intervention could be a great help. Longshots due to distance: [ ] The Brettonnians have a long history of aiding those in need, and their experiences with Mousillon have given them great reason to seek vengeance against the Undead. [ ] Cut out the middle-dwarf. Send an envoy to Karaz-a-Karak, the capital of the dwarves. [ ] Kislev is experiencing something of a renaissance, purging a great deal of terrors from their land. Perhaps they can lend some of their martial might to Stirland. [ ] You've got one elf, why not go for more? Send an envoy to Ulthuan's embassy. Alternately, perhaps this time could be better spent honing your own skills. [ ] Last-minute combat training. [ ] An even more hurried and slapdash attempt at weaponizing the Qhaysh Juice. [ ] There is an awful lot of Dhar around. And it is, you've heard, easy to use and quite empowering... Spoiler: Campaign Map --- - The Stirland Terrier is based on the Manchester Terrier. If you look for information on this breed, keep in mind that there's a 'toy' version of the animal far removed from the historical one - these dogs are shorter than most, but still come up to a man's waist. - Training above proficiency is not normally quite so difficult, but here it was combined with picking up the Fitness proficiency. - If there's another faction you think might be convinced to chip in, or if there's something else you think one of the provinces could contribute, let me know and I'll add it to the list. Keep in mind distance, however - someone further afield will be harder to convince and will contribute less than someone close by. - Same goes for last-minute preparations.

Assault on Drakenhof, Part 1: An Army Assembles

Spoiler: Winning Vote [*] Plan Light and Death -[*] Send for Battle Wizards from a College of Magic (pick which, can be taken multiple times). --[*] Order of Light --[*] Amethyst Order -[*] Recommend to Van Hal: --[*] Grand Theogonist --[*] The Slayer Keep, Karak Kadrin, is close enough to Sylvania to inspire a dislike for it. Ask if they'd be willing to join in. The meeting isn't quite the return to status quo that you'd hoped, since there's only one topic on the agenda: the assault on Drakenhof. But it's still good to see faces you've seen far too little of in the past two years, and you exchange a few words before you have to get down to business. On one side of the spectrum, Anton has greatly enjoyed his travels throughout the Empire and beyond, and speaks of them with his characteristic enthusiasm at every opportunity. On the other, the Purge seems to have visibly aged Wilhelmina, who features new lines on her face and an almost constant harried look as she dashes around, trying to keep tens of thousands of men fed and supplied. When everyone is gathered, Van Hal takes the lead. "The army of Stirland is significantly below strength," he begins, "but that's more than made up for by the Throng of Zhufbar. It's a rare blessing to approach the end of a campaign with greater forces than one started with, but that's no excuse not to try for more. Suggestions?" "Not mercenaries," Wilhelmina says immediately. "Stirland's coffers are hurting as it is. In fact, we could use food a lot more than steel. Perhaps the Moot could contribute?" "Battle Wizards," you say. "The Amethyst and Light Orders in particular." "Cavalry," Gustav says. "Without the pistoliers all we have are knights. Averland's army is currently mopping up greenskins, surely they could spare some of their horsemen." "I'll mention the need for cavalry in Reikland," Anton puts forward. "Or we could go to Bretonnia - none better for mounted warriors." "While you're in Reikland, you should see the Grand Theogonist," you suggest. "Perhaps he could contribute, either on his own behalf or by flexing some theological influence." "Cannon," Schultz says, his eyes aglow. "One simply cannot have enough. We should talk to Wissenland." "I agree with Mathilde, the Theogonist should be brought in," Kasmir says. "Or the Templars of Sigmar." "If Schultz wants more cannon, who better than the dwarves?" Wilhelmina suggests. "Send to Zhufbar, add your own request to reinforcements to that of the Throng." "Or the Slayer Keep," you say. "They're near enough to Sylvania to have an enmity for it." Van Hal looks down at his notes, tapping the nib of his quill against the page thoughtfully. "Anton, Mathilde, Kasmir, head to Altdorf. Anton, get any help the Emperor will provide. Mathilde, see to whatever wizards you see fit. Kasmir, the Grand Theogonist - if any cause is holy, this one is. Schultz, Gustav is right, we need cavalry. Head to Talabecland, see if any more knights are willing to join this crusade. Gustav, how well do you get on with dwarves?" "We share a love of blackpowder and beards," he says with a grin. "Then head to Karak Kadrin. See if they're willing to seek their Doom in Sylvania. Wilhelmina..." he hesitates, then balls his hand into a fist. "Visit the Moot. Ask their help in this matter. If the Hills can be tamed, they'll go some way to replacing the land the Moot took from Stirland." --- The trip to Altdorf is long, even after Kasmir reluctantly accepts your offer of a tireless shadowhorse, and your pace too rapid to spend much time in conversation. Even in the inns you stay in, the two of them are too exhausted by the tireless gaits of their mounts to be good company. So you pass the time reading and ignoring the looks the other two give you as you casually page through a book while riding at a full gallop. When you finally arrive, since you're still a journeywoman it's not permitted for you to seek lodgings inside the Grey Order, so you get a room in the same tavern that Kasmir and Anton are staying in. As a courtesy, you write a note to your Master to let him know you're in town; because you know him, you leave it locked in a chest in your room and aren't even surprised when it's no longer there the next morning, and he joins you for breakfast. "Been keeping busy?" he asks as you sit at the table, and you note that breakfast is already waiting for you. And it's the breakfast you would have ordered for yourself. You deny your Master any sort of surprised reaction you know he's going for, and start to dig in. "Fairly. A little academia, a bit of networking, a touch of crafting the epilogue to the Vampire Wars." "So I've heard. Decent work on all three fronts. You going to go for Magister soon?" You shrug. "Things have been busy." "Always will be. That's the nature of the world we live in." The innkeeper appears at his shoulder, and your Master reaches out and takes the tankard of cider without looking. "Though the business in Sylvania is a decent reason to put things on hold elsewhere. I take it that's what brings you here?" "It is." "Reinforcements?" "Naturally." "Hmm." He drinks deeply from the tankard. "Purple?" "And white." He winces. "Red." "No. The Hierophants." He sighs. "Sigmarites. Okay. I can at least give you an in with the former, but I doubt anything can help with the latter." He finishes his drink and rises. "Come back soon. It's about time you graduated." --- The Amethyst College overlooks the vast cemetery of Old Altdorf, and you spend some time taking in the sight. The cemetery is filled primarily with victims of the Red Pox, a terrible cousin to the Black Death that so shaped Sylvania's history, and you wonder at that. Was it chosen because a cemetery is a cemetery, or was there some deeper meaning? The Red Pox was before the Orders were founded, but if there was some magical underpinning to the Red Pox as some theorize there was for the Black Plague... But that was irrelevant to the matter at hand. You turn to the open doors, and give them a long look. The magic woven into the portal - both in the poetic sense of the doorway, and in the literal sense of the actual portal that overlays it - is impossible for you to follow, densely woven and tucked in on itself again and again like a tapestry. The uninvited go one way, where they wander empty rooms filled with an aura of subtle terror until they either lose their nerve and run or are given an invitation to join the Amethyst Order. Members go another, into the actual College, where they can go about their work without interruption. For invited guests, however... You tap the tarnished brass bell hanging by the door, and immediately a cowled steward appears in the doorway, his face masked in shadows but giving the impression of peering out at you. "Dame Mathilde Weber," you say to him, or possibly it. "I'm expected." The figure looks at you for a moment longer, then nods and disappears back into the depths of the building. You turn back to the view of the cemetery, which stretches uncomfortably far, and has an almost bulging aspect to it, as too little land was asked to hold too many bodies. Were you not a wizard, the man you had come to meet would have appeared at your shoulder suddenly and without a sound; but out of respect, fellow wizards are paid the courtesy of audible footsteps. You turn to face the man; he is dressed in purple robes so deep as to be almost black and has the look of a man in the twilight of his life, with bags under his eyes and bushy grey eyebrows, and the air of a man whose twilight has lasted a long, long time. His staff is a scythe, and you know from reputation that it's as practical as it is ceremonial, the blade razor-sharp and the haft built to channel Shyish. "Patriarch Hexensohn," you greet him. "Journeywoman Weber," he replies. His voice is unexpectedly deep and rich. "I'm here today as Spymistress of Stirland, rather than as a wizard." "Ah." He smiles, gently. "Does Sylvania stir?" "We've decided not to wait for it to start spewing out horrors," you reply. "Stirland, Ostermark and Zhufbar are all marching against it; the Haunted Hills, the Ghoul Wood and the Dead Wood have all been purged. Now the combined forces of Stirland and Zhufbar are marching on Drakenhof." "The castle or the town?" he asks thoughtfully. "Both." "Ambitious. And you want our help?" "Who better to counter the necromancy that is sure to be thrown at us?" "Who indeed." He looks out over the graveyard, and silence stretches between the two of you. "This would be under Abelhelm Van Hal?" "He is the Elector Count of Stirland." "Mmm. Old name. Interesting name. I take it you know the history?" You give him a flat look, and glance pointedly down at your grey robes, and he smiles. "Shadowmancers tend to be more interested in the present than the past." You frown. "I know of Frederick Van Hal. I also know of thirteen centuries of loyal Witch Hunters." "No aspersion intended." He looks at you searchingly, and you return the look with a glare. You're no peasant to be put off by the robes and scythe; you are practically a Magister of the Grey Order and you will not be intimidated. "Mm. Yes, I think it would be for the best if our Order were to be present for this campaign. Tell your Elector Count Van Hal to expect us." Somehow, it sounds more like a threat than an offer of assistance. "Thank you," you say, nevertheless. Whatever gets them to Sylvania, you think to yourself. --- Contact with the Hierophants is a lot more difficult than ringing a bell. It takes you some time to track down even a trace of an idea of where to find them, and you're eventually directed to a maze of streets in the poorer part of town. The tale you were told speaks of standing at a certain point on a street corner and turning ninety degrees in six different ways; you opt for standing near that certain point and grabbing the first person that's glowing. That person, a young lad with a stutter, is told to bring his Master out to have a chat, he agrees nervously and scampers off into the bizarre dimensional knot on the street corner. You scowl at it. A few minutes later, the man's Master emerges and comes over. The man is utterly bald, his skin is as pure-white as his robes, and his eyes glow. He hurts to look at. "A Shadowmancer, seeking the Order of Light. It almost sounds like the start of a riddle." "I'm here on behalf of Stirland, not the Grey Order," you reply. "We're assaulting Sylvania, and seek the assistance of the Light Wizards." "Sylvania, hmm? Interesting." He purses his lips thoughtfully. "We're aware of the assault, and have decided our attentions are needed elsewhere. However, I am due a holiday and this does seem interesting. Tell your master that the Sunscryer will join in the fun." By the time you've formulated a response, he's turned and disappeared into the dimensional snarl. You glare, then throw a rock at it. The rock passes through the empty air without effect, but it makes you feel better. You've wasted enough time chasing after the stupid Light Wizards too good to have a street address. It's time to return to Stirland. --- The army you left in Stirland has swelled further by the time you return; of note to you specifically, it's swelled by four wizards - the two wizards you met in Altdorf and two amethyst Battle Wizards besides. You don't like what could have brought the Patriarch of the Amethyst Order here, but it's too late to take it back now. The council convenes once more to discuss the additions made, and you take the lead to get it over with. "The Amethyst Order's Patriarch has come in person," you say, to raised eyebrows, "and he's brought two battle wizards besides. I was also able to get a Magister from the Light Order to attend." You look across the table at Van Hal, trying to communicate your concerns, and you think it works; his expression is more wary than you'd expect from someone who just had four theoretically friendly battle wizards dropped in his lap. "I'm sure they'll make themselves useful," he notes. "Anton?" "The Emperor sent the Altdorf Company of Honour," he reports happily. "Though I don't know why it's called that, because it's actually a Regiment." "It started as a Company, and the name stuck," Gustav replies. "They recruit the best and bravest from the other regiments of Altdorf. Highly-trained, well-equipped, and ferocious in battle." "I had hoped for more from the Emperor than a single regiment, but I suppose as regiments go... Kasmir, how did Altdorf treat you?" "Not well, I'm afraid. The Ar-Ulric has backed the Middenland land claims, and in response the Grand Theogonist has backed Nordland. He's completely preoccupied with matters up north, and has no attention to spare for matters here." Kasmir's tone is very carefully neutral. Van Hal opens his mouth to reply, and then just sighs. "Very well. Herr Schultz, how was your visit home?" "Talabheim is always a jewel," he says, "but sadly, they're unable to contribute more than they have." "If memory serves, the Knights came of their own accord, and Talabecland has actually contributed nothing," Van Hal notes, and Schultz is unable to meet his eye. He watches the man for another moment, before turning to Gustav. "News from the dwarves?" "They've sent a Throng," he reports plainly. "Four thousand dwarves, including about five hundred Doomseekers. Their leader spent about a week comparing ancestry with Thori and then placed his forces under the Throng of Zhufbar, so he can concentrate on seeking his own death." "I daresay they'll find Sylvania suitable. Wilhelmina?" "The Moot was very welcoming, doubly so when they learned why I'd come. They've been watching Stirland, and are happy that we've been carving grazelands from Sylvania instead of pursuing revanchism against them. The bulk of their contributions are in the form of food for the final leg of the campaign, but they've also sent two regiments of archers." "I suppose a halfling can pull a bowstring as well as a man can. And with those regiments, they've exceeded the manpower contributions of the rest of the Empire combined." He glances down at his notes. "The Throng of Zhufbar's reinforcements aren't quite what was hoped - apparently the beastmen in the lower levels of their hold weren't as pacified as they appeared - but they have increased their artillery considerably. That's the final additions to our army - not as much as I'd hoped, but better than I'd feared. Now all that remains is to plan, and to march." He drums his fingers against the table. "Anton, you're to return to Wurtbad." "But-!" "No arguments. If all goes wrong, you are to keep Stirland together until a successor is chosen. Wilhelmina, go with him. You've given me far too many years to fall in battle, and you can coordinate the supply train just as easily from there." She doesn't look happy, but she nods. "Everyone else, now's the last chance to seek employment elsewhere." Gustav snorts a laugh at the thought, Kasmir makes no reaction, and Schultz wavers for a moment before apparently coming to a decision, and he remains silent. It doesn't even occur to you that you, too, should be considering your options until later. Van Hal smiles. "Very well. Let's plan the end to this campaign." --- There are, as it turns out, three very different ways to go about things, and the differences come down to the inherent ambiguity of 'Drakenhof'. Because there is a town of Drakenhof, which intelligence suggests is in the sway of some 'Countess von Carstein', and there's Castle Drakenhof, some way upriver and built perilously atop a mountain peak, that Van Hal is determined to see destroyed. Spoiler: Castle Drakenhof Spoiler: Campaign Map The first plan is to blaze a path along the eastern edge of the Haunted Hills, ford the river as close to Drakenhof as possible, and besiege it, ignoring the town of Drakenhof altogether. This has the advantage of simplicity and means the majority of the supply lines are on the controlled side of the river, but it does leave anyone within the town free to act however they desire to disrupt the attack. The second plan is to ford instead at the town of Drakenhof, and assault and take the town with the element of surprise. If it works, this would result in a fortified forward base to operate out of while still having the supply lines mostly on the purged side. The third plan is to acknowledge that trying to ford a river in early spring is ridiculous, and to instead cross at the bridge at Pfaffbach and go up the road towards Castle Drakenhof, taking the village of Regrakhof and the town of Drakenhof as you go. This means the supply lines will be almost entirely on the unoccupied side of the river, but it does have the advantage of pre-existing bridges and roads, and the nearby population centers will be taken out of play. The conversation is going back and forth; Gustav likes the simplicity of the first plan, Kasmir supports the second out of caution for what evils the town may hold, and Schultz favours the third plan for practical, logistical reasons. Van Hal sits back, staring at the map thoughtfully. What is your thoughts on the matter? [ ] Plan One: The towns and villages are distractions. We should go straight for Castle Drakenhof. [ ] Plan Two: We can't leave the 'Countess' in play. Strike at the town of Drakenhof. [ ] Plan Three: Pre-existing roads and bridges are necessary for a proper supply line. We should go via Pfaffbach. Whichever plan is chosen, where do you plan to be for the opening stages of the siege? [ ] By Van Hal's side, whatever happens. [ ] With the rank and file; your display at Fang Island has made you a balm for morale. [ ] With your fellow wizards, so that you can work with them on the magical side of things. [ ] With the dwarves; you hope to make a good impression on them. [ ] With Asarnil. Your Shadowsteed means you can keep pace with him, and why would you pass up the chance to fight alongside a dragon? [ ] Bugger this for a game of soldiers. I'm going back to Wurtbad. Total Forces: Lords and Heroes Elector Count Abelhelm Van Hal Marshal Gustav von Jungfreud Journeywoman Mathilde Weber, Grey Wizard Magister Patriarch Viggo Hexensohn, Amethyst Wizard Lord Magister Sigismund Herwig, Amethyst Battle Wizard Magister Marike Grünberg, Amethyst Battle Wizard Magister Jovi Sunscryer, Light Wizard Asarnil the Dragonlord Thori Stoneheart, Dwarf Thane Narfi Hammerfist, Dwarf Engineer Giantslayer Bjorgvin, Dwarf Slayer Army of Stirland 12,000 spearmen 7,000 swordsmen 9,000 crossbowmen 800 pistoliers (dismounted) 500 greatswords 70 cannon 20 mortars Throngs of Zhufbar and Karak Kadrin 6,000 Warriors 2,000 Miners 4,000 Thunderers 1,500 Quarrelers 500 Slayers 40 cannon 30 grudge throwers 20 organ guns Other Black Guard of Morr, 1,000 knights Talabeclander Knightly Orders, 400 knights Altdorf Company of Honour, 2,500 infantry Halfling Regiments, 5,000 archers